<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000270863"><TermName>multiple endocrine adenomatosis</TermName><TermPronunciation>(MUL-tih-pul EN-doh-krin A-deh-NOH-muh-TOH-sis)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare, inherited disorder that affects the endocrine glands and can cause tumors in the parathyroid and pituitary glands and the pancreas. These tumors  are usually benign (not cancer). They cause the glands to secrete high levels of hormones, which can lead to other medical problems, such as kidney stones, fertility problems, and severe ulcers. In some cases, tumors inside the pancreas can become malignant (cancer). Also called MEN1 syndrome, multiple endocrine neoplasia type 1 syndrome,  and Wermer syndrome.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000709798" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;multiple endocrine adenomatosis&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000709797" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;adenomatosis endocrina múltiple&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>adenomatosis endocrina múltiple</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno hereditario poco frecuente que afecta las glándulas endocrinas y puede causar tumores en las glándulas paratiroideas y la hipófisis, así como en el páncreas. Estos tumores por lo general son benignos (no cancerosos), y hacen que las glándulas segreguen concentraciones altas de hormonas, lo que puede conllevar a otros problemas médicos como cálculos renales, problemas de fecundidad y úlceras graves.   En algunos casos, los tumores dentro del páncreas se pueden convertir en malignos (cáncer).   También se llama síndrome de NEM1, síndrome de neoplasia endocrina múltiple tipo 1,  y síndrome de Wermer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2003-01-26</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2009-06-18</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
