<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000270731"><TermName>3-dimensional conformal radiation therapy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(3-dih-MEN-shuh-nul kun-FOR-mul RAY-dee-AY-shun THAYR-uh-pee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>3-dimensional conformal radiation therapy involves the use of computed tomography (CT) imaging in the planning of radiation therapy. The CT scan provides not only 3-dimensional imaging of the target and surrounding normal tissues, but also information about tissue density and tissue depth from the skin to the target. These parameters are critical in calculating the dose distribution. In addition to CT imaging, supplemental imaging modalities, such as magnetic resonance imaging or positron emission tomography, can be used to improve target delineation. With 3-dimensional conformal radiation therapy, conformal beams are used to shape the dose delivered to the target, and wedges or compensators can be used to optimize the dose distribution. Conformal beams are shaped either with a high-density material (e.g., Cerrobend) that allows beam contouring or with multi-leaf collimators, which are an array of high-density leaves (usually tungsten) situated in the head of the linear accelerator (LINAC) whose position is controlled via independent stepping motors that allow beam shaping. Wedges are high-density devices that are placed on the head of the LINAC to act as a tissue compensator and/or beam modifier. The effect of a wedge can be created by a moving jaw at the head of the LINAC. With 3-dimensional conformal radiation therapy, variable field weighting and/or use of different energies (higher energies are more penetrating) are additional tools that enable optimization of the dose distribution.  Also called 3-dimensional radiation therapy and 3D-CRT.</DefinitionText><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure that uses a computer to create a 3-dimensional picture of the tumor. This allows doctors to give the highest possible dose of radiation to the tumor, while sparing the normal tissue as much as possible. Also called 3-dimensional radiation therapy and 3D-CRT.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710233" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;3-dimensional conformal radiation therapy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><SpanishTermName>radioterapia conformada tridimensional</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>La radioterapia conformada tridimensional consiste en el uso de imaginología por tomografía computarizada (TC) durante la planificación de la radioterapia.  La exploración por TC no solo provee  una imagen tridimensional  de la lesión y los tejidos normales circundantes, sino también información sobre la densidad y profundidad del tejido desde la piel hasta la lesión.  Estos parámetros son de suma importancia al momento de calcular la distribución de la dosis.  Además de la imaginología por TC, modalidades de imaginología suplementarias, como la imaginología por resonancia magnética o la tomografía por emisión de positrones se pueden usar para mejorar la delineación de la lesión. Con la radioterapia conformada tridimensional se usan rayos conformados para darle forma a la dosis administrada a la lesión y se pueden usar cuñas o compensadores para optimizar la distribución de la dosis.  Los haces conformados se formulan ya sea con un material de densidad alta (como Cerrobend) que permite la delimitación de los haces  o mediante  colimadores multiláminas los cuales forman un arreglo con hojas de alta densidad (por lo general tungsteno) situados en el cabezal del acelerador linear (LINAC) cuya posición se controla con motores de pasos independientes que permiten dar forma a los haces.  Las cuñas son partículas de densidad alta que se colocan en el cabezal del LINAC para fungir como compensador tisular o modificador de haz. El efecto de una cuña se puede crear mediante el movimiento de una pieza en forma de quijada al cabezal del LINAC.  Con la radioterapia conformada tridimensional, el peso del campo variable o el uso de diferentes potencias (mientras más alta es la potencia más penetrante es esta) son instrumentos adicionales que permiten la optimización en la distribución de la dosis.    También se llama radioterapia tridimensional y RTC-3D.</DefinitionText><Audience>Health professional</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento para el que se usa una computadora para crear una imagen tridimensional del tumor. Esto permite que los médicos administren la dosis de radiación más alta posible al tumor y, a la vez, protejan lo más posible de la radiación al tejido normal. También se llama radioterapia tridimensional y RTC-3D.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2003-01-26</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2007-03-01</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
