<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000270742"><TermName>targeted therapy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(TAR-geh-ted THAYR-uh-pee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of treatment that uses drugs or other substances to identify and attack specific types of cancer cells with less harm to normal cells. Some targeted therapies block the action of certain enzymes, proteins, or other molecules involved in the growth and spread of cancer cells. Other types of targeted therapies help the immune system kill cancer cells or deliver toxic substances directly to cancer cells and kill them. Targeted therapy may have fewer side effects than other types of cancer treatment. Most targeted therapies are either small molecule drugs or monoclonal antibodies.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710252" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;targeted therapy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710251" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;terapia dirigida&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>terapia dirigida</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de tratamiento en el que se usan medicamentos u otras sustancias para identificar y combatir tipos específicos de células cancerosas y que causa menos daño a las células normales. Algunas terapias dirigidas impiden la acción de ciertas enzimas, proteínas u otras moléculas que participan en el crecimiento y diseminación de las células cancerosas. Otros tipos de terapia dirigida ayudan al sistema inmunitario a destruir las células cancerosas o a llevar sustancias tóxicas directamente a estas y destruirlas.   La terapia dirigida puede producir  menos efectos secundarios que otros tipos de tratamiento del cáncer. La mayoría de terapias dirigidas son medicamentos de moléculas pequeñas o anticuerpos monoclonales.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2003-01-26</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-08-30</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/types/targeted-therapies/targeted-therapies-fact-sheet">Targeted Cancer Therapies
</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/tipos/terapia-dirigida/hoja-informativa-terapias-dirigidas">Terapias dirigidas contra el cáncer
</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
