<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000270858"><TermName>FAMMM syndrome</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>An inherited condition marked by the following: (1) one or more first- or second-degree relatives (parent, sibling, child, grandparent, grandchild, aunt, or uncle) with malignant melanoma; (2) many moles, some of which are atypical (asymmetrical, raised, and/or different shades of tan, brown, black, or red) and often of different sizes; and (3) moles that have specific features when examined under a microscope. FAMMM syndrome increases the risk of melanoma and may increase the risk of pancreatic cancer. Also called familial atypical multiple mole melanoma syndrome.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000731408" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;FAMMM syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000731409" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de FAMMM&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>síndrome de FAMMM</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección  hereditaria que tiene las siguientes características: 1) uno o más parientes de primer o segundo grado (padre, hermano, hijo, abuelo, nieto, tía o tío) con melanoma maligno; 2) muchos lunares, algunos de los cuales son atípicos (asimétricos, elevados o de diferentes tonalidades de color tostado, marrón, negro o rojo) y, con frecuencia, de tamaños distintos; y 3) lunares que tienen características específicas cuando se examinan bajo un microscopio. El síndrome de FAMMM aumenta el riesgo de melanoma y puede aumentar el riesgo de cáncer de páncreas. También se llama síndrome de melanoma familiar atípico con molas múltiples.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2003-01-26</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-08-20</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
