<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000269473"><TermName>UVB radiation</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… RAY-dee-AY-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Invisible rays that are part of the energy that comes from the sun. UVB radiation causes sunburn, darkening and thickening of the outer layer of the skin, and melanoma and other types of skin cancer. It may also cause problems with the eyes and the immune system. Skin specialists recommend that people use sunscreens that protect the skin from ultraviolet radiation. In medicine, UVB radiation also comes from special lamps or a laser and is used to treat certain skin conditions such as psoriasis, vitiligo, and skin tumors of cutaneous T-cell lymphoma. Also called ultraviolet B radiation.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710281" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;UVB radiation&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710282" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;radiación UVB&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>radiación UVB</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Rayos invisibles que forman parte de la energía que viene del sol. La radiación UVB causa quemaduras de sol, oscurecimiento y engrosamiento de la capa exterior de la piel, y melanoma y otros tipos de cáncer de piel. También puede causar problemas en los ojos y el sistema inmunitario. Los especialistas de la piel recomiendan que las personas usen filtros solares que protegen la piel de la radiación ultravioleta. En el campo de la medicina, la radiación UVB también surge de lámparas o rayos láser especiales que se usan para tratar ciertas afecciones de la piel como soriasis, vitiligo y tumores de la piel causados por el linfoma cutáneo de células T. También se llama radiación ultravioleta B.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2002-12-21</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2010-06-14</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
