<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000256554"><TermName>AJCC staging system</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... STAY-jing SIS-tem)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A system to describe the amount and spread of cancer in a patient’s body, using TNM. T describes the size of the tumor and any spread of cancer into nearby tissue; N describes spread of cancer to nearby lymph nodes; and M describes metastasis (spread of cancer to other parts of the body). This system was created and is updated by the American Joint Committee on Cancer (AJCC) and the International Union Against Cancer (UICC). The AJCC staging system is used to describe most types of cancer. Also called TNM staging system.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710109" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;AJCC staging system&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710110" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sistema de estadificación del AJCC&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>sistema de estadificación del AJCC</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Sistema que se usa para describir tanto la cantidad de cáncer como su diseminación en el cuerpo de un paciente mediante las letras TNM. La letra T  describe el tamaño del tumor y la diseminación del cáncer hacia el tejido cercano; la letra N describe la diseminación del cáncer hasta los ganglios linfáticos cercanos y la letra M describe las metástasis (diseminación del cáncer hacia otras partes del cuerpo). El American Joint Committee on Cancer  (AJCC) y la International Union Against Cancer (UICC) crearon este sistema y se encargan de actualizarlo. El sistema de estadificación del AJCC se usa para describir la mayoría de los tipos de cáncer. También se llama sistema de estadificación TNM.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2011-10-05</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
