<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000389464"><TermName>oral cavity</TermName><TermPronunciation>(OR-ul KA-vih-tee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Refers to the mouth. It includes the lips, the lining inside the cheeks and lips, the front two thirds of the tongue, the upper and lower gums, the floor of the mouth under the tongue, the bony roof of the mouth, and the small area behind the wisdom teeth.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713422" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;oral cavity&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713423" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cavidad oral&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000716338" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomy of the oral cavity; drawing shows the lip, hard palate, soft palate, retromolar trigone, front two-thirds of the tongue, gingiva, buccal mucosa, and floor of mouth. Also shown are the teeth, uvula, and tonsil." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Anatomy of the oral cavity. The oral cavity includes the lips, hard palate (the bony front portion of the roof of the mouth), soft palate (the muscular back portion of the roof of the mouth), retromolar trigone (the area behind the wisdom teeth), front two-thirds of the tongue, gingiva (gums), buccal mucosa (the inner lining of the lips and cheeks), and floor of the mouth under the tongue.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000732817" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomía de la cavidad oral; el dibujo muestra el labio, el paladar duro, el paladar blando, el trígono retromolar, los dos tercios delanteros de la lengua, la encía, la mucosa bucal y el piso de la boca. También se muestran los dientes, la úvula y la amígdala." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Anatomía de la cavidad oral. La cavidad oral incluye los labios, el paladar duro (la porción delantera ósea del techo de la boca) el paladar blando (la porción muscular posterior del techo de la boca), el trígono retromolar (el área entre las muelas del juicio), los dos tercios delanteros de la lengua, las encías, la mucosa bucal (el revestimiento interno de los labios y las mejillas) y el piso de la boca debajo de la lengua.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cavidad oral</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Se refiere a la boca. Incluye los labios, el revestimiento interior de las mejillas y los labios, los dos tercios anteriores de la lengua, la encías superior e inferior, el piso de la boca debajo de la lengua, la parte ósea del paladar y el área pequeña detrás de las muelas del juicio.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2004-09-03</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2012-05-16</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/head-and-neck">Head and Neck Cancer</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
