<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000363609"><TermName>stage IIIC breast cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... brest KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage III is
          divided into stages IIIA, IIIB, and IIIC. In stage IIIC, no
          tumor is found in the breast or the tumor may be any size.
          Cancer may have spread to the skin of the breast and caused
          swelling or an ulcer and/or has spread to the chest wall.
          Also, cancer has spread to: (1) 10 or more axillary lymph
          nodes; or (2) lymph nodes above or below the collarbone; or
          (3) axillary lymph nodes and lymph nodes near the
          breastbone. Cancer that has spread to the skin of the
          breast may also be inflammatory breast cancer. For
          treatment, stage IIIC breast cancer is divided into
          operable and inoperable stage IIIC.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711686" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IIIC breast cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711687" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de mama en estadio IIIC&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000732263" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIIC breast cancer. The drawing on the left shows cancer in lymph nodes in the axilla. The drawing in the middle shows cancer in lymph nodes above the collarbone. The drawing on the right shows cancer in lymph nodes in the axilla and in lymph nodes near the breastbone." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Stage IIIC breast cancer. No tumor is found in the breast or the tumor may be any size and may have spread to the chest wall and/or to the skin of the breast and caused swelling or an ulcer. Also, cancer has spread to 10 or more axillary lymph nodes (left panel); OR to lymph nodes above or below the collarbone (middle panel); OR to axillary lymph nodes and lymph nodes near the breastbone (right panel). Cancer that has spread to the skin of the breast may be inflammatory breast cancer.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000740903" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de mama  en estadio lllC. El dibujo de la izquierda  muestra cáncer en los ganglios linfáticos de la axila. El dibujo del medio muestra cáncer en los ganglios linfáticos encima de la clavícula. El dibujo de la derecha  muestra cáncer en ganglios linfáticos de la axila y en los ganglios linfáticos cerca del esternón." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de mama  en estadio lllC. No se encuentra tumor en la mama o el tumor puede ser de cualquier tamaño, y se pudo diseminar hasta la pared del pecho o  la piel de la mama . Además, el cáncer se diseminó hasta 10 o más ganglios linfáticos de la axila (dibujo de la izquierda); o hasta los ganglios linfáticos encima o debajo de la clavícula (dibujo del medio); O a los ganglios linfáticos de la axila o debajo de la clavícula (dibujo del medio); O hasta los ganglios linfáticos de la axila y  los ganglios linfáticos cerca del esternón (dibujo de la derecha). </Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de mama en estadio IIIC</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El
estadio III se divide en estadios IIIA, IIIB y
IIIC. En el estadio IIIC,
no se encuentra un tumor en la
mama o el tumor puede medir cualquier tamaño. El cáncer se
puede haber diseminado hasta la piel de la mama y haber
causado hinchazón o una úlcera, o se diseminó
hasta la pared del
pecho.
Además, el cáncer
se diseminó hacia 1) 10 o más
ganglios linfáticos axilares; o 2) los ganglios linfáticos
por encima o debajo de la clavícula; o 3) los ganglios
linfáticos axilares o los ganglios linfáticos cerca del
esternón. El cáncer que se diseminó hasta la piel de la
mama también puede ser cáncer de mama inflamatorio. Para el
tratamiento, el cáncer de mama en estadio IIIC se divide en
estadio IIIC operable o estadio IIIC no
operable.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2004-03-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2012-10-02</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062955">Breast Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256762">Cáncer de seno (mama): Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
