<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000386227"><TermName>sestamibi breast imaging</TermName><TermPronunciation>(SES-tuh-MIH-bee brest IH-muh-jing)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of breast imaging test that is used to detect cancer cells in the breasts of some women who have had abnormal mammograms, or who have dense breast tissue.  It is not used for screening or in place of a mammogram. In this test, a woman receives an injection of a small amount of a radioactive substance called technetium 99, which is taken up by cancer cells, and a gamma camera is used to take pictures of the breasts. Also called Miraluma test and scintimammography.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713222" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sestamibi breast imaging&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713221" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;gammagrafía de mama con sestamibi&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>gammagrafía de mama con sestamibi</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de prueba de imaginología de la mama que se usa para detectar células cancerosas en las mamas de algunas mujeres que han tenido mamografías anormales del tejido de la mama o cuyo tejido de la mama es denso. No se usa para la detección ni en lugar de un mamograma. En esta prueba, una mujer recibe una inyección con una pequeña cantidad de una sustancia radiactiva llamada tecnecio 99, que es absorbida por las células cancerosas; a continuación, se usa una cámara de rayos gamma para tomar imágenes de las mamas. También se llama centellografía de la mama y prueba de Miraluma.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2004-08-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2008-11-21</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
