<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000390305"><TermName>paraganglioma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(PAYR-uh-GANG-glee-OH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare, usually benign tumor that develops from cells of the paraganglia. Paraganglia are a collection of cells that came from embryonic nervous tissue, and are found near the adrenal glands and some blood vessels and nerves. Paragangliomas that develop in the adrenal gland are called pheochromocytomas. Those that develop outside of the adrenal glands near blood vessels or nerves are called glomus tumors or chemodectomas.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713188" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;paraganglioma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713187" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;paraganglioma&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000739011" type="image/jpeg" alt="Paraganglioma of the head and neck; drawing shows a tumor near the carotid artery in the head and neck. " language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Paraganglioma of the head and neck. A rare tumor that often forms near the carotid artery. It may also form along nerve pathways in the head and neck and in other parts of the body.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000751475" type="image/jpeg" alt="Paraganglioma de la cabeza y el cuello; la imagen muestra el tumor cerca de la arteria carótida en la cabeza y el cuello." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Paraganglioma de la cabeza y el cuello. Tumor poco común que con frecuencia se forma cerca de la arteria carótida.  También se puede formar sobre las vías nerviosas en la cabeza y el cuello y otras partes del cuerpo.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>paraganglioma</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tumor poco común que, por lo general, es benigno; se deriva de las células de los paraganglios. Los paraganglios son un conjunto de células que provienen del tejido nervioso embrionario; se encuentran cerca de las glándulas suprarrenales y algunos vasos sanguíneos y nervios. Los paragangliomas que se presentan en la glándula suprarrenal se llaman feocromocitomas. Aquellos que se desarrollan fuera de las glándulas suprarrenales, cerca de los vasos sanguíneos o los nervios, se llaman tumores glómicos o quemodectomas.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2004-11-22</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-08-08</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
