<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000377729"><TermName>percutaneous transhepatic biliary drainage</TermName><TermPronunciation>(per-kyoo-TAY-nee-us TRANZ-heh-PA-tik BIH-lee-ayr-ee DRAY-nij)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure to drain bile to relieve pressure in the bile ducts caused by a blockage. An x-ray of the liver and bile ducts locates the blockage of bile flow. Images made by ultrasound guide placement of a stent (tube), which remains in the liver. Bile drains through the stent into the small intestine or into a collection bag outside the body. This procedure may relieve jaundice before surgery. Also called percutaneous transhepatic cholangiodrainage and PTCD.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000703947" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;percutaneous transhepatic biliary drainage&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000703948" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;drenaje biliar transhepático percutáneo&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>drenaje biliar transhepático percutáneo</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento que se usa para drenar la bilis y aliviar la presión que causa una obstrucción en los conductos biliares. Una radiografía del hígado y los conductos biliares localiza la obstrucción que impide el flujo de la bilis. Se usan imágenes creadas por ecografía para guiar la instalación de una cánula (tubo) que permanece en el hígado. La bilis drena a través de la cánula hacia el intestino delgado o una bolsa de recolección fuera del cuerpo. Este procedimiento puede aliviar la ictericia antes de la cirugía. También se llama colangiodrenaje transhepático percutáneo y DBTP.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2004-06-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2008-02-21</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
