<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000350231"><TermName>interleukin-1</TermName><TermPronunciation>(in-ter-LOO-kin …)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>One of a group of related proteins made by leukocytes (white blood cells) and other cells in the body. Interleukin-1 is made mainly by one type of white blood cell, the macrophage, and helps another type of white blood cell, the lymphocyte, fight infections. It also helps leukocytes pass through blood vessel walls to sites of infection and causes fever by affecting areas of the brain that control body temperature. There are two forms of interleukin-1, alpha and beta, which act the same. Interleukin-1 made in the laboratory is used as a biological response modifier to boost the immune system in cancer therapy. Interleukin-1 is a type of cytokine. Also called IL-1.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711139" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;interleukin-1&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711140" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;interleucina-1&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>interleucina-1</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Pertenece a un grupo de proteínas relacionadas que elaboran los leucocitos (glóbulos blancos) y otras células del cuerpo. Principalmente los macrófagos, un tipo de glóbulos blancos, elaboran la interleucina-1 y esta ayuda a otro tipo de glóbulos blancos, los linfocitos, a combatir infecciones.   También ayuda a  que los leucocitos pasen a través de las paredes de los vasos sanguíneos y lleguen a los sitios de la infección; además, causa fiebre porque afecta zonas del cerebro que controlan la temperatura del cuerpo. Hay dos formas de interleucina-1, alfa y beta, que actúan de la misma manera. La interleucina-1 que se produce en el laboratorio se usa en el tratamiento del cáncer como modificador de la respuesta biológica para estimular el sistema inmunitario. La interleucina-1 es un tipo de citocina. También se llama IL-1.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2003-12-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2010-07-19</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
