<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000368448"><TermName>stage III nonmelanoma skin cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… non-MEH-luh-NOH-muh skin KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The tumor has spread to the jaw, eye socket, or side of the skull. Cancer may have spread to one lymph node on the same side of the body as the tumor. The lymph node is not larger than 3 centimeters; or, cancer has spread to one lymph node on the same side of the body as the tumor. The lymph node is not larger than 3 centimeters and one of the following is true:  (1) the tumor is not larger than 2 centimeters at its widest point and may have one high-risk feature (is thicker than 2 millimeters, has spread into the lower layer of the dermis or into the layer of fat below the skin, has grown and spread along nerve pathways, began on an ear or on a lip that has hair on it, or has cells that look very different from normal cells under a microscope);  or (2) the tumor is larger than 2 centimeters at its widest point; or (3) the tumor is any size and has two or more high-risk features (is thicker than 2 millimeters, has spread into the lower layer of the dermis or into the layer of fat below the skin, has grown and spread along nerve pathways, began on an ear or on a lip that has hair on it, or has cells that look very different from normal cells under a microscope).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711690" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III nonmelanoma skin cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711691" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de piel no melanoma en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000599856" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage III nonmelanoma skin cancer (1); drawing shows a primary tumor in one arm and parts of the body where it may spread, including the bones of the jaw, eye socket, or side of the skull." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="en">Stage III nonmelanoma skin cancer (1). Cancer has spread from the primary tumor to bones of the jaw, eye socket, or side of the skull.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000726705" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage III nonmelanoma skin cancer (2); drawing shows a primary tumor in one arm and cancer in a lymph node on the same side of the body as the primary tumor.  Insets show 2 centimeters is about the size of a peanut and 3 centimeters is about the size of a grape." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_5"><Caption language="en">Stage III nonmelanoma skin cancer (2). Cancer has spread to one lymph node that is 3 centimeters or smaller and is on the same side of the body as the primary tumor. Also, the tumor is  2 centimeters or smaller at its widest point and may have one high-risk feature; OR the tumor is larger than 2 centimeters at its widest point; OR the tumor is any size and has two or more high-risk features. There are five high-risk features: (1) the tumor is thicker than 2 millimeters; (2) the tumor has spread into the lower layer of the skin or into the layer of fat below the skin; (3) the tumor has grown and spread along nerve pathways; (4) the tumor began on an ear or on a lip that has hair on it; and (5) the tumor has cells that look very different from normal cells under a microscope.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000738952" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de la piel no melanoma en estadio III (1); el dibujo muestra un tumor primario en un brazo y partes del cuerpo donde se podría diseminar, como los huesos de la mandíbula, la cuenca del ojo o un costado del cráneo." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_6"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de la piel no melanoma en estadio III (1). El cáncer se diseminó desde el tumor primario hasta los huesos de la madíbula, la cuenca del ojo o un costado del cráneo.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000738953" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de la piel no melanoma en estadio III (2); el dibujo muestra un tumor primario en un brazo, y cáncer en un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuerpo que el tumor primario. En el recuadro, se observan 2 cm, que es el tamaño aproximado de un maní, y 3 cm, que es el tamaño aproximado de una uva." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_7"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de la piel no melanoma en estadio III (2). El cáncer se diseminó hasta un ganglio linfático que mide tres centímetros o menos, y está en el mismo lado del cuerpo que el tumor primario. Además, el tumor mide dos centímetros o menos en su parte más ancha y puede tener una característica de riesgo alto; O el tumor mide más de dos centímetros en su parte más ancha; O el tumor es de cualquier tamaño  y tiene dos o más características de riesgo alto. Hay cinco características de riesgo alto: 1) el tumor tiene más de dos milímetros de espesor; 2)  el tumor se diseminó hacia la capa inferior de la piel o hacia la capa de grasa debajo de esta; 3) el tumor creció y se diseminó a lo largo de las vías nerviosas; 4) el tumor empezó en una oreja o un labio que tienen vellos sobre ellos, y 5) el tumor tiene células con aspecto muy diferente al de las células normales cuando se las observa bajo un microscopio. </Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de piel no melanoma en estadio III</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El tumor se diseminó hasta la mandíbula, la cuenca de un ojo o un costado del cráneo. El cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuerpo  donde está el tumor. El ganglio linfático no mide más de tres centímetros o el cáncer se diseminó hasta un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuerpo  donde está el tumor. El ganglio linfático no mide más de tres centímetros y se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) el tumor no mide más de dos centímetros en su punto más ancho y puede tener una característica de riesgo alto (tiene más de dos milímetros de grosor, se diseminó hasta la capa más interna de la dermis o la capa de grasa debajo de la piel, creció y se diseminó a lo largo de las vías nerviosas, empezó en una oreja o un labio que tienen pelo, o tiene células con aspecto muy diferente al de las células normales cuando se las observa bajo un microscopio); o 2) el tumor mide más de dos centímetros en su punto más ancho, o 3) el tumor es de cualquier tamaño y tiene dos o más características de riesgo alto (tiene más de dos milímetros de grosor, se diseminó hacia la capa más interna de la dermis o hacia la capa de grasa debajo de la piel, creció y se diseminó a lo largo de las vías nerviosas, empezó en una oreja o en un labio que tiene pelo, o tiene células con aspecto muy diferente al de las células normales cuando se las observa bajo un microscopio).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2004-05-28</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2012-09-20</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258035">Skin Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256809">Cáncer de piel: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
