<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000340934"><TermName>pertuzumab</TermName><TermPronunciation>(per-TOO-zoo-mab)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used with other drugs to treat breast cancer that is HER2-positive. It is used in patients whose disease has spread to other parts of the body and has not been treated with anticancer drugs. It is also used before surgery in certain patients who are at high risk for their disease to recur (come back) or spread to other parts of the body. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Pertuzumab binds to HER2 on the surface of some cancer cells, and may kill them. It is a type of monoclonal antibody. Also called Perjeta.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711657" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pertuzumab&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711656" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pertuzumab&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>pertuzumab</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa con otros fármacos para tratar el cáncer de mama HER2 positivo. Se usa para pacientes cuya enfermedad se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo y  no se ha tratado con otros medicamentos contra el cáncer. También se usa antes de la cirugía para ciertos pacientes que tienen un riesgo alto de que la enfermedad recidive (vuelva) o se disemine a otras partes del cuerpo. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El pertuzumab se une al HER2 en la superficie de algunas células cancerosas y puede destruirlas. Es un tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal. También se llama Perjeta.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2003-10-25</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-10-23</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000735473">Pertuzumab</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
