<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000322883"><TermName>sensitivity</TermName><TermPronunciation>(SEN-sih-TIH-vih-tee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>In medicine, sensitivity may describe how well a test can detect a specific disease or condition in people who actually have the disease or condition. No test has 100% sensitivity because some people who have the disease or condition will not be identified by the test (false-negative test result). Sensitivity may also refer to the way the body reacts to the environment or to drugs, chemicals, or other substances. For example, a person who is sensitive to the sun may have skin that burns easily or get a rash when exposed to the sun. A person who is sensitive to caffeine may need only small amounts of it to feel its effects.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The frequency with which a test yields a true positive result among individuals who actually have the disease or the gene mutation in question. A test with high sensitivity has a low false-negative rate and thus does a good job of correctly identifying affected individuals.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000731826" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sensitivity&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000731827" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sensibilidad&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>sensibilidad</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>En medicina, la sensibilidad describe qué tan bien una prueba puede detectar una enfermedad o afección determinada en las personas que en realidad la presentan. Ninguna prueba tiene 100% de sensibilidad porque es posible que la prueba no identifique a algunas personas que presentan la enfermedad o la afección (resultado negativo falso de la prueba). La sensibilidad también se puede referir a la forma en que el cuerpo reacciona al ambiente o a medicamentos, químicos u otras sustancias. Por ejemplo, una persona que es sensible al sol puede tener una piel que se quema con facilidad o presentar sarpullido al exponerse al sol. Una persona sensible a la cafeína  puede necesitar solo cantidades muy pequeñas de esta para sentir sus efectos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2003-07-26</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-07-16</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
