<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000346488"><TermName>coenzyme Q10</TermName><TermPronunciation>(koh-EN-zime ...)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A nutrient that the body needs in small amounts to function and stay healthy. Coenzyme Q10 helps mitochondria (small structures in the cell) make energy. It is an antioxidant that helps prevent cell damage caused by free radicals (highly reactive chemicals). Coenzyme Q10 is fat-soluble (can dissolve in fats and oils) and is found in fatty fish, beef, soybeans, peanuts, and spinach. It is being studied in the prevention and treatment of some types of cancer and heart disease and in the relief of side effects caused by some cancer treatments.  Also called CoQ10, Q10, ubiquinone,  and vitamin Q10.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711566" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;coenzyme Q10&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711565" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;coenzima Q10&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>coenzima Q10</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Nutriente que el cuerpo necesita en pequeñas cantidades para funcionar y mantenerse sano. La coenzima Q10 ayuda a las mitocondrias (estructuras pequeñas de la célula) a producir energía. Es un antioxidante que ayuda a prevenir el daño que los radicales libres (sustancias químicas altamente reactivas) causan a las células. La coenzima Q10 es soluble en grasas (se puede disolver en grasas y aceites) y se encuentra en los peces grasos, la carne vacuna, la soya, los maníes y la espinaca.   Está en estudio para la prevención y el tratamiento de algunos tipos de cáncer y enfermedades del corazón,  y para aliviar los efectos secundarios que causan algunos tratamientos de cáncer. También se llama CoQ10, Q10, ubiquinona,  y vitamina Q10.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2003-11-20</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2008-12-12</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000446290">Coenzyme Q10</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
