<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000330109"><TermName>stage II childhood non-Hodgkin lymphoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... non-HOJ-kin lim-FOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cancer is found (1) in one area outside the lymph nodes and in nearby lymph nodes; or (2) in two or more areas above or below the diaphragm (the thin muscle below the lungs that helps breathing and separates the chest from the abdomen), and may or may not have spread to nearby lymph nodes; or (3) to have started in the stomach or intestines and can be completely removed by surgery. Cancer may or may not have spread to certain nearby lymph nodes.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711574" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage II childhood non-Hodgkin lymphoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711575" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;linfoma no Hodgkin infantil en estadio II&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000633800" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage II childhood non-Hodgkin lymphoma; drawing shows cancer in lymph node groups above and below the diaphragm, in the liver, and in the appendix. The colon and small intestine are also shown.  An inset shows a lymph node with a lymph vessel, an artery, and a vein. Lymphoma cells containing cancer are shown in the lymph node." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Stage II childhood non-Hodgkin lymphoma. Cancer is found in one area outside the lymph nodes and in nearby lymph nodes (a); or in two or more areas above (b) or below (c) the diaphragm; or cancer started in the stomach, appendix, or intestines (d) and can be removed by surgery. </Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000650476" type="image/jpeg" alt="Linfoma no Hodgkin infantil en estadio II; la imagen muestra el cáncer en grupos de ganglios linfáticos por encima o debajo del diafragma, en el hígado y en el apéndice. También se observan el intestino delgado y el colon. En el recuadro se observa un ganglio linfático con un vaso linfático, una arteria y una vena. En el ganglio linfático se observan las células de linfoma (cancerosas)." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Linfoma no Hodgkin infantil en estadio II. El cáncer se encuentra en un área fuera de los ganglios linfáticos y en ganglios linfáticos cercanos (a); o en dos o más áreas por encima (b) o debajo (c) del diafragma; o el cáncer empezó en el estómago, el apéndice o los intestinos (d) y se puede extirpar mediante cirugía.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>linfoma no Hodgkin infantil en estadio II</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>En el estadio II, el cáncer se encuentra en: 1)  un área afuera de los ganglios linfáticos y en los ganglios linfáticos cercanos; o 
2) en dos o más áreas por encima o debajo del diafragma (el músculo delgado bajo los pulmones que ayuda en la respiración y que separa el pecho del abdomen), y se puede haber diseminado o no hasta los ganglios linfáticos cercanos; o 
3) comenzó en el estómago o los intestinos y se puede extirpar completamente mediante cirugía. El cáncer se puede haber diseminado o no hasta ciertos ganglios linfáticos cercanos. 
</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2003-08-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2009-08-06</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
