<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000335062"><TermName>apocrine gland</TermName><TermPronunciation>(A-poh-krin ...)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of gland that is found in the skin, breast, eyelid, and ear. Apocrine glands in the breast secrete fat droplets into breast milk and those in the ear help form earwax. Apocrine glands in the skin and eyelid are sweat glands. Most apocrine glands in the skin are in the armpits, the groin, and the area around the nipples of the breast. Apocrine glands in the skin are scent glands, and their secretions usually have an odor. Another type of gland (eccrine gland or simple sweat gland) produces most sweat.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711348" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;apocrine gland&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711349" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;glándula apocrina&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>glándula apocrina</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de glándula que se encuentra en la piel, la mama, el párpado y el oido.La glándulas apocrinas de las mamas segregan gotas minúsculas de grasa en la leche materna y las de los oidos ayudan en la formación de la cerilla. Las glándulas apocrinas de la piel y los párpados son glándulas sudoríficas. La mayoría de las glándulas apocrinas de la piel están en las axilas, las ingles y el área alrededor de los pezones. Las glándulas apocrinass de la piel liberan esencias y, por lo general, sus secreciones tienen olor. Otro tipo de glándula (la glándula ecrina o glándula sudorífica simple) produce la mayor parte del sudor.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2003-09-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2004-11-04</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
