<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000389271"><TermName>green tea extract</TermName><TermPronunciation>(green tee EK-strakt)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A mixture that is prepared from the leaves of the Camellia sinensis plant. It contains substances called flavonoids and polyphenols, which are antioxidants. Antioxidants help protect cells from damage caused by certain chemicals that may increase the risk of cancer and other diseases. Green tea extract may be taken to treat certain conditions. It is also being studied in the prevention of cancer and other diseases.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000730790" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;green tea extract&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000730791" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;extracto de té verde&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>extracto de té verde</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Una mezcla que se prepara con las hojas de la planta Camellia sinensis.  Esta contiene sustancias que se llaman flavonoides y polifenoles, las cuales son antioxidantes.  Los antioxidantes ayudan a proteger las células del daño que causan ciertos químicos los cuales pueden aumentar el riesgo de cáncer y otras enfermedades. El extracto del té verde se puede tomar para tratar ciertos tipos de afecciones. También está en estudio para la prevención del cáncer y otras enfermedades.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2004-08-24</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/risk/diet/tea-fact-sheet">Tea and Cancer Prevention: Strengths and Limits of the Evidence</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/riesgo/dieta/hoja-informativa-te">El té y la prevención del cáncer: Solidez y límites de la evidencia científica</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
