<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000386203"><TermName>everolimus</TermName><TermPronunciation>(eh-veh-ROH-lih-mus)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used with another drug to treat some postmenopausal women with advanced breast cancer that is hormone-receptor positive and HER2 negative. It is also used to treat certain types of pancreatic cancer, a type of advanced kidney cancer, and subependymal giant cell astrocytoma in some patients, including children. Everolimus is being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. It stops cancer cells from dividing and may prevent the growth of new blood vessels that tumors need to grow. It also lowers the body’s immune response. It is a type of kinase inhibitor, a type of angiogenesis inhibitor, and a type of immunosuppressant. Also called Afinitor, Afinitor Disperz,  and RAD001.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713182" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;everolimus&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713181" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;everolimús&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>everolimus</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa con otro fármaco para tratar a algunas mujeres posmenopáusicas con cáncer de mama en estadio avanzado que es positivo al receptor hormonal y negativo al HER2. También se usa para tratar ciertos tipos de cáncer de páncreas, un tipo de cáncer de riñón en estadio avanzado, y algunos pacientes de astrocitoma subependimario de células gigantes, incluso en algunos niños. El everolimús está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Impide que las células cancerosas se multipliquen y podría prevenir la formación de  los nuevos vasos sanguíneos que los tumores necesitan para crecer. También disminuye la respuesta inmunitaria del cuerpo. Es un tipo de inhibidor de la cinasa, un tipo de inhibidor de la angiogénesis y un tipo de inmunodepresor. También se llama Afinitor, Afinitor Disperz,  y RAD001.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2004-08-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2012-09-25</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000640318">Everolimus</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
