<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000318814"><TermName>histone</TermName><TermPronunciation>(HIS-tone)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of protein found in chromosomes. Histones bind to DNA, help give chromosomes their shape, and help control the activity of genes.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711182" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;histone&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711181" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;histona&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000761781" type="image/jpeg" alt="Structure of DNA; drawing shows a chromosome, nucleosome, histone, gene, and nucleotide base pairs: guanine, cytosine, adenine, and thymine. Also shown is a cell and its nucleus." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Structure of DNA. Most DNA is found inside the nucleus of a cell, where it forms the chromosomes. Chromosomes have proteins called histones that bind to DNA. DNA has two strands that twist into the shape of a spiral ladder called a helix. DNA is made up of four building blocks called nucleotides: adenine (A), thymine (T), guanine (G), and cytosine (C). The nucleotides attach to each other (A with T, and G with C) to form chemical bonds called base pairs, which connect the two DNA strands. Genes are short pieces of DNA that carry specific genetic information.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000768574" type="image/jpeg" alt="Estructura del ADN; la imagen muestra un cromosoma, nucleosoma, histona, gen y pares de bases nucleotídicas: guanina, citosina, adenina y timina. También muestra una célula con su núcleo." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">La mayor parte del ADN se encuentra en el interior del núcleo de una célula, donde forma los cromosomas. Los cromosomas contienen proteínas llamadas histonas que se unen al ADN. El ADN tiene dos hebras que se enroscan y forman una escalera de caracol que se llama hélice. El ADN se compone de cuatro componentes básicos que se llaman nucleótidos: adenina (A), timina (T), guanina (G) y citosina (C). Los nucleótidos se unen entre sí (A con T y G con C) para formar enlaces químicos llamados pares de bases, que conectan las dos cadenas de ADN. Los genes son pequeñas piezas de ADN que transportan información genética específica. </Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>histona</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de proteína que se encuentra en los cromosomas. Las histonas se unen al ADN, ayudan a dar su forma a los cromosomas y ayudan a controlar la actividad de los genes.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2003-07-26</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2015-02-09</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
