<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000335073"><TermName>intensity-modulated radiation therapy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(in-TEN-sih-tee-MAH-juh-LAY-tid RAY-dee-AY-shun THAYR-uh-pee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Intensity-modulated radiation therapy is a 3-dimensional conformal radiation therapy  planning and delivery tool that shapes the radiation dose distribution and minimizes the dose to normal structures. Intensity-modulated radiation therapy implies inverse planning algorithms (i.e., the physician determines radiation treatment parameters to maximize dose to the target and minimize dose to normal tissues, and the planning algorithm maximizes the adherence to these parameters by modifying the beam spatially and/or temporally).  Spatial and temporal beam modification is often achieved by dynamically moving multi-leaf collimators. Intensity-modulated radiation therapy can also be achieved via custom-made beam compensators, which are derived from inverse planning algorithms. A novel way to deliver intensity-modulated radiation therapy is tomotherapy, in which a bank of collimated leaves shutter open and closed while rotating around the patient in a spiral manner. The unifying principle of all intensity-modulated radiation therapy planning and delivery methods is inverse planning.  Intensity-modulated radiation therapy results in a greater deposition of low doses to normal tissue, which may increase the risk of second malignancies.  Also called IMRT.</DefinitionText><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of 3-dimensional radiation therapy that uses computer-generated images to show the size and shape of the tumor. Thin beams of radiation of different intensities are aimed at the tumor from many angles. This type of radiation therapy reduces the damage to healthy tissue near the tumor. Also called IMRT.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711364" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;intensity-modulated radiation therapy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711365" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;radioterapia de intensidad modulada&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>radioterapia de intensidad modulada</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>La radioterapia de intensidad modulada es una herramienta para la planificación y administración de radioterapia conformal tridimensional (RTC-3D) que da forma  a la distribución de la dosis de radiación y minimiza la dosis a las estructuras normales. La radioterapia de intensidad modulada implica los algoritmos de planificación inversa (por ejemplo, el médico determina los parámetros del tratamiento de radiación para potenciar la dosis al objetivo y reducir al mínimo la dosis a los tejidos normales y la planificación del algoritmo maximiza la adherencia a estos parámetros mediante la modificación del haz de forma espacial o temporal).   La modificación  espacial o temporal del haz a menudo se logra mediante el movimiento dinámico de los colimadores multiláminas.  La radioterapia de intensidad modulada también se puede lograr mediante el uso de compensadores de haces,  los cuales se derivan de los algoritmos de planificación inversa. Una forma novedosa de administrar radioterapia de intensidad modulada es la tomoterapia, en la cual un banco de láminas colimatadas se abren y cierran a la vez que rotan alrededor del paciente en forma de espiral.  El principio unificador de  todos los métodos de  planificación y administración de radioterapia de intensidad modulada es la planificación inversa.  La radioterapia de intensidad modulada resulta de una deposición mayor de dosis bajas al tejido normal lo cual puede aumentar el riesgo de segundos cánceres. También se llama RTIM.</DefinitionText><Audience>Health professional</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de radioterapia tridimensional que usa imágenes creadas por una computadora para mostrar el tamaño y la forma de un tumor. Se dirigen haces delgados de radiación de diferentes intensidades y desde diferentes ángulos hacia el tumor. Este tipo de radioterapia reduce el daño a las células sanas que están cerca del tumor. También se llama RTIM.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2003-09-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2006-11-20</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
