<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000393539"><TermName>autologous expanded mesenchymal stem cells OTI-010</TermName><TermPronunciation>(aw-TAH-luh-gus … meh-ZEN-kih-mul …)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A product that is made of special stem cells taken from a patient’s bone marrow and grown in the laboratory. After a patient’s bone marrow is destroyed by treatment with whole body irradiation or chemotherapy, these cells are injected back into the patient to help rebuild bone marrow. Autologous expanded mesenchymal stem cells OTI-010 has been studied in the prevention of graft-versus-host disease during stem cell transplant in patients receiving treatment for cancer. Autologous expanded mesenchymal stem cells OTI-010 is used in cellular therapy. Also called Stromagen.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713396" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;autologous expanded mesenchymal stem cells OTI-010&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713397" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;células madre mesenquimatosas ampliadas autólogas OTI-010&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>células madre mesenquimatosas ampliadas autólogas OTI-010</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Producto elaborado con células madre especiales que se toman de la médula ósea del paciente y se cultivan en el laboratorio. Después de que el tratamiento con irradiación a todo el cuerpo o quimioterapia destruye la médula ósea del paciente, estas células se reinyectan en el paciente para ayudar a reconstruir la médula ósea. Las células madre mesenquimatosas ampliadas autólogas OTI-010 se han estudiado para la prevención de la enfermedad de injerto contra huésped durante un trasplante de células madres en los pacientes tratados por cáncer. Las células madre mesenquimatosas ampliadas autólogas OTI-010 se usan  para la terapia celular. También se llama Stromagen.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2004-11-22</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2009-01-19</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
