<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000339331"><TermName>variable expression</TermName><TermPronunciation>(VAYR-ee-uh-bul ek-SPREH-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Variation in the manner in which a trait is manifested. When there is variable expressivity, the trait may vary in clinical expression from mild to severe. For example, the condition neurofibromatosis type 1 may be mild, presenting with café-au-lait spots only, or may be severe, presenting with neurofibromas and brain tumors.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Refers to the difference in the way that signs and symptoms of a genetic condition can show up in individual patients who have that condition. For example, some patients with neurofibromatosis type 1 may have only mild symptoms, such as brown spots and freckling on the skin, and others may have more severe symptoms, such as brain tumors and tumors on the nerves.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000736955" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;variable expression&quot;" language="en" id="_2"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000747087" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;expresión variable&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>expresión variable</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Se refiere a la diferencia en la manera en que los signos y síntomas de una afección genética pueden aparecer en determinados pacientes que tienen esa afección. Por ejemplo, algunos pacientes de neurofibromatosis tipo 1 pueden tener solo síntomas leves, como manchas morenas y pecas en la piel, y otros pueden tener síntomas más graves, como tumores cerebrales y tumores en los nervios.  </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2003-10-03</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
