<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000390275"><TermName>enteral nutrition</TermName><TermPronunciation>(EN-teh-rul noo-TRIH-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A form of nutrition that is delivered into the digestive system as a liquid. Drinking nutrition beverages or formulas and tubefeeding are forms of enteral nutrition. People who are unable to meet their needs with food and beverages alone, and who do not have vomiting or uncontrollable diarrhea may be given tubefeedings. Tubefeeding can be used to add to what a person is able to eat or can be the only source of nutrition. A small feeding tube may be placed through the nose into the stomach or the small intestine, or it may be surgically placed into the stomach or the intestinal tract through an opening made on the outside of the abdomen, depending on how long it will be used.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000731244" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;enteral nutrition&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000731245" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;nutrición enteral&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>nutrición enteral</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de nutrición que se administra al sistema digestivo en forma de líquido. La toma de bebidas nutritivas o fórmulas alimenticias y la alimentación por sonda son formas de nutrición enteral. Las personas que no pueden satisfacer sus necesidades solamente con alimentos y bebidas, y que no padecen de vómitos o diarrea incontrolable, pueden ser alimentadas por sonda. La alimentación por sonda puede usarse para complementar lo que una persona puede comer o puede ser la única fuente de nutrición. Se coloca una pequeña sonda por la nariz, hasta el estómago o el intestino delgado, o esta puede colocarse quirúrgicamente en el estómago o en el intestino mediante una abertura en el exterior del abdomen de acuerdo con el período de tiempo que ha de ser utilizada.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2004-11-22</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
