<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000306500"><TermName>gonadotropin-releasing hormone agonist</TermName><TermPronunciation>(goh-NA-doh-TROH-pin-reh-LEE-sing HOR-mone A-guh-nist)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A substance that keeps the testicles and ovaries from making sex hormones by blocking other hormones that are needed to make them. In men, gonadotropin-releasing hormone agonists cause the testicles to stop making testosterone. In women, they cause the ovaries to stop making estrogen and progesterone. Some gonadotropin-releasing hormone agonists are used to treat prostate cancer.  Also called GnRH agonist, LH-RH agonist,  and luteinizing hormone-releasing hormone agonist.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711482" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;gonadotropin-releasing hormone agonist&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711483" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;agonista de la hormona liberadora de gonadotropina&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>agonista de la hormona liberadora de gonadotropina</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Sustancia que impide que los testículos y los ovarios elaboren hormonas sexuales al bloquear otras hormonas necesarias para producirlas. En los hombres,  los agonistas de la hormona liberadora de gonadotropina hacen que los testículos dejen de elaborar testosterona. En las mujeres, hacen que los ovarios dejen de elaborar estrógeno y progesterona. Algunos agonistas de la hormona liberadora de gonadotropina se usan para tratar el cáncer de próstata. También se llama agonista de la HL-HL, agonista de la HLGn,  y agonista de la hormona liberadora de hormona luteinizante.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2003-05-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-11-26</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/prostate/prostate-hormone-therapy-fact-sheet">Hormone Therapy for Prostate Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/prostata/hoja-informativa-terapia-hormonal">Terapia hormonal para el cáncer de próstata</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
