<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000368449"><TermName>stage IV nonmelanoma skin cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… non-MEH-luh-NOH-muh skin KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The tumor is any size and may have spread to the jaw, eye socket, or side of the skull. Cancer has spread to one lymph node on the same side of the body as the tumor and the affected node is larger than 3 centimeters but not larger than 6 centimeters, or cancer has spread to more than one lymph node on one or both sides of the body and the affected nodes are not larger than 6 centimeters; or, the tumor is any size and may have spread to the jaw, eye socket, skull, spine, or ribs. Cancer has spread to one lymph node that is larger than 6 centimeters; or, the tumor is any size and has spread to the base of the skull, spine, or ribs. Cancer may have spread to the lymph nodes; or, cancer has spread to other parts of the body, such as the lung.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711240" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IV nonmelanoma skin cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711241" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de piel no melanoma en estadio IV&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000600819" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IV nonmelanoma skin cancer (1); drawing shows a primary tumor in one arm with cancer in a lymph node on the same side of the body as the primary tumor.  Insets show 3 centimeters is about the size of a grape and 6 centimeters is about the size of an egg." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="en">Stage IV nonmelanoma skin cancer (1). The tumor is any size. Cancer has spread to one lymph node that is larger than 3 centimeters but not larger than 6 centimeters and is on the same side of the body as the tumor; OR to more than one lymph node 6 centimeters or smaller on one or both sides of the body; OR to one lymph node that is larger than 6 centimeters.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000726760" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IV nonmelanoma skin cancer (2); drawing shows a primary tumor in one arm and parts of the body where it may spread, such as the ribs, base of skull, spine, or lung. An inset shows cancer spreading through the blood and lymph nodes to other parts of the body." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_5"><Caption language="en">Stage IV nonmelanoma skin cancer (2). The tumor is any size and has spread to the base of the skull, spine, ribs, lung, or other parts of the body.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000738954" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de la piel no melanoma en estadio IV (1); el dibujo muestra un tumor primario en un brazo, con cáncer en un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuerpo que el tumor primario. El recuadro muestra que 3 centímetros es el tamaño aproximado de una uva y 6 centímetros es el tamaño aproximado de un huevo." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_6"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de la piel no melanoma en estadio IV (1). El tumor es de cualquier tamaño. El cáncer se diseminó  hasta un ganglio linfático que mide más de tres centímetros, pero no más de seis centímetros, y está del mismo lado del cuerpo que el tumor; O hasta más de un ganglio linfático de seis centímetros o menos en uno o ambos lados del cuerpo; O hasta un ganglio linfático de más de seis centímetros.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000738955" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de la piel no melanoma en estadio IV (2); el dibujo muestra un tumor primario en un brazo y partes del cuerpo hasta donde se puede diseminar, como las costillas, la base del cráneo, la columna vertebral o el pulmón. En un recuadro se observa el cáncer que se disemina a través de la sangre y los ganglios linfáticos hasta otras partes del cuerpo." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_7"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de la piel no melanoma en estadio IV (2). El tumor es de cualquier tamaño y se diseminó hasta la base del cráneo, la columna vertebral, las costillas, el pulmón u otras partes del cuerpo.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de piel no melanoma en estadio IV</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El tumor es de cualquier tamaño y se puede haber diseminado hasta la mandíbula, la cuenca de un ojo o un costado del cráneo. El cáncer se diseminó hasta un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuerpo que el tumor y el ganglio afectado mide más de tres centímetros, pero no más de seis centímetros, o el cáncer se diseminó hasta más de un ganglio linfático de uno o ambos lados del cuerpo y los ganglios afectados no miden más de seis centímetros, o el tumor es de cualquier tamaño y se puede haber diseminado hasta la mandíbula, la cuenca de un ojo, el cráneo, la columna vertebral o las costillas. El cáncer se diseminó hasta un ganglio linfático que mide más de seis centímetros o el tumor es de cualquier tamaño y se diseminó hasta la base del cráneo, la columna vertebral o las costillas. El cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta los ganglios linfáticos o el cáncer se diseminó hasta partes distantes del cuerpo, como el pulmón.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2004-05-28</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2012-09-20</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258035">Skin Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256809">Cáncer de piel: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
