<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000354453"><TermName>beta-human chorionic gonadotropin</TermName><TermPronunciation>(BAY-tuh-HYOO-mun KOR-ee-AH-nik goh-NA-doh-TROH-pin)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A hormone found in the blood and urine during pregnancy. It may also be found in higher than normal amounts in patients with some types of cancer, including testicular, ovarian, liver, stomach, and lung cancers, and in other disorders. Measuring the amount of beta-human chorionic gonadotropin in the blood or urine of cancer patients may help to diagnose cancer and find out how well cancer treatment is working. Beta-human chorionic gonadotropin is a type of tumor marker. Also called beta-hCG.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711578" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;beta-human chorionic gonadotropin&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000711579" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;gonadotropina coriónica humana beta&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>gonadotropina coriónica humana β</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Hormona que se encuentra en la sangre y la orina durante el embarazo. También se puede encontrar en cantidades más altas que las normales en pacientes de algunos tipos de cáncer como los cánceres de testículo, ovario, hígado, estómago, pulmón y  otros trastornos. La medición de la gonadotropina coriónica humana β en la sangre u orina de los pacientes puede ayudar a diagnosticar el cáncer y determinar si el tratamiento es eficaz. La gonadotropina coriónica humana β es un tipo de marcador tumoral. También se llama GCH-ß.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2004-01-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2012-02-06</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
