<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000428385"><TermName>stage IVB laryngeal cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... luh-RIN-jee-ul KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage IV is divided into stage IVA, stage IVB, and stage IVC. In stage IVB, (1) cancer has spread to the space in front of the spinal column,  surrounds the carotid artery, or has spread to parts of the chest; cancer may have spread to one or more lymph nodes anywhere in the neck and the lymph nodes may be any size; or (2) cancer has spread to a lymph node that is larger than 6 centimeters and may have spread as far as the space in front of the spinal column, around the carotid artery, or to parts of the chest. The vocal cords may not move normally.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713433" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IVB laryngeal cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713432" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de laringe en estadio IVB&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de laringe en estadio IVB</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio IV se divide en los estadios IVA, IVB y IVC. En el estadio IVB, 1) el cáncer se diseminó hasta el espacio que está enfrente de la columna espinal, rodea la arteria carótida o se diseminó hasta uno o más ganglios linfáticos de cualquier lugar del cuello, y los ganglios linfáticos pueden ser de cualquier tamaño; 2) el cáncer se diseminó hasta un ganglio linfático que mide más de seis centímetros y se puede haber diseminado tan lejos como el espacio que está enfrente de la columna espinal, alrededor de la arteria carótida o hasta partes del pecho. Las cuerdas vocales pueden no moverse normalmente.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-04-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2010-11-17</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258016">Laryngeal Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000393556">Cáncer de laringe: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
