<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046701"><TermName>stereotactic radiosurgery</TermName><TermPronunciation>(STAYR-ee-oh-TAK-tik RAY-dee-oh-SER-juh-ree)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stereotactic radiosurgery (SRS) implies the delivery of a single, high dose of radiation using stereotactic techniques. Classically, for cranial SRS, a rigid neurosurgical frame is attached to the patient’s skull, and a stereotactic localizing device is attached to the frame to allow for improved targeting accuracy. Commercial SRS systems are available in which immobilization is achieved without a rigid neurosurgical frame. While there are innumerable commercial SRS and stereotactic radiation therapy systems, all of these systems utilize the same underlying principles: (1) patient immobilization, (2) targeting accuracy, (3) delivery of high doses of radiation, and (4) heterogeneous dose distribution with a steep dose gradient. Commercial SRS systems include Gamma Knife, which utilizes 201 radioactive cobalt sources positioned in a semispherical array, and Cyberknife, which utilizes robotics technology allowing the linear accelerator (LINAC) to track the patient position in real time during treatment. A standard LINAC can be equipped with cones attached to its head, allowing for circular collimation of the beam. The dose distribution from Gamma Knife, Cyberknife, or a standard LINAC equipped with cones is spherical, and thus treating nonspherically shaped targets requires the superposition of multiple spherical dose distributions. A LINAC equipped with multi-leaf collimators can also be used for SRS, which allows more conformal beam shaping.  Also called radiation surgery, radiosurgery,  and stereotaxic radiosurgery.</DefinitionText><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of external radiation therapy that uses special equipment to position the patient and precisely give a single large dose of radiation to a tumor. It is used to treat brain tumors and other brain disorders that cannot be treated by regular surgery. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Also called radiation surgery, radiosurgery,  and stereotaxic radiosurgery.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000709953" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stereotactic radiosurgery&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000709954" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;radiocirugía estereotáctica&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>radiocirugía estereotáctica</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>La radiocirugía estereotáctica (RE) consiste en la administración de una dosis alta de radiación única mediante el uso de técnicas estereotácticas.  Usualmente, en la RE, craneal se fija en el craneo del paciente un marco neuroquirúrgico rígido, y en este a su vez, se fija un dispositivo  estereotáctico localizador a fin de  permitir una localización más precisa de la lesión.  Hay sistemas de RE comerciales ya disponibles en los cuales se logra la inmobilización sin un marco neuroquirúgico rígido.  Si bien existen innumerables sistemas radioterapéuticos de RE comerciales y estereotácticos, todos estos sistemas usan los mismos principios delineados: (1) inmobilización del paciente, (2) localización precisa de la lesión, (3) administración de dosis altas de radiación y  (4) distribución de dosis heterogéneas con un gradiante inclinado en las dosis.  Los sistemas de RE comerciales incluyen Gamma Knife, el cual utiliza 201 recursos de cobalto radiactivo ubicados en arreglos semiesféricos y Cyberknife, el cual utiliza tecnología robótica la cual permite al acelerador lineal (LINAC) para rastrear la posición del paciente en tiempo real durante el tratamiento.  Un LINAC estándar puede estar equipado con conos atados a su cabezal, permitiendo la colimación circular de su haz.  La dosis de distribución de  Gamma Knife, Cyberknife, o un LINAC estándar equipada con conos es esférica y, por tanto, el tratamiento de las lesiones con forma no esférica requiere la superposición de distribuciones de dosis esféricas múltiples. También se puede usar un LINAC equipado con colimadores multiláminas para la  RE, la cual permite otorgarle una mejor forma al haz conformal. También se llama cirugía por radiación, radiocirugía,  y radiocirugía estereotáxica.</DefinitionText><Audience>Health professional</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de radioterapia externa en la que se usa un equipo especial para poner en posición al paciente y dirigir una sola dosis grande de radiación hacia un tumor de modo preciso. Se usa para tratar tumores cerebrales y otros trastornos del cerebro que no se pueden tratar con la cirugía habitual. Asimismo, está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. También se llama cirugía por radiación, radiocirugía,  y radiocirugía estereotáxica.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2008-02-04</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
