<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044266"><TermName>National Cancer Institute</TermName><TermPronunciation>(NA-shuh-nul KAN-ser IN-stih-TOOT)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The National Cancer Institute, part of the National Institutes of Health of the United States Department of Health and Human Services, is the Federal Government's principal agency for cancer research. The National Cancer Institute conducts, coordinates, and funds cancer research, training, health information dissemination, and other programs with respect to the cause, diagnosis, prevention, and treatment of cancer. Access the National Cancer Institute Web site at <ExternalRef xref="http://www.cancer.gov">http://www.cancer.gov</ExternalRef>. Also called NCI.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000727880" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;National Cancer Institute&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000727879" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Instituto Nacional del Cáncer&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Instituto Nacional del Cáncer</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El Instituto Nacional del Cáncer (National Cancer Institute), que forma parte de los Institutos Nacionales de Salud del Departamento de Salud y Servicios Humanos de los Estados Unidos de América (<ForeignWord>National Institutes of Health of the United States Department of Health and Human Services</ForeignWord>) es el organismo principal del Gobierno Federal para la investigación del cáncer. El Instituto Nacional del Cáncer conduce, coordina y financia la investigación en cáncer, la capacitación, la diseminación de información de salud y otros programas relacionados con la causa, el diagnóstico, la prevención y el tratamiento de cáncer. Se puede visitar el portal de Internet del Instituto Nacional del Cáncer en <ExternalRef xref="http://www.cancer.gov">http://www.cancer.gov</ExternalRef>. También se llama NCI.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2008-01-10</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/about-nci/overview">NCI Overview</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/instituto/general">Aspectos generales del NCI</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
