<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046726"><TermName>stage I malignant mesothelioma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(...muh-LIG-nunt MEH-zoh-THEE-lee-OH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage I is divided into stages IA and IB. In stage IA, cancer is found in one side of the chest in the lining of the chest wall and may also be found in the lining of the chest cavity between the lungs and/or  the lining that covers the diaphragm. Cancer has not spread to the lining that covers the lung. In stage IB, cancer is found in one side of the chest in the lining of the chest wall and the lining that covers the lung. Cancer may also be found in the lining of the chest cavity between the lungs and/or the lining that covers the diaphragm. </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000709997" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage I malignant mesothelioma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000709996" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mesotelioma maligno en estadio I&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>mesotelioma maligno en estadio I</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio I se divide en los estadios IA y IB.   En el estadio IA, el cáncer se encuentra en un lado del pecho, en el revestimiento de la pared torácica y también se puede encontrar en el revestimiento de la cavidad torácica entre los pulmones o el revestimiento del diafragma.   El cáncer no se diseminó hasta el revestimiento del pulmón.   En el estadio IB, el cáncer se encuentra en un lado del pecho, en el revestimiento de la pared torácica y en el revestimiento que cubre el pulmón.   El cáncer también se puede encontrar en el revestimiento de la cavidad torácica entre los pulmones o el revestimiento del diafragma.  </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2011-10-19</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000269299">Malignant Mesothelioma Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000433305">Mesotelioma maligno: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
