<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045280"><TermName>stage IV lip and oral cavity cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... OR-ul KA-vih-tee KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage  IV is divided into stages IVA, IVB, and IVC. In stage IVA, (1) the tumor has spread through tissue in the lip or oral cavity into nearby tissue and/or bone   (jaw, tongue, floor of mouth, maxillary sinus, or skin of chin  or nose);  cancer may have spread to one lymph node that is 3 centimeters or smaller, on the same side of the neck as the tumor; or (2) the tumor is any size or has spread through tissue in the lip or oral cavity into nearby tissue and/or bone (jaw, tongue, floor of mouth, maxillary sinus, or skin of chin or nose). Cancer  has spread to one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the tumor and the lymph node is larger than 3 centimeters but not larger than 6 centimeters, or  to more than one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the tumor and the lymph nodes are not larger than 6 centimeters, or to lymph nodes on the opposite side of the neck as the tumor or on both sides of the neck, and the lymph nodes are not larger than 6 centimeters.   In stage IVB, (1) the tumor may be any size and has spread to one or more lymph nodes that are larger than 6 centimeters; or (2) the tumor has spread further into the muscles or bones in the oral cavity, or to the base of the skull and/or the carotid artery. Cancer may have spread to one or more lymph nodes anywhere in the neck.  In stage IVC, the tumor has spread beyond the lip or oral cavity to distant parts of the body, such as the lungs. The tumor may be any size and may have spread to lymph nodes. </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705256" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IV lip and oral cavity cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705257" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer del labio y la cavidad oral en estadio IV&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer del labio y la cavidad oral en estadio IV</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio IV se divide en estadios IVA, IVB y IVC. En el estadio IVA, 1) el tumor se diseminó a través del tejido del labio o la cavidad oral hacia el tejido cercano  o el hueso (mandíbula, lengua, piso de la boca, seno maxilar, o piel del mentón o la nariz); el cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta un ganglio linfático que mide tres centímetros o menos del mismo lado del cuello que el tumor; o 2) el tumor puede medir  cualquier tamaño o se diseminó a través del tejido del labio o la cavidad oral hacia el tejido cercano o el hueso (mandíbula, lengua, piso de la boca, seno maxilar, o piel del mentón o la nariz). El cáncer se diseminó hasta un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello que el tumor y el ganglio linfático mide más de tres centímetros, pero no más de seis centímetros, o hasta más de un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello que el tumor y los ganglios linfáticos no miden más de seis centímetros, o hasta ganglios linfáticos del lado opuesto del cuello que el tumor o de ambos lados del cuello, y los ganglios linfáticos no miden más de seis centímetros. En el estadio IVB, 1) el tumor puede medir cualquier tamaño y se diseminó hasta uno o más ganglios linfáticos que miden más de seis centímetros; o 2) el tumor se diseminó más todavía hacia los músculos o los huesos de la cavidad oral, o la base del cráneo o la arteria carótida. El cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta uno o más ganglios linfáticos de cualquier lugar del cuello. En el estadio IVC, el tumor se diseminó más allá del labio o la cavidad oral hasta partes distantes del cuerpo, como los pulmones. El tumor puede tener cualquier tamaño y se puede haber diseminado hasta los ganglios linfáticos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2010-11-24</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258017">Lip and Oral Cavity Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000486932">Cáncer de labio y de cavidad oral: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
