<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045764"><TermName>lymphatic system</TermName><TermPronunciation>(lim-FA-tik SIS-tem)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The tissues and organs that produce, store, and carry white blood cells that fight infections and other diseases. This system includes the bone marrow, spleen, thymus, lymph nodes, and lymphatic vessels (a network of thin tubes that carry lymph and white blood cells). Lymphatic vessels branch, like blood vessels, into all the tissues of the body.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000703936" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;lymphatic system&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000703935" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sistema linfático&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000533339" type="image/jpeg" alt="Lymph system; drawing shows the lymph vessels and lymph organs including the lymph nodes, tonsils, thymus, spleen, and bone marrow.  One inset shows the inside structure of a lymph node and the attached lymph vessels with arrows showing how the lymph (clear fluid) moves into and out of the lymph node. Another inset shows a close up of bone marrow with blood cells." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_2"><Caption language="en">Anatomy of the lymph system, showing the lymph vessels and lymph organs including lymph nodes, tonsils, thymus, spleen, and bone marrow. Lymph (clear fluid) and lymphocytes travel through the lymph vessels and into the lymph nodes where the lymphocytes destroy harmful substances. The lymph enters the blood through a large vein near the heart.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000557593" type="image/jpeg" alt="Sistema linfático; el dibujo muestra los vasos linfáticos y los órganos linfáticos, incluso los ganglios linfáticos, las amígdalas, el timo, el bazo y la médula ósea. Un recuadro muestra la estructura interior de un ganglio linfático y de los vasos linfáticos adjuntos, con flechas que indican cómo circula la linfa (un líquido claro) hacia adentro y afuera del ganglio linfático. Otro recuadro muestra una vista ampliada de la médula ósea con células sanguíneas." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Anatomía del sistema linfático; se muestran los vasos linfáticos y los órganos linfáticos, incluidos los ganglios linfáticos, las amígdalas, el timo, el bazo y la médula ósea. La linfa (un líquido claro) y los linfocitos se desplazan a través de los vasos linfáticos hasta los ganglios linfáticos, donde los linfocitos destruyen las sustancias que son dañinas. La linfa entra en la sangre a través de una vena grande cerca del corazón. </Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>sistema linfático</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tejidos y órganos que producen, almacenan y transportan los glóbulos blancos que combaten las infecciones y otras enfermedades. El sistema incluye la médula ósea, el bazo, el timo, los ganglios linfáticos y los vasos linfáticos (red de tubos delgados que transportan la linfa y los glóbulos blancos). Los vasos linfáticos se ramifican, como los vasos sanguíneos, por todos los tejidos del cuerpo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2010-01-29</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
