<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045130"><TermName>stage II prostate cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(...PROS-tayt KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage II is divided into stages IIA and IIB. In stage IIA, cancer is found (1) by needle biopsy or in a small amount of tissue during surgery for other reasons; the prostate-specific antigen (PSA) level is lower than 20 and the Gleason score is 7; or (2) by needle biopsy or in a small amount of tissue during surgery for other reasons; the PSA level is at least 10 but lower than 20 and the Gleason score is 6 or lower; or (3) in one-half or less of one lobe of the prostate; the PSA level is at least 10 but lower than 20 and the Gleason score is 6 or lower; or (4) in one-half or less of one lobe of the prostate; the PSA level is lower than 20 and the Gleason score is 7; or (5) in more than one-half of one lobe of the prostate; the PSA level is lower than 20 and the Gleason score is 7 or lower; or (6) in more than one-half of one lobe of the prostate, and the PSA level and Gleason score are not known. In stage IIB, cancer (1) is found in opposite sides of the prostate; the PSA can be any level and the Gleason score can range from 2 to 10; or (2) cannot be felt during a digital rectal exam and is not visible by imaging, and the tumor has not spread outside the prostate; the PSA level is 20 or higher and the Gleason score can range from 2 to 10; or (3) cannot be felt during a digital rectal exam and is not visible by imaging, and the tumor has not spread outside the prostate; the PSA can be any level and the Gleason score is 8 or higher.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705047" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage II prostate cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705046" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de próstata en estadio II&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000442273" type="image/jpeg" alt="Prostate cancer staging; six  panel drawing showing a side view of normal  male  anatomy and closeup views of Stage I, Stage IIA, Stage IIB, Stage III, and Stage IV  showing cancer growing from within the  prostate to nearby tissue and then to lymph nodes or other parts of the body." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_2"><Caption language="en">As prostate cancer progresses from Stage I to Stage IV, the cancer cells grow within the prostate, through the outer layer of the prostate into nearby tissue, and then to lymph nodes or other parts of the body. </Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000457829" type="image/jpeg" alt="Estadificación del cáncer de próstata; el dibujo de cinco paneles muestra una imagen de la anatomía masculina normal y ampliaciones del estadio I, estadio IIA, estadio IIB, estadio III y estadio IV que muestran un cáncer que crece desde el interior de la próstata hasta el tejido cercano y, luego, hasta los ganglios linfáticos u otras partes del cuerpo." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">A medida que el cáncer avanza desde el estadio I al estadio IV, las células cancerosas crecen dentro de la próstata, a través de la capa externa de la próstata hacia el tejido cercano y, luego, hasta los ganglios linfáticos u otras partes del cuerpo.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de próstata en estadio II</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El cáncer de próstata en estadio II se divide en estadios IIA y IIB. En el estadio IIA, el cáncer se encuentra: 1) mediante biopsia con aguja o en una cantidad pequeña de tejido durante una cirugía realizada por otras razones;  la concentración del antígeno prostático específico (APE) es menor de 20 y el puntaje de Gleason es 7; o 2)  mediante biopsia con aguja o en una cantidad pequeña de tejido durante una cirugía realizada por otras razones; la concentración de APE es de por lo menos 10, pero menor de 20 y el puntaje de Gleason es de 6 o menos; o 3) en la mitad o menos de un lóbulo de la próstata; la concentración de APE es de por lo menos 10, pero menos de 20, y el puntaje de Gleason es de 6 o menos; o 4) en la mitad o menos de un lóbulo de la próstata; la concentración de APE es menor de 20 y el puntaje de Gleason es 7; o 5) en más de la mitad de un lóbulo de la próstata; la concentración del APE es menor de 20 y el puntaje de Gleason es 7 o menos; o 6) en más de la mitad de un lóbulo de la próstata, y se desconoce la concentración de APE y el puntaje de Gleason. En el estadio IIB, el cáncer 1) se encuentra en lados opuestos de la próstata; la concentración de APE puede ser cualquiera y el puntaje de Gleason puede variar entre 2 y 10; o 2) no se puede palpar durante un examen digital del recto y no es visible mediante pruebas de imágenes, y el tumor no se diseminó fuera de la próstata; la concentración de APE es de 20 o más y el puntaje de Gleason puede variar entre 2 y 10; o 3) no se puede palpar durante un examen digital del recto y no es visible mediante pruebas de imágenes, y el tumor no se diseminó fuera de la próstata; la concentración de APE puede ser cualquiera y el puntaje de Gleason es de 8 o más. </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2012-06-04</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062965">Prostate Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256810">Cáncer de próstata: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
