<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000446562"><TermName>calendula ointment</TermName><TermPronunciation>(kuh-LEN-juh-luh OYNT-ment)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A substance made from the flower of the marigold plant <ScientificName>Calendula officinalis</ScientificName>. Calendula-based skin products have been used to treat minor cuts, burns, and skin irritation. The products that are available in the United States may not contain the same amount or mixture of ingredients and may not be effective. Another product, Calendula ointment, is being studied in France in the prevention of dermatitis in patients having radiation therapy for breast cancer. The ointment being studied is not available in the United States.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714615" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;calendula ointment&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714614" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pomada de caléndula&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>pomada de caléndula</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Sustancia elaborada con la flor de la planta de caléndula <ScientificName>Calendula officinalis</ScientificName>. Los productos para la piel elaborados con base en la caléndula, se han usado para tratar cortaduras menores, quemaduras e irritación de la piel. Puede ser que los productos disponibles en los Estados Unidos no contengan la misma cantidad o mezcla de ingredientes y pueden no ser eficaces. Otro producto, el ungüento de Caléndula, se está estudiando en Francia para prevenir la dermatitis de los pacientes que reciben radioterapia contra el cáncer de mama (seno). El ungüento en estudio no está disponible en los Estados Unidos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-12-22</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
