<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000430898"><TermName>stage III childhood Hodgkin lymphoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(...HOJ-kin lim-FOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage III is divided into stages III, IIIE, IIIS, and IIIE,S. In stage III, cancer is found in lymph node groups above and below the diaphragm (the thin muscle below the lungs that helps breathing and separates the chest from the abdomen). In stage IIIE, cancer is found in lymph node groups above and below the diaphragm and outside the lymph nodes in a nearby organ or area. In stage IIIS, cancer is found in lymph node groups above and below the diaphragm, and in the spleen. In stage IIIE,S, cancer is found in lymph node groups above and below the diaphragm, outside the lymph nodes in a nearby organ or area, and in the spleen.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713642" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III childhood Hodgkin lymphoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713641" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;linfoma de Hodgkin infantil en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000648704" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage III childhood Hodgkin lymphoma; drawing shows cancer in lymph node groups above and below the diaphragm, in the left lung, and in the spleen. An inset shows a lymph node with a lymph vessel, an artery, and a vein. Lymphoma cells containing cancer are shown in the lymph node." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Stage III childhood Hodgkin lymphoma. Cancer is found in one or more lymph node groups above and below the diaphragm (a). In stage IIIE, cancer is found in lymph node groups above and below the diaphragm and outside the lymph nodes in a nearby organ or area (b). In stage IIIS, cancer is found in lymph node groups above and below the diaphragm (a) and in the spleen (c). In stage IIIS plus E, cancer is found in lymph node groups above and below the diaphragm, outside the lymph nodes in a nearby organ or area (b), and in the spleen (c).</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000650472" type="image/jpeg" alt="Linfoma de Hodgkin infantil en estadio III; la imagen muestra el cáncer en grupos de ganglios linfáticos por encima y debajo del diafragma, en el pulmón izquierdo y en el bazo. En el recuadro se observa un ganglio linfático con un vaso linfático, una arteria y una vena. En el ganglio linfático se observan las células de linfoma (cancerosas)." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Linfoma de Hodgkin infantil en estadio III. El cáncer se encuentra en uno o más grupos de ganglios linfáticos por encima y debajo del diafragma (a). En el estadio IIIE, el cáncer se encuentra en grupos de ganglios linfáticos por encima y debajo del diafragma, y en un órgano o áreas cercanas fuera de los ganglios linfáticos (b). En el estadio IIIS, el cáncer se encuentra en grupos de ganglios linfáticos por encima y debajo del diafragma (a) y en el bazo (c). En el estadio IIIS más el estadio E, el cáncer se encuentra en grupos de ganglios linfáticos por encima y debajo del diafragma, en un órgano o área cercanos fuera de los ganglios linfáticos (b) y en el bazo (c).</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>linfoma de Hodgkin infantil en estadio III</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio III se divide en los estadios III, IIIE, IIIS y IIIES. En el estadio III, el cáncer se encuentra en grupos de ganglios linfáticos encima o debajo del diafragma (el músculo delgado ubicado debajo de los pulmones que ayuda a respirar y separa el pecho del abdomen). 
En el estadio IIIE, el cáncer se encuentra en grupos de ganglios linfáticos encima o debajo del diafragma, y fuera de los ganglios linfáticos en un órgano o área  cercanos. 
En el estadio IIIS, el cáncer se encuentra en grupos de ganglios linfáticos encima o debajo del diafragma, y en el bazo. 
En el estadio  IIIE+S, el cáncer se encuentra en grupos de ganglios linfáticos encima o debajo del diafragma, fuera de los ganglios linfáticos en un área u órgano cercanos, y en el bazo. 
</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-01-05</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2012-10-18</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000257999">Childhood Hodgkin Lymphoma Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256830">Linfoma de Hodgkin infantil: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
