<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000440109"><TermName>kidney failure</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KID-nee FAYL-yer)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A condition in which the kidneys stop working and are not able to remove waste and extra water from the blood or keep body chemicals in balance. Acute or severe kidney failure happens suddenly (for example, after an injury) and may be treated and cured. Chronic kidney failure develops over many years, may be caused by conditions like high blood pressure or diabetes, and cannot be cured. Chronic kidney failure may lead to total and long-lasting kidney failure, called end-stage renal disease (ESRD). A person in ESRD needs dialysis (the process of cleaning the blood by passing it through a membrane or filter) or a kidney transplant. Also called renal failure.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713724" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;kidney failure&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713725" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;insuficiencia del riñón&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>insuficiencia del riñón</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección en la cual los riñones dejan de funcionar y no pueden eliminar los desperdicios y el agua adicional de la sangre, o mantener en equilibrio  las sustancias químicas del cuerpo. La insuficiencia del riñón aguda o grave se presenta repentinamente (por ejemplo, después de una lesión), y puede tratarse y curarse. La insuficiencia del riñón crónica  evoluciona en el curso de muchos años, puede ser provocada por afecciones como la presión arterial alta o la diabetes, y no se puede curar. La insuficiencia del riñón crónica puede llevar a una insuficiencia del riñón total y duradera que se llama enfermedad renal en estadio terminal (ERET). El individuo que padece de ERET necesita diálisis (el proceso de limpiar la sangre haciéndola pasar por una membrana o filtro) o un trasplante de riñón. También se llama insuficiencia renal.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-08-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2008-11-21</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
