<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046100"><TermName>stage IV oropharyngeal cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... OR-oh-fuh-RIN-jee-ul KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage IV oropharyngeal cancer is divided into stages IVA, IVB, and IVC. In stage IVA, cancer  (1) has spread to the larynx, front part of the roof of the mouth, lower jaw, or muscles that move the tongue or are used for chewing. Cancer may have spread to one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the tumor and the lymph node is 3 centimeters or smaller;   or (2) has spread to one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the tumor (the lymph node is larger than 3 centimeters but not larger than 6 centimeters) or to more than one lymph node anywhere in the neck (the lymph nodes are 6 centimeters or smaller), and one of the following is true: (1) tumor in the oropharynx is any size and may have spread to the epiglottis (the flap that covers the trachea during swallowing); or (2) tumor has spread to the larynx, front part of the roof of the mouth, lower jaw, or muscles that move the tongue or are used for chewing. In stage IVB, the tumor (1) surrounds the carotid artery or has spread to the muscle that opens the jaw, the bone attached to the muscles that move the jaw, nasopharynx, or base of the skull. Cancer may have spread to one or more lymph nodes, which can be any size;  or (2) may be any size and has spread to one or more lymph nodes that are larger than 6 centimeters. In stage IVC,  the tumor may be any size and has spread beyond the oropharynx to other parts of the body, such as the lung, bone, or liver.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707673" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IV oropharyngeal cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707672" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de la orofaringe en estadio IV&quot;" language="es" id="_3"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de orofaringe en estadio IV</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio IV del cáncer de la orofaringe se divide en los estadios IVA, IVB y IVC. En el estadio IVA, el cáncer: 1) se diseminó hasta la laringe, la parte de adelante del paladar, la mandíbula inferior o los músculos que mueven la lengua o se usan para masticar. El cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello en que está el tumor y el ganglio linfático mide 3 cm o menos; o 2) se diseminó hasta un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello en que está el tumor (el ganglio linfático mide más de 3 cm, pero no más de 6 cm) o hasta más de un ganglio linfático en cualquier parte del cuello (los ganglios linfáticos miden 6 cm o menos) y se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: a) el tumor en la orofaringe tiene cualquier tamaño y se puede haber diseminado hasta la epiglotis (la aleta que tapa la tráquea mientras se traga); o b) el tumor se diseminó hasta la laringe, la parte de adelante del paladar, la mandíbula inferior o los músculos que mueven la lengua o se usan para masticar. En el estadio IVB, el tumor 1) rodea la arteria carótida o se diseminó hasta el músculo que abre la mandíbula, el hueso unido a los músculos que mueven la mandíbula, la nasofaringe o la base del cráneo. El cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta uno o más ganglios linfáticos que pueden tener cualquier tamaño; o 2) puede tener cualquier tamaño y se diseminó hasta uno o más ganglios linfáticos que miden más de 6 cm. En el estadio IVC,  el tumor puede tener cualquier tamaño y se diseminó más allá de la orofaringe hasta otras partes del cuerpo, como el pulmón, el hueso o el hígado.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2011-06-20</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258025">Oropharyngeal Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000525763">Cáncer de orofaringe: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
