<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000410745"><TermName>Herceptin</TermName><TermPronunciation>(her-SEP-tin)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat breast cancer that is HER2-positive (expresses the human epidermal growth factor receptor 2). It is also used with other drugs to treat HER2-positive stomach cancer that has not already been treated and has spread to other parts of the body. It is being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Herceptin binds to HER2 on the surface of HER2-positive cancer cells, and may kill them. It is a type of monoclonal antibody. Also called trastuzumab.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713130" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Herceptin&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713129" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Herceptin&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Herceptin</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para tratar el cáncer de mama que es positivo al HER2 (expresa el receptor 2 del factor de crecimiento epidérmico humano). También se usa con otros medicamentos para tratar el cáncer de estómago que es positivo al HER2, que todavía no fue tratado y se diseminó hasta otras partes del cuerpo. Está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Herceptin se une al HER2 en la superficie de las células cancerosas que son positivas al HER y puede destruirlas. Es un tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal. También se llama trastuzumab.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-03-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2011-12-29</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000502211">Trastuzumab</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
