<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000430869"><TermName>NHL</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Any of a large group of cancers of lymphocytes (white blood cells). NHLs can occur at any age and are often marked by lymph nodes that are larger than normal, fever, and weight loss. There are many different types of NHL. These types can be divided into aggressive (fast-growing) and indolent (slow-growing) types, and they can be formed from either B-cells or T-cells. B-cell NHLs include Burkitt lymphoma, chronic lymphocytic leukemia/small lymphocytic lymphoma (CLL/SLL), diffuse large B-cell lymphoma, follicular lymphoma, immunoblastic large cell lymphoma, precursor B-lymphoblastic lymphoma, and mantle cell lymphoma. T-cell NHLs include mycosis fungoides, anaplastic large cell lymphoma, and precursor T-lymphoblastic lymphoma. Lymphomas that occur after bone marrow or stem cell transplantation are usually B-cell NHLs. Prognosis and treatment depend on the stage and type of disease. Also called non-Hodgkin lymphoma.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><SpanishTermName>LNH</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cualquiera de un grupo grande de cánceres de linfocitos (glóbulos blancos). Los LNH se pueden presentar a cualquier edad y a menudo se caracterizan por ganglios linfáticos más grandes de lo normal, fiebre y pérdida de peso. Hay muchos tipos diferentes de LNH. Estos tipos se pueden dividir en dinámicos (de crecimiento rápido) e indolentes (de crecimiento lento) y pueden estar formados por células B o células T. Los LNH de células B incluyen el linfoma de Burkitt, la leucemia linfocítica crónica o el linfoma linfocítico pequeño (LLC o LLP), el linfoma difuso de células B grandes, el linfoma folicular, el linfoma inmunoblástico de células grandes, el linfoma linfoblástico de células B precursoras y el linfoma de células de manto. Los LNH de células T incluyen la micosis fungoides, el linfoma anaplásico de células grandes y el linfoma linfoblástico de células T precursoras. Los linfomas que se presentan después de un trasplante de médula ósea o un trasplante de células madre son habitualmente LNH de células B. El pronóstico y el tratamiento dependen del estadio y el tipo de la enfermedad. También se llama linfoma no Hodgkin.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-05-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2009-04-24</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/lymphoma">Lymphoma</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/linfoma">Linfoma</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
