<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046122"><TermName>stage III vulvar cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... VUL-ver KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The tumor may be any size and may have spread into the lower part of the urethra, the lower part of the vagina, or the anus. Cancer has spread to one or more nearby lymph nodes. Stage III is divided into stages IIIA, IIIB, and IIIC. In stage IIIA, cancer is found in 1 or 2 lymph nodes that are smaller than 5 millimeters or in one lymph node that is 5 millimeters or larger. In stage IIIB, cancer is found in 2 or more lymph nodes that are 5 millimeters or larger, or in 3 or more lymph nodes that are smaller than 5 millimeters. In stage IIIC, cancer is found in lymph nodes and has spread to the outside surface of the lymph nodes.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707708" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III vulvar cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707709" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de vulva en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de vulva en estadio III</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El tumor mide cualquier tamaño y se ha diseminado a la parte inferior de la uretra, la parte inferior de la vagina o el ano. El cáncer se ha diseminado a uno o más ganglios linfáticos. El estadio lll se divide en estadios  IIIA, IIIB y IIIC. En el estadio IIIA, el cáncer se encuentra entre 1 y 2 ganglios linfáticos que miden menos de 5 milímetros o en un ganglio linfático que mide 5 milímetros o más. En el estadio lllB, el cáncer se encuentra en 2 o más ganglios linfáticos que miden 5 milímetros o más, o   en 3 o más ganglios linfáticos que miden menos de 5 milímetros. En el estadio lllC, el cáncer se encuentra en los ganglios linfáticos y se ha diseminado a la superficie externa de los ganglios linfáticos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2012-10-15</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000419665">Vulvar Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000452963">Cáncer de vulva: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
