<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044650"><TermName>breast carcinoma in situ</TermName><TermPronunciation>(brest KAR-sih-NOH-muh in SY-too)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>There are 3 types of breast carcinoma in situ: ductal carcinoma in situ (DCIS), lobular carcinoma in situ (LCIS), and Paget disease of the nipple. DCIS is a noninvasive condition in which abnormal cells are found in the lining of a breast duct. The abnormal cells have not spread outside the duct to other tissues in the breast. In some cases, DCIS may become invasive cancer and spread to other tissues. At this time, there is no way to know which lesions could become invasive. LCIS is a condition in which abnormal cells are found in the lobules of the breast. This condition seldom becomes invasive cancer. However, having LCIS in one breast increases the risk of developing breast cancer in either breast. Paget disease of the nipple is a condition in which abnormal cells are found in the nipple only. Also called stage 0 breast carcinoma in situ.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705795" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;breast carcinoma in situ&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705796" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;carcinoma de mama in situ&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>carcinoma de mama in situ</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Hay tres tipos de carcinoma de mama in situ: carcinoma ductal in situ  (CDIS), carcinoma lobulillar  in situ (CLIS) y enfermedad de Paget del pezón. El CDIS es una afección no invasiva en la que se encuentran células anormales en el revestimiento de un conducto de la mama. Las células anormales no se diseminaron fuera del conducto hacia otros tejidos de la mama. En algunos casos, el CDIS se puede volver cáncer invasivo y diseminarse hasta otros tejidos. Por ahora, no se sabe cuáles lesiones se pueden convertir en cáncer invasivo. El CLIS es una afección en la que se encuentran células anormales en los lóbulos de la mama. Esta afección rara vez se convierte en cáncer invasivo. Sin embargo, tener un CLIS en una de las mamas aumenta el riesgo de cáncer en ambas. La enfermedad de Paget del pezón es una afección en la que se encuentran células anormales solamente en el pezón. También se llama carcinoma de mama in situ en estadio 0.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2012-08-01</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062955">Breast Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256762">Cáncer de seno (mama): Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
