<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000438733"><TermName>eculizumab</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ek-yoo-LIH-zoo-mab)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to prevent red blood cells from being destroyed in patients with a rare red blood cell disorder called paroxysmal nocturnal hemoglobinuria (PNH).  It is also used to treat another rare disorder called atypical hemolytic urea syndrome (aHUS), in which blood clots form in small blood vessels. Eculizumab binds to an immune system protein called C5. This helps keep red blood cells from breaking down and helps keep blood clots from forming. Eculizumab is a type of monoclonal antibody. Also called Soliris.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713751" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;eculizumab&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713750" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;eculizumab&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>eculizumab</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText> Medicamento que se usa para prevenir que se destruyan los glóbulos rojos de pacientes de una enfermedad poco frecuente que se llama hemoglobinuria nocturna paroxística (HNP). También se usa para tratar otro trastorno poco frecuente que se llama síndrome urémico hemolítico atípico (SUHa), por la que se forman coágulos pequeños en los vasos sanguíneos. El eculizumab se une a una proteína del sistema inmunitario que se llama C5. Esto ayuda a impedir que los glóbulos rojos se descompongan y ayuda a impedir la formación de coágulos. El eculizumab es un tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal. También se llama Soliris.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-08-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2014-02-17</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
