<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046476"><TermName>cell</TermName><TermPronunciation>(sel)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>In biology, the smallest unit that can live on its own and that makes up all living organisms and the tissues of the body. A cell has three main parts: the cell membrane, the nucleus, and the cytoplasm. The cell membrane surrounds the cell and controls the substances that go into and out of the cell. The nucleus is a structure inside the cell that contains the nucleolus and most of the cell’s DNA.  It is also where most RNA is made. The cytoplasm is the fluid inside the cell. It contains other tiny cell parts that have specific functions, including the Golgi complex, the mitochondria, and the endoplasmic reticulum.  The cytoplasm is where most chemical reactions take place and most proteins get made. The human body has more than 30 trillion cells.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708802" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cell&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708803" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;célula&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000761780" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing showing a cell containing organelles, including the nucleus (contains DNA), the nucleolus, Golgi complex, mitochondria, and endoplasmic reticulum. Also shown are the cell membrane and a membrane receptor." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Parts of a cell.  A cell is surrounded by a membrane, which has receptors on the surface. A cell has several small structures inside it, including the nucleus, mitochondria, endoplasmic reticulum, and Golgi complex. These all have specific functions in the cell. </Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000765321" type="image/jpeg" alt="En la ilustración, se muestra una célula con sus organelos, como el núcleo (contiene ADN), el nucléolo, el aparato de Golgi, las mitocondrias y el retículo endoplasmático. También se muestran la membrana celular y un receptor de membrana." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Partes de una célula. La célula está rodeada por una membrana, con receptores en la superficie; además,  tiene varias estructuras pequeñas en su interior, como el núcleo, las mitocondrias, el retículo endoplasmático y el  aparato de Golgi. Estas desempeñan funciones específicas en la célula.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>célula</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>En biología, es la unidad más pequeña que puede vivir por sí sola y  que constituye todos los organismos vivos y los tejidos del cuerpo. Una  célula se compone de tres partes principales: la membrana celular, el núcleo y el citoplasma. La membrana celular rodea la célula y controla las sustancias que entran y salen de esta. El núcleo es la estructura dentro de la célula que contiene el nucléolo y la mayoría del ADN de la célula. También es la  parte  donde se elabora la mayor parte del ARN. El citoplasma es el líquido dentro de la célula que contiene otras partículas celulares  diminutas con  funciones específicas, como el aparato de Golgi, las mitocondrias y el retículo endoplasmático. El citoplasma es donde sucede la mayor parte de las reacciones químicas y se elabora la mayoría de las proteínas. El cuerpo humano se compone de más de 30 billones de células.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2014-11-18</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
