<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000444968"><TermName>bladder cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(BLA-der KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cancer that forms in tissues of the bladder (the organ that stores urine). Most bladder cancers are transitional cell carcinomas (cancer that begins in cells that normally make up the inner lining of the bladder). Other types include squamous cell carcinoma (cancer that begins in thin, flat cells) and adenocarcinoma (cancer that begins in cells that make and release mucus and other fluids). The cells that form squamous cell carcinoma and adenocarcinoma develop in the inner lining of the bladder as a result of chronic irritation and inflammation.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714534" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;bladder cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714535" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de vejiga&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de vejiga</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cáncer que se forma en los tejidos de la vejiga (el órgano que almacena orina). La mayoría de los cánceres de vejiga son carcinomas de células de transición (cáncer que empieza en células que normalmente forman el recubrimiento interno de la vejiga). Otros tipos incluyen el carcinoma de células escamosas (cáncer que empieza en células delgadas y planas) y el adenocarcinoma (cáncer que empieza en las células que elaboran y liberan moco y otros líquidos). Las células que forman el carcinoma de células escamosas y el adenocarcinoma se desarrollan en el recubrimiento interno de la vejiga como resultado de irritación crónica e inflamación.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-10-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2006-12-01</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/bladder">Bladder Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/vejiga">Cáncer de vejiga</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
