<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045367"><TermName>stage IIIA non-small cell lung cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... sel lung KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage III non-small cell lung cancer is divided into stages IIIA and IIIB. In stage IIIA, cancer has spread to lymph nodes on the same side of the chest as the tumor. Also, (1) the tumor may be any size; (2) part of the lung (where the trachea joins the bronchus) or the whole lung may have collapsed or become inflamed; (3) there may be one or more separate tumors in the same lobe of the lung; and/or (4) cancer may have spread to any of the following: main bronchus (but not the area where the trachea joins the bronchus), chest wall, diaphragm and the nerve that controls it, or membrane around the heart, lung, or lining the chest wall. OR in stage IIIA, cancer has spread to lymph nodes on the same side of the chest as the tumor. Also, (1) the tumor may be any size; (2) the whole lung may have collapsed or become inflamed; (3) there may be one or more separate tumors in any of the lobes of the lung with cancer; and/or (4) cancer may have spread to any of the following: main bronchus (but not the area where the trachea joins the bronchus), chest wall, diaphragm and the nerve that controls it, membrane around the lung or lining the chest wall, heart or the membrane around it, trachea, carina (where the trachea joins the bronchi), esophagus, sternum (chest bone), backbone, major blood vessels that lead to or from the heart, or the nerve that controls the larynx (voice box). OR in stage IIIA, cancer has not spread to the lymph nodes and the tumor may be any size. Cancer has spread to any of the following: trachea, carina, esophagus, sternum, backbone,   heart, major blood vessels that lead to or from the heart, or the nerve that controls the larynx.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705381" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IIIA non-small cell lung cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705380" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio IIIA&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000521911" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIIA non-small cell lung cancer (1). Drawing shows cancer in lymph nodes, left main bronchus, and diaphragm; there may be separate tumors in the same lung; the trachea is also shown. Top inset shows cancer that has spread from the lung through the lung lining and chest wall lining into the chest wall; a rib is also shown. Bottom inset shows the heart and cancer that has spread from the lung into the membrane around the heart." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_5"><Caption language="en">Stage IIIA non-small cell lung cancer (1). Cancer has spread to certain lymph nodes on the same side of the chest as the primary tumor. The cancer may have  spread to (a) the main bronchus; (b) lung lining, chest wall lining, or chest wall; (c) diaphragm; and/or (d) membrane around the heart; and/or (e) there may be one or more separate tumors in the same lobe of the lung. Cancer may have spread to the nerve that controls the diaphragm, and part or all of the lung may have collapsed or become inflamed (not shown).</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000682116" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIIA lung cancer  (2). Drawing shows cancer in the lymph nodes, trachea, carina, left main bronchus, esophagus, sternum, diaphragm, and major blood vessels that lead to or from the heart; there may be separate tumors in the same lung. Top inset shows cancer that has spread from the lung through the lung lining and chest wall lining into the chest wall; a rib is also shown. Bottom inset shows cancer that has spread from the lung, through the membrane around the heart, into the heart." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_6"><Caption language="en">Stage IIIA lung cancer (2). Cancer has spread to certain lymph nodes on the same side of the chest as the primary tumor. The cancer may have spread to (a) the main bronchus; (b) the lung lining, chest wall lining, or chest wall; (c) diaphragm; (d) heart and/or membrane around the it; (e) major blood vessels that lead to or from the heart; (f) trachea; (g) esophagus; (h) sternum; and/or (i) carina; and/or (j) there may be one or more separate tumors in any lobe of the same lung. Cancer may have spread to the nerves that control the diaphragm and larynx, and the whole lung may have collapsed or become inflamed (not shown).</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000682121" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIIA non-small cell lung cancer (3). Drawing shows cancer in the heart, major blood vessels that lead to or from the heart, the trachea, esophagus, sternum, and carina; the diaphragm is also shown. Inset shows cancer that has spread from the lung, through the membrane around the heart, into the heart." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_10"><Caption language="en">Stage IIIA non-small cell lung cancer (3). Cancer has spread to (a) the heart; (b) major blood vessels that lead to or from the heart; (c) trachea; (d) esophagus; (e) sternum; and/or (f) carina. Cancer may have spread to the nerve that controls the larynx (not shown).</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000537567" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio IIIA (1). El dibujo muestra  cáncer en los ganglios linfáticos, el bronquio principal izquierdo y el diafragma; puede haber tumores separados en el mismo pulmón; también se muestra la tráquea. El recuadro superior muestra un cáncer que se diseminó desde el pulmón a través del revestimiento del pulmón y el revestimiento de la pared del pecho, hacia la pared del pecho; también se muestra una costilla. En ambos recuadros se  muestran el corazón y  cáncer que se diseminó desde el pulmón hacia la membrana que rodea el corazón." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_8"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio IIIA (1). El cáncer se diseminó hasta ciertos ganglios linfáticos del mismo lado del pecho que el tumor primario. El cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta: a) el bronquio principal; b) el revestimiento del pulmón, el revestimiento de la pared del pecho o la pared del pecho; c) el diafragma, o d) la membrana que rodea el corazón; o e) puede haber dos o más tumores separados en el mismo lóbulo del pulmón. El cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta el nervio que controla el diafragma, y una parte o todo el pulmón se puede haber hundido o inflamado (no se muestra).</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000686748" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer del pulmón en estadio IIIA (2). El dibujo muestra cáncer en los ganglios linfáticos, la tráquea, la carina, el bronquio principal izquierdo, el esófago, el esternón, el diafragma y los vasos sanguíneos principales que van hacia el corazón o salen del mismo; puede haber tumores separados en el mismo pulmón. El recuadro superior muestra un cáncer que se diseminó desde el pulmón, a través del revestimiento del pulmón y el revestimiento de la pared del pecho, hacia la pared del pecho; también se muestra una costilla. El recuadro inferior muestra un cáncer que se diseminó desde el pulmón, a través de la membrana que rodea el corazón, hacia el corazón." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_9"><Caption language="es">Cáncer del pulmón en estadio IIIA (2). El cáncer se diseminó hasta ciertos ganglios linfáticos del mismo lado del pecho en el que está el tumor primario. El cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta: a) el bronquio principal, b) el revestimiento del pulmón, el revestimiento de la pared del pecho o la pared del pecho, c) el diafragma, d) el corazón o la membrana que lo rodea, e) los vasos sanguíneos principales que van hacia el corazón o salen del mismo, f) la tráquea, g) el esófago, h) el esternón, o i) la carina; o j) puede haber uno o más tumores separados en cualquier lóbulo del mismo pulmón.  El cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta los nervios que controlan el diafragma y la laringe, y todo el pulmón se puede haber hundido o inflamado (no se muestra).</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000686753" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio IIIA (3). El dibujo muestra cáncer en el corazón, los vasos sanguíneos principales que van hacia el corazón o salen del mismo, la tráquea, el esófago, el esternón y la carina; también se muestra el diafragma. El recuadro muestra un cáncer que se diseminó desde el pulmón, a través de la membrana que rodea el corazón, hacia el corazón." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_11"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio IIIA (3). El cáncer se diseminó hasta: a) el corazón, b) los vasos sanguíneos principales que van hacia el corazón o salen del mismo, c) la tráquea, d) el esófago, e) el esternón, o f) la carina. El cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta el nervio que controla la laringe (no se muestra).</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio IIIA</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio III se divide en estadios IIIA y IIIB. En el estadio IIIA, el cáncer se diseminó hasta los ganglios linfáticos del mismo lado del pecho en el que está el tumor. Además, 1) el tumor puede tener cualquier tamaño; 2) una parte del pulmón (donde la tráquea se une con el bronquio) o todo el pulmón se pueden haber hundido o inflamado; 3) puede haber uno o más tumores separados en el mismo lóbulo del pulmón, o 4) el cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta cualquiera de los siguientes sitios: el bronquio principal (pero no el área en donde la tráquea se une con el pulmón), la pared del pecho, el diafragma y el nervio que lo controla, o la membrana que rodea el corazón, el pulmón o el revestimiento de la pared del pecho. O, en el estadio IIIA, el cáncer se diseminó hasta los ganglios del mismo lado del pecho en donde está el tumor. También, 1) el tumor puede tener cualquier tamaño; 2) todo el pulmón se puede haber hundido o inflamado; 3) puede haber uno o más tumores separados en cualquiera de los lóbulos del pulmón con cáncer, o 4) el cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta cualquiera de los siguientes sitios: el bronquio principal (pero no el área en donde la tráquea se une con el bronquio), la pared del pecho, el diafragma y el nervio que lo controla, la membrana que rodea el pulmón o el revestimiento de la pared del pecho, el corazón o la membrana que lo rodea, la tráquea, la carina (donde la tráquea se une con el bronquio), el esófago, el esternón (hueso del pecho), la columna vertebral, los vasos sanguíneos principales que van hacia el corazón o salen del mismo, o el nervio que controla la laringe. O, en el estadio IIIA, el cáncer no se diseminó hasta los ganglios linfáticos y el tumor puede tener cualquier tamaño. El cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta cualquiera de los siguientes sitios: la tráquea, la carina, el esófago, el esternón, la columna vertebral, el corazón, los vasos sanguíneos principales que van hacia el corazón o salen del mismo, o el nervio que controla la laringe.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2010-10-21</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062956">Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer Treatment </RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256766">Cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
