<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045746"><TermName>laparoscopic-assisted colectomy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(LA-puh-ruh-SKAH-pik-uh-SIS-ted koh-LEK-toh-mee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Surgery done with the aid of a laparoscope to remove all or part of the colon through several small incisions made in the wall of the abdomen. A laparoscope is a thin, tube-like instrument with a light and a lens for viewing. It may also have a tool to remove tissue to be checked under a microscope for signs of disease. The laparoscope is inserted through one opening to guide the surgery. Surgical instruments are inserted through the other openings to perform the surgery. When only part of the colon is removed, it is called a partial colectomy.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707179" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;laparoscopic-assisted colectomy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707180" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;colectomía asistida con laparoscopio&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>colectomía asistida con laparoscopio</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cirugía realizada con la ayuda de un laparoscopio para extraer todo el colon o una parte del mismo a través de varios cortes pequeños hechos en la pared del abdomen. Un laparoscopio es un instrumento delgado con forma de tubo con una luz y una lente para hacer observaciones. También puede tener una herramienta para extraer tejido que se debe examinar para determinar si hay signos de enfermedad. Se inserta el laparoscopio a través de una abertura para guiar la cirugía. Cuando solo se extrae una parte del colon, el procedimiento se llama colestomía parcial.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2006-10-03</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
