<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000454837"><TermName>stage II mycosis fungoides</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... my-KOH-sis fun-GOY-deez)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage II is divided into stages IIA and IIB. In stage IIA, any amount of the skin surface is covered with patches, papules, and/or plaques. Lymph nodes are enlarged but cancer has not spread to them. In stage IIB, one or more tumors that are 1 centimeter or larger are found on the skin. Lymph nodes may be enlarged but cancer has not spread to them. In stages IIA and IIB, there may be abnormal lymphocytes in the blood but they are not cancerous.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000715088" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage II mycosis fungoides&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000715087" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;micosis fungoide en estadio II&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>micosis fungoide en estadio II</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio II se divide en los estadio IIA y IIB. En el estadio IIA, cualquier cantidad de la superficie de la piel está cubierta por parches, pápulas o placas. Los ganglios linfáticos están agrandados, pero el cáncer no se diseminó hasta ellos. En el estadio IIB, se encuentran uno o más tumores sobre la piel que miden un centímetro o más. Los ganglios linfáticos pueden estar agrandados pero el cáncer no se diseminó hasta ellos. En los estadios IIA y IIB, puede haber linfocitos anormales en la sangre, pero no son cancerosos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-11-25</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2012-02-23</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258022">Mycosis Fungoides and the Sézary Syndrome Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000433316">Micosis fungoide y síndrome de Sézary: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
