<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045126"><TermName>stage I testicular cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(...tes-TIH-kyoo-ler KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage I is divided into stage IA, stage IB, and stage IS, and is determined after a radical inguinal orchiectomy (surgery to remove the testicle) is done. In stage IA, cancer is in the testicle and epididymis and may have spread to the inner layer of the membrane surrounding the testicle; all tumor marker levels are normal. In stage IB, cancer is in the testicle and the epididymis and has spread to the blood or lymph vessels in the testicle; or has spread to the outer layer of the membrane surrounding the testicle; or is in the spermatic cord or the scrotum and may be in the blood or lymph vessels of the testicle; all tumor marker levels are normal. In stage IS, cancer is found anywhere within the testicle, spermatic cord, or the scrotum, and either all tumor marker levels are slightly above normal or one or more tumor marker levels are moderately above normal or high.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705038" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage I testicular cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705039" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de testículo en estadio I&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de testículo en estadio I</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio I se divide en estadio IA, estadio IB y estadio IS y se determina después de realizar una orquiectomía inguinal radical (cirugía para extirpar el testículo). En el estadio IA, el cáncer está en el testículo y el epidídimo y se puede haber diseminado hacia la capa interna de la membrana que rodea el testículo; todos los índices de los marcadores tumorales son normales. En el estadio IB, el cáncer está en el testículo y el epidídimo, y se ha diseminado a la sangre o los vasos linfáticos del testículo; o se ha diseminado hacia la capa exterior de la membrana que rodea el testículo; o está en el cordón espermático o el escroto y puede estar en la sangre o los vasos linfáticos del testículo; todos los índices de marcadores tumorales son normales. En el estadio IS, el cáncer se encuentra en cualquier lugar dentro del testículo, el cordón espermático o el escroto, o todos los índices de marcadores tumorales están levemente por encima de lo normal, o uno o más índices de los marcadores tumorales están moderadamente por encima de lo normal o son altos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2010-09-29</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
