<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000428383"><TermName>stage IVA laryngeal cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... luh-RIN-jee-ul KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage IV is divided into stage IVA, stage IVB, and stage IVC. In stage IVA, (1) cancer has spread through the thyroid cartilage and/or has spread to tissues beyond the larynx, such as the neck, trachea, thyroid, or esophagus; cancer may have spread to one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the original tumor and the lymph node is 3 centimeters or smaller; or (2) cancer has spread to one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the original tumor and the lymph node is larger than 3 centimeters but not larger than 6 centimeters, or has spread to more than one lymph node anywhere in the neck with none larger than 6 centimeters; cancer may have spread to tissues beyond the larynx, such as the neck, trachea, thyroid, or esophagus. The vocal cords may not move normally.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713082" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IVA laryngeal cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713081" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de laringe en estadio IVA&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de laringe en estadio IVA</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio IV se divide en los estadios IVA, IVB y IVC. En el estadio IVA, 1) el cáncer se diseminó a través del cartílago tiroideo o se diseminó hasta tejidos más allá de la laringe, como el cuello, la tráquea, la tiroidea o el esófago; el cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello donde está el tumor original y el ganglio linfático mide tres centímetros o menos; o 2) el cáncer se diseminó hasta un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello donde está el tumor original y el ganglio linfático mide más de tres centímetros, pero no más de seis centímetros, o se diseminó hasta más de un ganglio linfático en cualquier lugar del cuello y ninguno de esos ganglios mide más de seis centímetros; el cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta los tejidos más allá de la laringe, como el cuello, la tráquea, la tiroidea o el esófago. Las cuerdas vocales pueden no moverse normalmente.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-04-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2010-11-17</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258016">Laryngeal Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000393556">Cáncer de laringe: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
