<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000446539"><TermName>SNP</TermName><TermPronunciation>(snip)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The most common type of change in DNA (molecules inside cells that carry genetic information). SNPs occur when a single nucleotide (building block of DNA) is replaced with another. These changes may cause disease, and may affect how a person reacts to bacteria, viruses, drugs, and other substances. Also called single nucleotide polymorphism.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>DNA sequence variations that occur when a single nucleotide (adenine, thymine, cytosine, or guanine) in the genome sequence is altered; usually present in at least 1% of the population. Also called single nucleotide polymorphism.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000738749" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary&#10;         term &quot;SNP&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><SpanishTermName>PSN</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Polimorfismo de un solo nucleótido. Tipo de cambio más común en el ADN (moléculas dentro de las células que contienen información genética). El PSN se presenta cuando un solo nucleótido (elemento fundamental del ADN) es reemplazado por otro. Estos cambios pueden causar enfermedad y pueden afectar la forma en que una persona reacciona ante las bacterias, los virus, los medicamentos y otras sustancias. También se llama polimorfismo de un solo nucleótido.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-12-22</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2007-07-17</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.genome.gov/Glossary/index.cfm?id=185">Single Nucleotide Polymorphisms (SNPs)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.genome.gov/GlossaryS/index.cfm?id=185">Polimorfismos de nucleótido único (SNPs)
</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
