<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044060"><TermName>mitochondria</TermName><TermPronunciation>(MY-toh-KON-dree-uh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Small structures in a cell that are found in the cytoplasm (fluid that surrounds the cell nucleus). Mitochondria make most of the energy for the cell and have their own genetic material that is different from the genetic material found in the nucleus. Many diseases are caused by mutations (changes) in the DNA of mitochondria. Mitochondria are cell organelles.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704105" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mitochondria&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704106" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mitocondria&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000761780" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing showing a cell containing organelles, including the nucleus (contains DNA), the nucleolus, Golgi complex, mitochondria, and endoplasmic reticulum. Also shown are the cell membrane and a membrane receptor." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Parts of a cell.  A cell is surrounded by a membrane, which has receptors on the surface. A cell has several small structures inside it, including the nucleus, mitochondria, endoplasmic reticulum, and Golgi complex. These all have specific functions in the cell. </Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000765321" type="image/jpeg" alt="En la ilustración, se muestra una célula con sus organelos, como el núcleo (contiene ADN), el nucléolo, el aparato de Golgi, las mitocondrias y el retículo endoplasmático. También se muestran la membrana celular y un receptor de membrana." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Partes de una célula. La célula está rodeada por una membrana, con receptores en la superficie; además,  tiene varias estructuras pequeñas en su interior, como el núcleo, las mitocondrias, el retículo endoplasmático y el  aparato de Golgi. Estas desempeñan funciones específicas en la célula.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>mitocondria</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Estructuras pequeñas de una célula que se encuentran en el citoplasma (el líquido que rodea el núcleo). La mitocondria produce la mayor parte de la energía de la célula y cuentan con su propio material genético, que difiere del material genético del núcleo. Muchas enfermedades son el resultado de mutaciones (cambios) en el ADN de la mitocondria. Las mitocondrias son orgánulos celulares.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2014-11-19</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
