<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000413913"><TermName>stage IV gallbladder cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... GAWL-bla-der KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage IV gallbladder cancer is divided into stages IVA and IVB. In stage IVA, cancer has spread to a main blood vessel of the liver or to 2 or more nearby organs or areas other than the liver. Cancer may have spread to nearby lymph nodes. In stage IVB, cancer has spread to either (1) lymph nodes along large arteries in the abdomen and/or near the lower part of the backbone; or (2) to organs or areas far away from the gallbladder.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713282" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IV gallbladder cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713283" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de vesícula biliar en estadio IV&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de vesícula biliar en estadio IV</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio IV del cáncer de vesícula biliar se divide en estadios IVA y IVB. En el estadio IVA, el cáncer se diseminó hasta el vaso sanguíneo principal del hígado, o a dos o más órganos cercanos o áreas distintas del hígado. El cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta los ganglios linfáticos cercanos. En el estadio IVB, el cáncer se diseminó hasta alguno de los siguientes sitios: 1) los ganglios linfáticos ubicados a lo largo de las arterias del abdomen o cerca de la parte inferior de la columna vertebral, o 2) hasta órganos o áreas muy alejadas de la vesícula biliar.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-04-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2011-12-29</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000270720">Gallbladder Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256804">Cáncer de vesícula biliar: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
