<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044296"><TermName>relative survival rate</TermName><TermPronunciation>(REH-luh-tiv ser-VY-vul …)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A way of
          comparing the survival of people who have a specific
          disease with those who don’t, over a certain period of
          time. This is usually five years from the date of diagnosis
          or the start of treatment for those with the disease. It is
          calculated by dividing the percentage of patients with the
          disease who are still alive at the end of the period of
          time by the percentage of people in the general population
          of the same sex and age who are alive at the end of the
          same time period. The relative survival rate shows whether
          the disease shortens life.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704435" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;relative survival rate&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704434" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tasa relativa de supervivencia&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>tasa relativa de supervivencia</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Forma de comparar la
supervivencia de personas que padecen de una enfermedad
específica con aquellas que no la padecen. Este generalmente es de 5 años desde la fecha del diagnóstico o el principio del tratamiento de aquellos con la enfermedad. Se calcula dividiendo el porcentaje de pacientes con la enfermedad que todavía están vivos al final del período por el porcentaje de personas de la población general del mismo sexo y edad que están vivas al final del mismo período. La tasa relativa de
supervivencia muestra si la enfermedad acorta la
vida.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2012-08-15</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
