<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000443028"><TermName>palifermin</TermName><TermPronunciation>(pa-lee-FER-min)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A form of keratinocyte growth factor (KGF) that is made in the laboratory. KGF stimulates the growth of cells that line the surface of the mouth and intestinal tract. Palifermin is used to prevent and treat oral mucositis (mouth sores) caused by high-dose chemotherapy and radiation therapy in leukemia and lymphoma. It is also being studied in the prevention and treatment of oral mucositis and dysphagia (difficulty swallowing) in other types of cancer. Palifermin is a type of recombinant human keratinocyte growth factor. Also called Kepivance.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714641" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;palifermin&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714640" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;palifermina&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>palifermina</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Forma del factor de crecimiento de queratinocitos (KGF, por sus siglas en inglés) que se produce en el laboratorio. El KGF estimula el crecimiento de las células que recubren la superficie de la boca y los intestinos. La palifermina se usa para prevenir y tratar la mucositis oral (llagas bucales) provocadas por las dosis altas de quimioterapia y radioterapia en la leucemia y el linfoma. Asimismo, está en estudio para la prevención y el tratamiento de la mucositis oral y la disfagia (dificultad para tragar) en otros tipos de cáncer. La palifermina es un tipo de factor de crecimiento de queratinocitos humanos recombinantes. También se llama Kepivance.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2006-04-14</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2007-07-06</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000492043">Palifermin</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
