<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046043"><TermName>Castleman disease</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KA-sel-man dih-ZEEZ)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare disorder in which benign (not cancer) growths form in lymph node tissue. There are two main ways that Castleman disease occurs: localized (unicentric) and multicentric. Unicentric Castleman disease affects only one group of lymph nodes in one part of the body, usually in the chest or abdomen.  It may not cause symptoms. Multicentric Castleman disease affects many groups of lymph nodes and lymphoid tissue all through the body. It can weaken the immune system and cause problems such as infection, fever, weight loss, fatigue, night sweats, nerve damage, and anemia. People with  Castleman disease have an increased risk of lymphoma.  Also called angiofollicular lymph node hyperplasia and giant lymph node hyperplasia.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708057" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Castleman disease&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708058" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;enfermedad de Castleman&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>enfermedad de Castleman</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno poco frecuente en el que se forman masas benignas (no cancerosas) en el tejido de los ganglios linfáticos. Principalmente, la  enfermedad de Castleman se presenta de dos formas: localizada (unicéntrica) y multicéntrica.  La enfermedad de Castleman unicéntrica solo afecta un grupo  de ganglios linfáticos en una parte del cuerpo, por lo general, en el pecho o el abdomen y es posible que no cause síntomas. La enfermedad de Castleman multicéntrica afecta muchos grupos de ganglios linfáticos y el tejido linfoide de todo el cuerpo. Puede debilitar el sistema inmunitario y causar problemas como infecciones, fiebre, pérdida de peso, fatiga, sudores nocturnos, daño a los nervios y anemia. Las personas con enfermedad de Castleman tienen un riesgo más alto de linfoma. También se llama hiperplasia angiofolicular linfoide y hiperplasia de ganglio linfático gigante.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2014-07-31</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
