<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046614"><TermName>thrombocyte</TermName><TermPronunciation>(THROM-boh-site)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A tiny piece of cell that is made by breaking off of a large cell in the bone marrow. Thrombocytes are found in the blood and spleen. They help form blood clots to slow or stop bleeding, and to help wounds heal.  Also called platelet.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708495" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;thrombocyte&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708496" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;trombocito&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000503952" type="image/jpeg" alt="Blood cells; drawing shows six types of white blood cells (monocytes, lymphocytes, neutrophils, eosinophils, basophils, and macrophages), a red blood cell (erythrocyte), and platelets." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_2"><Caption language="en">Blood cells. Blood contains many types of cells: white blood cells (monocytes, lymphocytes, neutrophils, eosinophils, basophils, and macrophages), red blood cells (erythrocytes), and platelets. Blood circulates through the body in the arteries and veins.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000553586" type="image/jpeg" alt="Células sanguíneas; el dibujo muestra seis tipos de glóbulos blancos (monolitos, linfocitos, neutrófilos, eosinófilos, basófilos y macrófagos), un glóbulo rojo (eritrocito) y plaquetas." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Células sanguíneas. La sangre contiene muchos tipos de células: glóbulos blancos (monolitos, linfocitos, neutrófilos, eosinófilos, basófilos y macrófagos), glóbulos rojos (eritrocitos) y plaquetas. La sangre circula por el cuerpo a través de las arterias y las venas.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>trombocito</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Pedazo diminuto de célula que se produce cuando se rompe una célula grande de la médula ósea.   Los trombocitos se encuentran en la sangre y el bazo. Ayudan a formar coágulos de sangre para hacer más lento o impedir el sangrado, y ayudan a cicatrizar las heridas. También se llama plaqueta.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2012-08-14</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
