<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046637"><TermName>upper GI series</TermName><TermPronunciation>(UH-per ... SEER-eez)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A series of x-ray pictures of the esophagus, stomach, and duodenum (the first part of the small intestine). The x-ray pictures are taken after the patient drinks a liquid containing barium sulfate (a form of the silver-white metallic element barium). The barium sulfate coats and outlines the inner walls of the upper gastrointestinal tract so that they can be seen on the x-ray pictures. Also called upper gastrointestinal series.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000709843" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;upper GI series&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000709844" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;series gastrointestinales superiores&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000430686" type="image/jpeg" alt="Barium swallow; shows barium liquid flowing through the esophagus and into the stomach. " language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_5"><Caption language="en">Barium swallow. The patient swallows barium liquid and it flows through the esophagus and into the stomach. X-rays are taken to look for abnormal areas.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000747240" type="image/jpeg" alt="Ingesta de bario; muestra el bario líquido en su paso por del esófago hasta el estómago. " language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_6"><Caption language="es">Ingesta de bario. El paciente ingiere bario líquido y este pasa por el  esófago hacia el estómago. Se toma una radiografía para identificar áreas anormales.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>series gastrointestinales superiores</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Serie de imágenes de rayos X del esófago, el estómago y el duodeno (la primera parte del intestino delgado).   Las imágenes de rayos X se toman después de que el paciente bebe un líquido que contiene sulfato de bario (una forma del elemento metálico bario de color blanco plateado). El sulfato de bario recubre y permite ver el contorno de las paredes internas del aparato digestivo superior para que se puedan observar en las imágenes de rayos X. También se llama series del aparato digestivo superior.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2009-07-21</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
