<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000446196"><TermName>stage III uterine sarcoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(…YOO-teh-rin sar-KOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cancer has spread beyond the uterus and cervix, but has not spread beyond the pelvis. Stage III is divided into stages IIIA, IIIB, and IIIC, based on how far the cancer has spread within the pelvis. In stage IIIA, cancer has spread to the outer layer of the uterus and/or to the fallopian tubes, ovaries, and ligaments of the uterus. In stage IIIB, cancer has spread to the vagina or to the parametrium (connective tissue and fat around the uterus). In stage IIIC, cancer has spread to lymph nodes in the pelvis and/or around the aorta (largest artery in the body, which carries blood away from the heart).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704885" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III uterine sarcoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704884" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sarcoma uterino en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>sarcoma uterino en estadio III</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El cáncer se ha diseminado más allá del útero y el cuello uterino, pero no se ha diseminado más allá de la pelvis. El estadio lll se divide en estadios  lllA, lllB y  lllC dependiendo de cuánto se haya diseminado el cáncer en la pelvis. En el estadio lllA, el cáncer se ha diseminado a la capa exterior del útero o las trompas de falopio, ovarios y ligamentos del útero. En el estadio lllB, el cáncer se ha diseminado a la vagina o al parametrio (tejido conjuntivo y grasa alrededor del útero). En el estadio lllC, el cáncer se ha diseminado a los ganglios linfáticos en la pelvis o alrededor de la aorta (la arteria mayor del cuerpo, la cual conduce la sangre que sale del corazón).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-01-05</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2012-10-19</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000257805">Uterine Sarcoma Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef href="CDR0000452962">Sarcoma uterino: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
