<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000450139"><TermName>stage III nasal cavity and ethmoid sinus cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(...NAY-zul KA-vih-tee…ETH-moyd SY-nus KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cancer (1) has spread to any of the following: the eye socket, maxillary sinus, roof of the mouth, and/or the bone between the eyes; or (2) has spread to one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the cancer and the lymph node is 3 centimeters or smaller. Cancer has also spread to any of the following: the nasal cavity, ethmoid sinus, eye socket, maxillary sinus, roof of the mouth, and/or the bone between the eyes.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714999" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III nasal cavity and ethmoid sinus cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000715000" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de la cavidad nasal y el seno etmoideo en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de la cavidad nasal y el seno etmoideo en estadio III</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El cáncer 1) se diseminó a cualquiera de los siguientes sitios: la cuenca del ojo, el seno maxilar, el techo de la boca o el hueso que está entre los ojos; o 2) se diseminó a un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello en el que está el cáncer y el ganglio linfático mide tres centímetros o menos. El cáncer también se diseminó a cualquiera de los siguientes sitios: la cavidad nasal, el seno etmoideo, la cuenca del ojo, el seno maxilar, el techo de la boca o el hueso que está entre los ojos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2011-02-15</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258028">Paranasal Sinus and Nasal Cavity Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000558933">Cáncer de seno paranasal y de cavidad nasal:  Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
