<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046429"><TermName>endoscopic retrograde cholangiopancreatography</TermName><TermPronunciation>(en-doh-SKAH-pik REH-troh-grayd koh-LAN-jee-oh-PAN-kree-uh-TAH-gruh-fee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure that uses an endoscope to examine and x-ray the pancreatic duct, hepatic duct, common bile duct, duodenal papilla, and gallbladder. An endoscope is a thin, tube-like instrument with a light and a lens for viewing. The endoscope is passed through the mouth and down into the first part of the small intestine (duodenum). A smaller tube (catheter) is then inserted through the endoscope into the bile and pancreatic ducts. A dye is injected through the catheter into the ducts, and an x-ray is taken. Also called ERCP.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708722" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;endoscopic retrograde cholangiopancreatography&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708721" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;colangiopancreatografía retrógrada endoscópica&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>colangiopancreatografía retrógrada endoscópica</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento en el que se usa un endoscopio para examinar y tomar una radiografía del conducto pancreático, el conducto hepático, el conducto colédoco, la papila duodenal y la vesícula biliar. Un endoscopio es un instrumento delgado con forma de tubo con una luz y una lente para observar. El endoscopio se introduce por la boca hasta el primer segmento del intestino delgado (duodeno). Una sonda más pequeña (catéter) se inserta luego a través del endoscopio hasta las vías biliares y los conductos pancreáticos. Se inyecta un tinte a través del catéter en los conductos y se toma una radiografía. También se llama CPRE.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2007-01-24</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
