<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000470244"><TermName>Nexavar</TermName><TermPronunciation>(NEK-suh-var)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat advanced kidney cancer and a type of liver cancer that cannot be removed by surgery. It is also used to treat a type of advanced thyroid cancer that did not get better with radioactive iodine treatment. It is being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Nexavar stops cancer cells from dividing and may prevent the growth of new blood vessels that tumors need to grow. It is a type of kinase inhibitor and a type of antiangiogenesis agent. Also called BAY 43-9006 and sorafenib tosylate.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000716723" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Nexavar&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000716722" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Nexavar&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Nexavar</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para
tratar el cáncer avanzado de riñón y un tipo de cáncer del
hígado que no se puede extirpar mediante cirugía. También se usa en el tratamiento de un tipo de cáncer de tiroides avanzado que no mejora con el tratamiento de yodo radiactivo. Asimismo,
está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de
cáncer. Nexavar impide que las células se
multipliquen y puede prevenir  la formación de vasos sanguíneos nuevos que los tumores necesitan para
crecer. Es un tipo de inhibidor de la cinasa y un tipo de antiangiogénico. También se llama BAY 43-9006 y tosilato de sorafenib.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2006-02-21</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-12-30</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000492017">Sorafenib Tosylate</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
