<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046617"><TermName>megestrol acetate</TermName><TermPronunciation>(meh-JES-trol A-seh-tayt)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat advanced breast and endometrial cancer. It is also used to treat anorexia (loss of appetite) and cachexia (weakness and loss of body weight and muscle mass) in patients with AIDS.  It is also being studied in the treatment of anorexia and cachexia in patients with cancer or other conditions. Megestrol acetate blocks the effects of the hormone estrogen in the body, which may help keep some cancer cells from growing. It may also improve appetite. Megestrol acetate is a type of progestin. Also called Megace.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000731685" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;megestrol acetate&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000731684" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;acetato de megestrol&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/><SpanishTermName>acetato de megestrol</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para tratar el cáncer de mama y endometrio en estadio avanzado. También se utiliza para tratar la anorexia (pérdida del apetito) y la caquexia (debilidad y pérdida de peso corporal y masa muscular) en pacientes de SIDA. También está en estudio para tratar la anorexia y la caquexia en pacientes de cáncer y otras afecciones. El acetato de megestrol impide los efectos de la hormona estrógeno en el cuerpo, que puede impedir el crecimiento de algunas células cancerosas. Asimismo, puede ayudar a mejorar el apetito. El acetato de megestrol es un tipo de progestina. También se llama Megace.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2013-05-02</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
