<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045900"><TermName>stage II ovarian epithelial, fallopian tube, and primary peritoneal cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... oh-VAYR-ee-un EH-pih-THEE-lee-ul fuh-LOH-pee-in ... PRY-mayr-ee PAYR-ih-toh-NEE-ul KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cancer is found in one or both ovaries or fallopian tubes and has spread into other areas of the pelvis, or primary peritoneal cancer is found within the pelvis. Stage II is divided into stages IIA and IIB.  In stage IIA, cancer has spread from where it first formed to the uterus and/or the fallopian tubes and/or the ovaries. In stage IIB, cancer has spread from the ovary or fallopian tube to organs in  the peritoneal cavity (the body cavity that contains most of the organs in the abdomen).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707416" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage II ovarian epithelial, fallopian tube, and primary peritoneal cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707415" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer epitelial de ovario, de trompa de Falopio y primario de peritoneo en estadio II&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer epitelial de ovario, de trompa de Falopio y primario de peritoneo en estadio II</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El cáncer se encuentra en uno o ambos ovarios o trompas de Falopio y se ha diseminado a otras áreas de la pelvis, o el cáncer primario del peritoneo se encuentra dentro de la pelvis. El estadio ll se divide en estadio llA y llB. En el estadio llA, el cáncer se ha diseminado desde donde se originó hacia el útero o las trompas de Falopio, o los ovarios. En el estadio llB, el cáncer se diseminó de los ovarios o trompa de Falopio a los órganos que revisten la cavidad peritoneal (la cavidad del cuerpo que contiene la mayoría de los órganos del abdomen).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2015-06-11</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062963">Ovarian Epithelial, Fallopian Tube, and Primary Peritoneal Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256785">Cáncer epitelial de ovario, de trompa de Falopio y primario de peritoneo: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
