<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044271"><TermName>PDQ</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>PDQ is an online database developed and maintained by the National Cancer Institute. Designed to make the most current, credible, and accurate cancer information available to health professionals and the public, PDQ contains peer-reviewed summaries on cancer treatment, screening, prevention, genetics, complementary and alternative medicine, and supportive care; a registry of cancer clinical trials from around the world; and directories of physicians, professionals who provide genetics services, and organizations that provide cancer care. Most of this information, and more specific information about PDQ, can be found on the NCI's Web site at <ExternalRef xref="http://www.cancer.gov/publications/pdq">http://www.cancer.gov/publications/pdq</ExternalRef>. Also called Physician Data Query.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><SpanishTermName>PDQ</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El  PDQ es una base de datos en línea creada y mantenida por el Instituto Nacional del Cáncer. Ha sido diseñada para que la información sobre cáncer más actual, fiable y exacta esté a disposición de los profesionales de la salud y el público. El PDQ contiene resúmenes revisados por científicos sobre el tratamiento, los exámenes de detección, la prevención, la genética, la medicina complementaria y alternativa, y el cuidado médico de apoyo relacionados con el cáncer; un registro de los estudios clínicos sobre el cáncer de todo el mundo, y directorios de médicos, profesionales que proporcionan atención genética y organizaciones que proveen atención  del cáncer. Gran parte de esta información y otras más específicas acerca del PDQ se puede encontrar en el portal de Internet del Instituto Nacional del Cáncer en <ExternalRef xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/publicaciones/pdq">http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/publicaciones/pdq</ExternalRef>. También se llama Physician Data Query.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2015-06-03</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/publications/pdq">PDQ® -  NCI's Comprehensive Database</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/publicaciones/pdq">Base de datos integral del NCI - PDQ®</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
