<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046570"><TermName>scan</TermName><TermPronunciation>(skan)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of test that makes detailed pictures of areas inside the body. A scan may also refer to the picture that gets made during the test. Scans may be used to help diagnose disease, plan treatment, or find out how well treatment is working. There are many different types of scans, including computed tomography (CT) scans, magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) scans, and nuclear medicine scans (such as bone scans and liver scans). CT scans are done with an x-ray machine linked to a computer. MRI scans are done with radio waves and a powerful magnet linked to a computer. Nuclear medicine scans are done with small amounts of radioactive substances that are injected into the body and a special machine that detects the radioactive substance.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000731663" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;scan&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000731662" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;exploración&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>exploración</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de prueba en la que se toman  fotos detalladas de áreas del interior del cuerpo. Una exploración también puede hacer referencia a la imagen que se crea  durante la prueba. Las exploraciones también se usan para diagnosticar enfermedades, planificar  o determinar la eficacia de los tratamientos.  Hay muchos tipos diferentes de exploraciones, como la exploración por tomografía computarizada (TC), la exploración con imágenes por resonancia magnética  (IRM), y la exploración en medicina nuclear (como las exploraciones de los huesos o del hígado). Las exploraciones por TC se hacen con una máquina de rayos X conectada a una computadora. Las exploraciones con  IRM se hacen con ondas de radio y un imán potente conectado a una computadora. Las exploraciones en medicina nuclear se hacen con partículas pequeñas de sustancias radiactivas que se inyectan en el cuerpo y con una máquina especial que detecta la sustancia radiactiva.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2014-02-13</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000689578">imaging test</RelatedGlossaryTermRef><RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000045720">imaging procedure</RelatedGlossaryTermRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
