<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045368"><TermName>lymphoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(lim-FOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cancer that begins in cells of the immune system. There are two basic categories of lymphomas. One kind is Hodgkin lymphoma, which is marked by the presence of a type of cell called the Reed-Sternberg cell. The other category is non-Hodgkin lymphomas, which includes a large, diverse group of cancers of immune system cells. Non-Hodgkin lymphomas can be further divided into cancers that have an indolent (slow-growing) course and those that have an aggressive (fast-growing) course. These subtypes behave and respond to treatment differently. Both Hodgkin and non-Hodgkin lymphomas can occur in children and adults, and prognosis and treatment depend on the stage and the type of cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705383" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;lymphoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705382" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;linfoma&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>linfoma</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cáncer que empieza en las células del sistema inmunitario. Hay dos categorías básicas de linfomas. Una categoría es el linfoma de Hodgkin, que se caracteriza por la presencia de un tipo de célula llamada célula de Reed-Sternberg. La otra categoría es la de los linfomas no Hodgkin, que incluye un grupo grande y diverso de cánceres de las células del sistema inmunitario. Los linfomas no Hodgkin pueden dividirse aún más en cánceres que tienen una evolución o curso indolente (de crecimiento lento) y aquellos que tienen una evolución dinámica (de crecimiento rápido). Estos subtipos se comportan y responden al tratamiento de distinto modo. Tanto los linfomas de Hodgkin como los no Hodgkin se pueden presentar en niños y adultos, y el pronóstico y tratamiento dependen del estadio y el tipo de cáncer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2007-09-21</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
