<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045899"><TermName>stage I ovarian epithelial and fallopian tube cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(...oh-VAYR-ee-un EH-pih-THEE-lee-ul ... fuh-LOH-pee-in ... KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cancer is found in one or both ovaries or fallopian tubes. Stage I is divided into stages IA, IB, and IC. In stage IA, cancer is found inside a single ovary or fallopian tube. In stage IB, cancer is found inside both ovaries or fallopian tubes. In stage IC, cancer is found inside one or both ovaries or fallopian tubes and one of the following is true: (1) cancer is also found on the outside surface of one or both ovaries or fallopian tubes; or (2) the capsule (outer covering) of the ovary has ruptured (broken open); or (3) cancer cells are found in the fluid of the peritoneal cavity (the body cavity that contains most of the organs in the abdomen) or in washings of the peritoneum (tissue lining the peritoneal cavity).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707413" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage I ovarian epithelial and fallopian tube cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707414" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer epitelial de los ovarios en estadio I&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer epitelial de ovario y de trompa de Falopio en estadio I</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El cáncer se encuentra en uno o ambos ovarios, o en las trompas de Falopio. El estadio l se divide en los estadios lA, lB y lC. En el estadio lA, el cáncer se encuentra en el interior de un solo ovario o una trompa de Falopio. En el estadio IB, el cáncer se encuentra dentro de ambos ovarios o trompas de Falopio. En el estadio lC, el cáncer se encuentra dentro de uno o ambos ovarios o trompas de Falopio y uno de lo siguiente es cierto: 1) el cáncer también se encuentra fuera de la superficie de uno o ambos ovarios o trompas de Falopio; o 2) la cápsula (revestimiento externo) del ovario se ha roto (se abrió); o 3)  las células cancerosas se encuentran en el líquido de la cavidad peritoneal (la cavidad del cuerpo que contiene la mayoría de los órganos del abdomen) o en los lavados del peritoneo (tejidos que reviste la cavidad peritoneal).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2015-06-11</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062963">Ovarian Epithelial, Fallopian Tube, and Primary Peritoneal Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256785">Cáncer epitelial de ovario, de trompa de Falopio y primario de peritoneo: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
