<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045934"><TermName>ultraviolet radiation</TermName><TermPronunciation>(UL-truh-VY-oh-let RAY-dee-AY-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Invisible rays that are part of the energy that comes from the sun. Ultraviolet radiation that reaches the Earth's surface is made up of two types of rays, called UVA and UVB. Ultraviolet radiation also comes from sun lamps and tanning beds. It can cause skin damage, premature aging, melanoma, and other types of skin cancer. It can also cause problems with the eyes and the immune system. Skin specialists recommend that people use sunscreens that protect the skin from both kinds of ultraviolet radiation. In medicine, ultraviolet radiation also comes from special lamps or a laser and is used to treat certain skin conditions such as psoriasis, vitiligo, and skin tumors of cutaneous T-cell lymphoma. Also called UV radiation.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707474" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ultraviolet radiation&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707473" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;radiación ultravioleta&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>radiación ultravioleta</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Rayos invisibles que forman parte de la energía que viene del sol. La radiación ultravioleta que llega a la superficie de la Tierra se compone de dos tipos de rayos que se llaman UVA y UVB. La radiación ultravioleta también proviene de lámparas solares y camillas de bronceado. Puede producir daños en  la piel, envejecimiento prematuro, causar melanoma y otros tipos de cáncer de piel. También puede causar problemas en los ojos y el sistema inmunitario. Los especialistas de la piel recomiendan que las personas usen filtros solares  que protejan la piel de ambas clases de radiación ultravioleta. En el campo de la medicina, la radiación ultravioleta también surge de lámparas o rayos láser especiales que se usan para tratar ciertas afecciones de la piel como soriasis, vitiligo y tumores de la piel causados por el linfoma cutáneo de células T. También se llama radiación UV.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2010-06-08</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
