<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046325"><TermName>kidney</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KID-nee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>One of a pair of organs in the abdomen. The kidneys remove waste and extra water from the blood (as urine) and help keep chemicals (such as sodium, potassium, and calcium) balanced in the body. The kidneys also make hormones that help control blood pressure and stimulate bone marrow to make red blood cells.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708546" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;kidney&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708545" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;riñón&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000664288" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomy of the male urinary system; shows the right and left kidneys, the ureters, the bladder filled with urine, and the urethra passing through the penis. The inside of the left kidney shows the renal pelvis. An inset shows the renal tubules and urine.  Also shown is the prostate." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Anatomy of the male urinary system showing the kidneys, ureters, bladder, and urethra. Urine is made in the renal tubules and collects in the renal pelvis of each kidney. The urine flows from the kidneys through the ureters to the bladder. The urine is stored in the bladder until it leaves the body through the urethra.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000649519" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomy of the female urinary system; shows the right and left kidneys, the ureters, the bladder filled with urine, and the urethra. The inside of the left kidney shows the renal pelvis. An inset shows the renal tubules and urine. The uterus is also shown." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="en">Anatomy of the female urinary system showing the kidneys, ureters, bladder, and urethra. Urine is made in the renal tubules and collects in the renal pelvis of each kidney. The urine flows from the kidneys through the ureters to the bladder. The urine is stored in the bladder until it leaves the body through the urethra.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000668844" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomía del sistema urinario masculino; se observan los riñones derecho e izquierdo, los uréteres, la vejiga llena de orina y la uretra que pasa a través del pene. En el interior del riñón izquierdo se observa la pelvis renal. En el recuadro, se observan los túbulos renales y la orina. También se muestra la próstata." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_5"><Caption language="es">Anatomía del sistema urinario masculino: se muestran los riñones, los uréteres, la vejiga y la uretra. La orina se elabora en los túbulos renales y se almacena en la pelvis renal de cada riñón. La orina fluye desde los riñones y pasa a través de los uréteres hasta la vejiga. La orina se acumula en la vejiga hasta que sale del cuerpo a través de la uretra.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000668842" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomía del sistema urinario femenino; se observan los riñones derecho e izquierdo, los uréteres, la vejiga llena de orina y la uretra. En el interior del riñón izquierdo se observa la pelvis renal. En el recuadro, se observan los túbulos renales y la orina. También se muestra el útero." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_6"><Caption language="es">Anatomía del sistema urinario femenino: se muestran los riñones, los uréteres, la vejiga y la uretra. La orina se elabora en los túbulos renales y se almacena en la pelvis renal de cada riñón. La orina fluye desde los riñones y pasa a través de los uréteres hasta la vejiga. La orina se acumula en la vejiga hasta que sale del cuerpo a través de la uretra.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>riñón</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Uno de un par de órganos en el abdomen. Los riñones eliminan los desperdicios de la sangre y el exceso de agua (en forma de orina) y ayuda a mantener el balance de sustancias químicas  (como sodio, potasio y calcio)  en el cuerpo. Los riñones elaboran hormonas que ayudan a controlar la presión arterial y estimulan a la médula ósea a producir glóbulos rojos. </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2012-10-30</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/kidney">Kidney Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/rinon">Cáncer de riñón</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
