<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045127"><TermName>stage II testicular cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(...tes-TIH-kyoo-ler KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage II is divided into stage IIA, stage IIB, and stage IIC, and is determined after a radical inguinal orchiectomy (surgery to remove the testicle) is done. In stage IIA, cancer is anywhere within the testicle, spermatic cord, or scrotum; and has spread to up to 5 lymph nodes in the abdomen (none larger than 2 centimeters); all tumor marker levels are normal or slightly above normal. In stage IIB, cancer is anywhere within the testicle, spermatic cord, or scrotum; and has spread to up to 5 lymph nodes in the abdomen (at least one of the lymph nodes is larger than 2 centimeters, but none is larger than 5 centimeters), or has spread to more than 5 lymph nodes (the lymph nodes are not larger than 5 centimeters); all tumor marker levels are normal or slightly above normal. In stage IIC, cancer is anywhere within the testicle, spermatic cord, or scrotum; and has spread to a lymph node in the abdomen that is larger than 5 centimeters; all tumor marker levels are normal or slightly above normal.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705040" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage II testicular cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705041" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de testículo en estadio II&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de testículo en estadio II</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio II se divide en estadio IIA, estadio IIB y estadio IIC y se determina después de realizar una orquiectomía inguinal radical (cirugía para extirpar el testículo). En el estadio IIA, el cáncer está en cualquier lugar dentro del testículo, el cordón espermático o el escroto, y se diseminó a no más de cinco ganglios linfáticos del abdomen (ninguno de más de dos centímetros); todos los índices de marcadores tumorales son normales o ligeramente más altos que lo normal. En el estadio IIB, el cáncer está en cualquier lugar dentro del testículo, el cordón espermático o el escroto y se diseminó  a no más de cinco ganglios linfáticos en el abdomen (por lo menos uno de los ganglios linfáticos mide más de dos centímetros, pero ninguno mide más de cinco centímetros) o el cáncer se diseminó a más de cinco ganglios linfáticos (los ganglios linfáticos no miden más de cinco centímetros); todos los índices de marcadores tumorales son normales o ligeramente más altos de lo normal. En el estadio IIC, el cáncer está en cualquier lugar dentro del testículo, el cordón espermático o el escroto, y se diseminó a un ganglio linfático del abdomen  que mide más de cinco centímetros;  todos los índices de marcadores tumorales son normales o ligeramente más altos de lo normal.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2010-09-29</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
