<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046115"><TermName>bevacizumab</TermName><TermPronunciation>(beh-vuh-SIH-zoo-mab)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used alone or with other drugs to treat certain types of cervical, colorectal, lung, kidney, ovarian, fallopian tube, and primary peritoneal cancer, and glioblastoma (a type of brain cancer). It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Bevacizumab binds to a protein called vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF). This may prevent the growth of new blood vessels that tumors need to grow. It is a type of antiangiogenesis agent and a type of monoclonal antibody. Also called Avastin.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707697" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;bevacizumab&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707696" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;bevacizumab&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>bevacizumab</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa solo o con otros fármacos para tratar ciertos tipos de cáncer de cuello uterino, colorrectal, de pulmón, de riñón, de ovario, de trompas de Falopio, y el cáncer primario del peritoneo y el glioblastoma (un tipo de cáncer de cerebro). También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El bevacizumab se une a una proteína que se llama factor de crecimiento del endotelio vascular (FCEV). Puede prevenir la formación de nuevos vasos sanguíneos que los tumores necesitan para crecer. Es un tipo de antiangiogénico y un tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal. También se llama Avastin.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2014-11-24</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000487564">Bevacizumab</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
