<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000467833"><TermName>Consensus Development Program</TermName><TermPronunciation>(kun-SEN-sus dee-VEH-lup-ment PROH-gram)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A program of the <ExternalRef xref="https://consensus.nih.gov/">National Institutes of Health</ExternalRef> to bring together an independent group of experts to review scientific evidence related to an important public health issue. For a specific issue, a panel of experts (such as doctors and scientists) reviews reports and papers on the subject, listens to information presented by other experts in the field, and hears comments from the general public. Based on the evidence presented, the panel writes a report summarizing the findings, which is made available to the public. The report is not intended to be a practice guideline.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733224" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Consensus Development Program&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733225" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Programa de Desarrollo de Consenso&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Programa de Desarrollo de Consenso</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Programa de los Institutos Nacionales de la Salud (<ExternalRef xref="https://consensus.nih.gov/">National Institutes of Health</ExternalRef>) que reúne un grupo independiente de expertos que examine pruebas científicas relacionadas con un asunto importante y específico de salud pública. (Nota: la información contenida en el enlace anterior solo está disponible en inglés.) Un panel de expertos (como médicos y científicos) analiza los informes y documentos sobre el tema, escucha la información presentada por otros expertos en el campo y atiende las observaciones del público en general. Con base en las pruebas presentadas, el panel escribe un informe que resume los resultados y los pone a disposición del público. Este informe no pretende ser una pauta de tratamiento.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2006-05-11</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
