<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045333"><TermName>cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A term for
          diseases in which abnormal cells divide without control and
          can invade nearby tissues. Cancer cells can also spread to
          other parts of the body through the blood and lymph
          systems. There are several main types of cancer. Carcinoma
          is a cancer that begins in the skin or in tissues that line
          or cover internal organs. Sarcoma is a cancer that begins in
          bone, cartilage, fat, muscle, blood vessels, or other
          connective or supportive tissue. Leukemia is a cancer that
          starts in blood-forming tissue, such as the bone marrow, and
          causes large numbers of abnormal blood cells to be produced
          and enter the blood. Lymphoma and multiple myeloma are
          cancers that begin in the cells of the immune system.
          Central nervous system cancers are cancers that begin in
          the tissues of the brain and spinal cord. Also called malignancy.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705333" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705332" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Nombre dado a las enfermedades en las que  hay células anormales que se multiplican sin control y pueden invadir los tejidos cercanos. Las células de cáncer también se pueden diseminar hasta otras partes del cuerpo a través del torrente sanguíneo y el sistema linfático. El carcinoma es un cáncer que empieza en la piel o en los tejidos que revisten o cubren los órganos internos.   El sarcoma es un cáncer que empieza en el hueso, el cartílago, la grasa, el músculo, los vasos sanguíneos u otro tejido conjuntivo o de sostén. La leucemia es un cáncer que comienza en un  tejido donde se forman las células sanguíneas, como la médula ósea, y hace que se produzca un gran número de células sanguíneas anormales y que estas entren en la sangre.   El linfoma y el mieloma múltiple son cánceres que empiezan en las células del sistema inmunitario.   Los cánceres del sistema nervioso central empiezan en los tejidos del cerebro y la médula espinal. También se llama neoplasia maligna.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2013-01-24</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/what-is-cancer">What Is Cancer? </RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/que-es">¿Qué es el cáncer?</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
