<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000450093"><TermName>borderline personality disorder</TermName><TermPronunciation>(BOR-der-LINE PER-suh-NA-lih-tee dis-OR-der)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A serious mental illness marked by unstable moods and impulsive behavior. People with BPD have problems with relationships, family and work life, long-term planning, and self-identity. Symptoms include intense bouts of anger, depression, and anxiety that may lead to self-injury or suicide, drug or alcohol abuse, excessive spending, binge eating, or risky sex. A person with BPD who is diagnosed with cancer may be at an increased risk of suicide. Also called BPD.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000715147" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;borderline personality disorder&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000715148" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;trastorno limítrofe de la personalidad&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>trastorno limítrofe de la personalidad</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>BPD (por sus sigla en inglés). Enfermedad mental grave caracterizada por estados inestables de ánimo y comportamiento impulsivo. Las personas con BPD tienen problemas con las relaciones, la familia y la vida laboral, la planificación a largo plazo y la autoidentidad. Los síntomas incluyen episodios intensos de angustia, depresión y ansiedad que pueden conducir a lesiones en contra de uno mismo o suicidio, abuso de fármacos u alcohol, gasto excesivo, comer en forma compulsiva o mantener relaciones sexuales riesgosas. Una persona con BPD a quien se le diagnostica cáncer puede tener mayor riesgo de suicidarse. También se llama BPD.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2006-01-25</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2007-01-18</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
