<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000445084"><TermName>skin cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(skin KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cancer that forms in the tissues of the skin. There are several types of skin cancer. Skin cancer that forms in melanocytes (skin cells that make pigment) is called melanoma. Skin cancer that forms in the lower part of the epidermis (the outer layer of the skin) is called basal cell carcinoma. Skin cancer that forms in squamous cells (flat cells that form the surface of the skin) is called squamous cell carcinoma. Skin cancer that forms in neuroendocrine cells (cells that release hormones in response to signals from the nervous system) is called neuroendocrine carcinoma of the skin. Most skin cancers form in older people on parts of the body exposed to the sun or in people who have weakened immune systems.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714650" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;skin cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714651" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de piel&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000579036" type="image/jpeg" alt="Skin anatomy; drawing shows layers of the epidermis, dermis, and subcutaneous tissue including hair shafts and follicles, oil glands, lymph vessels, nerves, fatty tissue, veins, arteries, and a sweat gland." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_2"><Caption language="en">Anatomy of the skin, showing the epidermis, dermis, and subcutaneous tissue.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000609816" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomía de la piel; el dibujo muestra capas de la epidermis, la dermis y el tejido subcutáneo, como los tallos del pelo y los folículos pilosos, las glándulas sebáceas, los vasos linfáticos, los nervios, el tejido graso, las venas, las arterias y una glándula sudorípara." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Anatomía de la piel. Muestra la epidermis, la dermis y el tejido subcutáneo.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de piel</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cáncer que se forma en los tejidos de la piel. Hay varios tipos de cáncer de piel. El cáncer de piel que  se forma en los melanocitos (células de la piel que producen pigmento) se llama melanoma. El cáncer de piel que se forma en la parte interior de la epidermis (la capa más externa de la piel) se llama carcinoma de células basales. El cáncer de piel que se forma en las células escamosas (células planas que forman la superficie de la piel) se llama carcinoma de células escamosas. El cáncer de piel que se forma en las células neuroendocrinas (células que liberan hormonas en respuesta a una señal del sistema nervioso) se llama carcinoma neuroendocrino de la piel. La mayoría de los cánceres de la piel se forman en las partes del cuerpo expuestas al sol de las personas de edad avanzada  o en personas con un sistema inmunitario debilitado.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-10-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2010-06-08</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/skin">Skin Cancer (Including Melanoma)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/piel">Cáncer de piel</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
