<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045203"><TermName>Burkitt lymphoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(BER-kit lim-FOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>An aggressive (fast-growing) type of B-cell non-Hodgkin lymphoma that occurs most often in children and young adults. The disease may affect the jaw, central nervous system, bowel, kidneys, ovaries, or other organs. There are three main types of Burkitt lymphoma (sporadic, endemic, and immunodeficiency related). Sporadic Burkitt lymphoma occurs throughout the world, and endemic Burkitt lymphoma occurs in Africa. Immunodeficiency-related Burkitt lymphoma is most often seen in AIDS patients.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705145" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Burkitt lymphoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705144" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;linfoma de Burkitt&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>linfoma de Burkitt</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de linfoma no Hodgkin de células B dinámico (de crecimiento rápido)  que se presenta con mayor frecuencia en los niños y los adultos jóvenes. La enfermedad puede afectar la mandíbula, el sistema nervioso central, el intestino, los riñones, los ovarios u otros órganos. Hay tres tipos principales de linfoma de Burkitt: esporádico, endémico y relacionado con la inmunodeficiencia. El linfoma de Burkitt esporádico se presenta en todo el mundo, el linfoma de Burkitt endémico se presenta en el África y el linfoma de Burkitt relacionado con la inmunodeficiencia se observa con mayor frecuencia en los pacientes de SIDA.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2007-09-21</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/lymphoma">Lymphoma</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/linfoma">Linfoma</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
