<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000427252"><TermName>cholecalciferol</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KOH-leh-kal-SIH-feh-rol)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A nutrient that the body needs in small amounts to function and stay healthy. Cholecalciferol helps the body use calcium and phosphorus to make strong bones and teeth. It is fat-soluble (can dissolve in fats and oils) and is found in fatty fish, egg yolks, and dairy products. Skin exposed to sunshine can also make cholecalciferol. Not enough cholecalciferol can cause a bone disease called rickets. It is being studied in the prevention and treatment of some types of cancer.  Also called vitamin D.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713320" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cholecalciferol&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713321" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;colecalciferol&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>colecalciferol</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Nutriente que el cuerpo necesita para funcionar y mantenerse sano. El colecalciferol ayuda al cuerpo a usar el calcio y el fósforo para  fortificar los huesos y los dientes. Es soluble en grasas (se puede disolver en grasas y aceites) y se encuentra en los peces grasos, las yemas de huevos y los productos lácteos. La piel también puede producir colecalciferol cuando se expone a la luz del sol. No disponer de suficiente colecalciferol puede causar una enfermedad de los huesos que se llama raquitismo. Está en estudio para la prevención y el tratamiento de algunos tipos de cáncer. También se llama vitamina D.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-05-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2008-12-12</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/risk/diet/vitamin-d-fact-sheet">Vitamin D and Cancer Prevention</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/riesgo/dieta/hoja-informativa-vitamina-d">Vitamina D y prevención del cáncer</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
