<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046101"><TermName>stage III hypopharyngeal cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... HY-poh-fuh-RIN-jee-ul KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The tumor (1) is larger than 4 centimeters or has spread to the larynx (voice box) or esophagus. Cancer may have  spread to one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the tumor and the lymph node is 3 centimeters or smaller; or (2)  has spread to one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the tumor and the lymph node is 3 centimeters or smaller and cancer is found (1)  in one area of the hypopharynx and/or is 2 centimeters or smaller; or (2) in more than one area of the hypopharynx or in nearby tissues, or is larger than 2 centimeters but not larger than 4 centimeters and has not spread to  the larynx.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707675" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III hypopharyngeal cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707674" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de la hipofaringe en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de la hipofaringe en estadio III</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El tumor: 1) mide más  de cuatro centímetros o se ha diseminado a la laringe o el esófago. El cáncer se puede haber diseminado a un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello en que está el tumor y el ganglio linfático mide tres centímetros o menos; o 2) se ha diseminado a un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello en que está el tumor y el ganglio linfático  mide tres centímetros o menos y se encuentra cáncer en 1) un área de la hipofaringe o mide dos centímetros o menos; o en 2) más de un área de la hipofaringe o en los tejidos cercanos o mide más de dos centímetros pero no más de cuatro centímetros y no se ha diseminado a la laringe.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2011-05-24</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258014">Hypopharyngeal Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256820">Cáncer de hipofaringe: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
