<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046313"><TermName>liver-spleen scan</TermName><TermPronunciation>(LIH-ver ... skan)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure used to check for abnormal areas in the liver or spleen. A very small amount of a radioactive substance is injected into a vein and travels through the blood to the liver and spleen. It is detected by a scanner linked to a computer, which forms an image of the areas where the radioactive substance collects. A liver-spleen scan may be used to help find cancer in the liver or spleen, cirrhosis, hepatitis, and other liver or spleen problems.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708025" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;liver-spleen scan&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708026" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;exploración de hígado y bazo&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000658698" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomy of the liver; drawing shows the right and left  front lobes of the liver, bile ducts, gallbladder, stomach, spleen, pancreas, colon, and small intestine. The two back lobes of the liver are not shown." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Anatomy of the  liver. The liver is in the upper abdomen near the stomach, intestines, gallbladder, and pancreas. The liver has four lobes. Two lobes are on the front and two small lobes (not shown) are on the back of the liver.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000663939" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomía del hígado; la figura muestra los  lóbulos derecho e izquierdo del hígado, los conductos biliares, la vesícula biliar, el estómago, el bazo, el páncreas, el colon y el intestino delgado.  Los dos lóbulos posteriores del hígado no se muestran." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Anatomía del hígado.  El hígado está en la parte superior del abdomen, cerca del estómago, los intestinos, la vesícula biliar y el páncreas.  El hígado tiene cuatro lóbulos.  Dos lóbulos están adelante del hígado y dos lóbulos pequeños (que no se muestran) están atrás del hígado.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>exploración de hígado y bazo</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento que se usa para revisar áreas anormales del hígado o el bazo. Se inyecta una pequeña cantidad de una sustancia radiactiva en la vena que recorre el torrente sanguíneo hasta el hígado y el bazo.  Esta se detecta con un escáner conectado a una computadora que forma una imagen de las áreas del interior del cuerpo donde se acumula la sustancia radiactiva. Se puede hacer una exploración  de hígado y bazo para ayudar a encontrar cáncer en estos órganos,  cirrosis, hepatitis y otros problemas en el hígado o el bazo. </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2014-03-21</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
