<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000496506"><TermName>surveillance</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ser-VAY-lents)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Periodic clinical evaluation of an individual who is at increased risk of developing a condition (compared with the general population) aimed at detecting new or recurrent disease. In public health, surveillance may also refer to the systematic collection of information regarding the incidence, prevalence, and mortality related to various medical conditions or health-related events.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>In medicine, closely watching a patient’s condition but not treating it unless there are changes in test results. Surveillance is also used to find early signs that a disease has come back. It may also be used for a person who has an increased risk of a disease, such as cancer. During surveillance, certain exams and tests are done on a regular schedule. In public health, surveillance may also refer to the ongoing collection of information about a disease, such as cancer, in a certain group of people. The information collected may include where the disease occurs in a population and whether it affects people of a certain gender, age, or ethnic group. </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718349" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;surveillance&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718348" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;vigilancia&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>vigilancia</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>En medicina, la observación  detallada de  la afección de un paciente  pero sin darle tratamiento, a menos que haya cambios en los resultados de las pruebas. La vigilancia también se utiliza para encontrar signos tempranos de que la enfermedad haya regresado. También se puede usar en el caso de que  un paciente tenga un riesgo más alto de una enfermedad, como cáncer. Durante la vigilancia, se realizan ciertos exámenes y pruebas con regularidad. En salud pública, la vigilancia también se puede referir  a la constante recopilación de información sobre una enfermedad, como el cáncer, en cierto grupo de personas. La información recopilada puede incluir dónde se presenta la enfermedad en una población y si afecta a personas de determinado sexo, edad o grupo étnico. </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2006-10-21</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2014-07-31</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
