<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000413920"><TermName>stage 0 transitional cell carcinoma in situ of the renal pelvis and ureter</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... tran-ZIH-shuh-nul sel KAR-sih-NOH-muh in SY-too ... REE-nul PEL-vus ... YER-eh-ter)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Abnormal cells are found in tissue lining the inside of the renal pelvis or ureter. These abnormal cells may become cancer and spread into nearby normal tissue. Stage 0 is divided into stages 0a (noninvasive papillary carcinoma) and 0is (carcinoma in situ), depending on the type of tumor. Stage 0a may look like tiny mushrooms growing from the tissue lining the inside of the renal pelvis or ureter.  Stage 0is is a flat tumor on the tissue lining the inside of the renal pelvis or ureter.  </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713292" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage 0 transitional cell carcinoma in situ of the renal pelvis and ureter&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713293" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;carcinoma de células de transición de pelvis renal y uréter in situ, estadio 0&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>carcinoma de células de transición de pelvis renal y uréter in situ, estadio 0</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Se encuentran células anormales en el tejido que reviste el interior de la pelvis renal o el uréter. Estas células anormales se pueden volver cancerosas y diseminarse hasta el tejido normal cercano. El estadio 0 se divide en los estadios 0a (carcinoma papilar no invasor) y 0is (carcinoma in situ), según el tipo de tumor. En el estadio 0a, el tumor puede tener el aspecto de hongos diminutos que sobresalen del revestimiento de la pelvis renal o el uréter. El estadio 0is es un tumor plano en el tejido que reviste el interior de la pelvis renal o el uréter.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-04-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2011-11-17</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000343585">Transitional Cell Cancer of the Renal Pelvis and Ureter Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256834">Cáncer de células de transición de pelvis renal y de uréter: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
