<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044483"><TermName>biotherapy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(BY-oh-THAYR-uh-pee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of treatment that uses substances made from living organisms to treat disease. These substances may occur naturally in the body or may be made in the laboratory. Some biotherapies stimulate or suppress the immune system to help the body fight cancer, infection, and other diseases. Other biotherapies attack specific cancer cells, which may help keep them from growing or kill them. They may also lessen certain side effects caused by some cancer treatments. Types of biotherapy include immunotherapy (such as vaccines, cytokines, and some antibodies), gene therapy, and some targeted therapies. Also called biological response modifier therapy, biological therapy,  and BRM therapy.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704641" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;biotherapy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704640" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;bioterapia&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>bioterapia</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de tratamiento para el que se usan sustancias elaboradas por organismos vivos para tratar enfermedades. El cuerpo puede elaborar estas sustancias de forma natural o se pueden producir en un laboratorio. Algunas bioterapias estimulan o inhiben el sistema inmunitario para ayudar al cuerpo a combatir el cáncer, las infecciones y otras enfermedades. Otras bioterapias atacan células cancerosas específicas y pueden impedir su crecimiento o destruirlas. También pueden disminuir algunos efectos secundarios de ciertos tratamientos del cáncer. Los tipos de bioterapia son la inmunoterapia (como las vacunas, las citocinas y algunos anticuerpos), la terapia génica y algunas terapias dirigidas. También se llama terapia biológica, Terapia MRB,  y Tratamiento modificador de la respuesta biológica.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2013-09-24</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/types/immunotherapy/bio-therapies-fact-sheet">Biological Therapies for Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/tipos/inmunoterapia/hoja-informativa-terapias-biologicas-respuestas">Terapias biológicas para el cáncer</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
