<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000445074"><TermName>ovarian cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(oh-VAYR-ee-un KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cancer that forms in tissues of the ovary (one of a pair of female reproductive glands in which the ova, or eggs, are formed). Most ovarian cancers are either ovarian epithelial cancers (cancer that begins in the cells on the surface of the ovary) or malignant germ cell tumors (cancer that begins in egg cells). Fallopian tube cancer and primary peritoneal cancer are similar to ovarian epithelial cancer and are staged and treated the same way.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714636" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ovarian cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714637" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de ovario&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de ovario</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cáncer que se forma en los tejidos del ovario (par de glándulas reproductoras femeninas en la que se forman los óvulos o huevos). La mayoría de los cánceres de ovario son cánceres epiteliales de ovario (cáncer que empieza en las células de la superficie del ovario) o tumores de células germinativas de ovario malignos (cáncer que empieza en las células de los óvulos). El cáncer de la trompa de Falopio y el cáncer de peritoneo primario son similares al cáncer epitelial de ovario, y se estadifican y tratan de la misma forma.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-10-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2014-12-27</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/ovarian">Ovarian, Fallopian Tube, and Primary Peritoneal Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/ovario">Cáncer de ovario, de trompa de Falopio y primario de peritoneo</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
