<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044464"><TermName>stereotactic radiation therapy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(STAYR-ee-oh-TAK-tik RAY-dee-AY-shun THAYR-uh-pee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stereotactic is derived from the Greek words <Emphasis>stereos</Emphasis>, meaning solid (as in 3-dimensional) and <Emphasis>taxis</Emphasis>, meaning arrangement, order, or orientation. Stereotactic radiation therapy (SRT) implies the use of technologies, which improve targeting accuracy and allow for hypofractionated radiation delivery. Generally, a 3-dimensional coordinate system is used to localize the target(s) most accurately. Stereotactic techniques can be used with conventional fractionation (1.8–2 Gy per day), but because of improved targeting accuracy, SRT allows for hypofractionated radiation (larger doses per fraction, fewer number of fractions, and a shorter treatment course).  Also called stereotactic external-beam radiation therapy and stereotaxic radiation therapy.</DefinitionText><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of external radiation therapy that uses special equipment to position the patient and precisely deliver radiation to a tumor. The total dose of radiation is divided into several smaller doses given over several days. Stereotactic radiation therapy is used to treat brain tumors and other brain disorders. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer, such as lung cancer. Also called stereotactic external-beam radiation therapy and stereotaxic radiation therapy.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704624" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stereotactic radiation therapy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704625" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;radioterapia estereotáctica&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>radioterapia estereotáctica</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Estereotáctica se deriva de las palabras griegas <Emphasis>stereos</Emphasis>, que signifca sólido (como en tridimensional) y <Emphasis>taxis</Emphasis>, que significa arreglo, orden u orientación.  La radioterapia estereotáctica implica el uso de tecnología, las cuales mejoran la localización precisa de la lesión  y permiten la administración de radiación hipofraccionada.  Por lo general, se usa  un sistema de cordenadas tridimensionales con el fin de ubicar la lesión de una forma más precisa.  Las técnicas estereotácticas se pueden usar con fragmentación convencional  (1,8–2 Gy por día), pero debido a su superioridad en la localización precisa de la lesión,  la RE permite la radiación hipofraccionada (dosis más altas por fracción, menor cantidad de fracciones y  tratamientos más breves).  También se llama radioterapia estereotáctica de haz externo y radioterapia estereotáxica.</DefinitionText><Audience>Health professional</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de radioterapia externa en la que se usa un equipo especial para poner en posición al paciente y administrarle la radiación hacia el tumor de modo preciso. La dosis total de radiación se divide en varias dosis más pequeñas que se administran durante varios días. La radioterapia estereotáctica se usa para tratar tumores cerebrales y otros trastornos del cerebro. Asimismo, está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer como, por ejemplo, el cáncer de pulmón. También se llama radioterapia estereotáctica de haz externo y radioterapia estereotáxica.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2007-08-20</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
