<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046457"><TermName>craniotomy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KRAY-nee-AH-toh-mee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>An operation in which a piece of the skull is removed. A craniotomy may be done so doctors can remove a brain tumor or abnormal brain tissue. It may also be done to remove blood or blood clots from the brain, relieve pressure in the brain after an injury or stroke, repair a brain aneurysm (a bulge in a blood vessel wall) or skull fractures, or treat other brain conditions. The piece of skull that is removed is usually put back in place after the brain problem has been treated.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708768" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;craniotomy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708769" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;craneotomía&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000680519" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing of a craniotomy showing a section of the scalp that has been pulled back to remove a piece of the skull; the dura covering the brain has been opened to expose the brain. The layer of muscle under the scalp is also shown." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Craniotomy:  An opening is made in the skull and a piece of the skull is removed to show part of the brain.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000709151" type="image/jpeg" alt="Dibujo de una craneotomía que muestra una sección del cuero cabelludo que se retiró hacia atrás para extraer un trozo del cráneo;  se abrió la duramadre que cubre el cerebro para exponer el cerebro.   También se muestra la capa de músculo bajo el cuero cabelludo.  " language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Craneotomía. Se realiza una abertura en el cráneo y se extrae un trozo del cráneo para mostrar parte del cerebro.  </Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>craneotomía</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Operación en la que se extrae un pedazo del cráneo. Una craneotomía se realiza para que los médicos puedan extraer un tumor o tejido anormal del cerebro. También se puede realizar para extraer sangre o coágulos del cerebro, aliviar la presión en el cerebro después de una lesión o derrame, reparar un aneurisma cerebral (un abultamiento en la pared de un vaso sanguíneo) o fracturas del cráneo, o para tratar otras afecciones del cerebro. Con frecuencia, el pedazo de cráneo que se extrae se vuelve  a poner en su sitio luego del tratamiento del problema cerebral.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2013-08-30</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
