<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045148"><TermName>non-Hodgkin lymphoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(non-HOJ-kin lim-FOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Any of a large group of cancers of lymphocytes (white blood cells). Non-Hodgkin lymphomas can occur at any age and are often marked by lymph nodes that are larger than normal, fever, and weight loss. There are many different types of non-Hodgkin lymphoma. These types can be divided into aggressive (fast-growing) and indolent (slow-growing) types, and they can be formed from either B-cells or T-cells. B-cell non-Hodgkin lymphomas include Burkitt lymphoma, chronic lymphocytic leukemia/small lymphocytic lymphoma (CLL/SLL), diffuse large B-cell lymphoma, follicular lymphoma, immunoblastic large cell lymphoma, precursor B-lymphoblastic lymphoma, and mantle cell lymphoma. T-cell non-Hodgkin lymphomas include mycosis fungoides, anaplastic large cell lymphoma, and precursor T-lymphoblastic lymphoma. Lymphomas that occur after bone marrow or stem cell transplantation are usually B-cell non-Hodgkin lymphomas. Prognosis and treatment depend on the stage and type of disease. Also called NHL.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705078" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;non-Hodgkin lymphoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705079" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;linfoma no Hodgkin&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>linfoma no Hodgkin</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cualquiera de un grupo grande de cánceres de linfocitos (glóbulos blancos). Los linfomas no Hodgkin se pueden presentar a cualquier edad y a menudo se caracterizan por ganglios linfáticos más grandes de lo normal, fiebre y pérdida de peso. Hay muchos tipos diferentes de linfomas no Hodgkin. Estos tipos se pueden dividir en dinámicos (de crecimiento rápido) e indolentes (de crecimiento lento) y pueden estar formados por células B o células T. Los linfomas no Hodgkin de células B incluyen el linfoma de Burkitt, la leucemia linfocítica crónica o el linfoma linfocítico pequeño (LLC o LLP), el linfoma difuso de células B grandes, el linfoma folicular, el linfoma inmunoblástico de células grandes, el linfoma linfoblástico de células B precursoras y el linfoma de células de manto. Los linfomas no Hodgkin de células T incluyen la micosis fungoides, el linfoma anaplásico de células grandes y el linfoma linfoblástico de células T precursoras. Los linfomas que se presentan después de un trasplante de médula ósea o un trasplante de células madre son habitualmente linfomas no Hodgkin de células B. El pronóstico y el tratamiento dependen del estadio y el tipo de la enfermedad. También se llama LNH.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2009-04-24</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/lymphoma">Lymphoma</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/linfoma">Linfoma</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
