<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045283"><TermName>stage III laryngeal cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... luh-RIN-jee-ul KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage III laryngeal cancer depends on whether cancer has spread from the supraglottis, glottis, or subglottis. In stage III cancer of the supraglottis, (1) cancer is in the larynx only and the vocal cords cannot move, and/or cancer is in tissues next to the larynx; cancer may have spread to one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the original tumor and the lymph node is 3 centimeters or smaller; or (2) cancer is in one area of the supraglottis and in one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the original tumor; the lymph node is 3 centimeters or smaller and the vocal cords can move normally; or (3) cancer is in more than one area of the supraglottis or surrounding tissues and in one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the original tumor; the lymph node is 3 centimeters or smaller. In stage III cancer of the glottis, (1) cancer is in the larynx only and the vocal cords cannot move, and/or cancer is in tissues next to the larynx; cancer may have spread to one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the original tumor and the lymph node is 3 centimeters or smaller; or (2) cancer is in one or both vocal cords and in one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the original tumor; the lymph node is 3 centimeters or smaller and the vocal cords can move normally; or (3) cancer has spread to the supraglottis and/or the subglottis, and/or the vocal cords cannot move normally; cancer has also spread to one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the original tumor and the lymph node is 3 centimeters or smaller. In stage III cancer of the subglottis, (1) cancer is in the larynx and the vocal cords cannot move; cancer may have spread to one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the original tumor and the lymph node is 3 centimeters or smaller; or (2) cancer is in the subglottis and in one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the original tumor; the lymph node is 3 centimeters or smaller; or (3) cancer has spread to one or both vocal cords, which may not move normally; cancer has also spread to one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the original tumor and the lymph node is 3 centimeters or smaller.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705262" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III laryngeal cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705263" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de laringe en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de laringe en estadio III</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El cáncer de laringe en estadio III se determina según el cáncer se haya diseminado desde la supraglotis, la glotis o la subglotis. En el caso del cáncer de la supraglotis en estadio III, 1) el cáncer está solo en la laringe y las cuerdas vocales no se pueden mover, o el cáncer está en los tejidos cercanos a la laringe; el cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello donde estaba el tumor original; el ganglio linfático mide tres centímetros o menos; o 2) el cáncer está en un área de la supraglotis y en un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello donde estaba el tumor original; el ganglio linfático mide tres centímetros o menos, y las cuerdas vocales se pueden mover normalmente; o 3) el cáncer está en más de un área de la supraglotis o los tejidos que la rodean, y en un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello donde estaba el tumor original; el ganglio linfático mide tres centímetros o menos. En el caso del cáncer de la glotis en estadio III, 1) el cáncer está solo en la laringe y las cuerdas vocales no se pueden mover, o el cáncer está en los tejidos cerca de la laringe; el cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello donde estaba el tumor original y el ganglio linfático mide tres centímetros o menos; o 2) el cáncer está en una o ambas cuerdas vocales, y en un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello donde estaba el tumor original; el ganglio linfático mide tres centímetros o menos y las cuerdas vocales se pueden mover normalmente; o 3) el cáncer se diseminó hasta la supraglotis o la subglotis, o las cuerdas vocales no se pueden mover normalmente; el cáncer también se diseminó hasta un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello donde estaba el tumor original y el ganglio linfático mide tres centímetros o menos. En el caso del cáncer de la subglotis en estadio III, 1) el cáncer está en la laringe y las cuerdas vocales no se pueden mover; el cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello donde estaba el tumor original y el ganglio linfático mide tres centímetros o menos; o 2) el cáncer está en la subglotis y en un ganglio del cuello del mismo lado donde estaba el tumor original; el ganglio linfático mide tres centímetros o menos; o 3) el cáncer se diseminó hasta una o ambas cuerdas vocales, que pueden no moverse normalmente; el cáncer también se diseminó hasta un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello donde estaba el tumor original y el ganglio linfático mide tres centímetros o menos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2010-11-17</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258016">Laryngeal Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000393556">Cáncer de laringe: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
