<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000407756"><TermName>cholesterol</TermName><TermPronunciation>(koh-LES-teh-rol)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A waxy, fat-like substance made in the liver, and found in the blood and in all cells of the body. Cholesterol is important for good health and is needed for making cell walls, tissues, hormones, vitamin D, and bile acid. Cholesterol also comes from eating foods taken from animals such as egg yolks, meat, and whole-milk dairy products. Too much cholesterol in the blood may build up in blood vessel walls, block blood flow to tissues and organs, and increase the risk of developing heart disease and stroke.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713260" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cholesterol&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713259" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;colesterol&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>colesterol</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Sustancia cerosa, parecida a la grasa, que elabora el hígado; se encuentra en la sangre y en todas las células del cuerpo. El colesterol es importante para la buena salud y se necesita para fabricar las paredes de las células, los tejidos, las hormonas, la vitamina D y el ácido de la bilis. El colesterol también proviene del consumo de alimentos de origen animal, como las yemas de huevo, la carne y los productos lácteos elaborados con leche entera. Cuando hay demasiado colesterol en la sangre, se puede acumular en las paredes de los vasos sanguíneos, bloquear el flujo de sangre a los tejidos y los órganos, y aumentar el riesgo de contraer enfermedades del corazón y sufrir accidentes cerebrovasculares.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-01-24</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
