<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046181"><TermName>stage IV nasopharyngeal cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(...NAY-zoh-fuh-RIN-jee-ul KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage IV nasopharyngeal cancer is divided into stages IVA, IVB, and IVC. In stage IVA, cancer has spread beyond the nasopharynx and may have spread to the cranial nerves, the hypopharynx (bottom part of the throat), areas in and around the side of the skull or jawbone, and/or the bone around the eye. Cancer may have spread to one or more lymph nodes on one or both sides of the neck and/or to lymph nodes behind the pharynx, and the affected lymph nodes are 6 centimeters or smaller. In stage IVB, cancer has spread to lymph nodes between the collarbone and the top of the shoulder and/or the affected lymph nodes are larger than 6 centimeters. In stage IVC, cancer has spread beyond nearby lymph nodes to other parts of the body.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707796" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IV nasopharyngeal cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707797" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de nasofaringe en estadio IV&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de nasofaringe en estadio IV</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El cáncer de la nasofaringe en estadio IV se divide en los estadios IVA, IVB y IVC. En el estadio IVA, el cáncer se diseminó más allá de la nasofaringe y se puede haber diseminado hasta los nervios craneales, la hipofaringe (parte inferior de la garganta), áreas en el cráneo o la mandíbula o alrededor de ellas, o el hueso alrededor del ojo. El cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta uno o más ganglios linfáticos en uno o ambos lados del cuello, o hasta los ganglios linfáticos detrás de la faringe, los ganglios linfáticos afectados miden seis centímetros o menos. En el estadio IVB, el cáncer se diseminó hasta los ganglios linfáticos entre la clavícula y la parte superior del hombro, o los ganglios linfáticos afectados miden más de seis centímetros. En el estadio IVC, el cáncer se diseminó más allá de los ganglios linfáticos cercanos hasta otras partes del cuerpo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2011-01-26</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062966">Nasopharyngeal Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256817">Cáncer de nasofaringe: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
