<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045830"><TermName>phase I clinical trial</TermName><TermPronunciation>(fayz … KLIH-nih-kul TRY-ul)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The first step in testing a new treatment in humans. A phase I study tests the safety, side effects, best dose, and timing of a new treatment. It may also test the best way to give a new treatment (for example, by mouth, infusion into a vein, or injection) and how the treatment affects the body. The dose is usually increased a little at a time in order to find the highest dose that does not cause harmful side effects. Phase I clinical trials usually include only a small number of patients who have not been helped by other treatments. Sometimes they include healthy volunteers.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000731231" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;phase I clinical trial&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><SpanishTermName>ensayo clínico de fase I</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Primer paso en la puesta a prueba de un tratamiento nuevo en seres humanos. En los estudios de fase I se prueban la seguridad, los efectos secundarios, la mejor dosis y el momento adecuado de administración del tratamiento nuevo. También se puede evaluar la mejor manera de administrar un tratamiento nuevo (por ejemplo, por vía oral, por infusión intravenosa o por inyección) y la manera en que el tratamiento afecta el cuerpo. Por lo general, la dosis se aumenta un poco cada vez para encontrar la dosis más alta que no causa efectos secundarios perjudiciales. Por lo común, en los ensayos de fase I se incluye solo un número pequeño de pacientes que no mejoraron con otros tratamientos. En ocasiones, participan voluntarios sanos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2015-09-29</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
