<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000460127"><TermName>Ashkenazi Jews</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ASH-keh-NAH-zee jooz)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>One of two
          major ancestral groups of Jewish individuals, comprised of
          those whose ancestors lived in Central and Eastern Europe
          (e.g., Germany, Poland, Russia). The other group is
          designated Sephardic Jews and includes those whose
          ancestors lived in North Africa, the Middle East, and
          Spain. Most Jews living in the United States are of
          Ashkenazi descent.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>One of two
          major ancestral groups of Jewish individuals. The ancestors
          of Ashkenazi Jews lived in Central and Eastern Europe
          (e.g., Germany, Poland, Russia). The other group is called
          Sephardic Jews and includes those whose ancestors lived in
          North Africa, the Middle East, and Spain. Most Jews living
          in the United States are of Ashkenazi
          descent.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000736929" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Ashkenazi Jews&quot;" language="en" id="_2"/><SpanishTermName>judíos asquenazíes</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Uno de los dos principales grupos ancestrales de personas judías. Los antepasados
           de los judíos asquenazíes vivieron en Europa Central y Oriental
           (por ejemplo, en Alemania, Polonia y Rusia). El otro grupo es el de los judíos sefardíes e incluye a aquellos cuyos antepasados ​​vivieron en
           el norte de África, Oriente Medio y España. La mayoría de los judíos que viven
           en los Estados Unidos son de ascendencia asquenazí.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-12-22</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
