<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000445075"><TermName>pharyngeal cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(fuh-RIN-jee-ul KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cancer that forms in tissues of the pharynx (the hollow tube inside the neck that starts behind the nose and ends at the top of the windpipe and esophagus). Pharyngeal cancer includes cancer of the nasopharynx (the upper part of the throat behind the nose), the oropharynx (the middle part of the pharynx), and the hypopharynx (the bottom part of the pharynx). Cancer of the larynx (voice box) may also be included as a type of pharyngeal cancer. Most pharyngeal cancers are squamous cell carcinomas (cancer that begins in thin, flat cells that look like fish scales). Also called throat cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714777" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pharyngeal cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714776" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de faringe&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de faringe</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cáncer que se forma en los tejidos de la faringe (el tubo hueco dentro del cuello que comienza detrás de la nariz y termina en la parte superior de la tráquea y esófago). El cáncer de faringe incluye el cáncer de nasofaringe (la parte superior de la garganta detrás de la nariz), orofaringe (la parte media de la faringe) y hipofaringe (la parte inferior de la faringe). El cáncer de laringe también puede incluirse como un tipo de cáncer de faringe. La mayoría de los cánceres de faringe son carcinomas de células escamosas (cáncer que empieza en las células planas y delgadas que parecen escamas de pez). También se llama cáncer de garganta.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-10-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2007-01-10</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/head-and-neck">Head and Neck Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/cabeza-cuello">Cáncer de cabeza y cuello</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
