<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046549"><TermName>radical prostatectomy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(RA-dih-kul PROS-tuh-TEK-toh-mee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Surgery to remove the entire prostate and some of the tissue around it. Nearby lymph nodes may also be removed. In a radical retropubic prostatectomy, an incision (cut) is made in the wall of the lower abdomen. In a radical perineal prostatectomy, an incision (cut) is made in the perineum (the area between the anus and scrotum). In a laparoscopic radical prostatectomy, several small incisions (cuts) are made in the wall of the abdomen. A laparoscope (a thin, tube-like instrument with a light and lens for viewing) is inserted through one opening to guide the surgery. Surgical instruments are inserted through the other openings to do the surgery.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708931" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;radical prostatectomy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708932" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;prostatectomía radical&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000442274" type="image/jpeg" alt="Two panel drawing showing two ways  of doing a  radical prostatectomy;  in the first panel, dotted line shows where incision is made through the wall of the abdomen for a retropubic prostatectomy;  in the second panel, dotted line shows where incision is made in area between the scrotum and the anus for a perineal prostatectomy." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_2"><Caption language="en">Two types of radical prostatectomy. In a retropubic prostatectomy,  the prostate is removed through an incision in the wall of  the abdomen.  In a perineal prostatectomy, the prostate is removed through an incision in the area between the scrotum and the anus.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000457832" type="image/jpeg" alt="El dibujo a dos paneles muestra dos formas de hacer una prostatectomía radical; en el primer panel, la línea punteada muestra el lugar donde se hace la incisión a través de la pared del abdomen para realizar una prostatectomía retropúbica; en el segundo panel, la línea punteada muestra el lugar donde se hace la incisión entre el escroto y el ano para realizar una prostatectomía perineal." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Los dos  tipos de prostatectomía radical. En la prostatectomía retropúbica, se extirpa la próstata a través de una incisión en la pared del abdomen. En la prostatectomía perineal, se extirpa la próstata a través de una incisión entre el escroto y el ano.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>prostatectomía radical</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cirugía para extirpar toda la próstata y parte del tejido que la rodea. También se pueden extraer ganglios linfáticos cercanos. En una prostatectomía retropúbica radical, se hace una incisión (corte) en la pared del abdomen inferior. En una prostatectomía perineal radical, se hace una incisión (corte) en el perineo (el área entre el ano y el escroto). En una prostatectomía  laparoscópica radical,  se  hacen varias incisiones (cortes) en la pared del abdomen. Un laparoscopio (instrumento delgado en forma de tubo con una luz y un lente para observar) se introduce a través de una abertura para guiar la cirugía. Los instrumentos quirúrgicos se introducen a  través de las otras aberturas para llevar a cabo la cirugía.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2012-10-25</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
