<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045907"><TermName>stage II adult non-Hodgkin lymphoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... uh-dult non-HOJ-kin lim-FOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage II is divided into stages II and IIE. In stage II, cancer is found in two or more lymph node groups, and both are either  above or below  the diaphragm (the thin muscle below the lungs that helps breathing and separates the chest from the abdomen). In stage IIE, cancer is found in one or more lymph node groups either above or below the diaphragm and outside the lymph nodes in an organ or area on the same side of the diaphragm as the lymph nodes with cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707429" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage II adult non-Hodgkin lymphoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707430" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;linfoma no Hodgkin en adultos en estadio II&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000614648" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage II adult non-Hodgkin lymphoma; drawing shows cancer in lymph node groups above and below the diaphragm. An inset shows a lymph node with a lymph vessel, an artery, and a vein. Lymphoma cells containing cancer are shown in the lymph node." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Stage II adult non-Hodgkin lymphoma. Cancer is found in two or more lymph node groups, and both are either above (a) or below (b) the diaphragm.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000614650" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIE adult non-Hodgkin lymphoma; drawing shows cancer in one lymph node group above the diaphragm and in the left lung. An inset shows a lymph node with a lymph vessel, an artery, and a vein. Lymphoma cells containing cancer are shown in the lymph node." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_5"><Caption language="en">Stage IIE adult non-Hodgkin lymphoma. Cancer is found in one or more lymph node groups either above or below the diaphragm and outside the lymph nodes in an organ or area on the same side of the diaphragm as the lymph nodes with cancer (a).</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000632878" type="image/jpeg" alt="Linfoma no Hodgkin en adultos en estadio II; el dibujo muestra un cáncer en grupos de ganglios linfáticos por encima y por debajo del diafragma. En un recuadro, se puede ver un ganglio linfático con un vaso linfático, una arteria y una vena. En el ganglio linfático se pueden ver células de linfoma que contienen cáncer." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Linfoma no Hodgkin en adultos en estadio II. El cáncer se encuentra en dos o más grupos de ganglios linfáticos y ambos están por encima (a) o por debajo (b) del diafragma.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000632879" type="image/jpeg" alt="Linfoma no Hodgkin en adultos en estadio IIE; el dibujo muestra un cáncer en un grupo de ganglios linfáticos por encima del diafragma y en el pulmón izquierdo. En un recuadro, se puede ver un ganglio linfático con un vaso linfático, una arteria y una vena. En el ganglio linfático se puede ver células de linfoma que contienen cáncer." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_8"><Caption language="es">Linfoma no Hodgkin en adultos en estadio IIE. El cáncer se encuentra en uno o más grupos de ganglios linfáticos por encima o por debajo del diafragma, y en un área u órgano cercanos fuera de los ganglios linfáticos en el mismo lado del diafragma que los ganglios linfáticos con cancer (a).</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>linfoma no Hodgkin en adultos en estadio II</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio II se divide en los estadios II y IIE. En el estadio II, el cáncer se encuentra en dos o más grupos de ganglios linfáticos y ambos están por encima o por debajo del diafragma (el músculo delgado debajo de los pulmones que ayuda a respirar y separa el pecho del abdomen). En el estadio IIE, el cáncer se encuentra en uno o más grupos de ganglios linfáticos por encima o por debajo del diafragma y fuera de los ganglios linfáticos en un órgano o área del mismo lado del diafragma que los ganglios linfáticos con cáncer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2010-05-24</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
