<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046270"><TermName>neutrophil</TermName><TermPronunciation>(NOO-troh-fil)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of immune cell that is one of the first cell types to travel to the site of an infection. Neutrophils help fight infection by ingesting microorganisms and releasing enzymes that kill the microorganisms.  A neutrophil is a type of white blood cell, a type of granulocyte, and a type of phagocyte.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707945" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;neutrophil&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707946" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;neutrófilo&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000503952" type="image/jpeg" alt="Blood cells; drawing shows six types of white blood cells (monocytes, lymphocytes, neutrophils, eosinophils, basophils, and macrophages), a red blood cell (erythrocyte), and platelets." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_2"><Caption language="en">Blood cells. Blood contains many types of cells: white blood cells (monocytes, lymphocytes, neutrophils, eosinophils, basophils, and macrophages), red blood cells (erythrocytes), and platelets. Blood circulates through the body in the arteries and veins.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000553586" type="image/jpeg" alt="Células sanguíneas; el dibujo muestra seis tipos de glóbulos blancos (monolitos, linfocitos, neutrófilos, eosinófilos, basófilos y macrófagos), un glóbulo rojo (eritrocito) y plaquetas." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Células sanguíneas. La sangre contiene muchos tipos de células: glóbulos blancos (monolitos, linfocitos, neutrófilos, eosinófilos, basófilos y macrófagos), glóbulos rojos (eritrocitos) y plaquetas. La sangre circula por el cuerpo a través de las arterias y las venas.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>neutrófilo</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de célula inmunitaria; es uno de los primeros tipos de células que van al sitio de una infección. Los neutrófilos ayudan a combatir infecciones porque ingieren  los microorganismos y segregan enzimas que los destruyen. Un neutrófilo es un tipo de glóbulo blanco, un tipo de granulocito y un tipo de fagocito.  </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2009-02-05</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
