<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000407751"><TermName>small lymphocytic lymphoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... LIM-foh-SIH-tik lim-FOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>An indolent (slow-growing) type of lymphoma in which too many immature lymphocytes (white blood cells) are found mostly in the lymph nodes. This causes the lymph nodes to become larger than normal. Sometimes cancer cells are found in the blood and bone marrow, and the disease is called chronic lymphocytic leukemia. The disease is most often seen in people older than 50 years. Small lymphocytic lymphoma is a type of non-Hodgkin Lymphoma.  Also called SLL and well-differentiated lymphocytic lymphoma.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713255" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;small lymphocytic lymphoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713256" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;linfoma linfocítico pequeño&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>linfoma linfocítico pequeño</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de linfoma indolente (de crecimiento lento) en el que se encuentran demasiados linfocitos (glóbulos blancos) inmaduros en los ganglios linfáticos. Esto hace que los ganglios linfáticos se vuelvan más grandes de lo normal. A veces, se encuentran células cancerosas en la sangre y la médula ósea, y la enfermedad se llama leucemia linfocítica crónica. Esta enfermedad se presenta más a menudo en personas mayores de 50 años. El linfoma linfocítico pequeño es un tipo de linfoma no Hodgkin. También se llama linfoma linfocítico bien diferenciado y LLP.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-01-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2009-04-24</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/lymphoma">Lymphoma</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/linfoma">Linfoma</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
