<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000439436"><TermName>ascorbic acid</TermName><TermPronunciation>(uh-SKOR-bik A-sid)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A nutrient that the body needs in small amounts to function and stay healthy. Ascorbic acid helps fight infections, heal wounds, and keep tissues healthy. It is an antioxidant that helps prevent cell damage caused by free radicals (highly reactive chemicals). Ascorbic acid is found in all fruits and vegetables, especially citrus fruits, strawberries, cantaloupe, green peppers, tomatoes, broccoli, leafy greens, and potatoes. It is water-soluble (can dissolve in water) and must be taken in every day. Ascorbic acid is being studied in the prevention and treatment of some types of cancer.  Also called vitamin C.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713698" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ascorbic acid&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713699" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ácido ascórbico&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>ácido ascórbico</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Nutriente que el cuerpo necesita en pequeñas cantidades para funcionar y mantenerse sano. El ácido ascórbico ayuda a combatir las infecciones, cicatrizar las heridas y mantener los tejidos saludables. Es un antioxidante que ayuda a prevenir el daño a los tejidos causado por los radicales libres (sustancias químicas sumamente reactivas).  El ácido ascórbico se encuentra en todas las frutas y verduras, especialmente las frutillas, el melón, los pimientos verdes, los tomates, el brócoli, las verduras de hoja y las papas.  Es soluble en agua (se puede disolver en agua) y se debe tomar todos los días.  El ácido ascórbico está en estudio para la prevención y el tratamiento de algunos tipos de cáncer. También se llama vitamina C.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-07-08</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2010-05-25</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
