<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045128"><TermName>stage III testicular cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(...tes-TIH-kyoo-ler KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage III is divided into stage IIIA, stage IIIB, and stage IIIC, and is determined after a radical inguinal orchiectomy (surgery to remove the testicle) is done. In stage IIIA, cancer is anywhere within the testicle, spermatic cord, or scrotum; may have spread to one or more lymph nodes in the abdomen; and has spread to distant lymph nodes or to the lungs; tumor marker levels may range from normal to slightly above normal. In stage IIIB, cancer is anywhere within the testicle, spermatic cord, or scrotum; and may have spread to one or more lymph nodes in the abdomen, to distant lymph nodes or to the lungs; the level of one or more tumor markers is moderately above normal. In stage IIIC, cancer is anywhere within the testicle, spermatic cord, or scrotum; and may have spread to one or more lymph nodes in the abdomen, to distant lymph nodes, or to the lungs; the level of one or more tumor markers is high; OR, cancer is anywhere within the testicle, spermatic cord, or scrotum; and may have spread to one or more lymph nodes in the abdomen; and has not spread to distant lymph nodes or the lung but has spread to other parts of the body; tumor marker levels may range from normal to high.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705042" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III testicular cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705043" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de testículo en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de testículo en estadio III</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio III se divide en estadio IIIA, estadio IIIB y estadio IIIC, y se determina después de realizar una orquiectomía inguinal radical (cirugía para extirpar el testículo). En el estadio IIIA, el cáncer está en cualquier lugar dentro del testículo, el cordón espermático o el escroto; se puede haber diseminado a uno o más ganglios linfáticos del abdomen, hasta ganglios linfáticos lejanos o los pulmones; los índices de marcadores tumorales pueden ser normales o ligeramente más altos de lo normal. En el estadio IIIB, el cáncer está en cualquier lugar dentro del testículo, el cordón espermático o el escroto y se puede haber diseminado a uno o más ganglios linfáticos del abdomen, hasta ganglios linfáticos lejanos o hasta  los pulmones; el índice de uno o más marcadores tumorales está moderadamente por encima de lo normal. En el estadio IIIC, el cáncer está en cualquier lugar dentro del testículo, el cordón espermático o el escroto y se puede haber diseminado a uno o más ganglios linfáticos del abdomen o hasta ganglios linfáticos lejanos o hasta los pulmones; el índice de uno o más marcadores tumorales es alto; O el cáncer está en cualquier lugar dentro del testículo, el cordón espermático o el escroto; y se puede haber diseminado a uno o más ganglios linfáticos del abdomen;  y no se diseminó hasta ganglios linfáticos lejanos o el pulmón, pero se diseminó hasta otras partes del cuerpo; los índices de marcadores tumorales pueden variar de normales a altos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2010-09-29</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
