<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000446525"><TermName>small intestine cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... in-TES-tin KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare cancer that forms in tissues of the small intestine (the part of the digestive tract between the stomach and the large intestine). The most common type is adenocarcinoma (cancer that begins in cells that make and release mucus and other fluids). Other types of small intestine cancer include sarcoma (cancer that begins in connective or supportive tissue), carcinoid tumor (a slow-growing type of cancer), gastrointestinal stromal tumor (a type of soft tissue sarcoma), and lymphoma (cancer that begins in immune system cells).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714774" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;small intestine cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714775" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de intestino delgado&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000415499" type="image/jpeg" alt="Gastrointestinal (digestive) system anatomy; shows esophagus, liver, stomach, colon, small intestine, rectum, and anus." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_2"><Caption language="en">Anatomy of the lower digestive system, showing the colon and other organs.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000415510" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomía del aparato  gastrointestinal (digestivo); muestra el esófago, el hígado, el estómago, el colon, el intestino delgado, el recto y el ano." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Anatomía del aparato digestivo inferior, muestra el colon y otros órganos.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de intestino delgado</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cáncer poco común que se forma en los tejidos del intestino delgado (la parte del tubo digestivo ubicada entre el estómago y el intestino grueso). El tipo más común es el adenocarcinoma (cáncer que comienza en las células que producen y liberan el moco y otros líquidos). Otros tipos de cáncer de intestino delgado son el sarcoma (cáncer que comienza en el tejido conjuntivo o el tejido de sostén), el tumor carcinoide (tipo de cáncer de crecimiento lento), el tumor estromal gastrointestinal (un tipo de sarcoma del tejido blando) y el linfoma (cáncer que comienza en las células del sistema inmunitario).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-12-22</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2006-11-07</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/small-intestine">Small Intestine Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/intestino-delgado">Cáncer de intestino delgado</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
