<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000449953"><TermName>early menopause</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... MEH-nuh-pawz)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A condition in which the ovaries stop working and menstrual periods stop before age 40.  Natural menopause usually occurs around age 50.  A woman is said to be in menopause when she hasn’t had a period for 12 months in a row.  Symptoms of menopause include hot flashes, mood swings, night sweats, vaginal dryness, trouble concentrating, and infertility. Early menopause can be caused by some cancer treatments, surgery to remove the ovaries, and certain diseases or genetic conditions.  Also called premature menopause, premature ovarian failure,  and primary ovarian insufficiency.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000715203" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;early menopause&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000715202" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;menopausia temprana&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>menopausia temprana</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección en la cual los ovarios dejan de funcionar y se detiene la menstruación antes de los 40 años de edad. Por lo general, la menopausia natural se presenta alrededor de los 50 años. Se dice que una mujer está en la menopausia cuando no tuvo su menstruación durante 12 meses seguidos. Los síntomas incluyen sofocos, cambios del estado de ánimo, sudores nocturnos, sequedad vaginal, problemas para concentrarse y esterilidad. La menopausia temprana puede ser un efecto de algunos tratamientos para el  cáncer, la cirugía para extirpar los ovarios y ciertas enfermedades o afecciones genéticas. También se llama insuficiencia ovárica prematura, insuficiencia ovárica primaria,  y menopausia prematura.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-09-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2009-01-30</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
