<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045904"><TermName>stage III gastric cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... GAS-trik KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage III is divided into stages IIIA, IIIB, and IIIC, depending on where the cancer has spread. In stage IIIA, cancer has spread to (1) the serosa (outermost) layer of the stomach wall and is found in 1 or 2 lymph nodes near the tumor; or (2) the subserosa (layer of tissue next to the serosa) of the stomach wall and is found in 3 to 6 lymph nodes near the tumor; or (3) the muscle layer of the stomach wall and is found in 7 or more lymph nodes near the tumor. In stage IIIB, cancer has spread to (1)  nearby organs such as the spleen, transverse colon, liver, diaphragm, pancreas, kidney, adrenal gland, or small intestine, and may be found in 1 or 2 lymph nodes near the tumor; or (2) the serosa (outermost layer) of the stomach wall and is found in 3 to 6 lymph nodes near the tumor; or (3) the subserosa (layer of tissue next to the serosa) of the stomach wall and is found in 7 or more lymph nodes near the tumor. In stage IIIC, cancer has spread to (1) nearby organs such as the spleen, transverse colon, liver, diaphragm, pancreas, kidney, adrenal gland, or small intestine, and may be found in 3 or more lymph nodes near the tumor; or (2)  the serosa (outermost layer) of the stomach wall and is found in 7 or more lymph nodes near the tumor.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707424" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III gastric cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707423" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de estómago en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de estómago en estadio III</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio III se divide en los estadios IIIA, IIIB y IIIC de acuerdo con el lugar hasta donde se haya diseminado el cáncer. En el estadio IIIA, el cáncer se diseminó hasta 1) la capa de serosa (más externa) de la pared del estómago y se encuentra en 1 o 2 ganglios linfáticos cerca del tumor; o 2) la serosa (capa más externa) de la pared del estómago y se encuentra en 3 a 6 ganglios linfáticos cerca del tumor, o 3) la capa muscular de la pared del estómago y se encuentra en siete o más ganglios linfáticos cerca del tumor. En el estadio IIIB, el cáncer se diseminó hasta 1)  órganos cercanos como el bazo, el colon transverso, el hígado, el diafragma, el páncreas, un riñón, una glándula suprarrenal o el intestino delgado, y se puede encontrar en 1 o 2 ganglios linfáticos cerca del tumor; o 2) la serosa (capa más externa) de la pared del estómago y se encuentra en 3 a 6 ganglios linfáticos cerca del tumor; o 3) la subserosa (capa de tejido cerca de la serosa) de la pared del estómago y se encuentra en siete o más ganglios linfáticos cerca del tumor. En el estadio IIIC, el cáncer se diseminó hasta 1) órganos cercanos como el bazo, el colon transverso, el hígado, el diafragma, un riñón, una glándula suprarrenal o el intestino delgado, y se puede encontrar en tres o más ganglios linfáticos cerca del tumor; o 2)  la serosa (capa más externa) de la pared del estómago y se encuentra en siete o más ganglios linfáticos cerca del tumor.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2011-10-18</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000271446">Gastric Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256764">Cáncer de estómago: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
