<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045888"><TermName>stage III cervical cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... SER-vih-kul KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cancer has spread to the lower third of the vagina, and/or onto the pelvic wall, and/or has caused kidney problems. Stage III is divided into stages IIIA and IIIB, based on how far the cancer has spread. In stage IIIA, cancer has spread to the lower third of the vagina but not onto the pelvic wall. In stage IIIB, (1) cancer has spread onto the pelvic wall; or (2) the tumor has become large enough to block one or both ureters (tubes that connect the kidneys to the bladder) and has caused one or both kidneys to get bigger or stop working. </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707391" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III cervical cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707392" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de cuello uterino en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000670190" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIIA cervical cancer; drawing shows a cross-section of the cervix and vagina. Cancer is shown in the cervix and in the full length of the vagina." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Stage IIIA cervical cancer. Cancer has spread to the lower third of the vagina but not to the pelvic wall.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000670191" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIIB cervical cancer; drawing shows cancer in the cervix, the vagina, and  the pelvic wall, blocking the ureter on the right. The uterus and kidneys are also shown." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="en">Stage IIIB cervical cancer. Cancer has spread to the pelvic wall; and/or the tumor has become large enough to block the ureters (the tubes that connect the kidneys to the bladder). The drawing shows the ureter on the right blocked by the cancer. This blockage can cause the kidney to enlarge or stop working.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000729744" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de cuello uterino en estadio IIIA; el dibujo muestra un corte transversal del cuello uterino y la vagina. Se muestra el cáncer en el cuello uterino y a todo lo largo de la vagina." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_5"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de cuello uterino en estadio IIIA. El cáncer se diseminó hasta el tercio inferior de la vagina, pero no hasta la pared pélvica.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000729746" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de cuello uterino en estadio IIIB; el dibujo muestra el cáncer en el cuello uterino, la vagina y la pared pélvica, y bloquea el uréter  derecho. También se muestran el útero y los riñones. " language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_6"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de cuello uterino en estadio IIIB. El cáncer se diseminó hasta la pared pélvica o el tumor se volvió lo suficientemente grande como para bloquear los uréteres (los tubos que conectan los riñones con la vejiga). El dibujo muestra el uréter derecho bloqueado por el cáncer. El bloqueo puede hacer que el riñón se agrande o deje de funcionar.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de cuello uterino en estadio III</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El cáncer se diseminó hasta el tercio inferior de la vagina o a la pared de la pelvis, o causó problemas a los riñones. El estadio III se divide en los estadios IIIA y IIIB, de acuerdo con la distancia a donde se diseminó el cáncer. En el estadio IIIA, el cáncer se diseminó al tercio inferior de la vagina, pero no llegó a la pared de la pelvis. En el estadio IIIB, 1) el cáncer se diseminó a la pared de la pelvis,  o 2) el tumor creció tanto hasta impedir el paso por uno o ambos uréteres (tubos que conectan el riñón con la vejiga) y ha causado que uno o ambos riñones se agranden o dejen de funcionar. </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2015-06-25</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062961">Cervical Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256774">Cáncer de cuello uterino: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
