<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000463728"><TermName>peripheral venous catheter</TermName><TermPronunciation>(peh-RIH-feh-rul VEE-nus KA-theh-ter)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A device used to draw blood and give treatments, including intravenous fluids, drugs, or blood transfusions.  A thin, flexible tube is inserted into a vein, usually in the back of the hand, the lower part of the arm, or the foot. A needle is inserted into a port to draw blood or give fluids.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000716640" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;peripheral venous catheter&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000716641" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;catéter venoso periférico&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000771773" type="image/jpeg" alt="Peripheral venous catheter; drawing of a peripheral venous catheter in a vein in the lower part of the arm with the catheter tubing clamped and capped off at the end." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Peripheral venous catheter. A peripheral venous catheter is a thin, flexible tube that is inserted into a vein. It is usually inserted into the lower part of the arm or the back of the hand. It is used to give intravenous fluids, blood transfusions, chemotherapy, and other drugs.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000774009" type="image/jpeg" alt="Catéter venoso periférico; dibujo de un catéter venoso periférico dentro de una vena en la parte inferior del brazo con el tubo del catéter sujeto y sellado al final." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Catéter venoso periférico.  Un catéter venoso periférico es un tubo delgado y flexible que se inserta en una vena. Normalmente, se inserta en la parte inferior del brazo o la parte posterior de la mano.  Se usa para administrar líquidos, transfusiones de sangre, quimioterapia y otros medicamentos por vía intravenosa. </Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>catéter venoso periférico</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Dispositivo que se usa para extraer sangre y administrar tratamientos, como líquidos intravenosos, medicamentos o transfusiones de sangre. Se introduce en una vena un tubo delgado y flexible; por lo general, en el dorso de la mano, la parte inferior del brazo o el pie. Se introduce una aguja en una vía de acceso para extraer sangre o administrar líquidos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2006-05-05</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2015-10-12</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
