<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045685"><TermName>estrogen replacement therapy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ES-truh-jin reh-PLAYS-ment THAYR-uh-pee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Treatment with the hormone estrogen to increase the amount of estrogen in the body. It is given to women who have gone through menopause or to women who have early menopause caused by cancer treatment or by having their ovaries removed by surgery. Estrogen replacement therapy may help relieve symptoms of menopause, such as hot flashes, night sweats, vaginal dryness, and sleep problems. It may also help protect against osteoporosis (thinning of the bones) and lower the risk of breast cancer in postmenopausal women. Also called ERT.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707080" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;estrogen replacement therapy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707079" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;terapia de reemplazo de estrógenos&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>terapia de reemplazo de estrógenos</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tratamiento con la hormona estrógeno para aumentar la cantidad de estrógeno en el cuerpo. Se administra a mujeres que han pasado por la menopausia o a mujeres con menopausia prematura causada por el tratamiento de  cáncer o por una cirugía para extirpar los ovarios. La terapia de reemplazo de estrógenos puede ayudar a aliviar los síntomas de la menopausia, como sofocos, sudores nocturnos, sequedad vaginal y problemas de sueño. También puede ayudar a proteger contra la osteoporosis (pérdida de masa de los huesos) y disminuir el riesgo de cáncer de mama en mujeres posmenopáusicas. También se llama TRE.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2013-09-17</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
