<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045762"><TermName>lymph node</TermName><TermPronunciation>(limf node)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A small bean-shaped structure that is part of the body’s immune system. Lymph nodes filter substances that travel through the lymphatic fluid, and they contain lymphocytes (white blood cells) that help the body fight infection and disease. There are hundreds of lymph nodes found throughout the body. They are connected to one another by lymph vessels. Clusters of lymph nodes are found in the neck, axilla (underarm), chest, abdomen, and groin. For example, there are about 20-40 lymph nodes in the axilla. Also called lymph gland.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707200" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;lymph node&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707201" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ganglio linfático&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000533339" type="image/jpeg" alt="Lymph system; drawing shows the lymph vessels and lymph organs including the lymph nodes, tonsils, thymus, spleen, and bone marrow.  One inset shows the inside structure of a lymph node and the attached lymph vessels with arrows showing how the lymph (clear fluid) moves into and out of the lymph node. Another inset shows a close up of bone marrow with blood cells." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_2"><Caption language="en">Anatomy of the lymph system, showing the lymph vessels and lymph organs including lymph nodes, tonsils, thymus, spleen, and bone marrow. Lymph (clear fluid) and lymphocytes travel through the lymph vessels and into the lymph nodes where the lymphocytes destroy harmful substances. The lymph enters the blood through a large vein near the heart.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000557593" type="image/jpeg" alt="Sistema linfático; el dibujo muestra los vasos linfáticos y los órganos linfáticos, incluso los ganglios linfáticos, las amígdalas, el timo, el bazo y la médula ósea. Un recuadro muestra la estructura interior de un ganglio linfático y de los vasos linfáticos adjuntos, con flechas que indican cómo circula la linfa (un líquido claro) hacia adentro y afuera del ganglio linfático. Otro recuadro muestra una vista ampliada de la médula ósea con células sanguíneas." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Anatomía del sistema linfático; se muestran los vasos linfáticos y los órganos linfáticos, incluidos los ganglios linfáticos, las amígdalas, el timo, el bazo y la médula ósea. La linfa (un líquido claro) y los linfocitos se desplazan a través de los vasos linfáticos hasta los ganglios linfáticos, donde los linfocitos destruyen las sustancias que son dañinas. La linfa entra en la sangre a través de una vena grande cerca del corazón. </Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>ganglio linfático</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Estructura en forma de frijol que forma parte del sistema inmunitario. Los ganglios linfáticos filtran las sustancias que se desplazan a través del líquido linfático; contienen linfocitos (glóbulos blancos) que ayudan al cuerpo a combatir infecciones y enfermedades. Hay cientos de ganglios linfáticos en todo el cuerpo. Se conectan entre sí mediante vasos linfáticos.  Hay racimos de ganglios linfáticos en el cuello, la axila (debajo del brazo), el pecho, el abdomen y la ingle. Por ejemplo, en la axila hay entre 20 y 40 ganglios linfáticos. También se llama glándula linfática.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2015-10-12</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
