<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046466"><TermName>common bile duct</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KAH-mun bile dukt)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A tube that carries bile from the liver and the gallbladder through the pancreas and into the duodenum (the upper part of the small intestine).  It is formed where the ducts from the liver and gallbladder are joined. It is part of the biliary duct system.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708787" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;common bile duct&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000659742" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomy of the extrahepatic bile ducts; drawing shows the liver, right and left hepatic ducts, gallbladder, cystic duct, common hepatic duct (hilum region), common bile duct (distal region), extrahepatic bile duct, pancreas, and small intestine. An inset shows the liver, bile ducts, and gallbladder." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_5"><Caption language="en">Anatomy of the extrahepatic bile ducts. Extrahepatic bile ducts are small tubes that carry bile outside of the liver.  They are made up of the common hepatic duct (hilum region) and the common bile duct (distal region). Bile is made in the liver and flows through the common hepatic duct and the cystic duct to the gallbladder, where it is stored. Bile is released from the gallbladder  when food is being digested.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000668855" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomía de la vía biliare extrahepática; el dibujo muestra el hígado, los conductos hepáticos derecho e izquierdo, la vesícula biliar, el conducto cístico, el conducto hepático común (región del hilio), el conducto colédoco (región distal), la vía biliar extrahepática, el páncreas y el intestino delgado. El recuadro muestra el hígado, ls conductos biliaresy  la vesícula biliar." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_6"><Caption language="es">Anatomía de la vía biliar extrahepática. Los conductos biliares extrahepáticos son tubos pequeños que llevan bilis por fuera del hígado. Están formados por el conducto hepático común (región del hilio) y el conducto colédoco (región distal). El hígado produce bilis y esta fluye a través del conducto hepático común y el conducto cístico hasta la vesícula biliar, donde se almacena. La vesícula biliar libera la bilis cuando se digieren alimentos.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>conducto colédoco</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tubo que transporta la bilis desde el hígado y la vesícula biliar a través del páncreas y hasta el duodeno (la parte superior del intestino delgado). Se forma donde se unen los conductos que vienen del hígado y la vesícula biliar. Forma parte del sistema de las vías biliares.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2015-08-31</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
