<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000446190"><TermName>stage IV salivary gland cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>((...SA-lih-VAYR-ee gland KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage IV salivary gland cancer is divided into stages IVA, IVB, and IVC. In stage IVA, (1) the tumor may be any size and may have spread to soft tissue around the affected gland. Cancer has spread to a single lymph node on the same side as the tumor and the lymph node is larger than 3 centimeters but not larger than 6 centimeters, or has spread to more than one lymph node on either or both sides of the body and the lymph nodes are not larger than 6 centimeters; or (2) cancer has spread to the skin, jawbone, ear canal, and/or facial nerve, and may have spread to one or more lymph nodes on either or both sides of the body; the lymph nodes are not larger than 6 centimeters. In stage IVB, (1) the tumor may be any size and may have spread to soft tissue around the affected gland. Cancer has spread to a lymph node larger than 6 centimeters; or (2) cancer has spread to the base of the skull and/or the carotid artery, and may have spread to one or more lymph nodes of any size on either or both sides of the body. In stage IVC, the tumor may be any size and may have spread to soft tissue around the affected gland, to the skin, jawbone, ear canal, facial nerve, base of the skull, or carotid artery, or to one or more lymph nodes on either or both sides of the body. Cancer has spread to distant parts of the body. </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714708" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IV salivary gland cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714709" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de la glándula salival en estadio lV&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de la glándula salival en estadio lV</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El cáncer de la glándula salival en estadio lV se divide en los estadios IVA, IVB y IVC. En el estadio IVA, 1) el tumor puede medir cualquier tamaño y se puede haber diseminado hasta el tejido blando que rodea la glándula afectada. El cáncer se diseminó hasta un solo ganglio linfático del mismo lado que el tumor y el ganglio linfático mide más de tres centímetros, pero no más de seis centímetros, o se diseminó hasta más de un ganglio linfático de uno o ambos lados del cuerpo, y los ganglios linfáticos no miden más de seis centímetros; o 2) el cáncer se diseminó hasta la piel, la mandíbula, el canal del oído o el nervio facial, y se puede haber diseminado hasta uno o más ganglios linfáticos de uno o ambos lados del cuerpo; los ganglios linfáticos no miden más de seis centímetros. En el estadio IVB, 1) el tumor puede medir cualquier tamaño y se puede haber diseminado hasta el tejido blando que rodea la glándula afectada. El cáncer se diseminó hasta un ganglio linfático que mide más de seis centímetros; o 2) el cáncer se diseminó hasta la base del cráneo o la arteria carótida, y se puede haber diseminado hasta uno o más ganglios linfáticos de cualquier tamaño en uno o ambos lados del cuerpo. En el estadio IVC, el tumor puede medir  cualquier tamaño y se puede haber diseminado hasta el tejido blando que rodea la glándula afectada, hasta la piel, la mandíbula, el canal del oído, el nervio facial, la base del cráneo o la arteria carótida, o hasta uno o más ganglios linfáticos de uno o ambos lados del cuerpo. El cáncer se diseminó hasta partes distantes del cuerpo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-06-30</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2010-11-23</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258034">Salivary Gland Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000530606">Cáncer de glándulas salivales: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
