<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046746"><TermName>SCH 54031</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat melanoma and hepatitis C. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer.  It is used under the brand name Sylatron to treat melanoma in patients who have had surgery to remove cancer that has spread to lymph nodes. It is used under the brand name PEG-Intron to treat hepatitis C infections. SCH 54031 is a form of interferon alfa (a substance normally made by cells in the immune system) linked to a substance called PEG, which makes the drug stay in the body longer. SCH 54031 is made in the laboratory. It is a type of cytokine and a type of biological response modifier. Also called peginterferon alfa-2b.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><SpanishTermName>SCH 54031</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa en el tratamiento del melanoma y la hepatitis C. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Se usa bajo el nombre comercial Sylatron para el tratamiento del melanoma en pacientes que  han sido operados de cáncer que se diseminó a los ganglios linfáticos. Se usa bajo el nombre comercial PEG-Intron para el tratamiento de la infección por hepatitis C. SCH 54031 es una forma de interferón alfa (sustancia normalmente elaborada por las células del sistema inmunitario) vinculada a una sustancia llamada PEG, que causa que el medicamente dure mucho más en el cuerpo. SCH 54031 se produce en el laboratorio. es un tipo de citocina y modificador de la respuesta biológica. También se llama peginterferón a-2b.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2013-05-09</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000746606">Peginterferon Alfa-2b</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
