<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000413892"><TermName>stage II distal extrahepatic bile duct cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... DIS-tul EK-struh-heh-PA-tik bile dukt KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage II is divided into stages IIA and IIB. In stage IIA, cancer has spread from the distal extrahepatic bile duct (where the bile duct empties into the small intestine) to the gallbladder, pancreas, small intestine, or other nearby organs. In stage IIB, cancer has spread from the distal extrahepatic bile duct to nearby lymph nodes. Cancer may have spread through the wall of the distal extrahepatic bile duct or to the gallbladder, pancreas, small intestine, or other nearby organs.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713468" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage II distal extrahepatic bile duct cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713469" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de vía biliar extrahepática distal en estadio II&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de vía biliar extrahepática distal en estadio II</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio II se divide en los estadios IIA y IIB. En el estadio IIA, el cáncer se diseminó desde la vía biliar
extrahepática distal (donde el contenido de la vía biliar se vacía hacia el intestino delgado hasta la vesícula biliar, el páncreas, el intestino delgado u otros órganos cercanos. En el estadio IIB, el cáncer se disemina desde la vía biliar
extrahepática distal hasta los ganglios linfáticos cercanos. El cáncer se puede haber diseminado a través de la vía biliar extrahepática distal o hasta la vesícula biliar, el páncreas el intestino delgado u otros órganos cercanos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-04-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2012-09-06</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258011">Bile Duct Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256805">Cáncer de las vías biliares extrahepáticas: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
