<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045720"><TermName>imaging procedure</TermName><TermPronunciation>(IH-muh-jing proh-SEE-jer)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of test that makes detailed pictures of areas inside the body. Imaging procedures use different forms of energy, such as x-rays (high-energy radiation), ultrasound (high-energy sound waves), radio waves, and radioactive substances. They may be used to help diagnose disease, plan treatment, or find out how well treatment is working. Examples of imaging procedures are computed tomography (CT), ultrasonography, magnetic resonance imaging (MRI), and nuclear medicine tests. Also called imaging test.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000731186" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;imaging procedure&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000731187" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;procedimiento con imágenes&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>procedimiento con imágenes</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de prueba en la que se toman imágenes detalladas del interior del cuerpo.  En los procedimientos con imágenes se usan diferentes formas de energía, como rayos X (radiación de alta energía), ecografía (ondas de sonido de alta energía), ondas de radio y sustancias radiactivas.  Se pueden usar para diagnosticar enfermedades, planificar   o determinar la eficacia de los tratamientos. Entre los ejemplos de procedimientos con imágenes están la tomografía computarizada (TC), la ultrasonografía, las imágenes por resonancia magnética, (IRM) y las pruebas de medicina nuclear. También se llama prueba con imágenes.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2014-02-13</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000046570">scan</RelatedGlossaryTermRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
