<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044534"><TermName>patient advocate</TermName><TermPronunciation>(PAY-shunt AD-vuh-kut)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A person who helps a patient work with others who have an effect on the patient's health, including doctors, insurance companies, employers, case managers, and lawyers. A patient advocate helps resolve issues about health care, medical bills, and job discrimination related to a patient's medical condition. Cancer advocacy groups try to raise public awareness about important cancer issues, such as the need for cancer support services, education, and research. Such groups work to bring about change that will help cancer patients and their families.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000727984" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;patient advocate&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000727983" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;defensor del paciente&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>defensor del paciente</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Persona que ayuda al paciente a trabajar con otros que influyen en la salud del paciente, inclusive los médicos, las compañías de seguro, los empleadores, los gerentes de casos y los abogados. Un defensor del paciente lo ayuda a resolver los problemas relacionados con la atención de la salud, las facturas médicas y la discriminación en el trabajo relacionada con el trastorno médico de un paciente. Los grupos de defensores de la causa del cáncer tratan de aumentar la conciencia del público acerca de importantes temas sobre el cáncer, como la necesidad de servicios de apoyo para el cáncer, la educación y la investigación. Tales grupos trabajan para producir el cambio que ayudará a los pacientes con cáncer y sus familias.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition></GlossaryTerm>
