<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045011"><TermName>lymphoscintigraphy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(LIM-foh-sin-TIH-gruh-fee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A method used to check the lymph system for disease. A radioactive substance that flows through the lymph ducts and can be taken up by lymph nodes is injected into the body. A scanner or probe is used to follow the movement of this substance on a computer screen. Lymphoscintigraphy is used to find the sentinel lymph node (the first node to receive lymph from a tumor), which may be removed and checked for tumor cells. Lymphoscintigraphy is also used to diagnose certain diseases or conditions, such as lymphoma or lymphedema.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000706264" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;lymphoscintigraphy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000706265" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;linfocentellografía&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>linfocentellografía</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Método que se usa para comprobar si hay alguna enfermedad en el sistema linfático. Se inyecta en el cuerpo una sustancia radiactiva que fluye a través de los conductos linfáticos y que los ganglios linfáticos pueden absorber. Se usa un escáner o una sonda para seguir el movimiento de esta sustancia en una pantalla de computadora.   La linfocentellografía también se usa para encontrar el ganglio linfático centinela (el primer nódulo que recibe la linfa de un tumor), que se puede extirpar y revisar para determinar si tiene células tumorales.   Asimismo, la linfocentellografía se usa para diagnosticar ciertas enfermedades o afecciones, como el linfoma o el linfedema.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2009-07-16</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
