<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045901"><TermName>stage III ovarian epithelial, fallopian tube, and primary peritoneal cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... oh-VAYR-ee-un EH-pih-THEE-lee-ul fuh-LOH-pee-in ... PRY-mayr-ee PAYR-ih-toh-NEE-ul KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cancer is found in one or both ovaries or fallopian tubes, or is primary peritoneal cancer, and has spread outside the pelvis to other parts of the abdomen and/or to nearby lymph nodes. Stage III is divided into stages IIIA, IIIB, and IIIC. In stage IIIA, one of the following is true: (1) cancer has spread to lymph nodes in the area outside or behind the peritoneum (tissue that lines the abdominal wall and covers organs in the abdomen) only; or (2) cancer cells that can be seen only with a microscope have spread to the surface of the peritoneum outside the pelvis. Cancer may have spread to nearby lymph nodes. In stage IIIB, cancer has spread to the peritoneum outside the pelvis and the cancer in the peritoneum is 2 centimeters or smaller. Cancer may have spread to lymph nodes behind the peritoneum. In stage IIIC, cancer has spread to the peritoneum outside the pelvis and the cancer in the peritoneum is larger than 2 centimeters. Cancer may have spread to lymph nodes behind the peritoneum or to the surface of the liver or spleen.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707417" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III ovarian epithelial, fallopian tube, and primary peritoneal cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707418" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer epitelial de los ovarios en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer epitelial de ovario, de trompas de Falopio y primario de peritoneo en estadio III</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El cáncer se encuentra en uno o ambos ovarios o  trompas de Falopio, o es cáncer primario de peritoneo, y se diseminó fuera de la pelvis a otras partes del abdomen o a los ganglios linfáticos cercanos. El estadio lll se divide en los estadios IIIA, IIIB, y  IIIC. En el estadio lllA, uno de los siguientes casos es cierto:  1) el cáncer se diseminó solamente a los ganglios linfáticos en el área de afuera o atrás del peritoneo (el tejido que cubre la pared abdominal y cubre órganos en el abdomen); o 2) las células cancerosas que se pueden ver solo al microscopio se diseminaron a la superficie del peritoneo fuera de la pelvis.  El cáncer se puede haber diseminado a los ganglios linfáticos cercanos. En el estadio lllB el cáncer se diseminó al peritoneo fuera de la pelvis y el cáncer en el peritoneo mide 2 centímetros o menos. El cáncer se puede haber diseminado a los ganglios linfáticos detrás de peritoneo. En el estadio lllC, el cáncer se diseminó al peritoneo fuera de la pelvis y el cáncer del peritoneo mide más de 2 centímetros. El cáncer se puede haber diseminado a los ganglios linfáticos detrás del peritoneo o a la superficie del  hígado o  el bazo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2015-06-11</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062963">Ovarian Epithelial, Fallopian Tube, and Primary Peritoneal Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256785">Cáncer epitelial de ovario, de trompa de Falopio y primario de peritoneo: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
