<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046505"><TermName>bone marrow aspiration</TermName><TermPronunciation>(bone MAYR-oh AS-pih-RAY-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure in which a small sample of bone marrow is removed, usually from the hip bone, breastbone, or thigh bone. A small area of skin and the surface of the bone underneath are numbed with an anesthetic. Then, a special wide needle is pushed into the bone. A sample of liquid bone marrow is removed with a syringe attached to the needle. The bone marrow is sent to a laboratory to be looked at under a microscope. This procedure may be done at the same time as a bone marrow biopsy.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708849" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;bone marrow aspiration&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708850" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;aspiración de la médula ósea&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000554337" type="image/jpeg" alt="Bone marrow aspiration and biopsy; drawing shows a patient lying face down on a table and a bone marrow needle being inserted into the hip bone. Inset shows the bone marrow needle being inserted through the skin into the bone marrow of the hip bone." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_2"><Caption language="en">Bone marrow aspiration and biopsy. After  a small area of skin is numbed, a bone marrow needle is inserted into the patient’s hip bone.  Samples of blood, bone, and bone marrow   are removed for examination under a microscope.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000584849" type="image/jpeg" alt="Aspiración de la médula ósea y biopsia;  el dibujo muestra a un paciente acostado boca abajo en una camilla y una aguja para médula ósea que se inserta en el hueso de la cadera. El recuadro muestra la aguja para médula ósea que se inserta a través de la piel hasta la médula ósea del hueso de la cadera.  " language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Aspiración  de la médula ósea y biopsia. Después de adormecer un área pequeña de la piel, se inserta una aguja para médula ósea en el hueso de la cadera del paciente. Se extraen muestras de sangre, hueso y médula ósea para examinarlas bajo un microscopio.  </Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>aspiración de la médula ósea</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento por el que se extrae una pequeña muestra de médula ósea, habitualmente del hueso de la cadera, el esternón o el hueso del muslo.   Se adormece un área pequeña de la piel y la superficie del hueso debajo de ella con un anestésico.   Luego, se introduce en el hueso una aguja ancha especial. Se  extrae una muestra del líquido de la médula ósea con una jeringa adherida a la aguja y se envía la médula ósea a un laboratorio para observarla bajo un microscopio.   Este procedimiento se puede realizar al tiempo que una biopsia de médula ósea.  </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2010-03-30</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
