<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044899"><TermName>cervical intraepithelial neoplasia</TermName><TermPronunciation>(SER-vih-kul IN-truh-eh-pih-THEE-lee-ul NEE-oh-PLAY-zhuh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Abnormal cells are found on the surface of the cervix. Cervical intraepithelial neoplasia is usually caused by certain types of human papillomavirus (HPV) and is found when a cervical biopsy is done. Cervical intraepithelial neoplasia is not cancer, but may become cancer and spread to nearby normal tissue. It is graded on a scale of 1 to 3, based on how abnormal the cells look under a microscope and how much of the cervical tissue is affected. For example, CIN 1 has slightly abnormal cells and is less likely to become cancer than CIN 2 or CIN 3.  Also called CIN.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000706111" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cervical intraepithelial neoplasia&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000706112" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;neoplasia intraepitelial cervical&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>neoplasia intraepitelial cervical</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Se encuentran células anormales en la superficie del cuello uterino. La neoplasia intraepitelial cervical es causada, a menudo, por ciertos tipos de virus del papiloma humano (VPH) y se encuentra al realizar una biopsia de cuello uterino. La neoplasia intraepitelial cervical no es cáncer, pero se puede volver cancerosa y diseminar al tejido normal cercano. Se evalúa en una escala de 1 a 3, con base en la apariencia de las células al microscopio y en el grado de compromiso del cuello uterino. Por ejemplo, la NIC 1 tiene células levemente anormales y es menos propensa a volverse cáncer que la NIC 2 o la NIC 3. También se llama NIC.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2013-12-19</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
