<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046756"><TermName>barium swallow</TermName><TermPronunciation>(BAYR-ee-um SWAH-loh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The process of getting x-ray pictures of the esophagus or the upper gastrointestinal (GI) tract (esophagus, stomach, and duodenum). The x-ray pictures are taken after the patient drinks a liquid that contains barium sulfate (a form of the silver-white metallic element barium). The barium sulfate coats and outlines the inner walls of the esophagus and the upper GI tract so that they can be seen on the x-ray pictures.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710038" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;barium swallow&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710037" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ingesta de bario&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000430686" type="image/jpeg" alt="Barium swallow; shows barium liquid flowing through the esophagus and into the stomach. " language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_2"><Caption language="en">Barium swallow. The patient swallows barium liquid and it flows through the esophagus and into the stomach. X-rays are taken to look for abnormal areas.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000747240" type="image/jpeg" alt="Ingesta de bario; muestra el bario líquido en su paso por del esófago hasta el estómago. " language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Ingesta de bario. El paciente ingiere bario líquido y este pasa por el  esófago hacia el estómago. Se toma una radiografía para identificar áreas anormales.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>ingesta de bario</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Proceso mediante el cual se toman imágenes de rayos X del esófago o del tubo gastrointestinal superior (esófago, estómago y duodeno). Las imágenes de rayos X se toman después de que el paciente bebe un líquido que contiene sulfato de bario (una forma del elemento metálico bario de color blanco plateado). El sulfato de bario recubre y permite ver el contorno de las paredes internas del esófago y el aparato digestivo superior para que se puedan observar en las imágenes de rayos X.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition></GlossaryTerm>
