<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000439432"><TermName>tobacco</TermName><TermPronunciation>(tuh-BA-koh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A plant with leaves that have high levels of the addictive chemical nicotine.
 After harvesting, tobacco leaves are cured, aged, and processed in various ways. The resulting products may be smoked (in cigarettes, cigars, and pipes), applied to the
 gums (as dipping and chewing tobacco), or inhaled (as snuff). Cured tobacco leaves
 and the products made from them contain many cancer-causing chemicals, and
 tobacco use and exposure to secondhand tobacco smoke have been strongly linked to
 many types of cancer and other diseases. The scientific name of the most common
 tobacco plant is <ScientificName>Nicotiana tabacum</ScientificName>.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713695" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tobacco&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713694" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tabaco&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>tabaco</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Planta cuyas hojas tienen concentraciones altas de la sustancia química nicotina, que produce adicción. Después de su cosecha, las hojas de tabaco se curan y procesan de diferentes maneras. Los productos obtenidos se pueden fumar (en cigarrillos, cigarros y pipas), aplicar sobre las encías (como tabaco en polvo y tabaco de mascar) o inhalarse (como rapé).   Las hojas curadas de tabaco y sus productos contienen muchos productos químicos que causan cáncer. El consumo de tabaco y la exposición pasiva al humo de tabaco se vincularon fuertemente con muchos tipos de cáncer y otras enfermedades.   El nombre científico de la planta de tabaco más común es <ScientificName>Nicotiana tabacum</ScientificName>.  </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-07-08</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-01-29</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/risk/tobacco">Tobacco</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
