<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000454777"><TermName>National Center for Complementary and Integrative Health</TermName><TermPronunciation>(NA-shuh-nul SEN-ter ... KOM-pleh-MEN-tuh-ree ... IN-teh-gray-tiv helth)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A federal agency that uses science to explore complementary and integrative health (CIH) practices, trains CIH researchers, and provides authoritative information about CIH to professionals and the public. The National Center for Complementary and Integrative Health awards grants for research projects, training, and career development in CIH; sponsors conferences, educational programs, and exhibits; studies ways to use proven CIH practices along with conventional medical practice; and supports adding CIH to medical, dental, and nursing school programs. The National Center for Complementary and Integrative Health is part of the National Institutes of Health. Also called NCCIH.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000715042" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;National Center for Complementary and Integrative Health&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000715041" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Centro Nacional de Salud Complementaria e Integral &quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Centro Nacional de Salud Complementaria e Integral</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Organismo federal que usa la ciencia para explorar la práctica de la salud complementaria e integral (SCI),  capacitar investigadores en SCI y proporcionar información autorizada sobre la SCI a los profesionales y el público. El Centro Nacional de Medicina Complementaria y Alternativa subvenciona proyectos de investigación, capacitación y estimula profesionales en SCI; auspicia conferencias, programas educativos y exposiciones; estudia las formas de utilizar los procedimientos comprobados de SCI junto con el ejercicio profesional de la medicina convencional y apoya la incorporación de la SCI en los programas de las escuelas de medicina, odontología y enfermería. El Centro Nacional de Medicina Complementaria y Alternativa forma parte de los Institutos Nacionales de Salud. También se llama NCCIH.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2006-02-21</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2015-03-23</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
