<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000482156"><TermName>yangona</TermName><TermPronunciation>(yan-GOH-nuh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>An herb native to islands in the South Pacific. Substances taken from the root have been used in some cultures to relieve stress, anxiety, tension, sleeplessness, and problems of menopause. Yangona may increase the effect of alcohol and of certain drugs used to treat anxiety and depression. The U.S. Food and Drug Administration advises users that yangona may cause severe liver damage. The scientific name is <ScientificName>Piper methysticum</ScientificName>. Also called intoxicating pepper, kava kava, rauschpfeffer,  and tonga.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000716527" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;yangona&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000716526" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;yangona&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>yangona</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Hierba nativa de las islas del sur del Pacífico. Las sustancias tomadas de la raíz se han usado en algunas culturas para aliviar el estrés, la ansiedad, la tensión, el insomnio y los problemas de la menopausia. La yangona podría aumentar el efecto del alcohol y de ciertos medicamentos que se usan para tratar la ansiedad y la depresión. La Administración de Alimentos y Medicamentos de los Estados Unidos de América(U.S. Food and Drug Administration), informa a los usuarios que la yangona puede causar daño grave al hígado. El nombre científico es Piper methysticum También se llama kava kava, pimienta intoxicante, rauschpfeffer,  y tonga.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2006-04-21</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2006-11-29</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
