<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000454841"><TermName>stage IV mycosis fungoides</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... my-KOH-sis fun-GOY-deez)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage IV is divided into stages IVA and IVB. In stage IVA, most of the skin is reddened and any amount of the skin surface is covered with patches, papules, plaques, or tumors, and either (1) cancer has spread to lymph nodes and there may be cancerous lymphocytes in the blood; or (2) there are cancerous lymphocytes in the blood and lymph nodes may be enlarged, but cancer has not spread to them. In stage IVB, most of the skin is reddened and any amount of the skin surface is covered with patches, papules, plaques, or tumors. Cancer has spread to other organs in the body. Lymph nodes may be enlarged and cancer may have spread to them. There may be cancerous lymphocytes in the blood.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000715093" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IV mycosis fungoides&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000715094" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;micosis fungoide en estadio IV&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>micosis fungoide en estadio IV</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio IV se divide en los estadios IVA y IVB. En el estadio IVA, la mayor parte de la piel está enrojecida y cualquier cantidad de piel está cubierta con parches, pápulas,  placas o tumores y  se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) el cáncer se diseminó hasta los ganglios linfáticos y puede haber linfocitos cancerosos en la sangre; o 2) hay linfocitos cancerosos en la sangre y los ganglios linfáticos pueden estar agrandados, pero el cáncer no se diseminó hasta ellos. En el estadio IVB, la mayor parte de la piel está enrojecida y cualquier cantidad de piel está cubierta por parches, pápulas, placas o tumores. El cáncer se diseminó hasta otros órganos del cuerpo. Los ganglios linfáticos pueden estar agrandados y el cáncer puede haberse diseminado hasta ellos. Puede haber linfocitos cancerosos en la sangre.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-11-25</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2012-02-23</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258022">Mycosis Fungoides and the Sézary Syndrome Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000433316">Micosis fungoide y síndrome de Sézary: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
