<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046063"><TermName>mutation</TermName><TermPronunciation>(myoo-TAY-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Any change in the DNA sequence of a cell. Mutations may be caused by mistakes during cell division, or they may be caused by exposure to DNA-damaging agents in the environment. Mutations can be harmful, beneficial, or have no effect. If they occur in cells that make eggs or sperm, they can be inherited; if mutations occur in other types of cells, they are not inherited. Certain mutations may lead to cancer or other diseases.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A change in the usual DNA sequence at a particular gene locus. Mutations (including polymorphisms) can be harmful, beneficial, or neutral in their effect on cell function.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708090" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mutation&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708089" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mutación&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>mutación</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cualquier cambio en la secuencia del ADN de una célula. Las mutaciones podrían ser el resultado de  errores durante la multiplicación de las células o por la exposición a sustancias del ambiente que dañan el ADN. Las mutaciones pueden ser dañinas, beneficiosas o no tener ningún efecto. Si se presentan en las células que producen los óvulos o los espermatozoides, pueden heredarse; si las mutaciones se presentan en otros tipos de células, no se heredan. Ciertas mutaciones pueden producir cáncer u otras enfermedades.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2012-10-15</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.genome.gov/Glossary/index.cfm?id=134">Mutation</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.genome.gov/GlossaryS/index.cfm?id=134">Mutación</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
