<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045134"><TermName>Kaposi sarcoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(kuh-POH-zee sar-KOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of
          cancer in which lesions (abnormal areas) grow in the skin,
          lymph nodes, lining of the mouth, nose, and throat, and
          other tissues of the body. The lesions are usually purple
          and are made of cancer cells, new blood vessels, and blood
          cells. They may begin in more than one place in the body at
          the same time. Kaposi sarcoma is caused by Kaposi
          sarcoma-associated herpesvirus (KSHV). In the United
          States, it usually occurs in people who have a weak immune
          system caused by AIDS or by drugs used in organ
          transplants. It is also seen in older men of Jewish or
          Mediterranean descent, or in young men in
          Africa.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705055" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Kaposi sarcoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705054" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sarcoma de Kaposi&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>sarcoma de Kaposi</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de cáncer en el que
aparecen lesiones (áreas anormales) en la piel, los
ganglios linfáticos, el revestimiento de la boca, la nariz
y la garganta, y otros tejidos del cuerpo. Habitualmente, las lesiones son de color púrpura y se componen de células
cancerosas, vasos sanguíneos nuevos y células sanguíneas.
Estas se pueden presentar en más de un lugar del cuerpo al
mismo tiempo. El virus del herpes relacionado con el
sarcoma de Kaposi (VHSK) causa el sarcoma de Kaposi. En los
Estados Unidos, generalmente se presenta en personas con
un sistema inmunitario débil como consecuencia del SIDA o de
medicamentos que se usan en los trasplantes de órganos.
También se observa en hombres de edad avanzada de
ascendencia judía o mediterránea, o en hombres jóvenes en
África.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2013-09-24</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000442381">Kaposi Sarcoma Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000529998">Sarcoma de Kaposi: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
