<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046728"><TermName>stage III malignant mesothelioma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(...muh-LIG-nunt MEH-zoh-THEE-lee-OH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cancer (1) is found in one side of the chest in the lining of the chest wall. Cancer may have spread to the lining of the chest cavity between the lungs; the lining that covers the diaphragm; the lining that covers the lung; the diaphragm muscle; or the lung. Cancer has spread to lymph nodes where the lung joins the bronchus, along the trachea and esophagus, between the lung and diaphragm, or below the trachea; or (2) is found in one side of the chest in the lining of the chest wall; the lining of the chest cavity between the lungs; the lining that covers the diaphragm; and the lining that covers the lung. Cancer has spread into one or more of the following: tissue between the ribs and the lining of the chest wall; fat in the cavity between the lungs; soft tissues of the chest wall; and/or sac that covers the heart. Cancer may have spread to lymph nodes where the lung joins the bronchus, along the trachea and esophagus, between the lung and diaphragm, or below the trachea. </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710001" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III malignant mesothelioma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710000" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mesotelioma maligno en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>mesotelioma maligno en estadio III</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El cáncer 1) se encuentra en un costado del pecho, en el revestimiento de la pared torácica. El cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta el revestimiento de la pared torácica entre los pulmones, el revestimiento del diafragma, el revestimiento del pulmón, el diafragma o el pulmón. El cáncer se diseminó hasta los ganglios linfáticos del lugar donde el pulmón se une con el bronquio, a lo largo de la tráquea y el esófago, entre el pulmón y el diafragma o debajo de la tráquea; o 2) se encuentra en un lado del pecho, en el revestimiento de la pared torácica, el revestimiento de la cavidad torácica entre los pulmones, el revestimiento del diafragma y el revestimiento del pulmón. El cáncer se diseminó hacia uno de los siguientes sitios: el tejido entre las costillas y el revestimiento de la pared torácica, la grasa de la cavidad entre los pulmones, los tejidos blandos de la pared torácica o la bolsa que cubre el corazón. El cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta los ganglios linfáticos del lugar donde el pulmón se une con el bronquio, a lo largo de la tráquea y el esófago, entre el pulmón y el diafragma o debajo de la tráquea.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2011-10-19</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000269299">Malignant Mesothelioma Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000433305">Mesotelioma maligno: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
