<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044443"><TermName>NMRI</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure in which radio waves and a powerful magnet linked to a computer are used to create detailed pictures of areas inside the body. These pictures can show the difference between normal and diseased tissue. NMRI makes better images of organs and soft tissue than other scanning techniques, such as computed tomography (CT) or x-ray. NMRI is especially useful for imaging the brain, the spine, the soft tissue of joints, and the inside of bones. Also called magnetic resonance imaging, MRI,  and nuclear magnetic resonance imaging.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000428431" type="image/jpeg" alt="Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) of the abdomen; drawing shows the patient on a table that slides into the MRI machine, which takes pictures of the inside of the body. The pad on the patient’s abdomen helps make the pictures clearer." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_2"><Caption language="en">Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) of the abdomen. The patient lies on a table that slides into the MRI machine, which takes pictures of the inside of the body. The pad on the patient’s abdomen helps make the pictures clearer.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000742471" type="image/jpeg" alt="Imaginología por resonancia magnética (IRM) del abdomen; el dibujo muestra al paciente en una camilla que se desliza hacia la máquina de IRM, la cual toma una radiografía de la parte interior del cuerpo.  La almohadilla en el abdomen del paciente ayuda a tomar imágenes más claras." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Imaginología por resonancia magnética (IRM) del abdomen.  El paciente se acuesta en una camilla que se desliza hacia la máquina de IRM, la cual toma radiografías de la parte interior del cuerpo.  La almohadilla en el abdomen del paciente ayuda a tomar imágenes más claras.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>IRMN</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento para el que se usan ondas de radio y un imán muy potente conectado a una computadora para crear ilustraciones detalladas de áreas internas del cuerpo. Estas imágenes pueden mostrar la diferencia entre el tejido normal y el tejido enfermo. Las  IRMN producen mejores ilustraciones de los órganos y el tejido blando que otras técnicas de exploración como, por ejemplo, la exploración por tomografía computarizada o la radiografía. Las IRMN son especialmente útiles para crear ilustraciones del cerebro, la columna vertebral, el tejido blando de las articulaciones y el interior de los huesos. También se llama imágenes por resonancia magnética, imágenes por resonancia magnética nuclear,  y IRM.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2010-03-26</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
