<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000476765"><TermName>plaque radiotherapy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(plak RAY-dee-oh-THAYR-uh-pee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of radiation therapy used to treat eye tumors. A thin piece of metal (usually gold) with radioactive seeds placed on one side is sewn onto the outside wall of the eye with the seeds aimed at the tumor. It is removed at the end of treatment, which usually lasts for several days</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000716565" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;plaque radiotherapy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000716564" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;radioterapia con placa&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000736669" type="image/jpeg" alt="Plaque radiotherapy of the eye; drawing shows a cross-section of the eye. An inset shows a plaque with radioactive seeds; it is placed on the outside of the eye with the seeds aimed at the cancer. Also shown are the sclera, choroid, retina, and optic nerve." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Plaque radiotherapy of the eye.  A type of radiation therapy used to treat eye tumors. Radioactive seeds are placed on one side of a thin piece of metal (usually gold) called a plaque.  The plaque is sewn onto the outside wall of the eye.  The seeds give off radiation which kills the cancer. The plaque is removed at the end of treatment, which usually lasts for several days.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000741768" type="image/jpeg" alt="Radioterapia con placa; el dibujo muestra una sección transversal del ojo. En un recuadro se muestra una placa con semillas radiactivas; se coloca en el exterior del ojo con las semillas que apuntan hacia el cáncer.   También se muestra la esclerótica, la coroides, la retina y el nervio óptico." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Radioterapia con placa. Tipo de radioterapia que se usa para tratar tumores del ojo. Las semillas radiactivas se colocan a un costado de un trozo delgado de metal (por lo general, de oro) que se llama placa. Las semillas emiten radiación que destruye el cáncer. La placa se retira al final del tratamiento, que habitualmente dura varios días </Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>radioterapia con placa</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de radioterapia que se usa para tratar los tumores del ojo. Se coloca a un costado del ojo un trozo delgado de metal (por lo general, oro) con semillas radiactivas y se cose sobre la pared externa del ojo, con las semillas apuntando hacia el tumor. Se quita al final del tratamiento, que dura generalmente varios días</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-10-04</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2012-10-22</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
