<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045085"><TermName>ductal carcinoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(DUK-tul KAR-sih-NOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The most common type of breast cancer. It begins in the lining of the milk ducts (thin tubes that carry milk from the lobules of the breast to the nipple). Ductal carcinoma may be either ductal carcinoma in situ (DCIS) or invasive ductal carcinoma. DCIS is a noninvasive condition in which abnormal cells are found in the lining of a breast duct and have not spread outside the duct to other tissues in the breast. In some cases, DCIS may become invasive cancer. In invasive ductal carcinoma, cancer has spread outside the breast duct to surrounding normal tissue. It can also spread through the blood and lymph systems to other parts of the body.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704979" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ductal carcinoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704978" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;carcinoma ductal&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>carcinoma ductal</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo más común de cáncer de mama. Empieza en los revestimiento de los conductos galactóferos (tubos delgados que llevan leche desde los lobulillos de la mama hasta el pezón). El carcinoma ductal puede ser carcinoma ductal in situ (CDIS) o carcinoma ductal invasivo. CDIS es una afección no invasiva en la que se encuentran células anormales en el revestimiento de un conducto mamario que no se han diseminado fuera del conducto hacia otros tejidos de la mama. En algunos casos, el CDIS se puede convertir en cáncer invasivo. En el carcinoma ductal invasivo, el cáncer se diseminó fuera del conducto de la mama hacia el tejido normal circundante. También se puede diseminar hacia otras partes del cuerpo a través de los sistemas sanguíneo y linfático.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2013-07-10</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/breast">Breast Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/seno">Cáncer de seno (mama)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
