<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000434562"><TermName>bone cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(bone KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Primary bone cancer is cancer that forms in cells of the bone. Some types of primary bone cancer are osteosarcoma, Ewing sarcoma, malignant fibrous histiocytoma, and chondrosarcoma. Secondary bone cancer is cancer that spreads to the bone from another part of the body (such as the prostate, breast, or lung).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713586" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;bone cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713585" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de hueso&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000755927" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomy of the bone; drawing shows spongy bone, red marrow, and yellow marrow. A cross section of the bone shows compact bone and blood vessels in the bone marrow. Also shown are red blood cells, white blood cells, platelets, and a blood stem cell." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Anatomy of the bone. The bone is made up of compact bone, spongy bone, and bone marrow. Compact bone makes up the outer layer of the bone. Spongy bone is found mostly at the ends of bones and contains red marrow. Bone marrow is found in the center of most bones and has many blood vessels. There are two types of bone marrow: red and yellow. Red marrow contains blood stem cells that can become red blood cells, white blood cells, or platelets. Yellow marrow is made mostly of fat.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000761775" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomía del hueso; en la ilustración, se muestra el hueso esponjoso, la médula roja y la médula amarilla. En un corte  trasversal del hueso, se muestran el hueso compacto y los vasos sanguíneos en la médula ósea. También se muestran los glóbulos rojos, los glóbulos blancos, las plaquetas y las células madre sanguíneas. " language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Anatomía del hueso. El hueso se compone de hueso compacto, hueso esponjoso y médula ósea. El hueso compacto forma la capa exterior del hueso. El hueso esponjoso se encuentra, más que todo, a los extremos de los huesos y contiene médula roja. La médula ósea se encuentra en el centro de la mayoría de los huesos y tiene muchos vasos sanguíneos. Hay dos tipos de médula ósea: roja y amarilla. La médula roja contiene células madre sanguíneas que se pueden convertir en glóbulos rojos, glóbulos blancos o plaquetas. La médula amarilla está compuesta, en mayor parte, de grasa.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de hueso</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El cáncer primario de hueso es un cáncer que se forma en las células óseas. Algunos tipos de cáncer de hueso son el osteosarcoma, el cáncer de Ewing, el histiocitoma fibroso maligno y el condrosarcoma. El cáncer secundario de hueso es un cáncer que se disemina hacia el hueso desde otra parte del cuerpo (como la próstata, la mama o el pulmón).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-05-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2014-06-09</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/bone">Bone Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/hueso">Cáncer de hueso</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
