<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000410643"><TermName>punch biopsy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... BY-op-see)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure in
          which a small round piece of tissue about the size of a
          pencil eraser is removed using a sharp, hollow, circular
          instrument. The tissue is then checked under a microscope
          for signs of disease. A punch biopsy may be used to check
          for certain types of cancer, including skin, vulvar, and
          cervical cancer. It may also be used to check for certain
          skin conditions and changes that may lead to
          cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713054" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;punch biopsy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713053" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;biopsia con sacabocados&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000578083" type="image/jpeg" alt="Punch biopsy; drawing shows a hollow, circular scalpel being inserted into a lesion on the skin of a patient’s forearm. The instrument is turned clockwise and counterclockwise to cut into the skin and a small sample of tissue is removed to be checked under a microscope. The pullout shows that the instrument cuts down about 4 millimeters (mm) to the layer of fatty tissue below the dermis. " language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="en">Punch biopsy. A hollow, circular scalpel is used to cut into a lesion on the skin. The instrument is turned clockwise and counterclockwise to cut down about 4 millimeters (mm) to the layer of fatty tissue below the dermis. A small sample of tissue is removed to be checked under a microscope. Skin thickness is different on different parts of the body.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000747220" type="image/jpeg" alt="Biopsia con sacabocados; el dibujo muestra un bisturí hueco con forma circular que se inserta en una lesión de la piel del antebrazo del paciente. El instrumento se gira en el sentido de las agujas del reloj y en sentido contrario para cortar la piel y extraer una muestra pequeña de tejido que se observa al microscopio. La ampliación muestra que el instrumento corta alrededor de cuatro milímetros (mm) de grosor hasta llegar a la capa del tejido graso debajo de la dermis." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_5"><Caption language="es">Biopsia con sacabocados. Se usa un bisturí hueco con forma circular para cortar una  lesión de la piel. El instrumento se gira en el sentido de las agujas del reloj y en sentido contrario para cortar alrededor de cuatro milímetros (mm) de grosor hasta llegar a la capa de tejido graso debajo de la dermis. Se extrae una muestra pequeña de tejido para observarla al microscopio. El grosor de la piel es distinto en diferentes partes del cuerpo.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>biopsia con sacabocados</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento mediante el cual se
extrae un pedazo pequeño de tejido de forma redonda, del
tamaño del borrador de un lápiz, con un instrumento
afilado, hueco y circular. Luego se revisa el tejido al microscopio en busca de signos de enfermedad. La biopsia
con sacabocados se puede usar en busca de ciertos tipos de
cáncer, como el de piel, de vulva, y de cuello
uterino. También se usa para revisar ciertas afecciones de
la piel y cambios que pueden ocasionar un cáncer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2004-12-22</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2014-01-03</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
