<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045310"><TermName>stage III anal cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... AY-nul KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage III anal cancer is divided into stages IIIA and IIIB. In stage IIIA, the tumor may be any size and has spread to either (1) lymph nodes near the rectum; or (2) nearby organs, such as the vagina, urethra, and bladder. In stage IIIB, the tumor may be any size and has spread to (1) nearby organs and to lymph nodes near the rectum; or (2) lymph nodes on one side of the pelvis and/or groin, and may have spread to nearby organs; or (3) lymph nodes near the rectum and in the groin, and/or to lymph nodes on both sides of the pelvis and/or groin, and may have spread to nearby organs.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705294" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III anal cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705295" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de ano en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de ano en estadio III</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio III del cáncer de ano se divide en los estadios IIIA y IIIB. En el estadio IIIA, el tumor puede ser de cualquier tamaño y se ha diseminado hasta: (1) los ganglios linfáticos cercanos al recto, o (2) los órganos cercanos, como la vagina, la uretra y la vejiga. En el estadio IIIB, el tumor puede ser de cualquier tamaño y se ha diseminado hasta: (1) los órganos cercanos y los ganglios linfáticos cercanos al recto; (2) los ganglios linfáticos de un lado de la pelvis o la ingle, y puede haberse diseminado hasta los órganos cercanos, o (3) los ganglios linfáticos cerca del recto y la ingle, o a los ganglios linfáticos de ambos lados de la pelvis o la ingle, y puede haberse diseminado hasta los órganos cercanos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2008-07-01</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
