<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000444971"><TermName>breast cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(brest KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cancer that forms in tissues of the breast. The most common type of breast cancer is ductal carcinoma, which begins in the lining of the milk ducts (thin tubes that carry milk from the lobules of the breast to the nipple). Another type of breast cancer is lobular carcinoma, which begins in the lobules (milk glands) of the breast. Invasive breast cancer is breast cancer that has spread from where it began in the breast ducts or lobules to surrounding normal tissue.  Breast cancer occurs in both men and women, although male breast cancer is rare.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714537" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;breast cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714536" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de mama&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000415520" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing of female breast anatomy showing  the lymph nodes, nipple, areola, chest wall, ribs, muscle, fatty tissue, lobe, ducts, and lobules." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_2"><Caption language="en">Anatomy of the female breast. The nipple and areola are shown on the outside of the breast. The lymph nodes, lobes, lobules, ducts, and other parts of the inside of the breast are also shown.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710874" type="image/jpeg" alt="Dibujo de la anatomía de la mama femenina en el que se muestran los ganglios linfáticos, el pezón, la aréola, la pared torácica, las costillas, el músculo, el tejido graso, el lóbulo, los conductos y los lobulillos." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Anatomía de la mama femenina. Se muestran el pezón y la aréola en la parte externa de la mama. También se muestran los ganglios linfáticos, los lóbulos, los lobulillos, los conductos y otras partes internas de la mama.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de mama</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cáncer que se forma en los tejidos de la mama. El tipo de cáncer de mama más común es el carcinoma ductal, que empieza en el revestimiento de los conductos  galactóforos (tubos delgados que llevan leche desde los lobulillos de la mama hasta el pezón). Otro tipo de cáncer de mama es el carcinoma lobulillar, que empieza en los lobulillos (glándulas lácteas). El cáncer de mama invasivo es el que se diseminó desde el sitio en que empezó en los conductos mamarios o lobulillos hasta el tejido normal circundante. El cáncer de mama se presenta tanto en hombres como en mujeres, aunque el cáncer de mama masculino es poco frecuente.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-10-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-07-10</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/breast">Breast Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/seno">Cáncer de seno (mama)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
