<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000460228"><TermName>FISH</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A laboratory technique used to look at genes or chromosomes in cells and tissues. Pieces of DNA that contain a fluorescent dye are made in the laboratory and added to cells or tissues on a glass slide. When these pieces of DNA bind to specific genes or areas of chromosomes on the slide, they light up when viewed under a microscope with a special light. Also called fluorescence in situ hybridization.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A technique used to identify the presence of specific chromosomes or chromosomal regions through hybridization (attachment) of fluorescently-labeled DNA probes to denatured chromosomal DNA. Examination through a microscope under fluorescent lighting detects the presence of the colored hybridized signal (and hence presence of the chromosome material) or absence of the hybridized signal (and hence absence of the chromosome material). Also called fluorescence in situ hybridization.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000734717" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;FISH&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><SpanishTermName>HFIS</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Técnica utilizada para observar los genes o los cromosomas en las células y los tejidos. Se agregan a las células o los tejidos trozos de ADN preparados en el laboratorio que contienen un tinte fluorescente y se colocan en un portaobjetos de vidrio. Cuando estos pedazos de ADN se unen a genes o áreas específicas de los cromosomas en el portaobjetos, se encienden cuando se los ve bajo un microscopio con una luz especial.  También se llama hibridación fluorescente in situ.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-12-22</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2008-05-29</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.genome.gov/Glossary/index.cfm?id=65">Fluorescence In Situ Hybridization (FISH)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.genome.gov/GlossaryS/index.cfm?id=65">Hibridación fluorescente in situ (FISH)
</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
