<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046057"><TermName>retinol</TermName><TermPronunciation>(REH-tih-nol)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A nutrient that the body needs in small amounts to function and stay healthy. Retinol helps in vision, bone growth, reproduction, growth of epithelium (cells that line the internal and external surfaces of the body), and fighting infections. It is fat-soluble (can dissolve in fats and oils). Retinol is found in liver, egg yolks, and whole milk dairy products from animals and in fish oils. It can also be made in the body from a substance found in some fruits and vegetables, such as cantaloupes, carrots, spinach, and sweet potatoes. Retinol is being studied in the prevention and treatment of some types of cancer.  Also called vitamin A.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708080" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;retinol&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708079" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;retinol&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>retinol</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Nutriente que el cuerpo necesita en pequeñas cantidades para funcionar y mantenerse sano. El retinol ayuda la visión, el crecimiento de los huesos, la reproducción, el crecimiento del epitelio (células que revisten las superficies internas y externas del cuerpo) y combate las infecciones. Es soluble en grasas (se puede disolver en grasas y aceites). El retinol se encuentra en el hígado, la yema de huevo y los productos lácteos de leche entera animal, así como en los aceites de pescado. El cuerpo también puede elaborar retinol usando una sustancia que se encuentra en algunas frutas y verduras como los melones, las zanahorias, la espinaca y las batatas. El retinol está en estudio para la prevención y el tratamiento de algunos tipos de cáncer. También se llama vitamina A.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2008-12-12</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
