<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045138"><TermName>stage III melanoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... MEH-luh-NOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The tumor may be any thickness, with or without ulceration (a break in the skin), and one or more of the following is true: (1) cancer has spread to one or more lymph nodes; (2) lymph nodes may be joined together (matted); (3) cancer may be in a lymph vessel between the primary tumor and nearby lymph nodes; and/or  (4) very small tumors may be found on or under the skin, not more than 2 centimeters away from where the cancer first started.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705062" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III melanoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705063" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;melanoma en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000579061" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage III melanoma; drawing shows a primary tumor on the lower arm. In the top inset, cancer is shown (a) in lymph nodes near a blood vessel. In the bottom inset, cancer is shown (b) in lymph nodes that are joined together (matted), (c) in a lymph vessel, and (d) not more than 2 centimeters away from the primary tumor." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_2"><Caption language="en">Stage III melanoma. The tumor may be any thickness, with or without ulceration (a break in the skin), and (a) cancer has spread to one or more lymph nodes; (b) lymph nodes with cancer may be joined together (matted); (c) cancer may be in a lymph vessel between the primary tumor and nearby lymph nodes; and/or (d) very small tumors may be found on or under the skin, not more than 2 centimeters away from the primary tumor.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000609809" type="image/jpeg" alt="Melanoma en estadio III; el dibujo muestra un tumor primario en la parte inferior del brazo.  En el recuadro superior, se muestra un cáncer a) en los ganglios linfáticos cerca de un vaso linfático. En el recuadro inferior, se muestra un cáncer b) en ganglios linfáticos que están unidos entre sí (enredados); c) en un vaso linfático,  y d) a no más de 2 cm del tumor primario." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Melanoma en estadio III.  El tumor puede ser de cualquier grosor, con ulceración (ruptura de la piel) o sin esta, y a) el cáncer se diseminó hasta uno o más ganglios linfáticos; b) los ganglios linfáticos con cáncer pueden estar unidos entre sí (enredados); c) el cáncer puede estar en un vaso linfático entre el tumor primario y los ganglios linfáticos cercanos, o d) se pueden encontrar tumores muy pequeños debajo de la piel o sobre esta, que no están a más de 2 cm del tumor primario.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>melanoma en estadio III</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El tumor puede tener cualquier grosor, con ulceración (rotura en  la piel) o sin esta y se presenta una o más de las siguientes situaciones: 1) el cáncer se diseminó hasta uno o más ganglios linfáticos; 2) los ganglios linfáticos pueden estar unidos entre sí (apelmazados); 3) el cáncer puede estar en un vaso linfático entre el tumor primario y los ganglios linfáticos cercanos, o 4) se encuentran tumores muy pequeños sobre la piel o debajo de esta a no más de 2 centímetros de distancia del lugar donde comenzó el cáncer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2010-08-12</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062713">Melanoma Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256816">Melanoma: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
