<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000438724"><TermName>stage III ovarian germ cell tumor</TermName><TermPronunciation>(...oh-VAYR-ee-un jerm sel TOO-mer)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cancer is found in one or both ovaries and has spread outside the pelvis to other parts of the abdomen and/or nearby lymph nodes. Stage III is divided into stages IIIA, IIIB, and IIIC. In stage IIIA, the tumor is found in the pelvis only, but cancer cells that can be seen only with a microscope have spread to the surface of the peritoneum (tissue that lines the abdominal wall and covers most of the organs in the abdomen), the small intestines, or the tissue that connects the small intestines to the wall of the abdomen. In stage IIIB, cancer has spread to the peritoneum and the cancer in the peritoneum is 2 centimeters or smaller. In stage IIIC, cancer has spread to the peritoneum and the cancer in the peritoneum is larger than 2 centimeters and/or has spread to lymph nodes in the abdomen. Cancer that has spread to the surface of the liver is also considered stage III ovarian cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713653" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III ovarian germ cell tumor&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713654" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tumor de células germinativas del ovario en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000618030" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing of stage IIIA shows cancer inside both ovaries that has spread to lymph nodes behind the peritoneum.  Also shown is cancer cells that have spread to the  omentum. The small intestine, colon, fallopian tubes, uterus, and bladder are also shown. " language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">In stage IIIA, cancer is found in one or both ovaries or fallopian tubes and (a) cancer has spread to lymph nodes in the area outside or behind the peritoneum only, or (b) cancer cells that can be seen only with a microscope have spread to the surface of the peritoneum outside the pelvis. Cancer may have spread to nearby lymph nodes.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000655351" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing of stage IIIB shows cancer inside both ovaries that has spread to the omentum. The cancer in the omentum is 2 centimeters or smaller. An inset shows 2 centimeters is about the size of a peanut. Also shown are the fallopian tubes, uterus, bladder, colon, small intestine, and lymph nodes behind the peritoneum." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="en">In stage IIIB, cancer is found in one or both ovaries or fallopian tubes and has spread to the peritoneum outside the pelvis, and the cancer in the peritoneum is 2 centimeters or smaller.  Cancer may have spread to lymph nodes behind the peritoneum. </Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000655353" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing of stage IIIC shows cancer inside both ovaries that has spread to the omentum. The cancer in the omentum is larger than 2 centimeters. An inset shows 2 centimeters is about the size of a peanut. Also shown are the fallopian tubes,  uterus, bladder, colon, small intestine, and lymph nodes behind the peritoneum." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_5"><Caption language="en"> In stage IIIC, cancer is found in one or both ovaries or fallopian tubes and has spread to the peritoneum outside the pelvis, and the cancer in the peritoneum is larger than 2 centimeters. Cancer may have spread to lymph nodes behind the peritoneum or to the surface of the liver or spleen.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000659000" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer del ovario en estadio IIIA; el dibujo muestra tumores en el interior de ambos ovarios, que se diseminaron hacia el útero, el colon y la superficie del peritoneo.  También se muestran las trompas de Falopio, el intestino delgado y la vejiga." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_6"><Caption language="es">Cáncer del ovario en estadio IIIA. En el estadio IIIA, el cáncer se encuentra en uno o ambos ovarios y se diseminó hacia otros tejidos del interior de la pelvis.  Las células cancerosas que solo se pueden ver bajo un microscopio, se diseminaron hasta la superficie del peritoneo. El cáncer que se disemina hasta la superficie del hígado también se considera en estadio III. </Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000659004" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer del ovario en estadio IIIB; el dibujo muestra tumores en el interior de ambos ovarios, que se diseminaron hasta el útero, el colon, el intestino delgado y el peritoneo; miden 2 cm o menos de diámetro. En un recuadro, se muestra que 2 cm es aproximadamente el tamaño de un maní. También se muestran las trompas de Falopio y la vejiga." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_7"><Caption language="es">Cáncer del ovario en estadio IIIB. En el estadio IIIB, el cáncer se encuentra en uno o ambos ovarios y se diseminó hasta otros tejidos dentro del abdomen y hasta el peritoneo; mide 2 cm o menos de diámetro. El cáncer que se diseminó hasta la superficie del hígado también se considera en estadio III.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000659006" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer del ovario en estadio IIIC; el dibujo muestra tumores en el interior de ambos ovarios que se diseminaron hasta el útero, el colon, el intestino delgado, los ganglios linfáticos del abdomen y la superficie del peritoneo; miden más de 2 cm de diámetro. En un recuadro, se muestra que 2 cm es aproximadamente el tamaño de un maní. También se muestran las trompas de Falopio y la vejiga." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_8"><Caption language="es">Cáncer del ovario en estadio IIIC. En el estadio IIIC, el cáncer se encuentra en uno o ambos ovarios y se diseminó hasta: a) el peritoneo y mide más de 2 cm de diámetro, o b) los ganglios linfáticos del abdomen. El cáncer que se diseminó hasta la superficie del hígado también se considera en estadio III.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>tumor de células germinativas del ovario en estadio III</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El cáncer se encuentra en un ovario o en ambos, y se diseminó fuera de la pelvis hasta otras partes del abdomen o los ganglios linfáticos cercanos. El estadio III se divide en los estadios IIIA, IIIB y IIIC. En el estadio IIIA, el tumor se encuentra solo en la pelvis, pero las células cancerosas, que solo se pueden ver con un microscopio,  se diseminaron hasta la superficie del peritoneo (tejido que reviste la pared abdominal y cubre la mayoría de los órganos del abdomen), el intestino delgado o el tejido que conecta el intestino delgado con la pared del abdomen. En el estadio IIIB, el cáncer se diseminó hasta el peritoneo y el cáncer en el peritoneo mide dos centímetros o menos. En el estadio IIIC, el cáncer se diseminó hasta el peritoneo y el cáncer en el peritoneo mide más de dos centímetros de diámetro, o se diseminó hasta los ganglios linfáticos del abdomen. El cáncer que se diseminó hasta la superficie del hígado también se considera cáncer de ovario en estadio III.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-01-05</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2012-07-16</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062967">Ovarian Germ Cell Tumors Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256832">Tumores de células germinativas del ovario: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
