<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000463134"><TermName>alcohol</TermName><TermPronunciation>(AL-kuh-hol)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A chemical substance found in drinks such as beer, wine, and liquor. It is also found in some medicines, mouthwashes, household products, and essential oils (scented liquid taken from certain plants). It is made by a chemical process called fermentation that uses sugars and yeast. There are different types of alcohol. The type used to make alcoholic drinks is called ethyl alcohol (ethanol). Drinking regular or large amounts of alcohol may increase the risk of certain types of cancer, such as cancer of the mouth, throat, esophagus, breast, liver, colon, and rectum.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000716809" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;alcohol&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000716808" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;alcohol&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>alcohol</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Sustancia química que se encuentra en bebidas, como la cerveza, el vino y  el licor. También se encuentra  en algunas medicinas, enjuagues bucales, productos para la limpieza del hogar y aceites esenciales (líquido perfumado que se obtiene de ciertas plantas). Se elabora por medio de un proceso químico que se llama fermentación en el que se usan azúcares y levadura. Hay diferentes tipos de alcohol. El tipo que se usa para las bebidas alcohólicas se llama alcohol etílico (etanol). El consumo de cantidades moderadas o grandes de alcohol puede aumentar el riesgo de ciertos tipos de cáncer, como el cáncer de boca, garganta, esófago, mama, hígado, colon y recto.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2006-09-10</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-09-17</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/risk/alcohol/alcohol-fact-sheet">Alcohol and Cancer Risk</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/riesgo/alcohol/hoja-informativa-alcohol">Alcohol y el riesgo de cáncer</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
