<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044983"><TermName>spiral CT scan</TermName><TermPronunciation>(SPY-rul … skan)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure that uses a computer linked to an x-ray machine to make a series of detailed pictures of areas inside the body. The x-ray machine scans the body in a spiral path. This allows more images to be made in a shorter time than with older CT methods. A dye may be injected into a vein or swallowed to help the organs or tissues show up more clearly on the x-ray. Spiral CT scan also creates more detailed pictures and may be better at finding small abnormal areas inside the body. It may be used to help diagnose disease, plan treatment, or find out how well treatment is working. Also called helical computed tomography.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000728218" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;spiral CT scan&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000728219" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;exploración por TC en espiral&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>exploración por TC en espiral</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento para el que usa una computadora conectada a una máquina de rayos X para crear una serie de imágenes  detalladas de áreas del interior del cuerpo. La máquina de rayos X explora el cuerpo en un recorrido en espiral. Esto permite crear más imágenes en menos tiempo que el que tomaban los métodos más antiguos de TC. Se puede inyectar un tinte en la vena o  ingerir para que los órganos y los tejidos aparezcan más claramente en la imagen de rayos X. La   también crea imágenes más detalladas y puede ser mejor para encontrar áreas anormales pequeñas en el interior del cuerpo. Se puede usar para ayudar a diagnosticar una enfermedad, planificar un tratamiento o determinar si el tratamiento es eficaz. También se llama tomografía computarizada helicoidal.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2014-03-21</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/diagnosis-staging/ct-scans-fact-sheet">Computed Tomography (CT) Scans and Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/diagnostico-estadificacion/hoja-informativa-tomografia-computarizada">Tomografía computarizada (TC) y exploraciones para cáncer</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
