<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000413912"><TermName>stage III gallbladder cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... GAWL-bla-der KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage III gallbladder cancer is divided into stages IIIA and IIIB. In stage IIIA, cancer has spread through the thin layers of tissue that cover the gallbladder and/or to the liver and/or to one nearby organ (such as the stomach, small intestine, colon, pancreas, or bile ducts outside the liver). In stage IIIB, cancer has spread to nearby lymph nodes and (1) beyond the inner layer of the gallbladder to a layer of tissue with blood vessels or to the muscle layer; or (2) beyond the muscle layer to the connective tissue around the muscle; or (3) through the thin layers of tissue that cover the gallbladder and/or to the liver and/or to one nearby organ (such as the stomach, small intestine, colon, pancreas, or bile ducts outside the liver). </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713280" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III gallbladder cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713281" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de vesícula biliar en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de vesícula biliar en estadio III</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio III del cáncer de vesícula biliar se divide en estadios IIIA y IIIB. En el estadio IIIA, el cáncer se diseminó a través de las capas delgadas de tejido que cubren la vesícula biliar o hasta el hígado, o hasta un órgano cercano (como el estómago, el intestino delgado, el colon, el páncreas o los conductos biliares fuera del hígado). En el estadio IIIB, el cáncer se diseminó hasta los ganglios linfáticos cercanos y 1) más allá de la capa interna de la vesícula biliar hasta la capa de tejido con vasos sanguíneos, o hasta la capa muscular; o 2) más allá de la capa muscular hasta el tejido conjuntivo alrededor del músculo; o 3) a través de las capas delgadas de tejido que cubren la vesícula biliar o hasta el hígado, o hasta un órgano cercano (como el estómago, el intestino delgado, el colon, el páncreas o los conductos biliares fuera del hígado). </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-04-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2011-12-29</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000270720">Gallbladder Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256804">Cáncer de vesícula biliar: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
