<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000467821"><TermName>retinoic acid</TermName><TermPronunciation>(REH-tih-NOH-ik A-sid)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A nutrient that the body needs in small amounts to function and stay healthy. Retinoic acid is made in the body from vitamin A and helps cells to grow and develop, especially in the embryo. A form of retinoic acid made in the laboratory is put on the skin to treat conditions such as acne and is taken by mouth to treat acute promyelocytic leukemia (a fast-growing cancer in which there are too many immature blood-forming cells in the blood and bone marrow). Retinoic acid is being studied in the prevention and treatment of other types of cancer. Also called all-trans retinoic acid, ATRA, tretinoin,  and vitamin A acid.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000716615" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;retinoic acid&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000716614" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ácido retinoico&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>ácido retinoico</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Nutriente que el cuerpo necesita en pequeñas cantidades para funcionar y mantenerse sano. El ácido retinoico se elabora en el cuerpo a partir de la vitamina A y ayuda a las células a crecer y desarrollarse, especialmente en el embrión. Una forma de ácido retinoico que se produce en el laboratorio se aplica sobre la piel para tratar afecciones tales como el acné y se toma por boca para tratar la leucemia promielocítica aguda (cáncer de crecimiento rápido por el que se forman demasiadas células hematopoyéticas en la sangre y la médula ósea). El ácido retinoico está en estudio para la prevención y el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. También se llama ácido de vitamina A, ácido transretinoico total, ATRA,  y tretinoína.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2006-02-21</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2011-02-01</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
