<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000427271"><TermName>immunoassay fecal occult blood test</TermName><TermPronunciation>(IH-myoo-noh-A-say FEE-kul uh-KULT ...)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A test that checks for occult (hidden) blood in the stool. Small samples of stool are placed on special cards and sent to a doctor or laboratory for testing. An antibody that binds to a blood protein called hemoglobin is used to detect any blood. Blood in the stool may be a sign of colorectal cancer or other problems, such as polyps, ulcers, or hemorrhoids. Also called fecal immunochemical test, FIT, iFOBT, immunochemical fecal occult blood test,  and immunologic fecal occult blood test.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713073" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;immunoassay fecal occult blood test&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713074" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;análisis de sangre oculta en la materia fecal mediante inmunoensayo&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>análisis de sangre oculta en la materia fecal mediante inmunoensayo</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Prueba para determinar la presencia de sangre oculta (escondida) en la materia fecal. Se colocan muestras pequeñas de materia fecal en tarjetas especiales y se envían a un médico o un laboratorio para examinarlas. Se usa un anticuerpo que se liga a una proteína sanguínea llamada hemoglobina para detectar sangre. La sangre en la materia fecal puede ser un signo de cáncer colorrectal o de otros problemas, como pólipos, úlceras o hemorroides. También se llama análisis inmunológico de sangre oculta en la materia fecal, análisis inmunoquímico de sangre oculta en la materia fecal, iFOBT, PIF,  y prueba inmunoquímica fecal.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-03-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2014-06-16</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/colorectal/screening-fact-sheet">Tests to Detect Colorectal Cancer and Polyps</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/colorrectal/hoja-informativa-deteccion">Exámenes para detectar el cáncer colorrectal y los pólipos</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
