<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000446199"><TermName>internal exam</TermName><TermPronunciation>(in-TER-nul eg-ZAM)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A physical exam of the vagina, cervix, uterus, fallopian tubes, ovaries, and rectum. First, the area outside the vagina is checked for signs of disease. A speculum is then inserted into the vagina to widen it so the vagina and cervix can be checked for signs of disease. Cell samples may be taken for a Pap test, or to test for sexually transmitted diseases or other infections. The doctor or nurse then inserts one or two lubricated, gloved fingers of one hand into the vagina and presses on the lower abdomen with the other hand to feel for lumps and check the size, shape, and position of the uterus and ovaries. The rectum may also be checked for lumps or abnormal areas. Also called pelvic exam.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714720" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;internal exam&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714721" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;examen interno&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000609924" type="image/jpeg" alt="Pelvic exam; drawing shows a side view of the female reproductive anatomy during a pelvic exam. The uterus, left fallopian tube, left ovary, cervix, vagina, bladder, and rectum are shown. Two gloved fingers of one hand of the doctor or nurse are shown inserted into the vagina, while the other hand is shown pressing on the lower abdomen. The inset shows a woman covered by a drape on an exam table with her legs apart and her feet in stirrups. " language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Pelvic exam. A doctor or nurse inserts one or two lubricated, gloved fingers of one hand into the vagina and presses on the lower abdomen with the other hand. This is done to feel the size, shape, and position of the uterus and ovaries. The vagina, cervix,  fallopian tubes, and rectum are also checked.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000609927" type="image/jpeg" alt="Pap test; drawing shows a side view of the female reproductive anatomy during a Pap test. A speculum is shown widening the opening of the vagina. A brush is shown inserted into the open vagina and touching the cervix at the base of the uterus. The rectum is also shown. One inset shows the brush touching the center of the cervix. A second inset shows a woman covered by a drape on an exam table with her legs apart and her feet in stirrups. " language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_5"><Caption language="en">Pap test. A speculum is inserted into the vagina to widen it. Then, a brush is inserted into the vagina to collect cells from the cervix. The cells are checked under a microscope for signs of disease.  </Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000650437" type="image/jpeg" alt="Examen pélvico; la imagen muestra una vista lateral de la anatomía del aparato reproductor femenino durante un examen pélvico. Se observan el útero, la trompa de Falopio izquierda, el ovario izquierdo, el cuello uterino, la vagina, la vejiga y el recto. El médico o enfermero introduce dos dedos enguantados en la vagina, mientras se ve la otra mano presionando en la parte inferior del abdomen. El recuadro muestra a una mujer cubierta por una sábana sobre una camilla con las piernas separadas y los pies colocados en estribos. " language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Examen pélvico. El médico o enfermero introduce uno o dos dedos lubricados, enguantados en la vagina, mientras presiona la parte inferior del abdomen con la otra mano. Esto se realiza para palpar el tamaño, la forma y la posición del útero y los ovarios. También se revisa la vagina, el cuello uterino, las trompas de Falopio y el recto.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000650434" type="image/jpeg" alt="Prueba de Pap; la imagen muestra una vista lateral de la anatomía del aparato reproductor femenino durante una prueba de Pap. Se observa un espéculo que ensancha la abertura de la vagina. Se ve un cepillo que se introdujo en la vagina abierta y que toca el cuello uterino en la base del útero. También se puede ver el recto. En un recuadro, se observa el cepillo tocando el centro del cuello uterino. En otro recuadro, se observa a una mujer cubierta por una sábana en una camilla con las piernas separadas y los pies colocados en estribos. " language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_6"><Caption language="es">Prueba de Pap. Se introduce un espéculo en la vagina para ensancharla. Luego, se introduce un cepillo en la vagina para obtener células del cuello uterino. Las células se observan al microscopio para determinar si hay signos de enfermedad.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>examen interno</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Examen físico de la vagina, el cuello uterino, el útero, las trompas de Falopio, los ovarios y el recto. Primero, se estudia el área exterior de la vagina para determinar si hay signos de enfermedad. Luego, se introduce un espéculo en la vagina para ensancharla de modo de poder determinar si la vagina y el cuello uterino muestran signos de enfermedad. Se toman muestras para someterlas a una prueba de Pap o para determinar si hay enfermedades de transmisión sexual u otras infecciones. El médico o el enfermero introducen a continuación en la vagina uno o dos dedos de una mano enguantados y lubricados, y presionan con la otra mano la parte inferior del abdomen para palpar si hay masas y verificar el tamaño, la forma y la posición del útero y los ovarios. También se puede examinar el recto para determinar si hay masas o áreas anormales. También se llama examen pélvico.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2006-04-14</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2012-11-01</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
