<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045962"><TermName>central venous access catheter</TermName><TermPronunciation>(SEN-trul VEE-nus AK-ses KA-theh-ter)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A device used to draw blood and give treatments, including intravenous fluids, drugs, or blood transfusions.  A thin, flexible tube is inserted into a vein, usually below the collarbone. It is guided (threaded) into a large vein above the right side of the heart called the superior vena cava.   A needle is inserted into a port outside of the body to draw blood or give fluids.  A central venous access catheter may stay in place for weeks or months and helps avoid the need for repeated needle sticks. There are several types of central venous access catheters.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707514" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;central venous access catheter&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707513" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;catéter central de acceso venoso&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000756806" type="image/jpeg" alt="Central venous catheter; drawing of a central venous catheter that goes from a vein below the right collarbone to a large vein above the right side of the heart called the superior vena cava. An inset shows a central venous catheter in the right side of the chest with a clear plastic dressing over it." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Central venous catheter. A central venous catheter is a thin, flexible tube that is inserted into a vein, usually below the right collarbone, and guided (threaded) into a large vein above the right side of the heart called the superior vena cava. It is used to give intravenous fluids, blood transfusions, chemotherapy, and other drugs. The catheter is also used for taking blood samples. It may stay in place for weeks or months and helps avoid the need for repeated needle sticks.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000774006" type="image/jpeg" alt="Catéter venoso central; dibujo de un catéter venoso central que va desde una vena debajo de la clavícula derecha a una vena grande sobre el lado derecho del corazón llamada vena cava superior. En un recuadro se muestra un catéter venoso central en el lado derecho del pecho con un vendaje plástico transparente sobre este." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Catéter venoso central. Un catéter venoso central es un tubo delgado y flexible que se introduce en una vena, por lo general por debajo de la clavícula derecha, y guiado (insertado) hacia una vena grande sobre el lado derecho del corazón que se llama vena cava superior. Se utiliza para administrar líquidos intravenosos, transfusiones de sangre, quimioterapia y otros medicamentos. El catéter también se utiliza para tomar muestras de sangre. Puede permanecer en el lugar durante semanas o meses, y ayuda a evitar la necesidad de pinchazos repetidos.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>catéter central de acceso venoso</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Dispositivo que se usa para extraer sangre y administrar tratamientos, como líquidos intravenosos, medicamentos o transfusiones de sangre. Se introduce un tubo delgado y flexible en una vena; por lo general, debajo de la clavícula. Se guía (entreteje) en una vena grande por encima del lado derecho del corazón que se llama vena cava superior. Se introduce una aguja en una vía de acceso afuera del cuerpo para extraer sangre o administrar líquidos. Un catéter central de acceso venoso  se puede dejar en su lugar durante semanas o meses, y ayuda a evitar la necesidaded de repetir los pinchazos de aguja. Hay varios tipos de catéteres centrales de acceso venoso.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2015-10-12</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
