<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000415873"><TermName>benign breast disease</TermName><TermPronunciation>(beh-NINE brest dih-ZEEZ)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A group of conditions marked by changes in breast tissue that are benign (not cancer).  There are different types of benign breast disease, including some types caused by an increase in the number of cells or by the growth of abnormal cells in the breast ducts or lobes. Signs and symptoms of benign breast disease include irregular lumps or cysts, breast swelling or discomfort, skin redness or thickening, and nipple discharge. Most benign breast conditions do not increase the risk of breast cancer. Also called mammary dysplasia.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713530" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;benign breast disease&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713529" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;enfermedad benigna de la mama&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>enfermedad benigna de la mama</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Grupo de afecciones caracterizadas por cambios en el tejido de la mama que son benignos (no cancerosos). Hay diferentes tipos de enfermedad benigna de la mama, como algunos tipos que se presentan por un aumento del número de células o por el crecimiento de células anormales en los conductos o los lóbulos de la mama. Los signos y síntomas de enfermedad benigna de la mama incluyen bultos irregulares o quistes, hinchazón de la mama o incomodidad, piel enrojecida o que se vuelve más gruesa, y secreción de los pezones. La mayoría de las afecciones benignas de la mama no aumentan el riesgo de cáncer de mama. También se llama displasia mamaria.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-01-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2015-10-12</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
