<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000446210"><TermName>stage III penile cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... PEE-nile KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage III penile cancer is divided into stage IIIa and stage IIIb. In stage IIIa, cancer has spread to one lymph node in the groin and (1) to connective tissue just under the skin of the penis; cancer may have spread to lymph vessels or blood vessels, or the tumor cells may look very different from normal cells under a microscope; or (2) through connective tissue to erectile tissue (spongy tissue that fills with blood to make an erection); or (3) beyond erectile tissue to the urethra. In stage IIIb, cancer has spread to more than one lymph node on one side of the groin or to lymph nodes on both sides of the groin, and (1) to connective tissue just under the skin of the penis; cancer may have spread to lymph vessels or blood vessels, or the tumor cells may look very different from normal cells under a microscope; or (2) through connective tissue to erectile tissue (spongy tissue that fills with blood to make an erection); or (3) beyond erectile tissue to the urethra.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714732" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III penile cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714733" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de pene en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de pene en estadio III</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El cáncer de pene en estadio III se divide en estadio IIIa y estadio IIIb. En el estadio IIIa, el cáncer se diseminó hasta un ganglio linfático de la ingle y 1) hasta el tejido conjuntivo justo debajo de la piel del pene; el cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta los vasos linfáticos o los vasos sanguíneos, o el aspecto de las células tumorales puede ser muy diferente al de las células normales bajo un microscopio, o 2) a través del tejido conjuntivo hasta el tejido eréctil (tejido esponjoso que se llena de sangre para producir una erección, o 3) más allá del tejido eréctil hasta la uretra. En el estadio IIIb, el cáncer se diseminó hasta más de un ganglio linfático de un lado de la ingle o hasta los ganglios linfáticos de ambos lados de la ingle, y 1) hasta el tejido conjuntivo justo debajo de la piel del pene; el cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta los vasos linfáticos o los vasos sanguíneos, o el aspecto de las células tumorales puede ser muy diferente al de las células normales bajo un microscopio, o 2) el cáncer se diseminó a través del tejido conjuntivo hasta el tejido eréctil (tejido esponjoso que se llena de sangre para producir una erección), o 3) el cáncer se diseminó más allá del tejido eréctil hasta la uretra.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-01-05</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2010-10-04</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000438960">Penile Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000502300">Cáncer de pene: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
