<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000491158"><TermName>central nervous system depressant</TermName><TermPronunciation>(SEN-trul NER-vus SIS-tem dee-PREH-sunt)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of drug that slows down brain activity, which causes the muscles to relax and calms and soothes a person.  Central nervous system depressants are used to treat insomnia (trouble sleeping), anxiety, panic attacks, and seizures. They may also be used to relieve anxiety and tension before surgery. Examples of central nervous system depressants are benzodiazepines, barbiturates, and certain sleep medicines. Central nervous system depressants are sometimes called sedatives or tranquilizers. Also called CNS depressant.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000769346" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;central nervous system depressant&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000769347" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;depresor del sistema nervioso central&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>depresor del sistema nervioso central</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de medicamento que  hace más lenta la actividad del cerebro, lo que provoca que los músculos se relajen, y que la persona se calme y alivie. Los depresores del sistema nervioso central se usan para tratar el insomnio (dificultad para dormir), la ansiedad, los ataques de pánico y las crisis epilépticas. También se pueden usar para aliviar la ansiedad y la tensión antes de una cirugía. Entre los ejemplos de depresores del sistema nervioso central están las benzodiazepinas, los barbitúricos y ciertas medicinas para dormir. A veces, los depresores del sistema nervioso central se llaman sedantes o tranquilizantes. También se llama depresor del SNC.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2014-11-07</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
