<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046445"><TermName>differentiation</TermName><TermPronunciation>(DIH-feh-REN-shee-AY-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>In biology, describes the processes by which immature cells become mature cells with specific functions.  In cancer, this describes how much or how little tumor tissue looks like the normal tissue it came from. Well-differentiated cancer cells look more like normal cells and tend to grow and spread more slowly than poorly differentiated or undifferentiated cancer cells. Differentiation is used in tumor grading systems, which are different for each type of cancer.


</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708749" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;differentiation&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708750" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;diferenciación&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>diferenciación</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>En el campo de la biología, describe los procesos mediante los que las células inmaduras se vuelven células maduras con funciones específicas. Con respecto al cáncer, describe en qué medida el aspecto del tumor se parece al tejido del que surge. Las células cancerosa bien diferenciadas se parecen más a las células normales, y tienden a crecer y diseminarse más lentamente que las células cancerosas pobremente diferenciadas o indiferenciadas. La diferenciación se usa en los sistemas de gradación de tumores, que son distintos para cada tipo de cáncer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2012-08-14</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/diagnosis-staging/prognosis/tumor-grade-fact-sheet">Tumor Grade</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/diagnostico-estadificacion/pronostico/hoja-informativa-grado-tumor">Grado de un tumor</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
