<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045156"><TermName>stage III breast cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... brest KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage III is divided into stages IIIA, IIIB, and IIIC. In stage IIIA, (1) no tumor is found in the breast or the tumor may be any size. Cancer is found in 4 to 9 axillary lymph nodes or in the lymph nodes near the breastbone (found during imaging tests or a physical exam); or (2) the tumor is larger than 5 centimeters. Small clusters of breast cancer cells (larger than 0.2 millimeter but not larger than 2 millimeters) are found in the lymph nodes; or (3) the tumor is larger than 5 centimeters. Cancer has spread to 1 to 3 axillary lymph nodes or to the lymph nodes near the breastbone (found during a sentinel lymph node biopsy). In stage IIIB, the tumor may be any size and cancer has spread to the chest wall and/or to the skin of the breast and caused swelling or an ulcer. Also, cancer may have spread to: (1) up to 9 axillary lymph nodes; or (2) the lymph nodes near the breastbone.   Cancer that has spread to the skin of the breast may also be inflammatory breast cancer. In stage IIIC, no tumor is found in the breast or the tumor may be any size. Cancer may have spread to the skin of the breast and caused swelling or an ulcer and/or has spread to the chest wall. Also, cancer has spread to: (1) 10 or more axillary lymph nodes; or (2) lymph nodes above or below the collarbone; or (3) axillary lymph nodes and lymph nodes near the breastbone. Cancer that has spread to the skin of the breast may also be inflammatory breast cancer.  For treatment, stage IIIC breast cancer is divided into operable and inoperable stage IIIC.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705095" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III breast cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705094" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de mama (seno) en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000732259" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIIA breast cancer. The drawing on the left shows no tumor in the breast; cancer is found in 8 axillary lymph nodes. The drawing in the middle shows the tumor is larger than 5 cm and small clusters of cancer cells are in the lymph nodes. The drawing on the right shows the tumor is larger than 5 cm and cancer is in 3 axillary lymph nodes." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Stage IIIA breast cancer. No tumor is found in the breast or the tumor may be any size and cancer is found in 4 to 9 axillary lymph nodes or lymph nodes near the breastbone (left panel); OR the tumor is larger than 5 centimeters and small clusters of cancer cells (larger than 0.2 millimeter but not larger than 2 millimeters) are found in the lymph nodes (middle panel); OR the tumor is larger than 5 centimeters and cancer is found in 1 to 3 axillary lymph nodes or lymph nodes near the breastbone (right panel).</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000732260" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIIB breast cancer. The drawing on the left is a cross section of the breast showing  that cancer has spread to the chest wall. The ribs, muscle, and fatty tissue are also shown. The drawing on the right shows the tumor has spread to the skin of the breast. An inset shows inflammatory breast cancer." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="en">Stage IIIB breast cancer. The tumor may be any size and cancer has spread to the chest wall and/or to the skin of the breast and caused swelling or an ulcer. Cancer may have spread to up to 9 axillary lymph nodes or the lymph nodes near the breastbone. Cancer that has spread to the skin of the breast may be inflammatory breast cancer.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000732263" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIIC breast cancer. The drawing on the left shows cancer in lymph nodes in the axilla. The drawing in the middle shows cancer in lymph nodes above the collarbone. The drawing on the right shows cancer in lymph nodes in the axilla and in lymph nodes near the breastbone." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_5"><Caption language="en">Stage IIIC breast cancer. No tumor is found in the breast or the tumor may be any size and may have spread to the chest wall and/or to the skin of the breast and caused swelling or an ulcer. Also, cancer has spread to 10 or more axillary lymph nodes (left panel); OR to lymph nodes above or below the collarbone (middle panel); OR to axillary lymph nodes and lymph nodes near the breastbone (right panel). Cancer that has spread to the skin of the breast may be inflammatory breast cancer.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000740901" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de mama en estadio lllA. El dibujo de la izquierda  muestra que no hay tumor en la mama; se encuentra cáncer en 8 ganglios linfáticos de la axila. En el dibujo del medio el tumor mide más de 5 cm y hay pequeños grupos de células cancerosas en los ganglios linfáticos. El dibujo de la derecha muestra el tumor de más de 5 cm y el cáncer está en tres ganglios linfáticos de la axila." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_6"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de mama en estadio lllA. No se encuentra tumor en la mama o el tumor puede ser de cualquier tamaño, y el cáncer se encuentra entre 4 a 9 ganglios linfáticos de la axila, o en los ganglios linfáticos cerca del esternón (dibujo de la izquierda); O el tumor mide más de 5 cm y se encuentran pequeños grupos  de células cancerosas (de más de 0,2 mm, pero de no más de 2 mm) en los ganglios linfáticos (dibujo del medio); O el tumor mide más de 5 cm y se encuentra cáncer entre 1 a 3 ganglios linfáticos de la axila, o en los ganglios linfáticos cerca del esternón (dibujo de la derecha).</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000740902" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de mama en estadio lllB. El dibujo de la derecha es una sección transversal de la mama que muestra que el cáncer se diseminó hasta la pared del pecho. También se muestran las costillas, el músculo y el tejido graso. El dibujo de la derecha muestra el tumor que se diseminó hasta la piel de la mama.   En un recuadro se muestra el cáncer de mama inflamatorio." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_7"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de mama en estadio lllB. El tumor puede ser de cualquier tamaño y el cáncer se pudo diseminar hasta la pared del pecho o  la piel de la mama y causar hinchazón o una úlcera. El cáncer se pudo diseminar hasta  los ganglios linfáticos de la axila o  los ganglios linfáticos cerca del esternón. El cáncer que se diseminó hasta la piel de la mama puede ser cáncer de mama inflamatorio.  </Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000740903" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de mama  en estadio lllC. El dibujo de la izquierda  muestra cáncer en los ganglios linfáticos de la axila. El dibujo del medio muestra cáncer en los ganglios linfáticos encima de la clavícula. El dibujo de la derecha  muestra cáncer en ganglios linfáticos de la axila y en los ganglios linfáticos cerca del esternón." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_8"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de mama  en estadio lllC. No se encuentra tumor en la mama o el tumor puede ser de cualquier tamaño, y se pudo diseminar hasta la pared del pecho o  la piel de la mama . Además, el cáncer se diseminó hasta 10 o más ganglios linfáticos de la axila (dibujo de la izquierda); o hasta los ganglios linfáticos encima o debajo de la clavícula (dibujo del medio); O a los ganglios linfáticos de la axila o debajo de la clavícula (dibujo del medio); O hasta los ganglios linfáticos de la axila y  los ganglios linfáticos cerca del esternón (dibujo de la derecha). </Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de mama en estadio III</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio III se divide en los estadios IIIA, IIIB y IIIC. En el estadio IIIA, 1) no se encuentra un tumor en la mama o el tumor puede tener cualquier tamaño. El cáncer se encuentra en 4 a 9 ganglios linfáticos axilares o en los ganglios linfáticos cerca del esternón (se encontró mediante pruebas de imágenes o un examen físico); o 2) el tumor mide más de cinco centímetros. Se encuentran pequeños racimos de células de cáncer de mama (que miden más de 0,2 milímetros, pero no más de 2 milímetros) en los ganglios linfáticos; o 3) el tumor mide más de cinco centímetros. El cáncer se diseminó de 1 a 3 ganglios linfáticos axilares o hasta los ganglios linfáticos cerca del esternón (se encontró mediante una biopsia de ganglio linfático centinela). En el estadio IIIB, el tumor puede tener cualquier tamaño y el cáncer se diseminó hasta la pared del pecho o la piel de la mama, y causó hinchazón o una úlcera. Además, el cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta: 1) no más de nueve ganglios linfáticos axilares; o 2) los ganglios linfáticos cerca del esternón. En el estadio IIIC, no se encuentra un tumor en la mama o el tumor puede tener cualquier tamaño. El cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta la piel de la mama y haber causado hinchazón o una úlcera, o se diseminó hasta la pared del pecho. Además, el cáncer se diseminó hacia: 1) 10 o más ganglios linfáticos axilares; o 2) los ganglios linfáticos por encima o debajo de la clavícula; o 3) los ganglios linfáticos axilares y los ganglios linfáticos cerca del esternón. El cáncer que se diseminó hacia la piel de la mama también puede ser cáncer de mama inflamatorio. Para su tratamiento, el cáncer de mama en estadio IIIC se divide en estadio IIIC operable y estadio IIIC inoperable.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2012-10-02</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062955">Breast Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256762">Cáncer de seno (mama): Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
