<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046146"><TermName>hepatitis B virus</TermName><TermPronunciation>(HEH-puh-TY-tis ... VY-rus)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A virus that causes hepatitis (inflammation of the liver). It is carried and passed to others through the blood and other body fluids. Different ways the virus is spread include sharing needles with an infected person and being stuck accidentally by a needle contaminated with the virus.  Infants born to infected mothers may also become infected with the virus. Although many patients who are infected with hepatitis B virus may not have symptoms, long-term infection may lead to cirrhosis (scarring of the liver) and liver cancer. Also called HBV.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707743" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hepatitis B virus&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707742" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;virus de la hepatitis B&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>virus de la hepatitis B</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Virus que causa la hepatitis (inflamación del hígado). Se lleva y se contagia a los demás a través de la sangre y otros líquidos del cuerpo. Las diferentes maneras en que se transmite el virus incluyen compartir jeringas con una persona infectada y pincharse accidentalmente con una aguja contaminada por el virus. Los niños nacidos de madres infectadas también se pueden infectar con el virus. Aunque los pacientes infectados por el virus de la hepatitis B  pueden no tener síntomas, la infección a largo plazo puede conducir a padecer de cirrosis (cicatrización patológica del hígado) y cáncer de hígado. También se llama VHB.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2011-07-08</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
