<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046343"><TermName>islet cell carcinoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(I-let sel KAR-sih-NOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare cancer that forms in islet cells (hormone-making cells) of the pancreas. Islet cells make several different hormones that affect body functions, including controlling the amount of glucose (sugar) in the blood and helping digest food in the stomach. Functional islet cell carcinomas make extra amounts of these hormones, which can cause symptoms. Nonfunctional islet cell carcinomas do not make extra amounts of hormones, but they may cause symptoms as they grow and spread. Also called pancreatic endocrine cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708576" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;islet cell carcinoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708575" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;carcinoma de célula de los islotes&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>carcinoma de célula de los islotes</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cáncer poco frecuente que se forma en las células de los islotes (células que producen hormonas) del páncreas. Las células de los islotes producen varias hormonas diferentes que afectan el funcionamiento del cuerpo, como controlar la cantidad de glucosa (azúcar) en la sangre y ayudar al estómago a digerir los alimentos. Los carcinomas de células de los islotes funcionantes producen cantidades adicionales de estas hormonas, lo que puede causar síntomas. Los carcinomas de células de los islotes no funcionantes no producen cantidades adicionales de hormonas, pero pueden causar síntomas a medida que crecen y se diseminan.  También se llama cáncer de páncreas endocrino.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2013-12-03</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/pancreatic">Pancreatic Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/pancreas">Cáncer de páncreas</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
