<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045137"><TermName>stage II melanoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... MEH-luh-NOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage II is divided into stages IIA, IIB, and IIC.  In stage IIA, (1) the tumor is more than 1 but not more than 2 millimeters thick, with ulceration (a break in the skin); or (2) more than 2 but not more than 4 millimeters thick, with no ulceration. In stage IIB, (1) the tumor is either more than 2 but not more than 4 millimeters thick, with ulceration; or (2) more than 4 millimeters thick, with no ulceration. In stage IIC, the tumor is more than 4 millimeters thick, with ulceration.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705061" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage II melanoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705060" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;melanoma en estadio II&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000579056" type="image/jpeg" alt="Three-panel drawing of stage II melanoma. The left panel shows two stage IIA tumors. One tumor is more than 1 but not more than 2 millimeters thick, with ulceration (break in the skin); the other tumor is more than 2 but not more than 4 millimeters thick, with no ulceration. The right panel shows two stage IIB tumors. One tumor is more than 2 but not more than 4 millimeters thick, with ulceration; the other tumor is more than 4 millimeters thick, with no ulceration. The bottom panel shows a stage IIC tumor that is more than 4 millimeters thick, with ulceration. Also shown are the epidermis (outer layer of the skin), the dermis (inner layer of the skin), and the subcutaneous tissue below the dermis." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_2"><Caption language="en">Stage II melanoma. In stage IIA, the tumor is either more than 1 but not more than 2 millimeters thick, with ulceration (break in the skin), OR it is more than 2 but not more than 4 millimeters thick, with no ulceration. In stage IIB, the tumor is either more than 2 but not more than 4 millimeters thick, with ulceration, OR it is more than 4 millimeters thick, with no ulceration. In stage IIC, the tumor is more than 4 millimeters thick, with ulceration. Skin thickness is different on different parts of the body.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000609807" type="image/jpeg" alt="Dibujo de tres paneles del melanoma en estadio II. El panel de la izquierda muestra dos tumores en estadio IIA. Un tumor mide más de 1 mm pero no más de 2 mm de grosor, con úlcera (rotura de la piel); el otro tumor mide más de 2 mm pero no más de 4 mm de grosor, sin úlcera. El panel de la derecha muestra dos tumores en estadio IIB. Un tumor mide más de 2 mm pero no más de 4 mm de grosor, con úlcera; el otro tumor mide más de 4 mm de grosor, sin úlcera. El panel de abajo muestra un tumor en estadio IIC que mide más de 4 mm de grosor, con úlcera. También se muestra la epidermis (capa exterior de la piel), la dermis (capa interior de la piel) y el tejido subcutáneo debajo de la dermis." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Melanoma en estadio II. En el estadio IIA, el tumor mide más de 1 mm pero no más de 2 mm de grosor, con úlcera (rotura de la piel), O mide más de 2 mm pero no más de 4 mm de grosor, sin úlcera. En el estadio IIB, el tumor mide más de 2 mm pero no más de 4 mm de grosor, sin úlcera O mide más de 4 mm de grosor, sin úlcera. En el estadio IIC, el tumor mide más de 4 mm de grosor, con úlcera. El grosor de la piel es distinto en diferentes partes del cuerpo.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>melanoma en estadio II</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio II se divide en los estadios IIA, IIB y IIC. En el estadio IIA, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) el tumor mide más de 1 milímetro, pero no más de 2 milímetros de grosor, con ulceración (rotura de la piel),   o 2) el tumor mide más de 2 milímetros, pero no más de 4 milímetros de grosor, sin ulceración. En el estadio IIB, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) el tumor mide más de 2 milímetros, pero no más de 4 milímetros de grosor, con ulceración o 2) el tumor mide más de 4 milímetros de grosor, sin ulceración. En el estadio IIC, el tumor mide más de 4 milímetros de grosor, con ulceración.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2010-08-12</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062713">Melanoma Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256816">Melanoma: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
