<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045903"><TermName>stage I gastric cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... GAS-trik KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cancer has formed in the inside lining of the mucosa (innermost layer) of the stomach wall. Stage I is divided into stages IA and IB, depending on where the cancer has spread. In stage IA, cancer may have spread into the submucosa (layer of tissue next to the mucosa) of the stomach wall. In stage IB, cancer (1) may have spread into the submucosa (layer of tissue next to the mucosa) of the stomach wall and is found in 1 or 2 lymph nodes near the tumor; or (2) has spread to the muscle layer of the stomach wall.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707422" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage I gastric cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707421" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de estómago en estadio I&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de estómago en estadio I</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El cáncer se formó en el lado interno del revestimiento de la mucosa (capa más interna) de la pared del estómago. El estadio I se divide en los estadios IA y IB, de acuerdo con el lugar hasta donde se haya diseminado el cáncer. En el estadio IA, el cáncer se puede haber diseminado hacia la submucosa (la capa de tejido cerca de la mucosa) de la pared del estómago. En el estadio IB, el cáncer 1) se puede haber diseminado hacia la submucosa (capa de tejido cerca de la mucosa) de la pared del estómago y se encuentra en 1 o 2 ganglios linfáticos cerca del tumor; o 2) se diseminó hasta la capa muscular de la pared del estómago.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2011-10-18</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000271446">Gastric Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256764">Cáncer de estómago: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
