<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045289"><TermName>goserelin acetate</TermName><TermPronunciation>(GOH-seh-REH-lin A-seh-tayt)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat prostate cancer and to relieve the symptoms of advanced breast cancer. It is also used to treat problems with the endometrium (lining of the uterus). Goserelin acetate keeps the body from making the hormones luteinizing hormone-releasing hormone (LHRH) and luteinizing hormone (LH). This causes the testicles to stop making testosterone (a male hormone) in men, and the ovaries to stop making estradiol (a form of the hormone estrogen) in women. Goserelin acetate may stop the growth of cancer cells that need testosterone or estrogen to grow. It is a type of LHRH agonist. Also called ZDX and Zoladex.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705272" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;goserelin acetate&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000756039" type="audio/mpeg" alt="" language="es" id="_6"/><SpanishTermName>acetato de goserelina</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para tratar el cáncer de próstata y para aliviar los síntomas del cáncer de mama en estadio avanzado. También se usa para tratar problemas del endometrio (revestimiento del útero). El acetato de goserelina impide que el cuerpo elabore las hormonas liberadoras de hormona luteinizante (HL-HL) y la hormona luteinizante (HL). Esto hace que los testículos dejen de producir testosterona (una hormona masculina) en los hombres, y que los ovarios dejen de producir estradiol (una de las formas de la hormona estrógeno) en las mujeres. El acetato de goserelina puede detener la formación de las células cancerosas que necesitan testosterona o estrógeno para crecer. Es un tipo de agonista de la HL-HL.  También se llama ZDX y Zoladex.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2013-11-13</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000753175">Goserelin Acetate</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
