<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045616"><TermName>biological response modifier therapy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(BY-oh-LAH-jih-kul reh-SPONTS MAH-dih-FY-er THAYR-uh-pee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of treatment that uses substances made from living organisms to treat disease. These substances may occur naturally in the body or may be made in the laboratory. Some biological response modifier therapies stimulate or suppress the immune system to help the body fight cancer, infection, and other diseases. Other biological response modifier therapies attack specific cancer cells, which may help keep them from growing or kill them. They may also lessen certain side effects caused by some cancer treatments. Types of biological response modifier therapy include immunotherapy (such as vaccines, cytokines, and some antibodies), gene therapy, and some targeted therapies. Also called biological therapy, biotherapy,  and BRM therapy.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705681" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;biological response modifier therapy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705682" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;terapia modificadora de la respuesta biológica&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>terapia modificadora de la respuesta biológica</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de tratamiento para el que se usan sustancias elaboradas por organismos vivos para tratar enfermedades. El cuerpo puede elaborar estas sustancias de forma natural o se pueden producir en un laboratorio. Algunas terapias modificadoras de la respuesta biológica estimulan o inhiben el sistema inmunitario para ayudar al cuerpo a combatir el cáncer, las infecciones y otras enfermedades. Otras terapias modificadoras de la respuesta biológica atacan células cancerosas específicas y pueden impedir su crecimiento o destruirlas. También pueden disminuir algunos efectos secundarios de ciertos tratamientos del cáncer. Los tipos de terapia modificadora de la respuesta biológica son la inmunoterapia (como las vacunas, las citocinas y algunos anticuerpos), la terapia génica y algunas terapias dirigidas. También se llama bioterapia, terapia biológica,  y Terapia MRB.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2013-09-24</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/types/immunotherapy/bio-therapies-fact-sheet">Biological Therapies for Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/tipos/inmunoterapia/hoja-informativa-terapias-biologicas-respuestas">Terapias biológicas para el cáncer</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
