<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000439435"><TermName>vitamin C</TermName><TermPronunciation>(VY-tuh-min…)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A nutrient that the body needs in small amounts to function and stay healthy. Vitamin C helps fight infections, heal wounds, and keep tissues healthy. It is an antioxidant that helps prevent cell damage caused by free radicals (highly reactive chemicals). Vitamin C is found in all fruits and vegetables, especially citrus fruits, strawberries, cantaloupe, green peppers, tomatoes, broccoli, leafy greens, and potatoes. It is water-soluble (can dissolve in water) and must be taken in every day. Vitamin C is being studied in the prevention and treatment of some types of cancer.  Also called ascorbic acid.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713696" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;vitamin C&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713697" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;vitamina C&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>vitamina C</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Nutriente que el cuerpo necesita en pequeñas cantidades para funcionar y mantenerse sano. La vitamina C ayuda a combatir las infecciones, cicatrizar las heridas y mantener los tejidos saludables. Es un antioxidante que ayuda a prevenir el daño a los tejidos causado por los radicales libres (sustancias químicas sumamente reactivas).  La vitamina C se encuentra en todas las frutas y verduras, especialmente las frutillas, el melón, los pimientos verdes, los tomates, el brócoli, las verduras de hoja y las papas.  Es soluble en agua (se puede disolver en agua) y se debe tomar todos los días.  La vitamina C está en estudio para la prevención y el tratamiento de algunos tipos de cáncer. También se llama ácido ascórbico.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-07-08</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2010-05-25</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
