<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046287"><TermName>mediastinoscopy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(MEE-dee-uh-sty-NOS-koh-pee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure in which a mediastinoscope is used to examine the organs in the area between the lungs and nearby lymph nodes. A mediastinoscope is a thin, tube-like instrument with a light and a lens for viewing. It may also have a tool to remove tissue to be checked under a microscope for signs of disease. The mediastinoscope is inserted into the chest through an incision above the breastbone. This procedure is usually done to get a tissue sample from the lymph nodes on the right side of the chest.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707975" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mediastinoscopy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707976" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mediastinoscopia&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000466554" type="image/jpeg" alt="Mediastinoscopy; shows mediastinoscope with light and lens inserted into&#10;the chest through an incision above the breastbone. Drawing shows right&#10;and left lungs, trachea, and lymph nodes. Inset shows anterior&#10;mediastinotomy (Chamberlain procedure) with incision beside the&#10;breastbone.&#10;" language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_2"><Caption language="en">Mediastinoscopy. A mediastinoscope is inserted into the chest through an
incision above the breastbone to look for abnormal areas between the
lungs. A mediastinoscope is a thin, tube-like instrument with a light
and a lens for viewing. It may also have a cutting tool. Tissue samples
may be taken from lymph nodes on the right side of the chest and checked
under a microscope for signs of cancer. In an anterior mediastinotomy
(Chamberlain procedure), the incision is made beside the breastbone to
remove tissue samples from the lymph nodes on the left side of the
chest.
</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000494346" type="image/jpeg" alt="Mediastinoscopía; muestra el mediastinoscopio con una luz y una lente insertadas en el pecho mediante una incisión en la parte superior del esternón.  El dibujo muestra el pulmón derecho e izquierdo, la tráquea y los ganglios linfáticos.  El recuadro muestra la mediastinoscopía anterior (Procedimiento de Chamberlain) con una incisión al lado del esternón." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Mediastinoscopía.  Se inserta un mediastinoscopio en el pecho mediante una incisión en la parte superior del esternón para determinar si existen áreas anormales entre los pulmones.  Un mediastinoscopio es un instrumento en forma de tubo delgado con una luz y una lente, que se utiliza para observar. También puede tener un instrumento para cortar.   Se pueden tomar muestras de tejido de los ganglios linfáticos que se encuentran a la derecha del pecho para analizarlas al microscopio y determinar si hay algún signo de cáncer. En una mediastinoscopía anterior (Procedimiento de Chamberlain), la incisión se hace al lado del esternón para extraer muestras de tejido de los ganglios linfáticos que se encuentran al lado izquierdo del pecho.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>mediastinoscopia</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento en el que se usa un mediastinoscopio para examinar los órganos ubicados en el área entre los pulmones y los ganglios linfáticos cercanos. Un mediastinoscopio es un instrumento parecido a un tubo delgado con una luz y una lente para mirar. También puede tener una herramienta para extraer tejido y revisarlo bajo un microscopio, y observar si hay signos de enfermedad. El mediastinoscopio se inserta en el pecho a través de una incisión por encima del esternón. Por lo general, este procedimiento se realiza para obtener una muestra del tejido de los ganglios linfáticos del lado derecho del pecho.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2006-11-29</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
