<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000413883"><TermName>stage IIB breast cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... brest KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage II is divided into stages IIA and IIB. In stage IIB, the tumor is (1) larger than 2 centimeters but not larger than 5 centimeters. Small clusters of breast cancer cells (larger than 0.2 millimeter but not larger than 2 millimeters) are found in the lymph nodes; or (2) larger than 2 centimeters but not larger than 5 centimeters. Cancer has spread to 1 to 3 axillary lymph nodes or to the lymph nodes near the breastbone (found during a sentinel lymph node biopsy); or (3) larger than 5 centimeters. Cancer has not spread to the lymph nodes.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713099" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IIB breast cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713100" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de mama en estadio IIB&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000732258" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIB breast cancer. The drawing on the left shows the tumor is larger than 2 cm but not larger than 5 cm and small clusters of cancer cells are in the lymph nodes. The drawing in the middle shows the tumor is larger than 2 cm but not larger than 5 cm and cancer is in 3 axillary lymph nodes. The drawing on the right shows the tumor is larger than 5 cm but has not spread to the lymph nodes." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Stage IIB breast cancer. The tumor is larger than 2 centimeters but not larger than 5 centimeters and small clusters of cancer cells (larger than 0.2 millimeter but not larger than 2 millimeters) are found in the lymph nodes (left panel); OR the tumor is larger than 2 centimeters but not larger than 5 centimeters and cancer is found in 1 to 3 axillary lymph nodes or lymph nodes near the breastbone (middle panel); OR the tumor is larger than 5 centimeters and has not spread to the lymph nodes (right panel).</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000740900" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de mama en estadio llB. El dibujo de la izquierda muestra el tumor de más de 2 cm, pero no más de 5 cm, y hay pequeños grupos  de células cancerosas en los ganglios linfáticos. El dibujo del medio  muestra el tumor de más de 2 cm, pero no más de 5 cm, y el cáncer está en tres ganglios linfáticos de la axila. El dibujo de la derecha muestra el tumor de más de 5 cm, pero que no se  diseminó hasta los ganglios linfáticos." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de mama en estadio llB. El tumor mide más de 2 cm, pero no más de 5 cm, y se encuentran pequeños grupos  de células cancerosas  en los ganglios linfáticos (dibujo de la izquierda); O el tumor mide más de 2 cm, pero no más de 5 cm, y el cáncer se encuentra entre 1 a 3 ganglios linfáticos de la axila o en los ganglios linfáticos cerca del esternón (dibujo del medio); O el tumor mide más de 5 cm, pero no se diseminó hasta los ganglios linfáticos (dibujo de la derecha).</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de mama en estadio IIB</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio II se divide en estadios IIA y IIB. En el estadio IIB, el tumor: 1) mide más de dos centímetros, pero no más de cinco
centímetros. Se encuentran pequeños racimos de células de cáncer de mama (que miden más de 0,2 milímetro, pero no más de 2 milímetros) en los ganglios linfáticos; o 2) mide más de dos centímetros, pero no más de cinco centímetros. El cáncer se diseminó de 1 a 3 ganglios linfáticos axilares o hasta los ganglios linfáticos cerca del esternón (que se encuentran mediante una biopsia de ganglio linfático centinela); o 3) mide más de cinco centímetros. El cáncer no se diseminó hasta los ganglios linfáticos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-04-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2012-10-02</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062955">Breast Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256762">Cáncer de seno (mama): Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
