<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000440112"><TermName>post-traumatic stress disorder</TermName><TermPronunciation>(post-traw-MA-tik stres dis-OR-der)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>An anxiety disorder that develops in reaction to physical injury or severe mental or emotional distress, such as military combat, violent assault, natural disaster, or other life-threatening events. Having cancer may also lead to post-traumatic stress disorder. Symptoms interfere with day-to-day living and include reliving the event in nightmares or flashbacks; avoiding people, places, and things connected to the event; feeling alone and losing interest in daily activities; and having trouble concentrating and sleeping. Also called PTSD.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713728" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;post-traumatic stress disorder&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713729" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;trastorno por tensión postraumática&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>trastorno por tensión postraumática</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno de ansiedad que se presenta como reacción a una lesión física o a un sufrimiento mental o emocional grave, como un combate militar, una agresión violenta, un desastre natural u otros acontecimientos potencialmente mortales. Padecer de cáncer también puede conducir a un trastorno por tensión postraumática. Los síntomas dificultan la vida diaria e incluyen revivir el acontecimiento en forma de pesadillas o escenas retrospectivas; evitar a personas, lugares y cosas conectadas con el acontecimiento; sentirse solo y perder interés en las actividades diarias, y tener dificultad para concentrarse y dormir. También se llama TTPT.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-08-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2008-01-16</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062831">Cancer-Related Post-traumatic Stress</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256660">Tensión postraumática relacionada con el cáncer</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
