<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045886"><TermName>stage I cervical cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... SER-vih-kul KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cancer is found in the cervix only. Stage I is divided into stages IA and IB, based on the amount of cancer that is found. In stage IA, a very small amount of cancer that can only be seen with a microscope is found in the tissues of the cervix. Stage IA is divided into stages IA1 and IA2, based on the size of the tumor. In stage IA1, the cancer is not more than 3 millimeters deep and not more than 7 millimeters wide. In stage IA2, the cancer is more than 3 but not more than 5 millimeters deep, and not more than 7 millimeters wide. Stage IB is divided into stages IB1 and IB2, based on the size of the tumor. In stage IB1, (1) the cancer can only be seen with a microscope and is more than 5 millimeters deep and more than 7 millimeters wide; or (2) the cancer can be seen without a microscope and is not more than 4 centimeters. In stage IB2, the cancer can be seen without a microscope and is more than 4 centimeters.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707388" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage I cervical cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707387" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de cuello uterino en estadio I&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000658902" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IA1 and IA2 cervical cancer; drawing shows a cross-section of the cervix and vagina. An inset shows cancer in the cervix that is up to 5 mm deep, but not more than 7 mm wide." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Stage IA1 and IA2 cervical cancer. A very small amount of cancer that can only be seen with a microscope is found in the tissues of the cervix. In stage IA1, the cancer is not more than 3 millimeters deep and not more than 7 millimeters wide. In stage IA2, the cancer is more than 3 but not more than 5 millimeters deep, and not more than 7 millimeters wide.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000658903" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IB1 and IB2 cervical cancer shown in three cross-section drawings of the cervix and vagina. An inset on the left shows stage IB1 cancer that is 7 mm wide and more than 5 mm deep. Drawing in the middle shows stage IB1 cancer that is smaller than 4 cm. Drawing on the right shows stage IB2 cancer that is larger than 4 cm." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="en">Stage IB1 and IB2 cervical cancer. In stage IB1, the cancer can only be seen with a microscope and is more than 5 mm deep and more than 7 mm wide OR the cancer can be seen without a microscope and is 4 cm or smaller. In stage IB2, the cancer is larger than 4 cm.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000729741" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de cuello uterino en estadios IA1 y IA2; el dibujo muestra un corte transversal del cuello uterino y la vagina. Un recuadro interior muestra un cáncer en el cuello uterino que mide hasta 5 mm en profundidad, pero no más de 7 mm de ancho." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_5"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de cuello uterino en estadios IA1 y IA2. En los tejidos del cuello uterino se encuentra una muy pequeña cantidad de cáncer que solo se puede ver bajo un microscopio. En el estadio IA1, el cáncer no mide más de 3 mm de profundidad y no más de 7 mm de ancho. En el estadio IA2, el cáncer mide más de 3 mm de profundidad, pero no más de 5 mm, y no mide más de 7 mm de ancho.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000729742" type="image/jpeg" alt="Se muestran los estadios IB1 y IB2 del cáncer de cuello uterino en tres cortes transversales del cuello uterino y la vagina. En el recuadro de la izquierda, se muestra un cáncer en estadio IB1 que mide 7 mm de ancho y no más de 5 mm de profundidad. El dibujo del medio muestra un cáncer en estadio IB1 que mide menos de 4 cm. El dibujo de la derecha muestra un cáncer en estadio IB2 que mide más de 4 cm. " language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_6"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de cuello uterino en estadios IB1 y IB2. En el estadio IB1, el cáncer solo se puede observar al microscopio y  mide más de 5 mm de profundidad o mide más de 7 mm de ancho, O se puede ver el cáncer sin un microscopio y mide 4 cm o menos. En el estadio IB2, el cáncer mide más de 4 cm.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de cuello uterino en estadio I</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El cáncer se encuentra solamente en el cuello uterino. El estadio I se divide en los estadios IA y IB según la cantidad de cáncer que se encuentre. En el estadio IA, se encuentra una cantidad muy pequeña de cáncer en los tejidos del cuello uterino que solo se puede ver con un microscopio. El estadio lA se divide en los estadios IA1 y IA2, de acuerdo con el tamaño del tumor. En el estadio IA1, el cáncer no mide más de 3 mm de profundidad y no más de 7 mm de ancho. En el estadio IA2, el cáncer mide más de 3 mm, pero no más de 5 mm de profundidad y no más de 7 mm de ancho. El estadio IB se divide en los estadios IB1 y IB2 según el tamaño del tumor. En el estadio IB1, 1) el cáncer solo se puede ver con un microscopio y mide más de 5 mm de profundidad y más de 7 mm de ancho; o 2) el cáncer se puede ver sin un microscopio y mide 4 cm o menos. En el estadio IB2, el cáncer se puede ver sin un microscopio y mide más de 4 cm.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2015-06-25</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062961">Cervical Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256774">Cáncer de cuello uterino: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
