<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045035"><TermName>port</TermName><TermPronunciation>(port)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A device used to draw blood and give treatments, including intravenous fluids, drugs, or blood transfusions.  The port is placed under the skin, usually in the chest. It is attached to a catheter (a thin, flexible tube) that is guided (threaded) into a large vein above the right side of the heart called the superior vena cava. A port may stay in place for many weeks or months. A needle is inserted through the skin into the port to draw blood or give fluids.   Also called port-a-cath.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000728255" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;port&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000756805" type="image/jpeg" alt="Port-a-cath (Port); drawing showing a port-a-cath under the skin in the right side of the chest. It is attached to a catheter that is threaded into a large vein above the right side of the heart called the superior vena cava. The top left inset shows the port-a-cath under the skin. The bottom right inset shows a needle being inserted into the port-a-cath and blood being drawn from it." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Port-a-cath (Port). A port-a-cath is a device placed under the skin in the right side of the chest. It is attached to a catheter (a thin, flexible tube) that is threaded into a large vein above the right side of the heart called the superior vena cava. A port-a-cath is used to give intravenous fluids, blood transfusions, chemotherapy, and other drugs. It is also used for taking blood samples. A port-a-cath may stay in place for weeks or months and helps avoid the need for repeated needle sticks.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000774008" type="image/jpeg" alt="Catéter implantable (vía); en un dibujo se muestra un catéter implantable debajo de la piel del lado derecho del pecho. Se conecta a un catéter que se  introduce en una vena grande sobre el lado derecho del corazón que se llama vena cava superior. En el recuadro superior izquierdo, se observa el catéter implantable debajo de la piel. En el recuadro del lado inferior derecho, se observa una aguja que se inserta en el catéter implantable y la sangre que se extrae de este." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Catéter implantable (vía). Un catéter implantable es un dispositivo colocado debajo de la piel del lado derecho del pecho. Se conecta a un catéter (tubo delgado y flexible) que se introduce en una vena grande sobre el lado derecho del corazón que se llama vena cava superior. Un catéter implantable se usa para administrar por vía intravenosa líquidos, trasfusiones de sangre, quimioterapia y otros medicamentos. También se usa para tomar muestras de sangre. Un catéter implantable puede permanecer en su lugar durante semanas o meses, y ayuda a evitar la necesidad de pinchazos repetidos de aguja.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>vía de acceso</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Dispositivo implantado por el que puede extraerse sangre e infundir los medicamentos sin pinchazos repetidos de aguja.Dispositivo que se usa para extraer sangre y administrar tratamientos, como líquidos intravenosos, medicamentos o transfusiones de sangre. El conector se coloca debajo de la piel; por lo general, en el pecho. Se une a un catéter (tubo delgado y flexible) que se guía (entreteje) en una vena grande por encima del lado derecho del corazón que se llama vena cava superior. Una vía de acceso se puede dejar en su lugar durante semanas o meses. Se introduce una aguja a traves de la piel hacia el conector para extraer sangre o administrar líquidos. También se llama vía de acceso implantada.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2015-10-12</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
