<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000488416"><TermName>Abraxane</TermName><TermPronunciation>(uh-BRAK-sayn)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat breast cancer that has come back or spread to other parts of the body. It is also used with carboplatin to treat advanced non-small cell lung cancer in patients who are not able to have surgery or radiation therapy. It is also used with gemcitabine hydrochloride to treat pancreatic cancer that has spread to other parts of the body. It is being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Abraxane is a form of the anticancer drug paclitaxel and may cause fewer side effects than paclitaxel. It stops cancer cells from growing and dividing, and may kill them. It is a type of mitotic inhibitor and a type of antimicrotubule agent. Also called ABI-007, nanoparticle paclitaxel, paclitaxel albumin-stabilized nanoparticle formulation,  and protein-bound paclitaxel.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718415" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Abraxane&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718414" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Abraxane&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Abraxane</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para tratar el cáncer de mama que volvió o que se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo. También se usa con carboplatino para tratar el cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio avanzado en pacientes que no se pueden someter a cirugía o radioterapia. Asimismo,  se usa con clorhidrato de gemcitabina para tratar el cáncer de páncreas que se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo. Está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Abraxane es una forma del medicamento contra el cáncer paclitaxel y puede producir menos efectos secundarios que este. Este medicamento impide el crecimiento y la multiplicación de las células cancerosas, y puede destruirlas. Es un tipo de inhibidor mitótico y un tipo de sustancia antimicrotubular. También se llama ABI-007, formulación de nanopartículas de paclitaxel estabilizadas con albúmina, nanopartícula de paclitaxel,  y paclitaxel fijado a una proteína.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2006-09-15</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-09-11</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000495323">Paclitaxel Albumin-stabilized Nanoparticle Formulation</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
