<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000439441"><TermName>opioid growth factor</TermName><TermPronunciation>(OH-pee-OYD grothe FAK-ter)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A substance that relieves pain and is being studied in the treatment of some types of cancer. Opioid growth factors bind to cells in the body, including tumor cells, which have opioid growth factor receptors on the surface. This may help stop the growth of the tumor cells. It may also prevent the growth of blood vessels that tumors need to grow. An opioid growth factor is a type of biological response modifier and a type of antiangiogenesis agent. Also called OGF.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713705" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;opioid growth factor&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713704" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;factor de crecimiento opioide&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>factor de crecimiento opioide</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Sustancia que alivia el dolor y que está en estudio para el tratamiento de algunos tipos de cáncer. El factor de crecimiento opioide se une a las células del cuerpo, incluso a las células tumorales, que tienen receptores del factor de crecimiento opioide en la superficie. Esto podría ayudar a impedir el crecimiento de las células tumorales. También podría prevenir la formación de vasos sanguíneos nuevos que los tumores necesitan para crecer. Un factor de crecimiento opioide es un tipo de modificador de la respuesta biológica y un tipo de antiangiogénico. También se llama FCO.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-07-08</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2009-05-01</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
