<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044806"><TermName>hepatic veno-occlusive disease</TermName><TermPronunciation>(heh-PA-tik VEE-noh-uh-KLOO-siv dih-ZEEZ)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A condition in which some of the veins in the liver are blocked. This causes a decrease in blood flow inside the liver and may lead to liver damage. Signs and symptoms include weight gain, yellowing of the skin and whites of the eyes, dark-colored urine, and increased liver size. It may occur at some point in time after radiation therapy to the liver and bile ducts or after high-dose anticancer drugs were given before a stem cell transplant. Also called sinusoidal obstruction syndrome.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705996" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hepatic veno-occlusive disease&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705995" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;enfermedad veno-oclusiva hepática&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>enfermedad veno-oclusiva hepática</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección que impide el funcionamiento de  algunas venas del hígado. Esto hace que disminuya el flujo de sangre en el hígado y  cause daños. Los signos y síntomas incluyen  aumento de peso y que tanto la piel como el blanco de los ojos se tornen amarillentos, el  color de la orina se torna oscuro y el hígado aumenta de tamaño. Esta se puede presentar en algún momento después de recibir radioterapia dirigida al hígado y a los conductos biliares, o después de recibir dosis altas de medicamentos contra el cáncer administradas antes de un trasplante de células madre. También se llama síndrome de obstrucción sinusoidal.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2012-06-13</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
