<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000492233"><TermName>sunitinib</TermName><TermPronunciation>(soo-NIH-tih-nib)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat certain types of pancreatic cancer. It is also used to treat gastrointestinal stromal tumors (GIST) in some patients and to treat advanced kidney cancer. It is being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Sunitinib stops cancer cells from dividing and may prevent the growth of new blood vessels that tumors need to grow. It is a type of tyrosine kinase inhibitor and a type of angiogenesis inhibitor. Also called SU011248, SU11248, sunitinib malate,  and Sutent.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718251" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sunitinib&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718250" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sunitinib&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>sunitinib</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para
tratar ciertos tipos de tumores de páncreas. También se usa para tratar tumores del estroma gastrointestinal (TEGI) en algunos pacientes y para tratar el cáncer avanzado de riñón. Está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El sunitinib impide que las células cancerosas se multipliquen y podría prevenir la formación de  nuevos vasos sanguíneos que los tumores necesitan para crecer. Es un tipo de
inhibidor de la tirosina cinasa y un tipo
de inhibidor de la angiogénesis.  También se llama malato de sunitinib, SU011248, SU11248,  y Sutent.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2006-06-26</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2011-06-13</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000491976">Sunitinib Malate</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
