<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045220"><TermName>dexrazoxane</TermName><TermPronunciation>(DEX-ruh-ZOK-sane)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The active ingredient in a drug used to treat severe side effects caused by certain anticancer drugs. Under the brand name Totect it is used to treat the toxic effects of an anticancer drug that leaks from a vein into surrounding tissue and causes tissue damage. Under the brand name Zinecard it is used to reduce heart damage in women given doxorubicin for breast cancer that has spread. Dexrazoxane is also being studied in the treatment of cancer. It is a type of cardioprotective agent, a type of chemoprotective agent, and a type of topoisomerase inhibitor.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705166" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;dexrazoxane&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705167" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;dexrazoxano&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>dexrazoxano</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Ingrediente activo de un medicamento que se usa para tratar los efectos tóxicos agudos causados por ciertos fármacos anticancerosos. Bajo la marca comercial Totect, se usa para tratar los efectos tóxicos de un medicamento anticanceroso que se escapa de las venas hacia el tejido cercano, dañando dichos tejidos. Bajo la marca comercial Zinecard, se usa para disminuir el daño al corazón que ocasiona la doxorrubicina que se administra a las mujeres para tratar el cáncer de mama que se ha diseminado. El dexrazoxano también está en estudio para el tratamiento de cáncer. Es un tipo de cardioprotector, quimioprotector, e inhibidor de la topoisomerasa.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2008-06-26</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
