<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046123"><TermName>stage IV vulvar cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... VUL-ver KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The tumor has spread into the upper part of the urethra, the upper part of the vagina, or to other parts of the body. Stage IV is divided into stages IVA and IVB. In stage IVA, (1) cancer has spread into the lining of the upper urethra, the upper vagina, the bladder, or the rectum, or has attached to the pelvic bone; or (2) cancer has spread to nearby lymph nodes and the lymph nodes are not moveable or have formed an ulcer. In stage IVB, cancer has spread to lymph nodes in the pelvis or to other parts of the body.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707710" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IV vulvar cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707711" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de vulva en estadio IV&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de vulva en estadio IV</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El tumor se ha diseminado a la parte superior de la uretra, la parte superior de la vagina  o a otras partes del cuerpo. El estadio lV se divide en estadio lVA y lVB . En el estadio lVA, 1) el cáncer se ha diseminado al revestimiento de la uretra superior, la parte superior de la vagina, la vejiga o el recto, o se ha unido al hueso de la pelvis; o 2) el cáncer se ha diseminado a los ganglios linfáticos cercanos y los ganglios linfáticos no son movibles o han formado una úlcera. En el estadio lVB, el cáncer se ha diseminado a los ganglios linfáticos en la pelvis  o a otras partes del cuerpo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2012-10-23</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000419665">Vulvar Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000452963">Cáncer de vulva: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
