<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045989"><TermName>colposcopy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(kol-POS-koh-pee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure in which a lighted, magnifying instrument called a colposcope is used to examine the cervix, vagina, and vulva. During colposcopy, an instrument called a speculum is inserted into the vagina to widen it so that the cervix can be seen more easily. A vinegar solution may be used to make abnormal tissue easier to see with the colposcope. Tissue samples may be taken using a spoon-shaped instrument called a curette and checked under a microscope for signs of disease. Colposcopy may be used to check for cancers of the cervix, vagina, and vulva, and changes that may lead to cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707549" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;colposcopy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707550" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;colposcopia&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>colposcopia</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento mediante el cual se usa un instrumento con aumento y luz que se llama colposcopio para examinar el cuello uterino, la vagina y la vulva. Durante la colposcopia, se introduce en la vagina un instrumento que se llama espéculo para ensancharla a modo de poder ver el cuello uterino con mayor facilidad.  Es posible el uso de una solución de vinagre para ver con más facilidad el tejido anormal mediante un colposcopio. Se pueden tomar muestras   de tejido con un instrumento en forma de cuchara que se llama cureta y revisarlas bajo el microscopio para determinar si hay signos de enfermedad. La colposcopía se usa para revisar si hay cáncer de cuello uterino, vagina y vulva, y cambios que puedan ocasionar cáncer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2014-01-03</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
