<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000413729"><TermName>polyethylene glycosylated recombinant human megakaryocyte growth and development factor</TermName><TermPronunciation>(PAH-lee-EH-thih-leen gly-KAH-sih-lay-ted ree-KOM-bih-nunt HYOO-mun MEH-guh-KAYR-ee-oh-site …)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A form of megakaryocyte growth and development factor (MGDF) that is made in the laboratory. MGDF comes from the protein thrombopoietin, which is normally made in the body to help make platelets. Polyethylene glycosylated recombinant human megakaryocyte growth and development factor is being studied as a way to increase the number of platelets in patients receiving chemotherapy. Also called PEG-MGDF and PEG-rhMGDF.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713064" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;polyethylene glycosylated recombinant human megakaryocyte growth and development factor&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713063" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;glicosilado de polietileno del factor de crecimiento y desarrollo del megacariocito humano recombinante&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>glicosilado de polietileno del factor de crecimiento y desarrollo del megacariocito humano recombinante</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Forma del factor de crecimiento y desarrollo megacariocítico (MGDF, por sus siglas en inglés) que se produce en el laboratorio. El MGDF proviene de la trombopoyetina proteica, que el cuerpo elabora normalmente para ayudar a producir plaquetas. El glicosilado de polietileno del factor de crecimiento y desarrollo megacariocítico humano recombinante está en estudio como una manera de aumentar el número de plaquetas en los pacientes que reciben quimioterapia. También se llama PEG-MGDF y PEG-rhMGDF.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-03-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2008-02-19</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
