<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045656"><TermName>NCI clinical trials cooperative group</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... KLIH-nih-kul TRY-uls koh-AH-pruh-tiv groop)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A group of researchers, cancer centers, and community doctors who are involved in studies of new cancer treatment, prevention, early detection, quality of life, and rehabilitation. Clinical trials carried out by cooperative groups are sponsored by the National Cancer Institute (NCI), and large numbers of patients take part in many locations. Examples include the Radiation Therapy Oncology Group (RTOG), Gynecologic Oncology Group (GOG), and Children’s Oncology Group (COG).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705741" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;NCI clinical trials cooperative group&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705742" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;grupo cooperativo de ensayos clínicos del NCI&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>grupo cooperativo de ensayos clínicos del NCI</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Grupo de investigadores, centros oncológicos y médicos comunitarios que participan en estudios sobre nuevos tratamientos para el cáncer, su prevención y detección temprana, bienestar general y rehabilitación de los pacientes. Los ensayos clínicos que llevan a cabo los grupos cooperativos son patrocinados por el NCI y en ellos toman parte un gran números de pacientes en diferentes centros. Entre estos grupos tenemos: el <ForeignWord>Radiation Therapy Oncology Group</ForeignWord> (RTOG —Grupo de Radioterapia Oncológica), el <ForeignWord>Gynecologic Oncology Group</ForeignWord> (GOG -Grupo de Oncología Ginecológica) y el <ForeignWord>Children’s Oncology Group</ForeignWord> (COG —Grupo de Oncología Infantil).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2008-01-29</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
