<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000482417"><TermName>ephedra</TermName><TermPronunciation>(eh-FEH-druh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A shrub native to China and India. The stems and roots are used in traditional medicine as a diuretic and for asthma, bronchitis, and cough. It has also been promoted as a decongestant, a weight loss aid, and as a supplement to increase energy. Ephedra may cause high blood pressure, increased heart rate, or death if used with certain drugs, and may reduce the effects of certain drugs used to treat cancer and other diseases. The U.S. Food and Drug Administration has banned the sale of dietary supplements that contain ephedra. The scientific name is <ScientificName>Ephedra sinica</ScientificName>. Also called ma huang.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000716582" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ephedra&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000716583" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;efedra&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>efedra</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Arbusto originario de China e India. Los tallos y las raíces se usan en la medicina tradicional como diurético y para el asma, la bronquitis y la tos. Asimismo, se ha promovido como descongestionante, suplemento para perder peso y suplemento para aumentar la energía. La efedra puede causar presión arterial alta, aumento de la frecuencia cardíaca o muerte si se consume con ciertos medicamentos. A la vez, puede reducir los efectos de ciertos medicamentos usados para tratar el cáncer y otras enfermedades. La Administración de Medicamentos y Alimentos de los Estados Unidos ha prohibido la venta de suplementos dietéticos que contengan efedra. El nombre científico es <ScientificName>Ephedra sinica</ScientificName>. También se llama ma huang.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2006-05-05</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2008-01-16</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
