<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000426416"><TermName>lobular carcinoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(LAH-byoo-ler KAR-sih-NOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cancer that begins in the lobules  (milk glands) of the breast. Lobular carcinoma may be either lobular carcinoma in situ (LCIS) or invasive lobular carcinoma. LCIS is a noninvasive condition in which abnormal cells are found in the lobules of the breast. LCIS rarely becomes invasive cancer, but having LCIS in one breast increases the risk of developing invasive cancer in either breast. In invasive lobular carcinoma, cancer has spread from the lobules to surrounding normal tissue. It can also spread through the blood and lymph systems to other parts of the body.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713364" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;lobular carcinoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713365" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;carcinoma lobulillar&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>carcinoma lobulillar</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cáncer que empieza en los
lobulillos de la mama (glándulas lácteas). El carcinoma lobulillar puede ser un carcinoma lobulillar in situ (CLIS) o un carcinoma lobulillar invasivo. El CLIS es una afección no invasiva en la que se encuentran células anormales en los lobulillos de la mama. No es frecuente
que el CLIS se convierta en carcinoma lobulillar invasivo, pero
tener un CLIS en una mama aumenta el riesgo de presentar
cáncer invasivo en cualquiera de las mamas. En el carcinoma lobulillar invasivo, el cáncer se diseminó desde los lobulillos hasta el tejido normal circundante. También se puede diseminar hasta otras partes del cuerpo a través de los sistemas sanguíneo y linfático.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-03-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-07-10</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/breast">Breast Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/seno">Cáncer de seno (mama)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
