<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045511"><TermName>stage IV pancreatic cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... PAN-kree-A-tik KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cancer may be of any size and has spread to distant organs, such as the liver, lung, and peritoneal cavity (the body cavity that contains most of the organs in the abdomen), and may have also spread to organs and tissues near the pancreas or to lymph nodes.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705559" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IV pancreatic cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705558" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de páncreas en estadio IV&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000687943" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IV pancreatic cancer; drawing shows cancer has spread beyond the pancreas. Inset shows cancer spreading through the blood and lymph nodes to the lung, liver, peritoneal cavity, and other parts of the body." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Stage IV pancreatic cancer. Cancer may be any size and has spread to distant organs, such as the lung, liver, and peritoneal cavity (the space in the abdomen that contains the intestines, stomach, and liver). Cancer may also have spread to tissue and organs near the pancreas or to lymph nodes.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000743867" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de páncreas en estadio lV;  el dibujo muestra que el cáncer se diseminó más allá del páncreas. El recuadro muestra el cáncer que se disemina a través de la sangre y los ganglios linfáticos hacia los pulmones, el hígado, la cavidad peritoneal y otras partes del cuerpo." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de páncreas en estadio lV. El cáncer mide cualquier tamaño y se diseminó a órganos distantes como los pulmones, el hígado y la cavidad peritoneal (el espacio en el abdomen que contiene los intestinos, el estómago y el  hígado). El cáncer también se pudo haber diseminado a los tejidos y órganos cerca del páncreas o los ganglios linfáticos.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de páncreas en estadio IV</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El cáncer puede ser de cualquier tamaño y se ha diseminado hasta órganos alejados, como el hígado y la cavidad peritoneal (la cavidad del cuerpo que contiene la mayoría de los órganos del abdomen), y puede haberse diseminado hasta los órganos y tejidos cercanos al páncreas o hasta los ganglios linfáticos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2013-01-23</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
