<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046729"><TermName>stage IV malignant mesothelioma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(...muh-LIG-nunt MEH-zoh-THEE-lee-OH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cancer cannot be removed by surgery and is found in one or both sides of the body. Cancer may have spread to lymph nodes anywhere in the chest or above the collarbone. Cancer has spread in one or more of the following ways: (1) through the diaphragm into the peritoneum (the thin layer of tissue that lines the abdomen and covers most of the organs in the abdomen);  (2) to the tissue lining the chest on the opposite side of the body as the tumor; (3) to the chest wall and may be found in the rib; (4) into the organs in the center of the chest cavity; (5) into the spine; (6) into the sac around the heart or into the heart muscle;  and/or (7) to distant parts of the body such as the brain, spine, thyroid, or prostate. </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710003" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IV malignant mesothelioma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710002" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mesotelioma maligno en estadio IV&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>mesotelioma maligno en estadio IV</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El cáncer no se puede extirpar mediante cirugía y se encuentra en uno o ambos lados del cuerpo. El cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta los ganglios linfáticos de cualquier lugar del pecho o encima de la clavícula. El cáncer se diseminó en una o más de las siguientes maneras: 1) a través del diafragma hacia el peritoneo (la capa delgada de tejido que reviste el abdomen y cubre la mayor parte de los órganos del abdomen); 2) el tejido que reviste el pecho en el lado opuesto del cuerpo en el que está el tumor; 3) hasta la pared torácica y se puede encontrar en la costilla; 4) hacia los órganos del centro de la cavidad torácica; 5) hacia la espina vertebral; 6) hacia la bolsa alrededor del corazón o hacia el músculo cardíaco, o 7) partes distantes del cuerpo como el cerebro, la espina vertebral, la tiroides o la próstata.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2011-10-19</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000269299">Malignant Mesothelioma Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000433305">Mesotelioma maligno: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
