<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044392"><TermName>D&amp;C</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure to scrape and remove tissue from the inner lining of the uterus. The cervix is dilated (made larger) and a curette (spoon-shaped instrument) is inserted into the uterus to remove tissue. A tissue sample may then be checked under a microscope for signs of disease, such as infection or cancer. A D&amp;C may also be done after a miscarriage or to treat certain conditions, such as abnormal bleeding.


 Also called dilatation and curettage and dilation and curettage.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000680398" type="image/jpeg" alt="Dilatation and curettage (D and C). Three-panel drawing showing a side view of the female reproductive anatomy during a D and C procedure. The first panel shows a speculum widening the opening of the vagina. The cervix, uterus with abnormal tissue, bladder, and rectum are also shown; an inset shows the lower half of a woman covered by a drape on an exam table with her legs apart  and her feet in stirrups. The middle panel shows the uterus and a dilator inserted through the vagina into the cervix. The third panel shows a curette scraping out abnormal tissue from the uterus; an inset shows a close up of the curette with the abnormal tissue in it." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_5"><Caption language="en">Dilatation and curettage (D and C). A speculum is inserted into the vagina to widen it in order to look at the cervix (first panel). A dilator is used to widen the cervix (middle panel). A curette is put through the cervix into the uterus to scrape out abnormal tissue (last panel).</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000687484" type="image/jpeg" alt="Dilatación y legrado (DyC). El dibujo a tres paneles muestra una vista lateral de la anatomía del aparato reproductor femenino durante un procedimiento de DyC. El primer panel muestra un espéculo que ensancha la abertura de la vagina. También se muestran el cuello uterino, el útero con tejido anormal, la vejiga y el recto; el recuadro muestra la parte inferior de una mujer cubierta por una sábana sobre una camilla con las piernas separadas y sus pies apoyados en los estribos. El panel del medio muestra el útero y un dilatador que se introduce por la vagina hacia el cuello uterino. El tercer panel muestra una cureta que raspa el tejido anormal del útero; el recuadro muestra una ampliación de la cureta con tejido anormal." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Dilatación y legrado (DyC). Se introduce un espéculo en la vagina para ensancharla a fin de observar el cuello uterino (primer panel). Se utiliza un dilatador para ensanchar el cuello uterino (panel del medio). Se introduce una cureta hacia el cuello uterino para raspar tejido anormal (último panel).</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>DyL</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento para raspar y extraer tejido del revestimiento interno del útero. Se dilata el cuello uterino (se agranda) y se introduce una legra (instrumento en forma de cuchara) en el útero para extraer tejido. Se puede revisar una muestra de tejido al microscopio para detectar signos de enfermedad, como una infección o un cáncer. También se puede hacer una DyL después de un aborto espontáneo o para tratar ciertas afecciones, como un sangrado anormal. También se llama dilatación y legrado.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2015-04-21</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
