<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045412"><TermName>stage IIIB breast cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... brest KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage III is divided into stages IIIA, IIIB, and IIIC. In stage IIIB, the tumor may be any size and cancer has spread to the chest wall and/or to the skin of the breast and caused swelling or an ulcer. Also, cancer may have spread to (1) up to 9 axillary lymph nodes; or (2) the lymph nodes near the breastbone. Cancer that has spread to the skin of the breast may also be inflammatory breast cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705432" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IIIB breast cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705433" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de mama en estadio IIIB&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000732260" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIIB breast cancer. The drawing on the left is a cross section of the breast showing  that cancer has spread to the chest wall. The ribs, muscle, and fatty tissue are also shown. The drawing on the right shows the tumor has spread to the skin of the breast. An inset shows inflammatory breast cancer." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Stage IIIB breast cancer. The tumor may be any size and cancer has spread to the chest wall and/or to the skin of the breast and caused swelling or an ulcer. Cancer may have spread to up to 9 axillary lymph nodes or the lymph nodes near the breastbone. Cancer that has spread to the skin of the breast may be inflammatory breast cancer.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000740902" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de mama en estadio lllB. El dibujo de la derecha es una sección transversal de la mama que muestra que el cáncer se diseminó hasta la pared del pecho. También se muestran las costillas, el músculo y el tejido graso. El dibujo de la derecha muestra el tumor que se diseminó hasta la piel de la mama.   En un recuadro se muestra el cáncer de mama inflamatorio." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de mama en estadio lllB. El tumor puede ser de cualquier tamaño y el cáncer se pudo diseminar hasta la pared del pecho o  la piel de la mama y causar hinchazón o una úlcera. El cáncer se pudo diseminar hasta  los ganglios linfáticos de la axila o  los ganglios linfáticos cerca del esternón. El cáncer que se diseminó hasta la piel de la mama puede ser cáncer de mama inflamatorio.  </Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de mama en estadio IIIB</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio III se divide en estadios IIIA, IIIB, IIIC. En
el estadio IIIB, el tumor puede medir  cualquier tamaño y el
cáncer se diseminó hasta la pared del pecho o la piel de
la mama, y causó hinchazón o una úlcera. Además, el cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta 1) un máximo de nueve ganglios linfáticos axilares; o 2) los ganglios linfáticos cerca del esternón. El cáncer que se diseminó hasta la piel de la mama puede ser cáncer de mama inflamatorio.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2012-10-02</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062955">Breast Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256762">Cáncer de seno (mama): Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
