<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045855"><TermName>radioactive iodine</TermName><TermPronunciation>(RAY-dee-oh-AK-tiv I-oh-dine)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A radioactive form of iodine, often used for imaging tests or to treat an overactive thyroid, thyroid cancer, and certain other cancers. For imaging tests, the patient takes a small dose of radioactive iodine that collects in thyroid cells and certain kinds of tumors and can be detected by a scanner. To treat thyroid cancer, the patient takes a large dose of radioactive iodine, which kills thyroid cells. Radioactive iodine is also used in internal radiation therapy for prostate cancer, intraocular (eye) melanoma, and carcinoid tumors. Radioactive iodine is given by mouth as a liquid or in capsules, by infusion, or sealed in seeds, which are placed in or near the tumor to kill cancer cells.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707346" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;radioactive iodine&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707345" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;yodo radiactivo&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>yodo radiactivo</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Forma radiactiva del yodo que se usa a menudo para pruebas de imágenes o para tratar una tiroides demasiado activa, cáncer de tiroides y ciertos cánceres determinados. Para las pruebas de imágenes, el paciente toma una dosis pequeña de yodo radiactivo, que se concentra en las células tiroideas y ciertas clases de tumores, y que puede detectarse con un escáner. Para el tratamiento del cáncer de tiroides, el paciente toma una dosis grande de yodo radiactivo que destruye las células tiroideas. El yodo radiactivo también se usa en la radioterapia interna para el cáncer de próstata, el melanoma intraocular (ojo) y los tumores carcinoides. El yodo radiactivo se administra por boca en forma líquida o en cápsulas, por infusión o en semillas selladas que se colocan en el tumor o cerca de él para que destruya las células cancerosas.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2007-08-20</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
