<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045569"><TermName>gemtuzumab ozogamicin</TermName><TermPronunciation>(gem-TOO-zoo-mab OH-zoh-ga-MIH-sin)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug that was used to treat acute myeloid leukemia (AML) that recurred (came back). It was used in older patients who were not able to take other anticancer drugs. Gemtuzumab ozogamicin was taken off the market but continues to be studied in clinical trials for the treatment of certain types of leukemia. It contains a monoclonal antibody that binds to a protein called CD33, which is found on some leukemia cells. It also contains a toxic substance, which may help kill cancer cells. Gemtuzumab ozogamicin is a type of antibody-drug conjugate. Also called Mylotarg.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705603" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;gemtuzumab ozogamicin&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705604" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ozogamicina gemtuzumab&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>ozogamicina gemtuzumab</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usó para tratar la leucemia mieloide aguda (LMA) que recidivó (volvió). Se usaba para pacientes de edad avanzada que no podían tomar otros medicamentos contra el cáncer.La ozogamicina gemtuzumab se sacó del mercado pero continúa en estudio en ensayos clínicos para el tratamiento de ciertos tipos de leucemia. Contiene un anticuerpo monoclonal que se une a una proteína que se llama CD33, que se encuentra en algunas células leucémicas. También contiene una sustancia tóxica que podría ayudar a destruir células cancerosas. La ozogamicina gemtuzumab es un tipo de conjugado anticuerpo-fármaco. También se llama Mylotarg.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2014-08-13</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000505269">Gemtuzumab Ozogamicin</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
