<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000445089"><TermName>survivorship</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ser-VY-ver-ship)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>In cancer, survivorship focuses on the health and life of a person with cancer post treatment until the end of life.  It covers the physical, psychosocial, and economic issues of cancer, beyond the diagnosis and treatment phases. Survivorship includes issues related to the ability to get health care and follow-up treatment, late effects of treatment, second cancers, and quality of life. Family members, friends, and caregivers are also considered part of the survivorship experience. </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714659" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;survivorship&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714658" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;supervivencia&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>supervivencia</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>En lo referente al  cáncer, la supervivencia se enfoca en la salud y la vida de una persona después del tratamiento de cáncer hasta el final de la vida. Esta  incluye aspectos relacionados con los asuntos físicos, psicosociales y económicos relacionados con el cáncer, más allá de la fase de diagnóstico y tratamiento. La supervivencia incluye asuntos relacionados  con la capacidad de obtener atención de salud y tratamiento de seguimiento, los efectos tardíos del tratamiento, los segundos cánceres y la calidad de vida. Los miembros de la familia, los amigos y las personas que cuidan al enfermo también forman parte del proceso que constituye  la supervivencia.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-10-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2012-06-06</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/coping/survivorship">Survivorship</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/sobrellevar/supervivencia">Supervivencia</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
