<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046171"><TermName>screening</TermName><TermPronunciation>(SKREE-ning)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Clinical evaluation of an asymptomatic individual in the general population aimed at identifying abnormalities which might signal the presence of a specific medical condition. The intent is to find diseases at the earliest possible stage in their development in order to improve the chances for cure or reduce morbidity. </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Checking for disease when there are no symptoms. Since screening may find diseases at an early stage, there may be a better chance of curing the disease. Examples of cancer screening tests are the mammogram (breast), colonoscopy (colon), and the Pap test and HPV test (cervix). Screening can also include checking for a person’s risk of developing an inherited disease by doing a genetic test.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707780" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;screening&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707781" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;examen de detección&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>examen de detección</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Verificación de la presencia de enfermedad cuando no hay síntomas. Debido a que los exámenes de detección pueden encontrar enfermedades que están en un estadio temprano, puede haber una mejor probabilidad de curar la enfermedad. Entre los ejemplos de los exámenes de detección del cáncer están el mamograma (mama), la colonoscopia (colon), y la prueba de PAP y  la prueba del VPH (cuello uterino). La detección también incluye verificar si una persona puede tener riesgo de una enfermedad hereditaria por medio de una prueba genética.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2012-03-27</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/cancertopics/screening">Cancer Screening</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
