<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044236"><TermName>computerized tomography</TermName><TermPronunciation>(kum-PYOO-teh-RIZED toh-MAH-gruh-fee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure that uses a computer linked to an x-ray machine to make a series of detailed pictures of areas inside the body. The pictures are taken from different angles and are used to create 3-dimensional (3-D) views of tissues and organs. A dye may be injected into a vein or swallowed to help the tissues and organs show up more clearly. A computerized tomography may be used to help diagnose disease, plan treatment, or find out how well treatment is working. Also called CAT scan, computed tomography scan, computerized axial tomography scan,  and CT scan.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704337" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;computerized tomography&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704336" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tomografía computarizada&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000428405" type="image/jpeg" alt="Computed tomography (CT) scan of the abdomen; drawing shows the patient on a table that slides through the CT machine, which takes x-ray pictures of the inside of the body." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_5"><Caption language="en">Computed tomography (CT) scan of the abdomen.  The patient lies on a table that slides through the CT machine, which takes x-ray pictures of the inside of the body.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000742472" type="image/jpeg" alt="Tomografía computadorizada (TC) del abdomen; el dibujo muestra al paciente en una camilla que se desliza hacia la máquina de TC, la cual toma radiografías de la parte interior del cuerpo. " language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_6"><Caption language="es">Tomografía computadorizada (TC) del abdomen. El paciente se acuesta en una camilla que se desliza hacia  la máquina de TC, la cual toma radiografías de la parte interior del cuerpo. </Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>tomografía computarizada</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento para el que se usa una computadora conectada a una máquina de rayos X para crear una serie de imágenes detalladas del interior del cuerpo. Las imágenes se toman desde diferentes ángulos y se usan para crear vistas tridimensionales (3D) de los tejidos y órganos. Se puede inyectar un tinte en una vena o ingerirse para que estos tejidos y órganos se destaquen de forma más clara.  Una   se puede usar para diagnosticar una enfermedad, planificar un tratamiento o determinar si el tratamiento es eficaz.  También se llama exploración por TAC, exploración por TC, exploración por tomografía axial computarizada,  y exploración por tomografía computada.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2014-03-21</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/diagnosis-staging/ct-scans-fact-sheet">Computed Tomography (CT) Scans and Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/diagnostico-estadificacion/hoja-informativa-tomografia-computarizada">Tomografía computarizada (TC) y exploraciones para cáncer</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
