<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045357"><TermName>stage IIA non-small cell lung cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... sel lung KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage II non-small cell lung cancer is divided into stages IIA and IIB. In stage IIA, cancer has spread to lymph nodes on the same side of the chest as the tumor. Also, one or more of the following is true: (1) the tumor is not larger than 5 centimeters; (2) cancer has spread to the main bronchus and is at least 2 centimeters below where the trachea joins the bronchus; (3) cancer has spread to the innermost layer of the membrane that covers the lung; and/or (4) part of the lung has collapsed or become inflamed. OR in stage IIA, cancer has not spread to lymph nodes and one or more of the following is true: (1) the tumor is larger than 5 centimeters but not larger than 7 centimeters; (2) cancer has spread to the main bronchus and is at least 2 centimeters below where the trachea joins the bronchus; (3) cancer has spread to the innermost layer of the membrane that covers the lung; and/or (4) part of the lung has collapsed or become inflamed.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705366" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IIA non-small cell lung cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705367" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio IIA&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000520465" type="image/jpeg" alt="Two-panel drawing of stage IIA non-small cell lung cancer. First panel shows cancer (5 cm or less), and cancer in the right main bronchus and lymph nodes; also shown are the trachea, bronchioles, and diaphragm. Second panel shows cancer (more than 5 cm but not more than 7 cm), and cancer in the left main bronchus; also shown are the trachea, lymph nodes, bronchioles, and diaphragm. Insets show cancer that has spread from the lung into the innermost layer of the lung lining; a rib is also shown." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="en">Stage IIA non-small cell lung cancer. Cancer has spread to certain lymph nodes on the same side of the chest as the primary tumor; the cancer is (a) 5 cm or smaller, (b) has spread to the main bronchus, and/or (c) has spread to the innermost layer of the lung lining. OR, cancer has not spread to lymph nodes; the cancer is (d) larger than 5 cm but not larger than 7 cm, (e) has spread to the main bronchus, and/or (f) has spread to the innermost layer of the lung lining. Part of the lung may have collapsed or become inflamed (not shown).</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000537558" type="image/jpeg" alt="Dibujo en dos paneles del cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio IIA.  El primer panel muestra  cáncer (5 cm o menos), y cáncer en el bronquio principal derecho y los ganglios linfáticos; también se muestran la tráquea, los bronquiolos y el diafragma. El segundo panel muestra  cáncer  (más de 5 cm, pero no más de 7 cm), y cáncer en el bronquio principal izquierdo; también se muestran la tráquea, los ganglios linfáticos, los bronquiolos y el diafragma. Un recuadro muestra el cáncer que se diseminó desde el pulmón hasta la capa más interna del revestimiento del pulmón; asimismo, se muestra una costilla." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_5"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio IIA. El cáncer se  diseminó hasta ciertos ganglios linfáticos del mismo lado del pecho en que está el cáncer como el tumor principal; el cancer a) mide 5 cm o menos, b) se diseminó hasta el bronquio principal o c) se diseminó hasta la capa más interna del revestimiento del pulmón. O, el cáncer  no se diseminó hasta los ganglios linfáticos; el cáncer  d) mide más de 5 cm, pero no más de 7 cm, e) se diseminó hasta el bronquip principal, o f) se diseminó hasta la capa más interna del revestimiento del pulmón.  Una parte del pulmón se puede haber hundido o inflamado (no se muestra).</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio IIA</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio II se divide en estadios IIA y IIB. En el estadio IIA, el cáncer se diseminó hasta los ganglios linfáticos del mismo lado del pecho donde está el tumor. Además, se presentan una o más de las siguientes situaciones: 1) el tumor no mide más de cinco centímetros; 2) el cáncer se diseminó hasta el bronquio principal y está a por lo menos dos centímetros debajo del lugar donde la tráquea se une con el bronquio; 3) el cáncer se diseminó hasta la capa más interna de la membrana que cubre el pulmón, o 4) parte del pulmón se colapsó o se inflamó. O, en el estadio IIA, el cáncer no se diseminó hasta los ganglios linfáticos y se presentan una o más de las siguientes situaciones: 1) el tumor mide más de cinco centímetros, pero no más de siete centímetros; 2) el cáncer se diseminó hasta el bronquio principal y está  por lo menos dos centímetros debajo del lugar donde la tráquea se une con el bronquio; 3) el cáncer se diseminó hasta la capa más interna de la membrana que cubre el pulmón, o 4) parte del pulmón se colapsó o se inflamó.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2010-10-21</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062956">Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer Treatment </RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256766">Cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
