<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044951"><TermName>complementary medicine</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KOM-pleh-MEN-tuh-ree MEH-dih-sin)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Treatments that are used along with standard treatments, but are not considered standard. Standard treatments are based on the results of scientific research and are currently accepted and widely used. Less research has been done for most types of complementary medicine. Complementary medicine includes acupuncture, dietary supplements, massage therapy, hypnosis, and meditation. For example, acupuncture may be used with certain drugs to help lessen cancer pain or nausea and vomiting.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000706190" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;complementary medicine&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000706191" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;medicina complementaria&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>medicina complementaria</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tratamientos que se usan junto con tratamientos estándares, pero que no se consideran estándar. Los tratamientos estándar se basan en la investigación científica y en el presente se aceptan y son ampliamente utilizados. Para la mayoría de los tipos de medicina complementaria se realizaron menos investigaciones. La medicina complementaria incluye acupuntura, terapia de masaje, hipnosis y meditación. Por ejemplo, se puede usar acupuntura junto con ciertos medicamentos para ayudar a reducir el dolor que causa el cáncer, o las náuseas y vómitos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2012-08-14</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/cam">Complementary and Alternative Medicine </RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/mca">Medicina complementaria y alternativa</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
