<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046046"><TermName>raloxifene</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ra-LOK-sih-feen)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The active ingredient in a drug used to reduce the risk of invasive breast cancer in postmenopausal women who are at high risk of the disease or who have osteoporosis. It is also used to prevent and treat osteoporosis in postmenopausal women. It is also being studied in the prevention of breast cancer in certain  premenopausal women and in the prevention and treatment of other conditions. Raloxifene blocks the effects of the hormone estrogen in the breast and increases the amount of calcium in bone. It is a type of selective estrogen receptor modulator (SERM).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708064" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;raloxifene&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000708063" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;raloxifeno&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>raloxifeno</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Ingrediente activo de un medicamento que se usa para reducir el riesgo de cáncer de mama invasor en las mujeres posmenopáusicas que corren un riesgo alto de contraer la enfermedad o que padecen de osteoporosis.  También se usa para prevenir y tratar la osteoporosis en las mujeres posmenopáusicas. Asimismo, se usa para prevenir el cáncer de mama en ciertas mujeres premenopáusicas, y para prevenir y tratar otras afecciones. El raloxifeno bloquea los efectos de la hormona estrógeno en la mama y aumenta la cantidad de calcio en los huesos. Es un tipo de modulador selectivo del receptor de estrógeno (MSRE).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2009-04-10</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000557341">Raloxifene Hydrochloride</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
