<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044441"><TermName>nicotinamide</TermName><TermPronunciation>(NIH-koh-TIH-nuh-MIDE)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A form of niacin (vitamin B3) that the body needs in small amounts to function and stay healthy. Nicotinamide is found in many plant and animal products and in dietary supplements. It is water-soluble (can dissolve in water) and must be taken in every day. Nicotinamide may be used to treat diabetes and certain skin conditions and is being studied in the treatment of some types of cancer. It may increase blood flow to cancer cells and block certain enzymes they need to repair damage to their DNA. This may make cancer cells easier to kill with radiation therapy and chemotherapy. Nicotinamide is a type of radiosensitizing agent and a type of chemosensitizing agent. Also called niacinamide.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704600" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;nicotinamide&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704599" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;nicotinamida&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>nicotinamida</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Una forma de niacina (vitamina B3) que el cuerpo necesita en cantidades pequeñas para funcionar y estar sano. La nicotinamida se encuentra en muchos productos derivados de plantas y animales y en complementos alimentarios. Es soluble en el agua (se puede disolver en el agua) y se debe tomar todos los días. La nicotinamida se puede usar para tratar la diabetes y algunas afecciones de la piel, y está en estudio para el tratamiento de algunos tipos de cáncer. Puede aumentar el flujo sanguíneo a las células cancerosas e impedir la acción de ciertas enzimas que estas necesitan para reparar el daño al ADN. Esto puede facilitar la destrucción de las células cancerosas con radiación o quimioterapia. La nicotinamida es un tipo de radiosensibilizador y un tipo de quimiosensibilizador. También se llama niacinamida.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2013-04-15</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
