<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000460214"><TermName>risk assessment</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… uh-SES-ment)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The quantitative or qualitative assessment of an individual’s risk of carrying a certain gene mutation, or developing a particular disorder, or of having a child with a certain disorder; sometimes done by using mathematical or statistical models incorporating such factors as personal health history, family medical history and ethnic background.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A process used to estimate the risk that a certain event will happen. In medicine, this may include a person’s risk of having a child with a certain condition or disease, such as cancer.  It may also be used to estimate the risk of carrying a certain gene mutation (change), or of having an adverse event (unexpected medical problem) in response to certain types of drugs or other substances. A risk assessment may be done  by collecting information about a person’s age, sex, personal and family medical history, ethnic background, lifestyle, and other factors and using statistics tools to calculate risk.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000736986" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;risk assessment&quot;" language="en" id="_2"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000767708" type="audio/mpeg" alt="" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>evaluación de riesgo</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Proceso que se usa para calcular el riesgo de que se presenten deteminados episodios. En medicina, esto puede incluir el riesgo de una persona de tener un hijo con ciertas afecciones o enfermedades, como cáncer. También se puede usar para calcular el riesgo de que una persona porte cierta mutación (cambio) en un  gen o presente un episodio adverso (problema médico inesperado) en respuesta a ciertos tipos de medicamentos u otras sustancias. Se puede realizar una evaluación de riesgo al reunir información de la persona sobre su  edad, sexo, antecedentes médicos personales o familiares, antecedentes étnicos, estilo de vida y otros factores, y al usar herramientas estadísticas de cálculo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-12-22</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/risk">Risk Factors for Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/riesgo">Factores de riesgo del cáncer</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
