<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046764"><TermName>folate</TermName><TermPronunciation>(FOH-layt)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A nutrient in the vitamin B complex that the body needs in small amounts to function and stay healthy. Folate helps to make red blood cells. It is found in whole-grain breads and cereals, liver, green vegetables, orange juice, lentils, beans, and yeast. Folate is water-soluble (can dissolve in water) and must be taken in every day. Not enough folate can cause anemia (a condition in which the number of red blood cells is below normal), diseases of the heart and blood vessels, and defects in the brain and spinal cord in a fetus. Folate is being studied with vitamin B12 in the prevention and treatment of cancer. Also called folic acid.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710046" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;folate&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000710045" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;folato&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>folato</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Nutriente del complejo de la vitamina B que el cuerpo necesita en pequeñas cantidades para funcionar y mantenerse sano. El folato ayuda a elaborar glóbulos rojos. Se encuentra en los panes integrales y los cereales, el hígado, las verduras, el jugo de naranja, las lentejas, los frijoles y la levadura. El folato es soluble en agua (puede disolverse en agua) y debe tomarse en todos los días. La insuficiencia de folato puede causar anemia (una afección en la que el número de glóbulos rojos está por debajo de lo normal), enfermedades del corazón y los vasos sanguíneos, y defectos en el cerebro y la médula espinal en el feto. El folato está en estudio con la vitamina B12 para la prevención y el tratamiento del cáncer. También se llama ácido fólico.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2010-05-26</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
