<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000439400"><TermName>coronary artery disease</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KOR-uh-NAYR-ee AR-tuh-ree dih-ZEEZ)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A disease in which there is a narrowing or blockage of the
coronary arteries (blood vessels that carry blood and oxygen to the heart). Coronary artery disease is usually caused by atherosclerosis (a buildup of fatty material and plaque inside the coronary arteries). The disease may cause chest pain, shortness of breath during exercise, and heart attacks. The risk of coronary artery disease is increased by having a family history of coronary artery disease before age 50, older age, smoking tobacco, high blood pressure, high cholesterol, diabetes, lack of exercise, and obesity. Also called CAD and coronary heart disease.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713763" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;coronary artery disease&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713762" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;enfermedad de la arteria coronaria&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>enfermedad de la arteria coronaria</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Enfermedad en la que las arterias coronarias (vasos sanguíneos que llevan sangre y oxígeno al corazón) se estrechan o se impide el flujo de sangre. La causa de la enfermedad de la arteria coronaria es generalmente la ateroesclerosis (una acumulación de materia grasa y placa dentro de las arterias coronarias). La enfermedad puede causar dolor de pecho, dificultad para respirar durante el ejercicio y ataques cardíacos. El riesgo de enfermedad de la arteria coronaria aumenta al tener antecedentes familiares de enfermedad de la arteria coronaria antes de los 50 años de edad, edad avanzada, fumar tabaco, tener hipertensión, colesterol alto, diabetes, falta de ejercicio y obesidad. También se llama EAC y enfermedad coronaria del corazón.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-07-08</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-01-29</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
