<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044964"><TermName>complementary and alternative medicine</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KOM-pleh-MEN-tuh-ree... all-TER-nuh-tiv MEH-dih-sin)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Forms of treatment that are used in addition to (complementary) or instead of (alternative) standard treatments. These practices generally are not considered standard medical approaches. Standard treatments go through a long and careful research process to prove they are safe and effective, but less is known about most types of complementary and alternative medicine. Complementary and alternative medicine may include dietary supplements, megadose vitamins, herbal preparations, special teas, acupuncture, massage therapy, magnet therapy, spiritual healing, and meditation. Also called CAM.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000706212" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;complementary and alternative medicine&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000706213" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;medicina complementaria y alternativa&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>medicina complementaria y alternativa</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Formas de tratamiento que se usan además de (complementaria) o en vez de (alternativa) los tratamientos estándares. Estas prácticas en general no se consideran enfoques médicos estándares. Los tratamientos estándares pasan por un proceso de investigación largo y cuidadoso para comprobar que son seguros y eficaces, pero no se sabe mucho de la mayor parte de tipos de medicina complementaria y alternativa. La medicina complementaria y alternativa puede incluir tomar suplementos alimentarios, megadosis de vitaminas, preparados de hierbas, tés especiales, acupuntura, terapia de masaje, terapia con imanes, curación espiritual y meditación. También se llama MCA.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2013-11-13</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/cam">Complementary and Alternative Medicine </RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/tratamiento/mca">Medicina complementaria y alternativa</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
