<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000450134"><TermName>stage IVB maxillary sinus cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(...MAK-sih-LAYR-ee SY-nus KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage IV maxillary sinus cancer is divided into stages IVA, IVB, and IVC. In stage IVB, cancer (1) has spread to any of the following: the back of the eye, brain, middle parts of the skull, nerves in the head that go to the brain, upper part of the throat behind the nose, and/or the base of the skull, and cancer may be found in one or more lymph nodes of any size, anywhere in the neck; or (2) is found in a lymph node larger than 6 centimeters. Cancer may also be found anywhere in or near the maxillary sinus.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714901" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IVB maxillary sinus cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714902" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de seno maxilar en estadio IVB&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de seno maxilar en estadio IVB</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio IV del cáncer de seno maxilar se divide en los estadios IVA, IVB y IVC. En el estadio IVB, el cáncer 1) se diseminó hasta cualquiera de los siguientes sitios: la parte de atrás del ojo, el cerebro, las partes medias del cráneo, los nervios de la cabeza que van hasta el cerebro, la parte superior de la garganta detrás de la nariz o la base del cráneo; el cáncer se puede encontrar en uno o más ganglios linfáticos de cualquier tamaño en cualquier lugar del cuello. O 2) el cáncer se encuentra en un ganglio linfático que mide más de seis centímetros. El cáncer también se puede encontrar en cualquier lugar del seno maxilar o cerca de este.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2011-02-15</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258028">Paranasal Sinus and Nasal Cavity Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000558933">Cáncer de seno paranasal y de cavidad nasal:  Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
