<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000430864"><TermName>intraductal papilloma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(IN-truh-DUK-tul PA-pih-LOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A benign (not cancer), wart-like growth in a milk duct of the breast. It is usually found close to the nipple and may cause a discharge from the nipple. It may also cause pain and a lump in the breast that can be felt. It usually affects women aged 35-55 years. Having a single papilloma does not increase the risk of breast cancer.  When there are multiple intraductal papillomas, they are usually found farther from the nipple. There may not be a nipple discharge and the papillomas may not be felt.   Having multiple intraductal papillomas may increase the risk of breast cancer.  Also called intraductal breast papilloma.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713670" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;intraductal papilloma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713669" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;papiloma intraductal&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>papiloma intraductal</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Crecimiento benigno (no canceroso), similar a las verrugas, en un conducto lácteo de la mama. Por lo general, se encuentra cerca del pezón y puede producir una secreción del pezón. También puede causar dolor y un nódulo en la mama que se puede palpar. Habitualmente afecta a las mujeres de 35 a 55 años de edad. Tener un solo papiloma por lo general no aumenta el riesgo de contraer cáncer. Cuando se presentan múltiples papilomas intraductales, por lo general lejos del pezón, puede no haber secreción y estos podrían no ser palpables. Tener papilomas intraductales puede aumentar el riesgo de contraer cáncer de mama. También se llama papiloma intraductal de la mama.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-05-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2009-04-10</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
