<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000410401"><TermName>LSIL</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Slightly abnormal cells are found on the surface of the cervix. LSIL is caused by certain types of human papillomavirus (HPV) and is a common abnormal finding on a Pap test. It usually goes away on its own without treatment but sometimes the abnormal cells become cancer and spread to nearby normal tissue. LSIL is sometimes called mild dysplasia. Also called low-grade squamous intraepithelial lesion.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752234" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cervical changes; drawing shows a cross-section of the uterus, cervix, and vagina. Also shown are four panels showing cell changes inside the cervix. The first panel shows normal cells. The second and third panels show abnormal cells called LSIL and HSIL. The fourth panel shows cervical cancer cells. Arrows are used between the panels to show that normal cells may become LSIL or HSIL, which may or may not become cancer." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Cervical changes. The cervix is the lower, narrow end of the uterus that forms a canal between the uterus and vagina.  Before cancer cells form in tissues of the cervix, the cells of the cervix go through abnormal changes called dysplasia. There are different types of dysplasia. Mild dysplasia, called low-grade intraepithelial lesion   (LSIL) is one type. Moderate or severe dysplasia, called high-grade intraepithelial lesion   (HSIL) is another type of dysplasia. LSIL and HSIL may or may not become cancer. </Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000763655" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cambios en el cuello uterino; en la ilustración se muestra un corte trasversal del útero, el cuello uterino y la vagina. También se muestran cuatro paneles con cambios celulares dentro del cuello uterino. En el primer panel, se muestran las células normales; en el segundo y el tercero, se muestran las células anormales que se llaman LSIL y HSIL y en el cuarto, se muestran las células cancerosas en el cuello uterino. Se usan flechas entre los paneles para indicar que las células normales se pueden convertir en LSIL o HSIL que, a su vez, se pueden convertir o no en cáncer." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>LSIL</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Se encuentran células ligeramente anormales en la superficie del cuello uterino. La LSIL es causada por ciertos tipos de virus del papiloma humano (VPH)  y es un hallazgo anormal común en la prueba de Pap. Con frecuencia, desaparece por sí sola sin necesidad de tratamiento pero, algunas veces, las células anormales se vuelven cancerosas y se diseminan al tejido normal cercano. La LSIL se llama,  a menudo, displasia leve. También se llama lesión escamosa intraepitelial de grado bajo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2004-12-22</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2014-11-26</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
