<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000444967"><TermName>B-cell lymphoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(…lim-FOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of cancer that forms in B cells (a type of immune system cell). B-cell lymphomas may be either indolent (slow-growing) or aggressive (fast-growing). Most B-cell lymphomas are non-Hodgkin lymphomas.  There are many different types of B-cell non-Hodgkin lymphomas. These include Burkitt lymphoma, chronic lymphocytic leukemia/small lymphocytic lymphoma (CLL/SLL), diffuse large B-cell lymphoma, follicular lymphoma, and mantle cell lymphoma. Prognosis and treatment depend on type and stage of the cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714533" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;B-cell lymphoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000714532" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;linfoma de células B&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>linfoma de células B</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de cáncer que se forma en las células B (un tipo de células del sistema inmunitario). Los linfomas de células B pueden ser indolentes (de crecimiento lento) o dinámicos (de crecimiento rápido). La mayoría de los linfomas de células B son linfomas no Hodgkin. Hay muchos tipos diferentes de linfomas no Hodgkin de células B. Ellos son el linfoma de Burkitt, la leucemia linfocítica crónica y linfoma linfocítico pequeño (LLC y LLP), el linfomade células B grandes difuso, el linfoma folicular y el linfoma de células del manto. El pronóstico y el tratamiento dependen del tipo y estadio del cáncer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-10-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-06-24</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/lymphoma">Lymphoma</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/linfoma">Linfoma</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
