<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045218"><TermName>hyperbaric oxygen</TermName><TermPronunciation>(HY-per-BAYR-ik OK-sih-jen)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Oxygen that is given at a pressure that is higher than the pressure of the atmosphere at sea level. In medicine, breathing hyperbaric oxygen increases the amount of oxygen in the body. It is used in treating certain kinds of wounds, injuries, and infections.  It is also used to treat carbon monoxide poisoning and other conditions in which the tissues are not getting enough oxygen. It is being studied in the treatment of some types of cancer. Hyperbaric oxygen may increase the amount of oxygen in cancer cells, which may make them easier to kill with radiation therapy and chemotherapy. It is a type of radiosensitizing agent and a type of chemosensitizing agent.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705164" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hyperbaric oxygen&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705165" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;oxígeno hiperbárico&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>oxígeno hiperbárico</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Oxígeno que se administra a una presión más alta que la de la atmósfera al nivel del mar. En medicina,  respirar con oxígeno hiperbárico aumenta la cantidad de oxígeno en el cuerpo. Se usa para el tratamiento de ciertos tipos de lesiones, heridas e infecciones. También se usa para tratar la intoxicación por monóxido de carbono y otras afecciones en las que los tejidos no reciben suficiente oxígeno. Se encuentra en estudio para el tratamiento de algunos tipos de cáncer. El oxígeno hiperbárico puede aumentar la cantidad de oxígeno en las células cancerosas, lo que permite facilitar su destrucción con radioterapia o quimioterapia. Es un tipo de radiosensibilizador y un tipo de quimiosensibilizador.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2013-04-01</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
