<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044904"><TermName>neuroendocrine tumor</TermName><TermPronunciation>(NOOR-oh-EN-doh-krin TOO-mer)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A tumor that forms from cells that release hormones into the blood in response to a signal from the nervous system. Neuroendocrine tumors may make higher-than-normal amounts of hormones, which can cause many different symptoms. These tumors may be benign (not cancer) or malignant (cancer). Some examples of neuroendocrine tumors are carcinoid tumors, islet cell tumors, medullary thyroid cancer, pheochromocytomas, neuroendocrine carcinoma of the skin (Merkel cell cancer), small cell lung cancer, and large cell neuroendocrine carcinoma (a rare type of lung cancer).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000706117" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;neuroendocrine tumor&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000706118" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tumor neuroendocrino&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>tumor neuroendocrino</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tumor que se forma en las células que liberan hormonas a la sangre como respuesta a una señal del sistema nervioso. Los tumores neuroendocrinos podrían elaborar cantidades de hormonas más altas de  lo normal, lo que puede ocasionar síntomas diferentes. Estos tumores pueden ser benignos (no cancerosos) o malignos (cancerosos). Algunos ejemplos de tumores neuroendocrinos son los tumores carcinoides, los  tumores de células de los islotes, el cáncer tiroideo medular, los feocromocitomas, el carcinoma neuroendocrino de la piel (cáncer de células de Merkel), el cáncer de pulmón de células pequeñas y el carcinoma neuroendocrino de células grandes (un tipo poco frecuente de cáncer de pulmón).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2013-04-25</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
