<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045887"><TermName>stage II cervical cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... SER-vih-kul KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cancer has spread beyond the uterus but not onto the pelvic wall (the tissues that line the part of the body between the hips) or to the lower third of the vagina. Stage II is divided into stages IIA and IIB, based on how far the cancer has spread. In stage IIA, cancer has spread beyond the cervix to the upper two thirds of the vagina but not to tissues around the uterus. Stage IIA is divided into stages IIA1 and IIA2, based on the size of the tumor. In stage IIA1, the tumor can be seen without a microscope and is not more than 4 centimeters. In stage IIA2, the tumor can be seen without a microscope and is more than 4 centimeters. In stage IIB, cancer has spread beyond the cervix to the tissues around the uterus but not onto the pelvic wall.   </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707389" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage II cervical cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000707390" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de cuello uterino en estadio II&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000658904" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage II cervical cancer; drawing shows a cross-section of the uterus, cervix and vagina. In stages IIA1 and IIA2, cancer that is 4 cm is shown in the cervix and in the upper third of the vagina. In stage IIB, cancer is shown in the cervix, the upper two thirds of the vagina, and in the tissues around the uterus." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Stage II cervical cancer. Cancer has spread beyond the cervix but not to the pelvic wall or to the lower third of the vagina. In stages IIA1 and IIA2, cancer has spread beyond the cervix to the vagina. In stage IIA1, the tumor can be seen without a microscope and is 4 centimeters or smaller. In stage IIA2, the tumor can be seen without a microscope and is larger than 4 centimeters. In stage IIB, cancer has spread beyond the cervix to the tissues around the uterus.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000729743" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de cuello uterino en estadio II; el dibujo muestra un corte transversal del útero, el cuello uterino y la vagina. En los estadios IIA1 y IIA2, se ve el cáncer que mide 4 cm en el cuello uterino y en el tercio superior de la vagina. En el estadio IIB, se ve el cáncer en el cuello uterino, los dos tercios superiores de la vagina y los tejidos que rodean el útero." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de cuello uterino en estadio II. El cáncer se diseminó más allá del cuello uterino, pero no hasta la pared pélvica o el tercio inferior de la vagina. En los estadios IIA1 y IIA2, el cáncer se diseminó más allá del cuello uterino hasta la vagina. En el estadio IIA1, se puede ver el tumor sin un microscopio y el tumor mide cuatro centímetros o menos. En el estadio IIA2, el tumor se puede ver sin un microscopio y mide más de cuatro centímetros. En el estadio IIB, el cáncer se diseminó más allá del cuello uterino hasta los tejidos que rodean el útero.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de cuello uterino en estadio II</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El cáncer se diseminó más allá del cuello uterino, pero no  hasta la pared de la pelvis (los tejidos que revisten la parte del cuerpo entre las caderas) o hasta el tercio inferior de la vagina. El estadio II se divide en los estadios IIA y IIB, de acuerdo con la distancia hasta donde se haya diseminado el cáncer. En el estadio IIA, el cáncer se diseminó más allá del cuello uterino a los dos tercios superiores de la vagina, pero no a los tejidos que rodean el útero. El estadio IIA se divide en estadios IIA1 y IIA2, de acuerdo con el tamaño del tumor. En el estadio IIA1, el tumor se puede ver sin un microscopio y mide 4 cm o menos. En el estadio IIA2, el tumor se puede ver sin un microscopio y mide más de 4 cm. En el estadio IIB, el cáncer se diseminó más allá del cuello uterino a los tejidos que rodean el útero pero no hasta la pared de la pelvis.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2015-06-25</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062961">Cervical Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256762">Cáncer de seno (mama): Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
