<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000044267"><TermName>NCI</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>NCI, part of the National Institutes of Health of the United States Department of Health and Human Services, is the Federal Government's principal agency for cancer research. It conducts, coordinates, and funds cancer research, training, health information dissemination, and other programs with respect to the cause, diagnosis, prevention, and treatment of cancer. Access the NCI Web site at <ExternalRef xref="http://www.cancer.gov">http://www.cancer.gov</ExternalRef>. Also called National Cancer Institute.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000734609" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;NCI&quot;" language="es" id="_3"/><SpanishTermName>NCI</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El NCI, que forma parte de los Institutos Nacionales de Salud del Departamento de Salud y Servicios Humanos de los Estados Unidos de América (<ForeignWord>National Institutes of Health of the United States Department of Health and Human Services</ForeignWord>) es el organismo principal del Gobierno Federal para la investigación del cáncer. El NCI conduce, coordina y financia la investigación en cáncer, la capacitación, la diseminación de información de salud y otros programas relacionados con la causa, el diagnóstico, la prevención y el tratamiento de cáncer. Se puede visitar el portal de Internet del NCI en <ExternalRef xref="http://www.cancer.gov">http://www.cancer.gov</ExternalRef>. También se llama Instituto Nacional del Cáncer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2008-01-10</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/about-nci/overview">NCI Overview</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/instituto/general">Aspectos generales del NCI</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
