<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000045183"><TermName>stage IIIA breast cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... brest KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage III is divided into stages IIIA, IIIB, and IIIC. In stage IIIA, (1) no tumor is found in the breast or the tumor may be any size. Cancer is found in 4 to 9 axillary lymph nodes  or in the lymph nodes near the breastbone (found during imaging tests or a physical exam); or (2) the tumor is larger than 5 centimeters. Small clusters of breast cancer cells (larger than 0.2 millimeter but not larger than 2 millimeters) are found in the lymph nodes; or (3) the tumor is larger than 5 centimeters. Cancer has spread to 1 to 3 axillary lymph nodes or to the lymph nodes near the breastbone (found during a sentinel lymph node biopsy).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705129" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IIIA breast cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000705128" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de mama en estadio IIIA&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000732259" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIIA breast cancer. The drawing on the left shows no tumor in the breast; cancer is found in 8 axillary lymph nodes. The drawing in the middle shows the tumor is larger than 5 cm and small clusters of cancer cells are in the lymph nodes. The drawing on the right shows the tumor is larger than 5 cm and cancer is in 3 axillary lymph nodes." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Stage IIIA breast cancer. No tumor is found in the breast or the tumor may be any size and cancer is found in 4 to 9 axillary lymph nodes or lymph nodes near the breastbone (left panel); OR the tumor is larger than 5 centimeters and small clusters of cancer cells (larger than 0.2 millimeter but not larger than 2 millimeters) are found in the lymph nodes (middle panel); OR the tumor is larger than 5 centimeters and cancer is found in 1 to 3 axillary lymph nodes or lymph nodes near the breastbone (right panel).</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000740901" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de mama en estadio lllA. El dibujo de la izquierda  muestra que no hay tumor en la mama; se encuentra cáncer en 8 ganglios linfáticos de la axila. En el dibujo del medio el tumor mide más de 5 cm y hay pequeños grupos de células cancerosas en los ganglios linfáticos. El dibujo de la derecha muestra el tumor de más de 5 cm y el cáncer está en tres ganglios linfáticos de la axila." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de mama en estadio lllA. No se encuentra tumor en la mama o el tumor puede ser de cualquier tamaño, y el cáncer se encuentra entre 4 a 9 ganglios linfáticos de la axila, o en los ganglios linfáticos cerca del esternón (dibujo de la izquierda); O el tumor mide más de 5 cm y se encuentran pequeños grupos  de células cancerosas (de más de 0,2 mm, pero de no más de 2 mm) en los ganglios linfáticos (dibujo del medio); O el tumor mide más de 5 cm y se encuentra cáncer entre 1 a 3 ganglios linfáticos de la axila, o en los ganglios linfáticos cerca del esternón (dibujo de la derecha).</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de mama en estadio IIIA</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio III se divide en estadios IIIA, IIIB, IIIC. En el estadio IIIA, 1) no se encuentra un tumor en la mama o el tumor puede medir cualquier tamaño. El cáncer se encuentra en 4 a 9 ganglios linfáticos axilares o en los ganglios linfáticos cerca del esternón (se encontraron mediante pruebas de imágenes o un examen físico); o 2) el tumor mide más de cinco centímetros. Se encuentran pequeños racimos de células de cáncer de mama (que miden más de 0,2 milímetros, pero no más de 2 milímetros) en los ganglios linfáticos; o 3) el tumor mide más de cinco centímetros. El cáncer se diseminó en 1 a 3 ganglios linfáticos axilares o hacia los ganglios linfáticos cerca del esternón (lo que se encontró mediante una biopsia de ganglio linfático centinela).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2012-10-02</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062955">Breast Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256762">Cáncer de seno (mama): Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
