<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000046636"><TermName>tumor marker</TermName><TermPronunciation>(TOO-mer MAR-ker)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A substance found in tissue, blood, or other body fluids that may be a sign of cancer or certain benign (noncancerous) conditions. Most tumor markers are made by both normal cells and cancer cells, but they are made in larger amounts by cancer cells. A tumor marker may help to diagnose cancer, plan treatment, or find out how well treatment is working or if cancer has come back. Examples of tumor markers include CA-125 (in ovarian cancer), CA 15-3 (in breast cancer), CEA (in colon cancer), and PSA (in prostate cancer).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000709841" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tumor marker&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000709842" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;marcador tumoral&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>marcador tumoral</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Sustancia que se encuentra en los tejidos, la sangre u otros líquidos del cuerpo; puede ser un signo de cáncer o de ciertos trastornos benignos (no cancerosos). Las células normales y las células cancerosas elaboran la mayoría de los marcadores tumorales, pero las células cancerosas los elaboran en cantidades más grandes. Un marcador tumoral puede ayudar a diagnosticar el cáncer, planificar el tratamiento o determinar si el tratamiento es eficaz o si el cáncer volvió. Entre los ejemplos de marcadores biológicos se encuentra el CA-125 (en el cáncer de ovario), el CA 15-3 (en el cáncer de mama), el CEA (en el cáncer de colon) y el PSA (en el cáncer de próstata).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateLastModified>2012-02-06</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/diagnosis-staging/diagnosis/tumor-markers-fact-sheet">Tumor Markers</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/diagnostico-estadificacion/diagnostico/hoja-informativa-marcadores-de-tumores">Marcadores de tumores</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
