<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000413882"><TermName>stage IIA breast cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... brest KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage II is divided into stages IIA and IIB. In stage IIA, (1) no tumor is found in the breast or the tumor is 2 centimeters or smaller. Cancer (larger than 2 millimeters) is found in 1 to 3 axillary lymph nodes or in the lymph nodes near the breastbone (found during a sentinel lymph node biopsy); or (2) the tumor is larger than 2 centimeters  but not larger than 5 centimeters. Cancer has not spread to the lymph nodes.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713094" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IIA breast cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000713093" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de mama en estadio IIA&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000732257" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIA breast cancer. Drawing on the left shows no tumor in the breast, but cancer is found in 3 axillary lymph nodes. Drawing in the middle shows the tumor size is 2 cm or smaller and cancer is found in 3 axillary lymph nodes. Drawing on the right shows the tumor is larger than 2 cm but not larger than 5 cm and has not spread to the lymph nodes." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Stage IIA breast cancer. No tumor is found in the breast and cancer is found in 1 to 3 axillary lymph nodes  or lymph nodes near the breastbone (left panel); OR the tumor is 2 centimeters or smaller and cancer is found in 1 to 3 axillary lymph nodes or lymph nodes near the breastbone (middle panel); OR the tumor is larger than 2 centimeters but not larger than 5 centimeters and has not spread to the lymph nodes (right panel).</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000740899" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de mama en estadio llA. El dibujo de la izquierda  muestra que no hay tumor en la mama, pero se encuentra cáncer en tres ganglios linfáticos de la axila. El dibujo del medio muestra el tumor que mide 2 cm o menos, y se encuentra cáncer en tres ganglios linfáticos de la axila. El dibujo de la derecha muestra el tumor que mide más de 2 cm, pero no más de 5 cm, y que no se diseminó hasta los ganglios linfáticos." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de mama en estadio llA. No hay un tumor en la mama, pero se encuentra cáncer en 1 a 3 ganglios linfáticos de la axila, o en los ganglios linfáticos cerca del esternón (dibujo de la izquierda); O el tumor mide 2 cm o menos, y se encuentra cáncer en 1 a 3 ganglios linfáticos de la axila o en los ganglios linfáticos cerca del esternón (dibujo del centro); O el tumor mide más de 2 cm, pero menos de 5 cm, y no se diseminó hasta los ganglios linfáticos (dibujo de la derecha).</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de mama en estadio IIA</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio II se divide en  estadios IIA y IIB. En el estadio IIA,1) no se encuentra tumor en la mama o el tumor mide dos centímetros o menos. El cáncer (que mide más de dos milímetros) se encuentra en 1 a 3 ganglios linfáticos axilares o en los ganglios linfáticos cerca del esternón (que se encuentran mediante una biopsia de ganglio linfático centinela); o 2) el tumor mide más de dos centímetros, pero no más de cinco centímetros. El cáncer no se diseminó hasta los ganglios linfáticos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2005-04-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2012-10-02</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062955">Breast Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256762">Cáncer de seno (mama): Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
