<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000560342"><TermName>stage A prostate cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… PROS-tayt KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A prostate cancer stage defined by the Jewett staging system. Stage A prostate cancer is cancer that began in the prostate and is found in the prostate only. It is usually found during surgery for other reasons, such as benign prostatic hyperplasia (a condition in which an overgrowth of prostate tissue occurs). Stage A is divided into stages A1 and A2. In stage A1, the cancer cells do not look very different from normal cells. In stage A2, the cancer cells look more abnormal or are in several areas in the prostate.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720988" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage A prostate cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720989" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de próstata en estadio A&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de próstata en estadio A</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio de un cáncer de próstata se define mediante el sistema de estadificación de Jewett. El cáncer de próstata en estadio A es cáncer que empezó en la próstata y solo está en la próstata. Por lo general, se encuentra durante una cirugía que se realiza por otras razones; por ejemplo, una hiperplasia prostática benigna (una afección en la que hay un crecimiento excesivo de tejido prostático). El estadio A se divide en los estadios A1 y A2. En el estadio A1, el aspecto de las células cancerosas no es muy distinto al de las células normales. En el estadio A2, las células cancerosas tienen aspecto más anormal o están en varias áreas de la próstata.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-07-18</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
