<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000512779"><TermName>vascular endothelial growth factor-antisense oligonucleotide</TermName><TermPronunciation>(VAS-kyoo-ler EN-doh-THEE-lee-ul grothe FAK-ter-AN-tee-sents AH-lih-goh-NOO-klee-oh-tide)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A substance that has been studied in the treatment of cancer. It binds to the RNA for a protein called vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF) that stimulates the growth of new blood vessels. Vascular endothelial growth factor-antisense oligonucleotide blocks the cell’s ability to make VEGF, which may kill tumors that need new blood vessels to grow. It is a type of antisense oligonucleotide and a type of gene expression inhibitor. Also called VEGF-AS.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718277" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;vascular endothelial growth factor-antisense oligonucleotide&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718278" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;oligonucleótido no codificante del factor de crecimiento endotelial vascular&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>oligonucleótido no codificante del factor de crecimiento endotelial vascular</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Sustancia en estudio para el tratamiento de cáncer. Se une al ARN de una proteína que se llama factor de crecimiento endotelial vascular (FCEV) que estimula la formación de vasos sanguíneos nuevos. El oligonucleótido no codificante del factor de crecimiento endotelial vascular impide que las células elaboren el FCEV, lo que puede destruir tumores que necesitan de vasos sanguíneos nuevos para crecer. Es un tipo de oligonucleótido no codificante y un tipo de inhibidor de la expresión génica. También se llama FCEV-NC.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2006-10-14</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2010-01-08</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
