<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000560745"><TermName>lung biopsy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… BY-op-see)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The removal of a small piece of lung tissue to be checked by a pathologist for cancer or other diseases. The tissue may be removed using a bronchoscope (a thin, lighted, tube-like instrument that is inserted through the trachea and into the lung). It may also be removed using a fine needle inserted through the chest wall, by surgery guided by a video camera inserted through the chest wall, or by an open biopsy. In an open biopsy, a doctor makes an incision between the ribs, removes a sample of lung tissue, and closes the wound with stitches.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000721139" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;lung biopsy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000721140" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;biopsia de pulmón&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000531057" type="image/jpeg" alt="Lung biopsy; drawing shows a patient lying on a table that slides through the computed tomography (CT) machine with an x-ray picture of a cross-section of the lung on a monitor above the patient. Drawing also shows a doctor using the x-ray picture to help place the biopsy needle through the chest wall and into the area of abnormal lung tissue. Inset shows a side view of the chest cavity and lungs with the biopsy needle inserted into the area of abnormal tissue." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_2"><Caption language="en">Fine-Needle Aspiration Biopsy of the Lung. The patient lies on a table that slides through the computed tomography (CT) machine, which takes x-ray pictures of the inside of the body. The x-ray pictures help the doctor see where the abnormal tissue is in the lung. A biopsy needle is inserted through the chest wall and into the area of abnormal lung tissue. A small piece of tissue is removed through the needle and checked under the microscope for signs of cancer. </Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000557253" type="image/jpeg" alt="Biopsia de pulmón; el dibujo muestra a un paciente tendido sobre una camilla que se desliza a través de una máquina de tomografía computarizada (TC), y una imagen de una radiografía de un corte transversal del pulmón en un monitor arriba del paciente. El dibujo también muestra a un médico usando la imagen radiográfica para ayudarlo a colocar la aguja de biopsia a través de la pared torácica, hasta el área del tejido anormal del pulmón. El dibujo del recuadro muestra una vista lateral de la cavidad torácica y los pulmones, con la aguja de biopsia insertada en el área de tejido anormal." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Biopsia de pulmón por aspiración con aguja fina. El paciente está tendido en una camilla que se desliza a través de la máquina de tomografía computarizada (TC), que toma radiografías del interior del cuerpo. Las radiografías ayudan al médico a ver dónde está el tejido anormal en el pulmón. Se inserta una aguja de biopsia a través de la pared torácica hasta el área del tejido anormal del pulmón. Se extrae un pedazo pequeño de tejido a través de la aguja y se observa al microscopio para determinar si hay signos de cáncer.  </Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>biopsia de pulmón</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Extracción de un pedazo pequeño de tejido del pulmón para que un patólogo lo observe y determine si hay cáncer u otras enfermedades. El tejido puede extraerse con un broncoscopio (un instrumento delgado, con luz, con forma de tubo, que se inserta a través de la tráquea hasta el pulmón). También puede extraerse mediante una aguja fina insertada a través de la pared torácica, por medio de cirugía guiada por una cámara de video insertada a través de la pared torácica o por una biopsia abierta. En una biopsia abierta, un médico hace una incisión entre las costillas, extrae una muestra de tejido del pulmón y cierra la herida con puntos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-11-06</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
