<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000564157"><TermName>cervical squamous intraepithelial neoplasia 1</TermName><TermPronunciation>(SER-vih-kul SKWAY-mus IN-truh-eh-pih-THEE-lee-ul NEE-oh-PLAY-zhuh ...)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Slightly abnormal cells are found on the surface of the cervix. Cervical squamous intraepithelial neoplasia 1 is usually caused by certain types of human papillomavirus (HPV) and is found when a cervical biopsy is done. Cervical squamous intraepithelial neoplasia 1 is not cancer and usually goes away on its own without treatment. Sometimes it becomes cancer and spreads to nearby normal tissue. Cervical squamous intraepithelial neoplasia 1 is sometimes called low-grade or mild dysplasia. Also called CIN 1.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720814" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cervical squamous intraepithelial neoplasia 1&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720815" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;neoplasia intraepitelial cervical escamosa 1&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>neoplasia intraepitelial cervical escamosa 1</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Se encuentran células levemente anormales en la superficie del cuello uterino. La neoplasia intraepitelial cervical escamosa 1 es causada, a menudo, por ciertos tipos de virus del papiloma humano (VPH) y se encuentra al realizar una biopsia de cuello uterino. La neoplasia intraepitelial cervical escamosa 1 no es cancerosa y, con frecuencia, desaparece por sí sola sin necesidad de tratamiento. Algunas veces se vuelve cancerosa y se disemina al tejido normal cercano. La NIC 1 también se puede llamar displasia leve o de grado bajo. También se llama NIC 1.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-08-21</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2014-08-19</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
