<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000564158"><TermName>cervical squamous intraepithelial neoplasia 2</TermName><TermPronunciation>(SER-vih-kul SKWAY-mus IN-truh-eh-pih-THEE-lee-ul NEE-oh-PLAY-zhuh ...)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Moderately abnormal cells are found on the surface of the cervix. Cervical squamous intraepithelial neoplasia 2 is usually caused by certain types of human papillomavirus (HPV) and is found when a cervical biopsy is done. Cervical squamous intraepithelial neoplasia 2 is not cancer, but may become cancer and spread to nearby normal tissue if not treated. Treatment for cervical squamous intraepithelial neoplasia 2 may include cryotherapy, laser therapy, loop electrosurgical procedure (LEEP), or cone biopsy to remove or destroy the abnormal tissue. Cervical squamous intraepithelial neoplasia 2 is sometimes called high-grade or moderate dysplasia. Also called CIN 2.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720817" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cervical squamous intraepithelial neoplasia 2&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720816" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;neoplasia intraepitelial cervical escamosa 2&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>neoplasia intraepitelial cervical escamosa 2</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Se encuentran células moderadamente anormales en la superficie del cuello uterino. La neoplasia intraepitelial cervical escamosa 2 es causada, a menudo, por ciertos tipos de virus del papiloma humano (VPH) y se encuentra al realizar una biopsia de cuello uterino. La neoplasia intraepitelial cervical escamosa 2 no es cáncer, pero se puede volver cancerosa y diseminar al tejido normal cercano si no se trata. El tratamiento de la neoplasia intraepitelial cervical escamosa 2 puede incluir crioterapia, terapia con láser, procedimiento de escisión electroquirúrgica con asa (PEEA) o biopsia de cono para extraer o destruir el tejido anormal. Algunas veces, la neoplasia intraepitelial cervical escamosa 2 se llama displasia moderada o de grado alto. También se llama NIC 2.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-08-21</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-12-19</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
