<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000570422"><TermName>cervical squamous intraepithelial neoplasia 3</TermName><TermPronunciation>(SER-vih-kul SKWAY-mus IN-truh-eh-pih-THEE-lee-ul NEE-oh-PLAY-zhuh …)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Severely abnormal cells are found on the surface of the cervix. Cervical squamous intraepithelial neoplasia 3 is usually caused by certain types of human papillomavirus (HPV) and is found when a cervical biopsy is done. If not treated, these abnormal cells may become cancer and spread to nearby normal tissue. Treatment for cervical squamous intraepithelial neoplasia 3 may include cryotherapy, laser therapy, loop electrosurgical procedure (LEEP), or cone biopsy to remove or destroy the abnormal tissue. Cervical squamous intraepithelial neoplasia 3 is sometimes called high-grade or severe dysplasia. Also called CIN 3 and stage 0 cervical carcinoma in situ.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720871" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cervical squamous intraepithelial neoplasia 3&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720870" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;neoplasia intraepitelial cervical escamosa 3&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>neoplasia intraepitelial cervical escamosa 3</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Se encuentran células sumamente anormales en la superficie del cuello uterino. Con frecuencia, la neoplasia intraepitelial cervical escamosa 3 es causada  por ciertos tipos de virus del papiloma humano (VPH) y se encuentra al realizar una biopsia de cuello uterino. Si no se tratan, estas células anormales se pueden convertir en cáncer y diseminar  a los tejidos normales cercanos. El tratamiento  de la neoplasia intraepitelial cervical escamosa 3 puede incluir crioterapia, terapia con láser, procedimiento de escisión electroquirúrgica con asa (PEEA) o biopsia de cono para extraer o destruir el tejido anormal. Algunas veces, la neoplasia intraepitelial cervical escamosa 3 se llama displasia grave o de grado alto.  También se llama carcinoma de cuello uterino in situ, estadio 0 y NIC 3.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-09-21</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-12-19</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062961">Cervical Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256774">Cáncer de cuello uterino: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
