<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000572411"><TermName>endoscopic ultrasound-guided fine needle aspiration</TermName><TermPronunciation>(en-doh-SKAH-pik UL-truh-sownd-GY-ded … NEE-dul AS-pih-RAY-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure to take a sample of tissue for examination under a microscope. An endoscope with an ultrasound probe and a biopsy needle at the end is inserted through the mouth into the esophagus. An endoscope is a thin, tube-like instrument that has a light and a lens for viewing. The ultrasound probe is used to bounce high-energy sound waves off internal organs and tissues to make a picture on a monitor. This picture helps the doctor see where to place the biopsy needle. Also called EUS-FNA.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720847" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;endoscopic ultrasound-guided fine needle aspiration&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720846" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;aspiración con aguja fina guiada por ecografía endoscópica&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000466552" type="image/jpeg" alt="Endoscopic ultrasound-guided fine-needle aspiration biopsy; drawing shows an endoscope with an ultrasound probe and biopsy needle inserted through the mouth and into the esophagus. Drawing also shows lymph nodes near the esophagus and cancer in one lung. Inset shows the ultrasound probe locating the lymph nodes with cancer and the biopsy needle removing tissue from one of the lymph nodes near the esophagus.  " language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_2"><Caption language="en">Endoscopic ultrasound-guided fine-needle aspiration biopsy. An endoscope that has an ultrasound probe and a biopsy needle is inserted through the mouth and into the esophagus. The probe bounces sound waves off body tissues to make echoes that form a sonogram (computer picture) of the lymph nodes near the esophagus. The sonogram helps the doctor see where to place the biopsy needle to remove tissue from the lymph nodes.  This tissue is checked under a microscope for signs of cancer. </Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000557564" type="image/jpeg" alt="Biopsia por aspiración con aguja fina guiada por ecografía endoscópica; el dibujo muestra un endoscopio con una sonda ecográfica y una aguja de biopsia insertada a través de la boca hasta el esófago. El dibujo también muestra los ganglios linfáticos cerca del esófago y el cáncer en un pulmón. El recuadro muestra la sonda ecográfica localizando los ganglios linfáticos con cáncer y la aguja de biopsia extrayendo tejido de uno de los ganglios linfáticos cerca del esófago. " language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Biopsia por aspiración con aguja fina guiada por ecografía endoscópica. Se inserta un endoscopio que tiene una sonda ecográfica y una aguja de biopsia a través de la boca hasta el esófago. La sonda hace rebotar ondas de sonido en los tejidos del cuerpo para producir ecos que componen una ecografía (imagen computarizada) de los ganglios linfáticos cercanos al esófago. La ecografía ayuda a que el médico vea dónde ubicar la aguja de biopsia para extraer tejido de los ganglios linfáticos. Este tejido se observa al microscopio para determinar si hay signos de cáncer.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>aspiración con aguja fina guiada por ecografía endoscópica</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento mediante el que se toma una muestra de tejido para examinarla bajo un microscopio. Se inserta por la boca hasta el esófago un endoscopio con una sonda de ecografía y una aguja de biopsia. Un endoscopio es un instrumento delgado con forma de tubo que tiene una luz y una lente para observar. La sonda de ecografía se usa para hacer rebotar ondas de sonido de alta energía contra los órganos y tejidos internos para obtener una imagen en un monitor. La imagen ayuda al médico a ver el lugar donde está la aguja de biopsia. También se llama AAF-EE.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-03-28</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
