<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000560140"><TermName>doxorubicin hydrochloride</TermName><TermPronunciation>(DOK-soh-ROO-bih-sin HY-droh-KLOR-ide)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat many types of cancer, including leukemia, lymphoma, neuroblastoma, sarcoma, Wilms tumor, and cancers of the lung, breast, stomach, ovary, thyroid, and bladder. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer.  Doxorubicin hydrochloride comes from the bacterium <ScientificName>Streptomyces peucetius</ScientificName>. It damages DNA and may kill cancer cells. It is a type of anthracycline antitumor antibiotic. The brand names Adriamycin PFS, Adriamycin RDF, and Rubex have been taken off the market and are no longer available. Also called doxorubicin and hydroxydaunorubicin.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720856" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;doxorubicin hydrochloride&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720857" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;clorhidrato de doxorrubicina&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>clorhidrato de doxorrubicina</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para tratar muchos tipos de cáncer, como la   leucemia, el linfoma, el neuroblastoma, el sarcoma, el tumor de Wilms y cánceres de pulmón, mama, estómago, ovario, tiroides y vejiga. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El clorhidrato de doxorrubicina se elabora con la bacteria <ScientificName>Streptomyces peucetius</ScientificName>. Daña el ADN y puede destruir células cancerosas. Es un tipo de antibiótico antitumoral de antraciclina. Las marcas comerciales Adriamicina PFS, Adriamicina RDF  y Rubex se retiraron del mercado y ya no están disponibles. También se llama doxorrubicina y hidroxidaunorrubicina.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-07-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2014-09-04</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000542867">Doxorubicin Hydrochloride</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
