<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000556406"><TermName>riboflavin</TermName><TermPronunciation>(RY-boh-FLAY-vin)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A nutrient in the vitamin B complex that the body needs in small amounts to function and stay healthy. Riboflavin helps make red blood cells, helps some enzymes work properly, and keeps skin, nails, and hair healthy. It is found in milk, eggs, malted barley, organ meats, yeast, and leafy vegetables. Riboflavin is water-soluble (can dissolve in water) and must be taken in every day. Not enough riboflavin can cause anemia (a low number of red blood cells), mouth sores, and skin problems. Amounts of riboflavin may be higher in the blood of patients with some types of cancer. Also called vitamin B2.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718594" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;riboflavin&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718595" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;riboflavina&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>riboflavina</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Nutriente del complejo de la vitamina B que el cuerpo necesita en pequeñas cantidades para funcionar y mantenerse sano. La riboflavina ayuda a elaborar glóbulos rojos, ayuda a algunas enzimas a funcionar correctamente y mantiene saludables la piel, las uñas y el cabello. Se encuentra en la leche, los huevos, la cebada malteada, las carnes de órganos, la levadura y las verduras de hojas. La riboflavina es soluble en agua (puede disolverse en agua) y debe tomarse todos los días. La insuficiencia de riboflavina puede causar anemia (una afección en la que el número de glóbulos rojos está por debajo de lo normal), heridas en la boca y problemas de la piel. Las cantidades de riboflavina pueden estar elevadas en la sangre de los pacientes de algunos tipos de cáncer.  También se llama vitamin B2.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-12-05</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
