<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000574286"><TermName>nodular lymphocyte-predominant Hodgkin lymphoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(NAH-juh-ler LIM-foh-site-preh-DAH-mih-nunt HOJ-kin lim-FOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare type of Hodgkin lymphoma (a cancer of the immune system). It is marked by the presence of lymphocyte-predominant cells, 
which used to be called popcorn cells. 
These cells are different from the typical Reed-Sternberg cells found in classical Hodgkin lymphoma. Nodular lymphocyte-predominant Hodgkin lymphoma may change into diffuse large B-cell lymphoma. Also called LPHL, lymphocyte-predominant Hodgkin lymphoma,  and NLPHL.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000703938" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;nodular lymphocyte-predominant Hodgkin lymphoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000703937" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;linfoma de Hodgkin con  predominio linfocítico, nodular&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>linfoma de Hodgkin con predominio linfocítico, nodular</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo poco frecuente de linfoma de Hodgkin, (tipo de cáncer del sistema inmunitario). Se caracteriza por la presencia de células con predomino de linfocitos, que antiguamente se llamaban células en forma de palomitas de maíz. Estas células son distintas de la célula de Reed-Sternberg típica que se encuentran en el linfoma de Hodgkin clásico. El linfoma de Hodgkin, predominio linfocítico, nodularse puede convertir en linfoma difuso de células B grandes. También se llama linfoma de Hodgkin con predominio linfocítico, LPHL,  y NLPHL.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-10-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-07-10</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
