<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000539072"><TermName>stage I soft tissue sarcoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(...TIH-shoo sar-KOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage I is divided into stages IA and IB. In stage IA, the tumor is low-grade (likely to grow and spread slowly) and 5 centimeters or smaller. It may be either superficial (in subcutaneous tissue with no spread into connective tissue or muscle below) or deep (in the muscle and may be in connective or subcutaneous tissue).  In stage IB, the tumor is low-grade (likely to grow and spread slowly) and larger than 5 centimeters. It may be either superficial (in subcutaneous tissue with no spread into connective tissue or muscle below) or deep (in the muscle and may be in connective or subcutaneous tissue).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718180" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage I soft tissue sarcoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718179" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sarcoma de tejido blando en estadio I&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>sarcoma de tejido blando en estadio I</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio I se divide en los estadios IA y IB. En el estadio IA, el tumor es de grado bajo (es probable que crezca y se disemine lentamente) y mide cinco centímetros o menos. Puede ser superficial (está en el tejido subcutáneo sin diseminación hacia el tejido conjuntivo   de abajo) o profundo (está en el músculo y puede estar en el tejido conjuntivo o el tejido subcutáneo). En el estadio IB, el tumor es de grado bajo (es probable que crezca y se disemine lentamente) y mide más de cinco centímetros.  Puede ser superficial (está en el tejido subcutáneo sin diseminación hacia el tejido conjuntivo de abajo) o profundo (está en el músculo y puede estar en el tejido conjuntivo o el tejido subcutáneo).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-07-01</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2010-12-17</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
