<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000520510"><TermName>Dukes C colorectal cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(dooks ... KOH-loh-REK-tul KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cancer (1) has spread through the mucosa (innermost layer) of the colon and/or rectal wall to the submucosa (layer of tissue under the mucosa) and may have spread to the muscle layer of the colon and/or rectal wall. Cancer has spread to at least one but not more than 3 nearby lymph nodes, or cancer cells have formed in tissues near the lymph nodes; or cancer has spread through the mucosa of the colon and/or rectal wall to the submucosa. Cancer has spread to at least 4 but not more than 6 nearby lymph nodes. OR, (2) cancer has spread through the muscle layer of the colon and/or rectal wall to the serosa (outermost layer) of the colon and/or rectal wall or has spread through the serosa but not to nearby organs. Cancer has spread to at least one but not more than 3 nearby lymph nodes, or cancer cells have formed in tissues near the lymph nodes; or cancer has spread to the muscle layer of the colon and/or rectal wall or to the serosa of the colon and/or rectal wall. Cancer has spread to at least 4 but not more than 6 nearby lymph nodes; or cancer has spread through the mucosa of the colon and/or rectal wall to the submucosa and may have spread to the muscle layer of the colon and/or rectal wall. Cancer has spread to 7 or more nearby lymph nodes. OR, (3) cancer has spread through the serosa of the colon and/or rectal wall but has not spread to nearby organs. Cancer has spread to at least 4 but not more than 6 nearby lymph nodes; or cancer has spread through the muscle layer of the colon and/or rectal wall to the serosa of the colon and/or rectal wall or has spread through the serosa but has not spread to nearby organs. Cancer has spread to 7 or more nearby lymph nodes; or cancer has spread through the serosa of the colon and/or rectal wall and has spread to nearby organs. Cancer has spread to one or more nearby lymph nodes, or cancer cells have formed in tissues near the lymph nodes. Also called stage III colorectal cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718126" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Dukes C colorectal cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718127" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer colorrectal en estadio C de Dukes&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer colorrectal en estadio C de Dukes</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El cáncer 1) se pudo haber diseminado a través de la mucosa (capa más interna) del colon o la pared rectal hasta la submucosa (capa de tejido bajo la mucosa) y se puede haber diseminado hasta la capa muscular del colon o la pared rectal. El cáncer se diseminó hasta por lo menos uno, pero no más de tres ganglios linfáticos cercanos, o se formaron células cancerosas en los tejidos cerca de los ganglios linfáticos; o el cáncer se diseminó a través de la mucosa del colon o la pared rectal hasta la submucosa. El cáncer se diseminó hasta por lo menos cuatro pero no más de seis ganglios linfáticos cercanos. O, 2) el cáncer se diseminó a través de la capa muscular del colon o pared rectal hasta la serosa (capa más externa) del colon o la pared rectal, o se diseminó a través de la serosa, pero no hasta órganos cercanos. El cáncer se diseminó hasta por lo menos uno, pero no más de tres, ganglios linfáticos cercanos, o se formaron células cancerosas en tejidos cercanos a los ganglios linfáticos; o el cáncer se diseminó hasta la capa muscular del colon o la pared rectal, o hasta la serosa del colon o la pared rectal. El cáncer se diseminó hasta por lo menos cuatro, pero no más de seis, ganglios linfáticos cercanos; o el cáncer se diseminó a través de la mucosa del colon o la pared rectal hasta la submucosa y se puede haber diseminado hasta la capa muscular del colon o la pared rectal. El cáncer se diseminó hasta siete o más ganglios linfáticos cercanos. O, 3) el cáncer se diseminó a través de la serosa del colon o la pared rectal, pero no se diseminó hasta órganos cercanos. El cáncer se diseminó hasta por lo menos cuatro, pero no más de seis, ganglios linfáticos cercanos; o el cáncer se diseminó a través de la capa muscular del colon o la pared rectal hasta la serosa del colon o la pared rectal, o se diseminó a través de la serosa, pero no se diseminó hasta órganos cercanos. El cáncer se diseminó hasta siete o más ganglios linfáticos cercanos; o el cáncer se diseminó a través de la serosa del colon o la pared rectal y se diseminó hasta órganos cercanos. El cáncer se diseminó hasta uno o más ganglios linfáticos cercanos, o se formaron células cancerosas en los tejidos cerca de los ganglios linfáticos. También se llama cáncer colorrectal en estadio III.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2006-11-13</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2015-03-11</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
