<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000523459"><TermName>extrahepatic bile duct cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(EK-struh-heh-PA-tik bile dukt KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare cancer that forms in the bile ducts outside the liver. A bile duct is a tube that carries bile (fluid made by the liver) between the liver and gallbladder and the small intestine. Cancer that forms in the area where the right and left bile ducts meet outside the liver is called Klatskin tumor. It is the most common type of bile duct cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718519" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;extrahepatic bile duct cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718520" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de las vías biliares extrahepáticas&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000659742" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomy of the extrahepatic bile ducts; drawing shows the liver, right and left hepatic ducts, gallbladder, cystic duct, common hepatic duct (hilum region), common bile duct (distal region), extrahepatic bile duct, pancreas, and small intestine. An inset shows the liver, bile ducts, and gallbladder." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Anatomy of the extrahepatic bile ducts. Extrahepatic bile ducts are small tubes that carry bile outside of the liver.  They are made up of the common hepatic duct (hilum region) and the common bile duct (distal region). Bile is made in the liver and flows through the common hepatic duct and the cystic duct to the gallbladder, where it is stored. Bile is released from the gallbladder  when food is being digested.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000668855" type="image/jpeg" alt="Anatomía de la vía biliare extrahepática; el dibujo muestra el hígado, los conductos hepáticos derecho e izquierdo, la vesícula biliar, el conducto cístico, el conducto hepático común (región del hilio), el conducto colédoco (región distal), la vía biliar extrahepática, el páncreas y el intestino delgado. El recuadro muestra el hígado, ls conductos biliaresy  la vesícula biliar." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Anatomía de la vía biliar extrahepática. Los conductos biliares extrahepáticos son tubos pequeños que llevan bilis por fuera del hígado. Están formados por el conducto hepático común (región del hilio) y el conducto colédoco (región distal). El hígado produce bilis y esta fluye a través del conducto hepático común y el conducto cístico hasta la vesícula biliar, donde se almacena. La vesícula biliar libera la bilis cuando se digieren alimentos.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de las vías biliares extrahepáticas</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cáncer poco frecuente que se forma en las vías biliares  (conductos biliares) fuera del hígado. Los conductos biliares son tubos que transportan la bilis (líquido elaborado por el hígado) entre el hígado,  la vesícula biliar y el intestino delgado. El cáncer que se forma en la área donde los conductos biliares hepáticos derecho e izquierdo se unen fuera del hígado se llama tumor de Klatskin. Es el tipo más común de cáncer de conducto biliar.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-01-16</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2015-06-12</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/liver">Liver and Bile Duct Cancer </RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/higado">Cáncer de hígado y de conducto biliar</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
