<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000560139"><TermName>LipoDox</TermName><TermPronunciation>(LY-poh-DOX)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A form of the anticancer drug doxorubicin that is contained in very tiny, fat-like particles. It may have fewer side effects and work better than doxorubicin. LipoDox is used to treat ovarian cancer, AIDS-related Kaposi sarcoma, and multiple myeloma in patients whose disease has not gotten better after treatment with other anticancer drugs. It may be used together with other anticancer drugs. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. LipoDox is a type of anthracycline antitumor antibiotic. Also called Dox-SL, Doxil, doxorubicin hydrochloride liposome, Evacet,  and liposomal doxorubicin hydrochloride.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000732912" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;LipoDox&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000732911" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;LipoDox&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>LipoDox</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Forma de doxorrubicina, un medicamento contra el cáncer, que está contenida en partículas diminutas semejantes a la grasa. Puede tener menos efectos secundarios y ser más eficaz que la doxorrubicina. LipoDox se usa para tratar el cáncer de ovarios, el sarcoma de Kaposi relacionado con el SIDA y el mieloma múltiple en pacientes cuya enfermedad no ha mejorado después del tratamiento con otros medicamentos contra el cáncer. Se puede usar junto con otros medicamentos contra el cáncer. Asimismo, está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. LipoDox es un tipo de antibiótico antitumoral de antraciclina. También se llama clorhidrato de doxorrubicina liposomal, Dox-SL, Doxil, Evacet,  y liposoma de clorhidrato de doxorrubicina.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-07-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2007-12-03</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000544235">Doxorubicin Hydrochloride Liposome</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
