<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000512921"><TermName>stage II Merkel cell carcinoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(stayj ... MER-kul sel KAR-sih-NOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage II Merkel cell carcinoma is divided into stages IIA, IIB, and IIC. In stage IIA, the tumor is larger than 2 centimeters and no cancer is found when the lymph nodes are checked under a microscope. In stage IIB, the tumor is larger than 2 centimeters and no swollen lymph nodes are found by a physical exam or imaging tests. In stage IIC, the tumor may be any size and has spread to nearby bone, muscle, connective tissue, or cartilage. It is has not spread to lymph nodes or distant parts of the body.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718365" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage II Merkel cell carcinoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718366" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;carcinoma de células de Merkel en estadio II&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>carcinoma de células de Merkel en estadio II</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El carcinoma de células de Merkel en estadio II se divide en los estadios IIA, IIB y IIC. En el estadio IIA, el tumor mide más de dos centímetros y no se encuentra cáncer cuando se examinan los ganglios linfáticos bajo un microscopio. En el estadio IIB, el tumor mide más de dos centímetros y no se encuentran  ganglios linfáticos inflamados cuando se realiza un examen físico o pruebas de imágenes. En el estadio IIC, el tumor puede ser de cualquier tamaño y se diseminó hasta el hueso, el músculo, el tejido conjuntivo o  cartílagos cercanos. No se diseminó hasta los ganglios linfáticos o partes distantes del cuerpo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-01-05</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2010-03-15</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
