<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000579671"><TermName>In 111 ibritumomab tiuxetan</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... ih-brih-TOO-moh-mab ty-UK-seh-tan)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A radiolabeled monoclonal antibody that is used to detect certain types of B-cell non-Hodgkin lymphoma and is being studied in the detection of other types of B-cell tumors. It is made up of the monoclonal antibody ibritumomab plus the radioisotope indium 111. It binds to the protein called CD20, which is found on B cells. A machine is used to detect which cells in the body have bound the antibody. In 111 ibritumomab tiuxetan is a type of radiopharmaceutical. Also called In 111 Zevalin and indium In 111 ibritumomab tiuxetan.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720467" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;In 111 ibritumomab tiuxetan&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720466" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;In 111 ibritumomab tiuxetán&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>In 111 ibritumomab tiuxetán</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Anticuerpo monoclonal radiomarcado que se usa para detectar ciertos tipos de linfoma no Hodgkin de células B y que está en estudio para la detección de otros tumores de células B. Está compuesto por el anticuerpo monoclonal ibritumomab más el radioisótopo indio 111. Se une a la proteína CD20, que se encuentra en las células B. Se usa una máquina para detectar cuáles células del cuerpo se han unido al anticuerpo. El In 111 ibritumomab tiuxetán es un tipo de radiofármaco. También se llama In 111 Zevalin y indio In 111 ibritumomab tiuxetán.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-11-30</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2007-11-30</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
