<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000559242"><TermName>carcinomatous meningitis</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KAR-sih-NOH-muh-tus MEH-nin-JY-tis)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A serious problem that may occur in cancer in which cancer cells spread from the original (primary) tumor to the meninges (thin layers of tissue that cover and protect the brain and spinal cord). It can happen in many types of cancer, but is the most common in melanoma, breast, lung, and gastrointestinal cancer. The cancer may cause the meninges to be inflamed. Also called leptomeningeal carcinoma, leptomeningeal carcinomatosis, leptomeningeal metastasis, meningeal carcinomatosis, meningeal metastasis,  and neoplastic meningitis.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720476" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;carcinomatous meningitis&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720477" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;meningitis carcinomatosa&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>meningitis carcinomatosa</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Problema grave que se puede presentar cuando las células de un cáncer se diseminan desde el tumor original (primario) hasta las meninges (capas delgadas de tejido que cubren y protegen el cerebro y la médula espinal). Puede ocurrir en muchos tipos de cáncer, pero es más común en el caso del melanoma y los cánceres de mama, pulmón y aparato digestivo. El cáncer puede hacer que las meninges se inflamen. También se llama carcinoma leptomeníngeo, carcinomatosis leptomeníngea, carcinomatosis meníngea, meningitis neoplásica, metástasis leptomeníngea,  y metástasis meníngea.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-07-06</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2010-01-08</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
