<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000579649"><TermName>Zevalin</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ZEH-vuh-lin)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A monoclonal antibody that is used to treat certain types of B-cell non-Hodgkin lymphoma and is being studied in the treatment and detection of other types of B-cell tumors. Monoclonal antibodies are made in the laboratory and can locate and bind to substances in the body, including cancer cells. Ibritumomab binds to the protein called CD20, which is found on B cells. It is linked to the compound tiuxetan. This allows certain radioisotopes to be attached before it is given to a patient. It is a type of monoclonal antibody-chelator conjugate. Also called ibritumomab tiuxetan.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720463" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Zevalin&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720462" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Zevalin&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Zevalin</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Anticuerpo monoclonal radiomarcado que se usa para detectar ciertos tipos de linfoma no Hodgkin de células B y que está en estudio para la detección de otros tumores de células B. Los anticuerpos monoclonales se producen en el laboratorio y pueden localizar sustancias en el cuerpo y unirse a ellas, incluso a las células cancerosas. El ibritumomab se une a la proteína CD20, que se encuentra en las células B. Está unido al compuesto tiuxetán. Este permite que se le unan ciertos radioisótopos antes de administrarlo al paciente. Es un tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal conjugado con un quelante. También se llama ibritumomab tiuxetán.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-11-29</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000562503">Ibritumomab Tiuxetan</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
