<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000533240"><TermName>LH-RH agonist</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... A-guh-nist)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A substance that keeps the testicles and ovaries from making sex hormones by blocking other hormones that are needed to make them. In men, LH-RH agonists cause the testicles to stop making testosterone. In women, they cause the ovaries to stop making estrogen and progesterone. Some LH-RH agonists are used to treat prostate cancer.  Also called GnRH agonist, gonadotropin-releasing hormone agonist,  and luteinizing hormone-releasing hormone agonist.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718266" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;LH-RH agonist&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718265" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;agonista de la HL-HL&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>agonista de la HL-HL</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Sustancia que impide que los testículos y los ovarios elaboren hormonas sexuales al bloquear otras hormonas necesarias para producirlas. En los hombres,  los agonistas de la HL-HL hacen que los testículos dejen de elaborar testosterona. En las mujeres, hacen que los ovarios dejen de elaborar estrógeno y progesterona. Algunos agonistas de la HL-HL se usan para tratar el cáncer de próstata. También se llama agonista de la HLGn, agonista de la hormona liberadora de gonadotropina,  y agonista de la hormona liberadora de hormona luteinizante.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-02-05</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-11-26</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/prostate/prostate-hormone-therapy-fact-sheet">Hormone Therapy for Prostate Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/prostata/hoja-informativa-terapia-hormonal">Terapia hormonal para el cáncer de próstata</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
