<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000580343"><TermName>scintigraphy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(sin-TIH-gruh-fee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure that produces pictures (scans) of structures inside the body, including areas where there are cancer cells. Scintigraphy is used to diagnose, stage, and monitor disease. A small amount of a radioactive chemical (radionuclide) is injected into a vein or swallowed. Different radionuclides travel through the blood to different organs. A machine with a special camera moves over the person lying on a table and detects the type of radiation given off by the radionuclides. A computer forms an image of the areas where the radionuclide builds up. These areas may contain cancer cells. Also called radionuclide scanning.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720657" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;scintigraphy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720656" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;centellografía&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>centellografía</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento mediante el cual se obtienen imágenes (gammagrafías) de las estructuras internas del cuerpo, incluso de las áreas donde hay células cancerosas. La centellografía se usa para diagnosticar, estadificar y vigilar una enfermedad. Se inyecta en una vena o se traga una cantidad pequeña de una sustancia química radiactiva (radionúclido). Los distintos radionúclidos se desplazan por el torrente sanguíneo hasta los diferentes órganos. Una máquina con una cámara especial se mueve alrededor de la persona tendida sobre una camilla y detecta los rayos gamma que emiten los radionúclidos. Una computadora compone una imagen de las áreas donde se acumulan los radionúclidos. En estas áreas puede haber células cancerosas. También se llama gammagrafía con radionúclido.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-12-14</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2008-01-10</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
