<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000532303"><TermName>EGFR inhibitor</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... in-HIH-bih-ter)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A substance that blocks the activity of a protein called epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR). EGFR is found on the surface of some normal cells and is involved in cell growth. It may also be found at high levels on some types of cancer cells, which causes these cells to grow and divide. Blocking EGFR may keep cancer cells from growing. Some EGFR inhibitors are used to treat cancer. Also called EGFR tyrosine kinase inhibitor, epidermal growth factor receptor inhibitor,  and epidermal growth factor receptor tyrosine kinase inhibitor.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000734650" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;EGFR inhibitor&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000734651" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;inhibidor del RFCE&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>inhibidor del RFCE</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Sustancia que bloquea la actividad de una proteína que se llama receptor del factor de crecimiento epidérmico (RFCE). El RFCE se encuentra sobre la superficie de algunas células normales y participa en el crecimiento de las células. También se puede encontrar en concentraciones altas en algunos tipos de células cancerosas; esto hace que estas células crezcan y se multipliquen. El bloqueo del RFCE puede impedir el crecimiento de las células cancerosas. Algunos inhibidores del RFCE se usan para tratar el cáncer. También se llama inhibidor de la tirosina cinasa del receptor del factor de crecimiento epidérmico, inhibidor de la tirosina cinasa del RFCE,  y inhibidor del receptor del factor de crecimiento epidérmico.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2012-04-11</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
