<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000512908"><TermName>stage IVA lip and oral cavity cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... OR-ul KA-vih-tee KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage IV is divided into stages IVA, IVB, and IVC. In stage IVA, (1) the tumor has spread through tissue in the lip or oral cavity into nearby tissue and/or bone (jaw, tongue, floor of mouth, maxillary sinus, or skin of chin  or nose); cancer may have spread to one lymph node that is 3 centimeters or smaller, on the same side of the neck as the tumor; or (2) the tumor is any size or has spread through tissue in the lip or oral cavity into nearby tissue and/or bone (jaw, tongue, floor of mouth, maxillary sinus, or skin of chin or nose). Cancer has spread to one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the tumor and the lymph node is larger than 3 centimeters but not larger than 6 centimeters, or to more than one lymph node on the same side of the neck as the tumor and the lymph nodes are not larger than 6 centimeters, or to lymph nodes on the opposite side of the neck as the tumor or on both sides of the neck, and the lymph nodes are not larger than 6 centimeters.    </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718579" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IVA lip and oral cavity cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718581" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer del labio y cavidad oral en estadio IVA&quot;" language="es" id="_3"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer del labio y la cavidad oral en estadio IVA</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio IV se divide en estadios IVA, IVB y IVC. En el estadio IVA, 1) el tumor se diseminó a través del tejido del labio o la cavidad oral hacia el tejido cercano o el hueso (mandíbula, lengua, piso de la boca, seno maxilar, o piel del mentón o la nariz); el cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta un ganglio linfático que mide tres centímetros o menos del mismo lado del cuello que el tumor; o 2) el tumor puede ser de cualquier tamaño y se diseminó a través del tejido del labio o la cavidad oral hacia el tejido cercano o el hueso (mandíbula, lengua, piso de la boca, seno maxilar, o piel del mentón o la nariz). El cáncer se diseminó hasta un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello que el tumor y el ganglio linfático mide más de tres centímetros, pero no más de seis centímetro, o hasta más de un ganglio linfático del mismo lado del cuello que el tumor y los ganglios linfáticos no miden más de seis centímetros, o hasta los ganglios linfáticos del lado opuesto del cuello que el tumor, o hasta ambos lados del cuello; los ganglios linfáticos no miden más de seis centímetros.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-01-05</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2010-11-24</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258017">Lip and Oral Cavity Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000486932">Cáncer de labio y de cavidad oral: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
