<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000561412"><TermName>isolated limb infusion</TermName><TermPronunciation>(I-soh-LAY-ted LIM in-FYOO-zhun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure used to deliver anticancer drugs directly to an arm or leg but not to the rest of the body. The flow of blood to and from the limb is temporarily stopped with a tourniquet (a tight band around the limb). Catheters (small, flexible tubes) attached to a pump are put into an artery and a vein in the limb so that blood can be circulated through the pump into the limb. Anticancer drugs are injected into the catheters. Wrapping the limb in a heated blanket or warming the drugs or blood may help the drugs work better.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720529" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;isolated limb infusion&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720528" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;infusión de un miembro aislado&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>infusión de un miembro aislado</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento que se usa para administrar medicamentos anticancerosos directamente en un brazo o una pierna, pero no en el resto del cuerpo. Se interrumpe temporalmente con un torniquete (banda ajustada alrededor del miembro) el flujo de sangre desde y hacia el miembro. Se colocan catéteres (tubos pequeños y flexibles) en una arteria y una vena del miembro que se conectan con una bomba, de modo que la sangre pueda circular por la bomba y todo el miembro. Se inyectan medicamentos anticancerosos en los catéteres. Al envolver el miembro en un paño caliente o entibiar los medicamentos o la sangre, se puede ayudar a que los medicamentos sean más eficaces.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-03-31</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2008-04-09</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
