<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000589395"><TermName>cervical intraepithelial neoplasia grade 2/3</TermName><TermPronunciation>(SER-vih-kul IN-truh-eh-pih-THEE-lee-ul NEE-oh-PLAY-zhuh …)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Abnormal cells are found on the surface of the cervix. Cervical intraepithelial neoplasia grade 2/3 is usually caused by certain types of human papillomavirus (HPV) and is found when a cervical biopsy is done. Cervical intraepithelial neoplasia grade 2/3 has features of CIN 2 and CIN 3. It is not cancer, but may become cancer and spread to nearby normal tissue if not treated. Treatment for cervical intraepithelial neoplasia grade 2/3 may include cryotherapy, laser therapy, loop electrosurgical procedure (LEEP), or cone biopsy to remove or destroy the abnormal tissue. Also called CIN 2/3.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000721105" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cervical intraepithelial neoplasia grade 2/3&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000721106" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;neoplasia intraepitelial cervical de grados 2 y 3&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>neoplasia intraepitelial cervical de grados 2 y 3</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Se encuentran células anormales en  la superficie del cuello uterino. Con frecuencia, la neoplasia intraepitelial cervical de grados 2 y 3 es causada por ciertos tipos de virus del papiloma humano (VPH) y se encuentra al realizar una biopsia de cuello uterino. La neoplasia intraepitelial cervical de grados 2 y 3 tiene características de la NIC 2 y la NIC 3. No es cáncer, pero se puede volver cancerosa y diseminar al tejido normal cercano si no se trata. El tratamiento de la neoplasia intraepitelial cervical de grados 2 y 3 puede incluir crioterapia, terapia con láser,  procedimiento de escisión electroquirúrgica con asa (PEEA) o biopsia de cono para extraer o destruir el tejido anormal. También se llama NIC 2 y 3.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-03-06</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-12-19</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
