<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000512926"><TermName>stage III Merkel cell carcinoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(stayj ... MER-kul sel KAR-sih-NOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage III Merkel cell cancer is divided into stages IIIA and IIIB. In stage IIIA, the tumor may be any size and may have spread to nearby bone, muscle, connective tissue, or cartilage. Cancer is found in the lymph nodes when they are checked under a microscope. In stage IIIB, the tumor may be any size and may have spread to nearby bone, muscle, connective tissue, or cartilage. Cancer has spread to the lymph nodes near the tumor and is found by physical exam or imaging test. The lymph nodes are removed and cancer is found in the lymph nodes when they are checked under a microscope. There may also be a second tumor, which is either between the primary tumor and nearby lymph nodes or farther away from the center of the body than the primary tumor is.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718368" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III Merkel cell carcinoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718367" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;carcinoma de células de Merkel en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>carcinoma de células de Merkel en estadio III</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El carcinoma de células de Merkel en estadio III, se divide en los estadios IIIA y IIIB. En el estadio IIIA, el tumor puede tener cualquier tamaño y se puede haber diseminado hasta el hueso, el músculo, el tejido conjuntivo o el cartílago cercanos. Se encuentra cáncer en los ganglios linfáticos cuando se examinan bajo un microscopio. En el estadio IIIB, el tumor puede tener cualquier tamaño y se puede haber diseminado hasta el hueso, el músculo, el tejido conjuntivo o el cartílago cercanos. El cáncer se diseminó hasta los ganglios linfáticos cerca del tumor y se localiza al llevar a cabo un examen físico o pruebas de imágenes. Los ganglios linfáticos se extirpan y se encuentra cáncer en los ganglios linfáticos cuando se examinan bajo un microscopio. También puede haber un segundo tumor que está entre el tumor primario y los ganglios linfáticos cercanos, o más lejos del centro del cuerpo donde está el tumor primario.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-01-05</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2010-05-18</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
