<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000509341"><TermName>tamoxifen citrate</TermName><TermPronunciation>(tuh-MOK-sih-FEN SIH-trayt)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat certain types of breast cancer in women and men. It is also used to prevent breast cancer in women who have had ductal carcinoma in situ (abnormal cells in the ducts of the breast) and in women who are at a high risk of developing breast cancer. Tamoxifen citrate is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. It blocks the effects of the hormone estrogen in the breast. Tamoxifen citrate is a type of antiestrogen. Also called tamoxifen.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718614" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tamoxifen citrate&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718613" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;citrato de tamoxifeno&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>citrato de tamoxifeno</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para tratar ciertos tipos de cáncer de mama en mujeres y hombres. Asimismo, se usa para prevenir el cáncer de mama en las mujeres que padecieron de carcinoma ductal in situ (células anormales en los conductos de la mama) y que tienen un riesgo alto de contraer cáncer de mama. El citrato de tamoxifeno también está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Bloquea los efectos de la hormona estrógeno en la mama. El citrato de tamoxifeno es un tipo de antiestrógeno. También se llama tamoxifeno.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2006-09-15</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2009-04-27</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000502250">Tamoxifen Citrate</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
