<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000595341"><TermName>leuprolide acetate</TermName><TermPronunciation>(LOO-proh-lide A-seh-tayt)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat advanced prostate cancer. Under the brand name Lupron, it is also used to treat early puberty in children and certain gynecologic conditions. Leuprolide acetate is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. It blocks the testicles from making testosterone (a male hormone) and the ovaries from making estrogen and progesterone (female hormones). It may stop the growth of prostate cancer cells that need testosterone to grow. Leuprolide acetate is a type of gonadotropin-releasing hormone (GnRH) agonist. Also called Eligard, Lupron,  and Viadur.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000721043" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;leuprolide acetate&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000721044" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;acetato de leuprolida&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>acetato de leuprolida</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para tratar el cáncer de próstata avanzado. El acetato de leuprolida impide que los testículos produzcan testosterona (una hormona masculina) y que los ovarios produzcan estrógeno y progesterona (hormonas femeninas). Puede detener el crecimiento de las células de cáncer de próstata que necesitan testosterona para crecer. El acetato de leuprolida es un tipo de agonista de la hormona liberadora de gonadotropina (HLGn).. También se llama Eligard, Lupron,  y Viadur.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-04-30</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-12-04</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000588951">Leuprolide Acetate</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
