<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000543514"><TermName>trabectedin</TermName><TermPronunciation>(truh-BEK-teh-din)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat liposarcoma and leiomyosarcoma (types of soft tissue sarcoma) that cannot be removed by surgery or have spread to other parts of the body. It is used in patients who were treated with other anticancer drugs. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Trabectedin may kill cancer cells by damaging their DNA and stopping them from dividing. It is a type of alkylating agent. Also called ecteinascidin 743, ET-743,  and Yondelis.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718291" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;trabectedin&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718290" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;trabectedina&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>trabectedina</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se utiliza en el tratamiento del liposarcoma y el leiomiosarcoma (tipos de sarcomas de tejido blando) que no se pueden extirpar mediante una cirugía o que se diseminaron a otras partes del cuerpo. Se utiliza en pacientes ya tratados con otros medicamentos contra el cáncer. También se estudia en el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. La trabectedina puede destruir las células cancerosas al dañar su ADN y detener su división. Es un tipo de alquilante. También se llama ecteinascidina 743, ET-743,  y Yondelis.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-04-13</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2015-11-03</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000776577">Trabectedin</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
