<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000589399"><TermName>duloxetine hydrochloride</TermName><TermPronunciation>(duh-LOK-suh-teen HY-droh-KLOR-ide)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat depression and peripheral neuropathy (pain, numbness, tingling, burning, or weakness in the hands or feet) that can occur with diabetes. It is also being studied in the treatment of peripheral neuropathy caused by certain anticancer drugs. Duloxetine hydrochloride increases the amount of certain chemicals in the brain that help relieve depression and pain. It is a type of serotonin and norepinephrine reuptake inhibitor. Also called Cymbalta and duloxetine.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000721112" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;duloxetine hydrochloride&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000721111" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;clorhidrato de duloxetina&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>clorhidrato de duloxetina</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para tratar la depresión y la neuropatía periférica (dolor, adormecimiento, cosquilleo, ardor, o debilidad en las manos o pies) que se pueden presentar con la diabetes. Asimismo, está en estudio para el tratamiento de la neuropatía periférica causado por ciertos medicamentos contra el cáncer. El clorhidrato de duloxetina aumenta la cantidad de ciertos productos químicos en el cerebro que ayudan a aliviar la depresión y el dolor. Es un tipo de inhibidor de la recaptación de la serotonina y la noradrenalina. También se llama Cymbalta y duloxetina.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-03-06</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2008-03-07</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
