<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000520552"><TermName>stage C prostate cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… PROS-tayt KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A prostate cancer stage defined by the Jewett staging system. Stage C prostate cancer is cancer that began in the prostate, has grown beyond the outer layer of the prostate to nearby tissues, and may be found in the seminal vesicles (glands that help produce semen). Stage C is divided into stages C1 and C2. In stage C1, the cancer has grown outside the prostate but has not spread to lymph nodes or other places in the body. In stage C2, the cancer has grown outside the prostate and blocks urine flow from the bladder or through the ureters.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718060" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage C prostate cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718059" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de próstata en estadio C&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000442273" type="image/jpeg" alt="Prostate cancer staging; six  panel drawing showing a side view of normal  male  anatomy and closeup views of Stage I, Stage IIA, Stage IIB, Stage III, and Stage IV  showing cancer growing from within the  prostate to nearby tissue and then to lymph nodes or other parts of the body." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_2"><Caption language="en">As prostate cancer progresses from Stage I to Stage IV, the cancer cells grow within the prostate, through the outer layer of the prostate into nearby tissue, and then to lymph nodes or other parts of the body. </Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000457829" type="image/jpeg" alt="Estadificación del cáncer de próstata; el dibujo de cinco paneles muestra una imagen de la anatomía masculina normal y ampliaciones del estadio I, estadio IIA, estadio IIB, estadio III y estadio IV que muestran un cáncer que crece desde el interior de la próstata hasta el tejido cercano y, luego, hasta los ganglios linfáticos u otras partes del cuerpo." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">A medida que el cáncer avanza desde el estadio I al estadio IV, las células cancerosas crecen dentro de la próstata, a través de la capa externa de la próstata hacia el tejido cercano y, luego, hasta los ganglios linfáticos u otras partes del cuerpo.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de próstata en estadio C</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio de un cáncer de próstata se define mediante el sistema de estadificación de Jewett. El cáncer de próstata en estadio C es un cáncer que empezó en la próstata, creció más allá de la capa externa de la próstata hasta los tejidos cercanos, y se puede encontrar en las vesículas seminales (glándulas que ayudan a producir el semen). El estadio C se divide en los estadios C1 y C2. En el estadio C1, el cáncer ha crecido fuera de la próstata, pero no se ha diseminado hasta los ganglios linfáticos u otras partes del cuerpo. En el estadio C2, el cáncer ha crecido fuera de la próstata y bloquea el paso de la orina desde la vejiga o a través de los uréteres.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2006-11-13</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2008-07-18</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
