<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000556410"><TermName>choline</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KOH-leen)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A nutrient in the vitamin B complex that the body needs in small amounts to function and stay healthy. Choline helps cells make membranes, make a neurotransmitter (a chemical that helps nerve cells communicate with other cells), and remove fat from the liver. It is found in whole milk, beef liver, eggs, soy foods, and peanuts. Choline is water-soluble (can dissolve in water) and must be taken in every day. Not enough choline can cause diseases of the heart and blood vessels and damage to the liver. A form of choline is being studied in the treatment of some types of cancer and to reduce pain and fever. Choline is also being studied together with vitamin B12 in the prevention and treatment of cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718604" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;choline&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718603" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;colina&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>colina</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Nutriente del complejo de la vitamina B que el cuerpo necesita en pequeñas cantidades para funcionar y mantenerse sano. La colina ayuda a las células a formar membranas, producir un neurotransmisor (sustancia química que ayuda a las células nerviosas a comunicarse con otras células) y a extraer grasa del hígado.   Se encuentra en la leche entera, el hígado de carne vacuna, los huevos, los alimentos de soja y los maníes.   La colina es soluble en agua (puede disolverse en agua) y debe ingerirse todos los días.   La insuficiencia de colina puede causar enfermedades del corazón y los vasos sanguíneos, y dañar el hígado.   Una forma de colina está en estudio para el tratamiento de algunos tipos de cáncer y para aliviar el dolor y la fiebre.   Asimismo, la colina está en estudio junto con la vitamina B12 para la prevención y el tratamiento de cáncer.  </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-12-05</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
