<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000539073"><TermName>stage II soft tissue sarcoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(...TIH-shoo sar-KOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage II is divided into stages IIA and IIB. In stage IIA, the tumor is mid-grade (somewhat likely to grow and spread quickly) or high-grade (likely to grow and spread quickly) and 5 centimeters or smaller. It may be either superficial (in subcutaneous tissue with no spread into connective tissue or muscle below) or deep (in the muscle and may be in connective or subcutaneous tissue). In stage IIB, the tumor is mid-grade (somewhat likely to grow and spread quickly) and larger than 5 centimeters. It may be either superficial (in subcutaneous tissue with no spread into connective tissue or muscle below) or deep (in the muscle and may be in connective or subcutaneous tissue).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718182" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage II soft tissue sarcoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718181" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sarcoma de tejido blando en estadio II&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>sarcoma de tejido blando en estadio II</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio II se divide en estadios IIA y IIB. En el estadio IIA, el tumor es de grado medio (tiene alguna probabilidad de crecer y diseminarse rápidamente) o es de grado alto (tiene probabilidad de crecer y diseminarse rápidamente) y mide cinco centímetros o menos. Puede ser superficial (está en el tejido subcutáneo  sin diseminación hacia el tejido conjuntivo  de abajo) o profundo (está en el músculo y puede estar en el tejido conjuntivo o el tejido subcutáneo). En el estadio IIB, el tumor es de grado medio (tiene alguna probabilidad de crecer y diseminarse rápidamente) y mide más de cinco centímetros. Puede ser superficial (está en el tejido subcutáneo  sin diseminación hacia el tejido conjuntivo  de abajo) o profundo (está en el músculo y puede estar en el tejido conjuntivo o el tejido subcutáneo).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-07-01</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2010-12-17</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
