<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000522475"><TermName>IL-1-alpha</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... AL-fuh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>One of a group of related proteins made by leukocytes (white blood cells) and other cells in the body. IL-1-alpha, one form of IL-1, is made mainly by one type of white blood cell, the macrophage, and helps another type of white blood cell, the lymphocyte, fight infections. It also helps leukocytes pass through blood vessel walls to sites of infection and causes fever by affecting areas of the brain that control body temperature. The other form of IL-1, IL-1-beta, acts the same as IL-1-alpha. IL-1-alpha made in the laboratory is used as a biological response modifier to boost the immune system in cancer therapy. IL-1-alpha is a type of cytokine.  Also called IL-1-alfa, interleukin-1-alfa,  and interleukin-1-alpha.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718109" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;IL-1-alpha&quot;" language="en" id="_2"/><SpanishTermName>IL-1-alpha (en inglés)</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Pertenece a un grupo de proteínas relacionadas que elaboran los leucocitos (glóbulos blancos) y otras células del cuerpo.   Principalmente los macrófagos, un tipo de glóbulos blancos, elaboran la IL-1-alpha (en inglés), una forma de , y esta ayuda a otro tipo de glóbulos blancos, los linfocitos, a combatir infecciones.   También ayuda a  que los leucocitos pasen a través de las paredes de los vasos sanguíneos y lleguen a los sitios de la infección; además, causa fiebre porque afecta zonas del cerebro que controlan la temperatura del cuerpo. La otra forma de , -beta, actúa igual que la IL-1-alpha (en inglés). La IL-1-alpha (en inglés) que se produce en el laboratorio se usa en el tratamiento de cáncer como modificador de la respuesta biológica para estimular el sistema inmunitario. La IL-1-alpha (en inglés) es un tipo de citocina.   También se llama IL-1-alfa y interleucina-1-alfa.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2006-11-17</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2008-12-02</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
