<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000538415"><TermName>infiltrating breast cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(IN-fil-TRAY-ting brest KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cancer that has spread from where it began in the breast to surrounding normal tissue. The most common type of infiltrating breast cancer is infiltrating ductal carcinoma, which begins in the lining of the milk ducts (thin tubes that carry milk from the lobules of the breast to the nipple). Another type is infiltrating lobular carcinoma, which begins in the lobules (milk glands) of the breast. Infiltrating breast cancer can spread through the blood and lymph systems to other parts of the body. Also called invasive breast cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718741" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;infiltrating breast cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718740" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de mama infiltrante&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de mama infiltrante</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cáncer que se diseminó del sitio donde comenzó en la mama al tejido sano que la rodea. El tipo más común de cáncer de mama infiltrante  es el carcinoma ductal infiltrante, que empieza en el revestimiento de los conductos galactóforos (tubos delgados que conducen la leche desde los lobulillos de la mama hasta el pezón). Otro tipo es el carcinoma lobulillar  infiltrante, que comienza en los lobulillos (glándulas lácteas) de la mama. El cáncer de mama infiltrante se puede diseminar a otras partes del cuerpo a través de los sistemas linfático y sanguíneo. También se llama cáncer de mama invasivo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-03-09</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-07-10</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/breast">Breast Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/seno">Cáncer de seno (mama)</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
