<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000514453"><TermName>mediastinoscope</TermName><TermPronunciation>(MEE-dee-uh-STY-noh-skope)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A thin, tube-like instrument used to examine the tissues and lymph nodes in the area between the lungs. These tissues include the heart and its large blood vessels, trachea, esophagus, and bronchi. The mediastinoscope has a light and a lens for viewing and may also have a tool to remove tissue. It is inserted into the chest through a cut above the breastbone.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718172" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mediastinoscope&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718171" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;mediastinoscopio&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000466554" type="image/jpeg" alt="Mediastinoscopy; shows mediastinoscope with light and lens inserted into&#10;the chest through an incision above the breastbone. Drawing shows right&#10;and left lungs, trachea, and lymph nodes. Inset shows anterior&#10;mediastinotomy (Chamberlain procedure) with incision beside the&#10;breastbone.&#10;" language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_2"><Caption language="en">Mediastinoscopy. A mediastinoscope is inserted into the chest through an
incision above the breastbone to look for abnormal areas between the
lungs. A mediastinoscope is a thin, tube-like instrument with a light
and a lens for viewing. It may also have a cutting tool. Tissue samples
may be taken from lymph nodes on the right side of the chest and checked
under a microscope for signs of cancer. In an anterior mediastinotomy
(Chamberlain procedure), the incision is made beside the breastbone to
remove tissue samples from the lymph nodes on the left side of the
chest.
</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000494346" type="image/jpeg" alt="Mediastinoscopía; muestra el mediastinoscopio con una luz y una lente insertadas en el pecho mediante una incisión en la parte superior del esternón.  El dibujo muestra el pulmón derecho e izquierdo, la tráquea y los ganglios linfáticos.  El recuadro muestra la mediastinoscopía anterior (Procedimiento de Chamberlain) con una incisión al lado del esternón." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Mediastinoscopía.  Se inserta un mediastinoscopio en el pecho mediante una incisión en la parte superior del esternón para determinar si existen áreas anormales entre los pulmones.  Un mediastinoscopio es un instrumento en forma de tubo delgado con una luz y una lente, que se utiliza para observar. También puede tener un instrumento para cortar.   Se pueden tomar muestras de tejido de los ganglios linfáticos que se encuentran a la derecha del pecho para analizarlas al microscopio y determinar si hay algún signo de cáncer. En una mediastinoscopía anterior (Procedimiento de Chamberlain), la incisión se hace al lado del esternón para extraer muestras de tejido de los ganglios linfáticos que se encuentran al lado izquierdo del pecho.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>mediastinoscopio</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Instrumento delgado parecido a un tubo que se usa para examinar los tejidos y los ganglios linfáticos del área ubicada entre los pulmones. Esos tejidos incluyen el corazón y sus vasos sanguíneos mayores, la tráquea, el esófago y los bronquios. El mediastinoscopio tiene una luz y una lente para observar, y también puede tener una herramienta para extirpar tejido. Se inserta en el pecho a través de un corte encima del esternón.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-02-12</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
