<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000572250"><TermName>raloxifene hydrochloride</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ra-LOK-sih-feen HY-droh-KLOR-ide)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to reduce the risk of invasive breast cancer in postmenopausal women who are at high risk of the disease or who have osteoporosis. It is also used to prevent and treat osteoporosis in postmenopausal women. It is also being studied in the prevention of breast cancer in certain  premenopausal women and in the prevention and treatment of other conditions. Raloxifene hydrochloride blocks the effects of the hormone estrogen in the breast and increases the amount of calcium in bone. It is a type of selective estrogen receptor modulator (SERM). Also called Evista.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720793" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;raloxifene hydrochloride&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720792" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;clorhidrato de raloxifeno&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>clorhidrato de raloxifeno</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para reducir el riesgo de un cáncer de mama invasor en mujeres posmenopáusicas que corren un riesgo alto de contraer la enfermedad o que padecen de osteoporosis. Asimismo, se usa para prevenir y tratar la osteoporosis en mujeres posmenopáusicas. También está en estudio para prevenir el cáncer de mama en ciertas mujeres premenopáusicas, y para la prevención y el tratamiento de otras afecciones. El clorhidrato de raloxifeno bloquea los efectos de la hormona estrógeno en la mama y aumenta la cantidad de calcio en los huesos. Es un tipo de modulador selectivo del receptor de estrógeno (MSRE). También se llama Evista.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-10-05</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2009-04-10</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000557341">Raloxifene Hydrochloride</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
