<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000523437"><TermName>comprehensive cancer center</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KOM-pree-HEN-siv KAN-ser ...)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A cancer research center that gets support from the National Cancer Institute (NCI) to do cancer research and provide services directly to cancer patients. Scientists and doctors at these centers do basic laboratory research and clinical trials, and they study the patterns, causes, and control of cancer in groups of people. Also, they take part in multicenter clinical trials, which enroll patients from many parts of the country. Comprehensive Cancer Centers also give cancer information to health care professionals and the public. More information about the NCI Cancer Centers Program can be found on the NCI's Web site at <ExternalRef xref="http://cancercenters.cancer.gov/">http://cancercenters.cancer.gov/</ExternalRef>.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733038" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;comprehensive cancer center&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733037" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;centro integral del cáncer&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>centro integral del cáncer</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Centro de investigación del cáncer que recibe apoyo del Instituto Nacional del Cáncer (NCI) para que realice investigaciones y proporcione servicios directamente a los pacientes. Los científicos y médicos de esos centros realizan investigaciones básicas de laboratorio y conducen ensayos clínicos; estudian los patrones, las causas y las formas de controlar el cáncer en grupos de personas. Además, participan en ensayos clínicos multicéntricos que inscriben pacientes de muchos lugares del país. Asimismo, los centros integrales del cáncer proporcionan información a los profesionales de la salud y el público. Para mayor información en inglés sobre el Programa de Centros Integrales del Cáncer consultar la página de Internet del NCI en el siguiente enlace: <ExternalRef xref="http://cancercenters.cancer.gov/">http://cancercenters.cancer.gov/</ExternalRef>.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2011-08-17</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
