<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000597156"><TermName>Jamshidi needle</TermName><TermPronunciation>(jam-SHEE-dee NEE-dul)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A long, hollow needle with a tapered cutting edge on one end and a handle with a place to attach a syringe on the other end. It is used to remove a sample of tissue from the bone marrow. The needle is inserted through the bone into the bone marrow and the syringe is attached to the top to remove the sample or to deliver drugs or fluid into the bone. A Jamshidi needle is a type of bone marrow needle.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720825" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Jamshidi needle&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720824" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;aguja de Jamshidi&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000554337" type="image/jpeg" alt="Bone marrow aspiration and biopsy; drawing shows a patient lying face down on a table and a bone marrow needle being inserted into the hip bone. Inset shows the bone marrow needle being inserted through the skin into the bone marrow of the hip bone." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_2"><Caption language="en">Bone marrow aspiration and biopsy. After  a small area of skin is numbed, a bone marrow needle is inserted into the patient’s hip bone.  Samples of blood, bone, and bone marrow   are removed for examination under a microscope.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000584849" type="image/jpeg" alt="Aspiración de la médula ósea y biopsia;  el dibujo muestra a un paciente acostado boca abajo en una camilla y una aguja para médula ósea que se inserta en el hueso de la cadera. El recuadro muestra la aguja para médula ósea que se inserta a través de la piel hasta la médula ósea del hueso de la cadera.  " language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Aspiración  de la médula ósea y biopsia. Después de adormecer un área pequeña de la piel, se inserta una aguja para médula ósea en el hueso de la cadera del paciente. Se extraen muestras de sangre, hueso y médula ósea para examinarlas bajo un microscopio.  </Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>aguja de Jamshidi</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Aguja larga y hueca con una borde de corte afilado en un extremo y una manija con un lugar para colocar la jeringa en el otro extremo. Se usa para extraer una muestra de tejido de la médula ósea. La aguja se introduce a través del hueso hacia  la médula ósea y la jeringa se conecta en la parte superior para extraer la muestra o administrar medicamentos o líquido en el hueso. Una aguja de Jamshidi es un tipo de aguja para la médula ósea.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-05-30</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2015-09-23</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
