<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000508929"><TermName>erlotinib hydrochloride</TermName><TermPronunciation>(er-LOH-tih-nib HY-droh-KLOR-ide)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat certain types of non-small cell lung cancer. It is also used with gemcitabine hydrochloride to treat pancreatic cancer that cannot be removed by surgery or has spread to other parts of the body. It is being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Erlotinib hydrochloride blocks a protein called epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR), which may help keep cancer cells from growing. It is a type of EGFR tyrosine kinase inhibitor. Also called CP-358,774, OSI-774,  and Tarceva.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718433" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;erlotinib hydrochloride&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718434" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;clorhidrato de erlotinib&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>clorhidrato de erlotinib</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para tratar ciertos tipos de cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas. También se usa junto con el hidrocloruro de gemcitabina, para el tratamiento del cáncer de páncreas que no se puede extirpar mediante una operación o que se ha diseminado hasta otras partes del cuerpo. Está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El clorhidrato de erlotinib bloquea una proteína que se llama receptor del factor de crecimiento epidérmico (RFCE), que impide el crecimiento de las células cancerosas. Es un tipo de inhibidor de la tirosina cinasa del RFCE. También se llama CP-358,774, OSI-774,  y Tarceva.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2006-09-15</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-07-10</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000492018">Erlotinib Hydrochloride</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
