<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000530385"><TermName>pancreatic endocrine cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(PAN-kree-A-tik EN-doh-krin KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare cancer that forms in islet cells (hormone-making cells) of the pancreas. Islet cells make several different hormones that affect body functions, including controlling the amount of glucose (sugar) in the blood and helping digest food in the stomach. Functional pancreatic endocrine cancers make extra amounts of these hormones, which can cause symptoms. Nonfunctional pancreatic endocrine cancers do not make extra amounts of hormones, but they may cause symptoms as they grow and spread. Also called islet cell carcinoma.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718815" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pancreatic endocrine cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718816" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de páncreas endocrino&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de páncreas endocrino</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cáncer poco frecuente que se forma en las células de los islotes (células que producen hormonas) del páncreas. Las células de los islotes producen varias hormonas diferentes que afectan el funcionamiento del cuerpo, como controlar la cantidad de glucosa (azúcar) en la sangre y ayudar al estómago a digerir los alimentos. Los cánceres de páncreas endocrino funcionantes producen cantidades adicionales de estas hormonas, lo que puede causar síntomas. Los cánceres de páncreas endocrino no funcionantes no producen cantidades adicionales de hormonas, pero pueden causar síntomas a medida que crecen y se diseminan.  También se llama carcinoma de célula de los islotes.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-01-16</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-12-03</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/pancreatic">Pancreatic Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/pancreas">Cáncer de páncreas</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
