<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000560344"><TermName>stage D prostate cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… PROS-tayt KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A prostate cancer stage defined by the Jewett staging system. Stage D prostate cancer is cancer that began in the prostate and has spread to lymph nodes near or far from the prostate, or to other parts of the body, often to the bones. Stage D is divided into stages D0, D1, D2, and D3. In stage D0, the level of prostatic acid phosphatase (PAP) is high. In stage D1, the cancer has spread to local lymph nodes only. In stage D2, the cancer has spread to distant lymph nodes and to bones or internal organs. In stage D3, prostate cancer has come back in patients who had received hormone therapy.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720992" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage D prostate cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720993" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de próstata en estadio D&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de próstata en estadio D</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio de un cáncer de próstata se define mediante el sistema de estadificación de Jewett. El cáncer de próstata en estadio D es cáncer que empezó en la próstata y se diseminó hasta los ganglios linfáticos cerca o lejos de la próstata, o hasta otras partes del cuerpo, con frecuencia hasta los huesos. El estadio D se divide en los estadios D0, D1, D2 y D3. En el estadio D0, la concentración de la fosfatasa ácida prostática (FAP) es alta. En el estadio D1, el cáncer solo se diseminó hasta los ganglios linfáticos locales. En el estadio D2, el cáncer se diseminó hasta los ganglios linfáticos distantes y los huesos u órganos internos. En el estadio D3, el cáncer de próstata volvió en pacientes que recibieron terapia hormonal.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-07-18</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
