<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000556402"><TermName>vitamin B complex</TermName><TermPronunciation>(VY-tuh-min ... KOM-plex)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A compound containing several or all of a group of vitamins and nutrients that the body needs in very small amounts to function and stay healthy. The B vitamins in the vitamin B complex include thiamine, riboflavin, niacin (nicotinic acid), niacinamide (nicotinamide), the vitamin B6 group (including pyridoxine, pyridoxal, pyridoxamine), biotin, pantothenic acid, folic acid, and vitamin B12. Aminobenzoic acid, inositol, and choline are sometimes included as part of the vitamin B complex. The vitamin B complex is water-soluble (can dissolve in water) and is found in yeast, seeds, eggs, liver, meat, and vegetables. Members of the vitamin B complex are being studied in the prevention and treatment of some types of cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718588" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;vitamin B complex&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718589" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;complejo de vitamina B&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>complejo de vitamina B</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Compuesto que contiene varias vitaminas y nutrientes o todo un grupo de los mismos, que el cuerpo necesita en cantidades muy pequeñas para funcionar y mantenerse sano. Las vitaminas B del complejo de vitamina B son la tiamina, la riboflavina, la niacina (ácido nicotínico), la niacinamida (nicotinamida), el grupo de vitaminas B6 (que incluye la piridoxina, el piridoxal y la piridoxamina), la biotina, el ácido pantoténico, el ácido fólico y la vitamina B12.   El ácido aminobenzoico, el inositol y la colina están a veces incluidos como parte del complejo de vitamina B. El complejo de vitamina B es soluble en agua (se puede disolver en agua) y se encuentra en la levadura, las semillas, los huevos, el hígado, la carne y las hortalizas.   Algunos miembros del complejo de vitamina B están en estudio para la prevención y el tratamiento de algunos tipos de cáncer.  </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-12-05</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
