<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000554836"><TermName>chorionic carcinoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KOR-ee-AH-nik KAR-sih-NOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A malignant, fast-growing tumor that develops from trophoblastic cells (cells that help an embryo attach to the uterus and help form the placenta). Almost all chorionic carcinomas form in the uterus after fertilization of an egg by a sperm, but a small number form in a testis or an ovary. Chorionic carcinomas spread through the blood to other organs, especially the lungs. They are a type of gestational trophoblastic disease. Also called chorioblastoma, choriocarcinoma,  and chorioepithelioma.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718754" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;chorionic carcinoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718756" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;carcinoma coriónico&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>carcinoma coriónico</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tumor maligno de crecimiento rápido, que se presenta en las células trofoblásticas (células del útero que ayudan al embrión a adherirse al útero y ayudan a formar la placenta). Casi todos los carcinomas coriónicos se forman en el útero después de que un espermatozoide fecunda un óvulo, pero un pequeño número se forma en un testículo o un ovario. Los carcinomas coriónicos se diseminan a través de la sangre hacia otros órganos, especialmente los pulmones. Son un tipo de enfermedad trofoblástica gestacional. También se llama corioblastoma, coriocarcinoma,  y corioepitelioma.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-06-08</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2007-08-20</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
