<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000556404"><TermName>thiamine</TermName><TermPronunciation>(THY-uh-min)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A nutrient in the vitamin B complex that the body needs in small amounts to function and stay healthy. Thiamine helps some enzymes work properly, helps break down sugars in the diet, and keeps nerves and the heart healthy. It is found in pork, organ meats, peas, beans, nuts, and whole grains. Thiamine is water-soluble (can dissolve in water) and must be taken in daily. Not enough thiamine can cause a disease called beriberi (a condition marked by heart, nerve, and digestive disorders). Too much thiamine may help cancer cells grow faster. Also called vitamin B1.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718593" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;thiamine&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718592" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tiamina&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>tiamina</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Nutriente del complejo de la vitamina B que el cuerpo necesita en pequeñas cantidades para funcionar y mantenerse sano. La tiamina ayuda a algunas enzimas a funcionar correctamente, ayuda a descomponer los azúcares de los alimentos y mantiene los nervios y el corazón saludables. Se encuentra en la carne de cerdo, las carne de órganos, las arvejas, los frijoles y los cereales integrales. La tiamina es soluble en agua (puede disolverse en agua) y debe tomarse  todos los días. La insuficiencia de tiamina puede causar una enfermedad que se llama beriberi (una afección caracterizada por trastornos del corazón, los nervios y los procesos digestivos). Demasiada tiamina puede ayudar a que las células cancerosas crezcan más rápido. También se llama vitamina B1.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-12-05</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
