<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000597249"><TermName>ziv-aflibercept</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ziv-a-FLIH-ber-sept)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used with other drugs to treat colorectal cancer that has spread to other  parts of the body and has not gotten better with chemotherapy. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Ziv-aflibercept blocks the action of a protein called vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF) and may prevent the growth of new blood vessels that tumors need to grow. It is a type of antiangiogenesis agent. Also called vascular endothelial growth factor trap, VEGF Trap,  and Zaltrap.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000721004" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ziv-aflibercept&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000739969" type="audio/mpeg" alt="" language="es" id="_6"/><SpanishTermName>ziv-aflibercept</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para tratar el cáncer colorrectal que se diseminó hasta otras partes del cuerpo y no mejoró con quimioterapia. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El ziv-aflibercept bloquea la acción de una proteína que se llama factor de crecimiento endotelial vascular (FCEV) y puede prevenir la formación de los vasos sanguíneos nuevos que los tumores necesitan para crecer. Es un tipo de antiangiogénico. También se llama bloqueador del factor de crecimiento endotelial vascular, bloqueador del FCEV,  y Zaltrap.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-06-16</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2012-08-14</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000738284">Ziv-Aflibercept</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
