<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000535555"><TermName>ipilimumab</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ih-pih-LIH-myoo-mab)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat melanoma that cannot be removed by surgery or has spread to other parts of the body. It is also used as adjuvant therapy to treat melanoma in the skin and lymph nodes in patients who have already had surgery. Ipilimumab is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Ipilimumab binds to a substance called CTLA-4, which is found on T cells (a type of white blood cell). Ipilimumab may block CTLA-4 and help the immune system kill cancer cells. It is a type of monoclonal antibody and a type of immune checkpoint inhibitor.   Also called MDX-010 and Yervoy.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718436" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ipilimumab&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718435" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ipilimumab&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>ipilimumab</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se utiliza para tratar el melanoma que no se puede extirpar mediante cirugía o que se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo.  También se utiliza como terapia adyuvante contra el  melanoma en la piel y los ganglios linfáticos en pacientes que se sometieron a cirugía. El ipilimumab también está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El ipilimumab se une a una sustancia que se llama CTLA-4, la cual se encuentra en la superficie de las células T (un tipo de glóbulo blanco). El ipilimumab puede impedir la acción de la CTLA-4 y ayudar al sistema inmunitario a destruir células cancerosas. Es un tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal y un tipo de inhibidor de puntos de control inmunitario. También se llama MDX-010 y Yervoy.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-02-16</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2015-11-05</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000698294">Ipilimumab</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
