<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000534234"><TermName>charged-particle radiation therapy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… PAR-tih-kul RAY-dee-AY-shun THAYR-uh-pee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Charged particles (such as protons and carbon) can be used to deliver therapeutic radiation. A proton is the charged nucleus of a hydrogen atom (hydrogen atom minus an electron).  Standard radiation is delivered with a linear accelerator (LINAC) that delivers photon therapy (akin to high energy light), while protons and other charged particles are generated from a cyclotron. The difference between charged-particle and photon irradiation is that charged particles stop abruptly in the tissue (Bragg peak), so there is less exit dose through normal tissue. A disadvantage of charged-particle therapy is the greater neutron exposure compared with essentially none using photons, and thus the benefit of protons in reducing radiation-associated malignancies is not known and controversial. Proton therapy can be used to deliver intensity-modulated radiation therapy, stereotactic radiation therapy, or stereotactic radiosurgery.</DefinitionText><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of external radiation therapy that uses a special machine to make invisible, high-energy particles (protons or helium ions) that kill cancer cells. This type of radiation may cause less damage to nearby healthy tissue than radiation therapy with high-energy x-rays.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718701" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;charged-particle radiation therapy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000718700" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;radioterapia con partículas cargadas&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>radioterapia con partículas cargadas</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Partículas con carga eléctrica (como los protones y los carbonos) que se usan en la adminstración de radiación terapéutica.  Un protón conforma el núcleo cargado de un átomo de hidrógeno (un átomo de hidrógeno menos un electrón).   La radiación estándar se administra con un acelerador lineal (LINAC) que administra terapia con fotones (similar a la luz de alta energía), mientras que los protones y otras partículas con carga eléctrica se generan de un ciclotron.  La diferencia entre la partícula con carga eléctrica y la irradiación de un fotón es que la partículas con carga eléctrica para de manera abrupta en el tejido (Bragg peak), de tal manera que hay menos salida de dosis a través del tejido normal.  Una desventaja de la terapia con partículas eléctricamente cargadas  es la exposición mayor de neutrones en comparación con prácticamente ninguna cuando se usan fotones y por tanto el beneficio de los protones en la reducción de cánceres relacionados con la radiación es desconocido y polémico.  La terapia con protón se puede usar en la administración de radioterapia de intensidad modulada, la radioterapia estereotáctica y la radiocirugía estereotáctica.</DefinitionText><Audience>Health professional</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de radioterapia externa en la que se usa una máquina especial para producir partículas invisibles de alta energía (protones o iones de helio) que destruyen las células cancerosas. Este tipo de radiación puede ocasionar menos daños al tejido sano cercano que la radioterapia con rayos X de alta energía.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-07-06</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
