<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000561720"><TermName>signaling pathway</TermName><TermPronunciation>(SIG-nuh-ling …)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Describes a group of molecules in a cell that work together to control one or more cell functions, such as cell division or cell death. After the first molecule in a pathway receives a signal, it activates another molecule.  This process is repeated until the last molecule is activated and the cell function  is carried out. Abnormal activation of signaling pathways can lead to cancer, and drugs are being developed to block these pathways.  These drugs may help block cancer cell growth and kill cancer cells.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720675" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;signaling pathway&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720674" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;vía de señalización&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>vía de señalización</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Describe un grupo de moléculas de una célula que trabajan juntas para controlar una o más funciones de las células, como la multiplicación celular o la muerte celular. Después de que la primera molécula en una vía de señalización recibe una señal, esta activa a las otras moléculas. Este proceso se repite hasta que la última molécula se activa y la célula realiza la función. La activación anormal de las vías de señalización puede conducir a un cáncer y se están creando medicamentos nuevos para bloquear estas vías. Estos medicamentos pueden ayudar a impedir el crecimiento de células cancerosas y destruirlas.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-11-06</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2012-10-15</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
