<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000579676"><TermName>Y 90 ibritumomab tiuxetan</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... ih-brih-TOO-moh-mab ty-UK-seh-tan)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used with the drug rituximab to treat certain types of B-cell non-Hodgkin lymphoma. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of B-cell tumors. Y 90 ibritumomab tiuxetan contains a monoclonal antibody that binds to a protein called CD20, which is found on B cells. It also contains a radioactive substance called yttrium Y 90, which may help kill cancer cells. Y 90 ibritumomab tiuxetan is a type of radioimmunoconjugate. Also called IDEC-Y2B8, Y 90 Zevalin,  and yttrium Y 90 ibritumomab tiuxetan.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720471" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Y 90 ibritumomab tiuxetan&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720470" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Y 90 ibritumomab tiuxetán&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Y 90 ibritumomab tiuxetán</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa con el  rituximab para tratar ciertos tipos de linfoma no Hodgkin de células B. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de tumores de células B. Y90 ibritumomab tiuxetán contiene un anticuerpo monoclonal que se une con una proteína que se llama CD20, la cual se encuentra en las células B. Asimismo, contiene una sustancia radiactiva que se llama itrio Y 90, la cual puede ayudar a destruir células cancerosas. Y90 ibritumomab tiuxetán es un tipo de radioinmunoconjugado. También se llama IDEC-Y2B8, itrio Y 90 ibritumomab tiuxetán,  y Y 90 Zevalin.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2007-11-30</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-01-15</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
