<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000698780"><TermName>neuromyotonia</TermName><TermPronunciation>(NOOR-oh-MY-oh-TOH-nee-uh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare nerve disorder that causes constant muscle activity that cannot be controlled, even during sleep. It often affects the muscles in the arms and legs, but may affect the whole body. Symptoms include muscle twitching, weakness, stiffness, and cramping; increased skin temperature, sweating, and heart rate; and problems with chewing, swallowing, speech, and breathing. The disorder often gets worse over time. Neuromyotonia usually occurs in people aged 15 to 60 years. It may occur with certain types of cancer and is sometimes inherited. Also called Isaac syndrome.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733267" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;neuromyotonia&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733268" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;neuromiotonía&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>neuromiotonía</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno nervioso poco frecuente que provoca una constante actividad muscular que no se puede controlar, aun cuando se duerme. A menudo afecta los músculos de los brazos y las piernas, pero puede afectar todo el cuerpo. Los síntomas incluyen contracciones musculares, debilidad, contracturas y retortijones;  aumento de la temperatura de la piel, de los sudores y de la frecuencia cardíaca,  y problemas para masticar, tragar, hablar y respirar. El trastorno a menudo empeora con el transcurso del tiempo.  La neuromiotonía habitualmente se presenta en personas de 15 a 60 años. El trastorno se puede presentar con ciertos tipos de cáncer y, a veces, es  hereditario. También se llama síndrome de Isaac.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2011-08-17</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
