<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000666663"><TermName>Bloom-Torre-Machacek syndrome</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... TOR-ay-muh-HA-chek SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare, inherited disorder marked by height that is shorter than average, a narrow face with redness and a rash, a high-pitched voice, and fertility problems. Patients with this disorder have an increased risk of cancer, especially leukemia and osteosarcoma (bone cancer). Bloom-Torre-Machacek syndrome is caused by changes in a protein that normally helps cells make copies of the DNA. Changes in this protein cause many breaks, rearrangements, and other mutations in the DNA. It is a type of autosomal recessive genetic disease. Also called Bloom syndrome.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000725986" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Bloom-Torre-Machacek syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000725987" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de Bloom-Torre-Machacek&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>síndrome de Bloom-Torre-Machacek</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno heredado poco frecuente que se caracteriza por una estatura más baja que el promedio, rostro delgado con enrojecimiento y dermatitis, voz aguda y problemas de fecundidad. Los pacientes de este trastorno tienen un mayor riesgo de cáncer, especialmente de leucemia y osteosarcoma (cáncer de hueso). La causa del síndrome de Bloom-Torre-Machacek son los cambios en una proteína que normalmente ayuda a las células a hacer copias del ADN.   Los cambios en esta proteína causan muchas interrupciones, reordenamientos y otras mutaciones en el ADN.   Es un tipo de enfermedad genética recesiva autosómica.   También se llama síndrome de Bloom.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-06-04</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
