<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000689082"><TermName>clinical trial phase</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KLIH-nih-kul TRY-ul fayz)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A part of the clinical research process that answers specific questions about whether treatments that are being studied work and are safe. Phase I trials test the best way to give a new treatment and the best dose. Phase II trials test whether a new treatment has an effect on the disease. Phase III trials compare the results of people taking a new treatment with the results of people taking the standard treatment. Phase IV trials are done using thousands of people after a treatment has been approved and marketed, to check for side effects that were not seen in the phase III trial.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733313" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;clinical trial phase&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733312" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;fase de un ensayo clínico&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>fase de un ensayo clínico</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Parte del proceso de investigación clínica que responde preguntas específicas sobre si un tratamiento en estudio es eficaz y seguro. Los ensayos de fase I prueban la mejor manera de administrar un tratamiento nuevo y la mejor dosis. Los ensayos de fase II prueban si un tratamiento nuevo tiene un efecto sobre la enfermedad. Los ensayos de fase III comparan los resultados de las personas que reciben un tratamiento nuevo con los resultados de las personas que reciben el tratamiento estándar. Los ensayos de fase IV se realizan con miles de personas después de que un tratamiento se aprueba y comercializa para determinar los efectos secundarios que no se observaron en el ensayo de fase III.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2011-08-18</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
