<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000682419"><TermName>stage IIB non-small cell lung cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... sel lung KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage II non-small cell lung cancer is divided into stages IIA and IIB. In stage IIB, cancer has spread to nearby lymph nodes on the same side of the chest as the tumor. Also, one or more of the following is true: (1) the tumor is larger than 5 centimeters but not larger than 7 centimeters; (2) cancer has spread to the main bronchus and is at least 2 centimeters below where the trachea joins the bronchus (3) cancer has spread to the innermost layer of the membrane that covers the lung; and/or (4) part of the lung has collapsed or become inflamed. OR in stage IIB, cancer has not spread to lymph nodes and one or more of the following is true: (1) the tumor is larger than 7 centimeters; (2) cancer has spread to the main bronchus (and is less than 2 centimeters below where the trachea joins the bronchus), the chest wall, the diaphragm, or the nerve that controls the diaphragm; (3) cancer has spread to the membrane around the heart or lining the chest wall; (4) the whole lung has collapsed or become inflamed; and/or (5) there are one or more separate tumors in the same lobe of the lung.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000727572" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IIB non-small cell lung cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000727571" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio IIB&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000682110" type="image/jpeg" alt="Two-panel drawing of stage IIB non-small cell lung cancer. First panel shows cancer (more than 5 cm but not more than 7 cm), and cancer in the right main bronchus and lymph nodes; also shown are the trachea, bronchioles, and diaphragm. Inset shows cancer that has spread from the lung to the innermost layer of the lung lining; a rib is also shown. Second panel shows cancer (more than 7 cm), and cancer in the left main bronchus; also shown are the trachea, lymph nodes, bronchioles, and diaphragm. Top inset shows cancer that has spread from the lung through the lung lining and chest wall lining into the chest wall; a rib is also shown.  Bottom inset shows the heart and cancer that has spread from the lung into the membrane around the heart." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Stage IIB non-small cell lung cancer. Cancer has spread to certain lymph nodes on the same side of the chest as the primary tumor; the cancer is (a) larger than 5 cm but not larger than 7 cm, (b) has spread to the main bronchus, and/or (c) has spread to the innermost layer of the lung lining. Part of the lung may have collapsed or become inflamed (not shown). OR, (d) the cancer is larger than 7 cm; (e) has spread to the main bronchus, (f) the diaphragm, (g) the chest wall or the lining of the chest wall; and/or (h) has spread to the membrane around the heart. There may be one or more separate tumors in the same lobe of the lung; cancer may have spread to the nerve that controls the diaphragm; the whole lung may have collapsed or become inflamed (not shown).</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000686747" type="image/jpeg" alt="Dibujo en dos paneles del cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio IIB. El primer panel muestra un cáncer (más de 5 cm, pero no más de 7 cm) y  cáncer en el bronquio principal derecho y los ganglios linfáticos; también muestra la tráquea, los bronquiolos y el diafragma. El recuadro muestra el cáncer que se diseminó desde el pulmón hasta la capa más interna del revestimiento del pulmón; asimismo, se muestra una costilla. El segundo panel muestra  cáncer (más de 7 cm) y el cáncer en el bronquio principal izquierdo, también se muestran la tráquea, los ganglios linfáticos, los bronquiolos y el diafragma. El recuadro superior muestra  cáncer que se diseminó desde el pulmón, a través del revestimiento del pulmón y el revestimiento de la pared torácica, hacia la pared del pecho; también se muestra una costilla. El recuadro inferior muestra el corazón y  cáncer que se diseminó desde el pulmón hacia la membrana que rodea el corazón." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio IIB. El cáncer se diseminó hasta  ciertos ganglios linfáticos del mismo lado del pecho que el tumor primario. El cáncer: a) mide más de 5 cm, pero no más de 7 cm; b) se diseminó hasta el bronquio principal, o c) se diseminó hasta la capa más interna del revestimiento del pulmón. Una parte del pulmón se puede haber hundido o inflamado (no se muestra). O, d) el cáncer mide más de 7 cm;  e) se diseminó hasta el bronquio principal, f) el diafragma, g) la pared torácica o el revestimiento de la pared torácica; o, h) se diseminó hasta la membrana que rodea el corazón. Puede haber dos o más tumores separados en el mismo lóbulo del pulmón; el cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta el nervio que controla el diafragma; todo el pulmón se puede haber hundido o inflamado (no se muestra).</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio IIB</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio II se divide en estadios IIA y IIB. En el estadio IIB, el cáncer se diseminó hasta los ganglios linfáticos cercanos del mismo lado del pecho en el que está el tumor. Asimismo, se puede presentar una o más de las siguientes situaciones: 1) el tumor mide más de cinco centímetros, pero no más de siete centímetros; 2) el cáncer se diseminó hasta el bronquio principal y está por lo menos  2 centímetros por debajo del lugar donde la tráquea se une con el bronquio; 3) el cáncer se diseminó hasta la capa más interna de la membrana que cubre el pulmón, o 4) una parte del pulmón se colapsó o inflamó. O, en el estadio IIB, el cáncer no se diseminó hasta los ganglios linfáticos y se presenta una o más de las siguientes situaciones: 1) el tumor mide más de siete centímetros; 2) el cáncer se diseminó hasta el bronquio principal (y está a menos de dos centímetros por debajo del lugar donde la tráquea se une con el bronquio), la pared del pecho, el diafragma o el nervio que controla el diafragma; 3) el cáncer se diseminó hasta la membrana que rodea el corazón o el revestimiento de la pared del pecho; 4) todo el pulmón se colapsó o inflamó, o 5) hay uno o más tumores separados en el mismo lóbulo del pulmón.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-07-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2010-10-21</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062956">Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer Treatment </RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256766">Cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
