<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000690362"><TermName>Prolia</TermName><TermPronunciation>(PROH-lee-uh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to prevent or treat certain bone problems. Under the brand name Xgeva, it is used to prevent broken bones and other bone problems caused by solid tumors that have spread to bone. It is also used in certain patients to treat giant cell tumor of the bone that cannot be removed by surgery. Under the brand name Prolia, it is used to treat osteoporosis (a decrease in bone mass and density) in postmenopausal women who have a high risk of breaking bones. Prolia is also being studied in the treatment of other conditions and types of cancer. It binds to a protein called RANKL, which keeps RANKL from binding to another protein called RANK on the surface of certain bone cells, including bone cancer cells. This may help keep bone from breaking down and cancer cells from growing. Prolia is a type of monoclonal antibody. Also called AMG 162, denosumab,  and Xgeva.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000727542" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Prolia&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000727541" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Prolia&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Prolia</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para prevenir o tratar ciertos problemas óseos. Bajo la marca comercial Xgeva, se usa para prevenir fracturas y otros problemas óseos causados por tumores sólidos que se diseminaron hasta un hueso. También se usa para tratar a ciertos pacientes con tumor de hueso de células gigantes que no se puede extirpar mediante cirugía. Bajo la marca comercial Prolia, se usa para tratar la osteoporosis (disminución de la masa y la densidad óseas) en mujeres posmenopáusicas que tienen un riesgo alto de que sus huesos se fracturen. Prolia también está en estudio para el tratamiento de otras afecciones y tipos de cáncer. Se une a una proteína que se llama RANKL, que impide que RANKL se una a otra proteína de la superficie de ciertas células óseas, como células cancerosas en el hueso. Esto puede ayudar a impedir fracturas óseas y la formación de células cancerosas. Prolia es un tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal. También se llama AMG 162, denosumab,  y Xgeva.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-12-10</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-07-10</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000689968">Denosumab</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
