<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000618614"><TermName>risk ratio</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… RAY-shee-oh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A measure of the risk of a certain event happening in one group compared to the risk of the same event happening in another group. In cancer research, risk ratios are used in prospective (forward looking) studies, such as cohort studies and clinical trials. A risk ratio of one means there is no difference between two groups in terms of their risk of cancer, based on whether or not they were exposed to a certain substance or factor, or how they responded to two treatments being compared. A risk ratio of greater than one or of less than one usually means that being exposed to a certain substance or factor either increases (risk ratio greater than one) or decreases (risk ratio less than one) the risk of cancer, or that the treatments being compared do not have the same effects. Also called relative risk.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722527" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;risk ratio&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722528" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cociente de riesgos&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cociente de riesgos</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medida del riesgo de que cierta situación suceda en un grupo en comparación con el riesgo de que la misma situación suceda en otro grupo. En el campo de la investigación del cáncer, el cociente de riesgos se usa en los estudios prospectivos (mirada hacia adelante), tales como los estudios de cohorte y los ensayos clínicos. Un cociente de riesgos igual a 1 significa que no hay ninguna diferencia entre dos grupos en cuanto a su riesgo de contraer cáncer, sobre la base de si estuvieron o no estuvieron expuestos a una sustancia o factor determinados, o sobre la base de cómo respondieron a dos tratamientos que se comparan. Un cociente de riesgos mayor que 1 o menor que 1 significa por lo general significa que la exposición a cierta sustancia o factor determinados aumenta (cociente de riesgos mayor de 1) o disminuye (cociente de riesgos menor de uno) el riesgo de contraer cáncer, o que los tratamientos que se comparan no tienen los mismos efectos. También se llama riesgo relativo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-10-28</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
