<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000663330"><TermName>TACE</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure in which the blood supply to a tumor is blocked after anticancer drugs are given in blood vessels near the tumor. Sometimes, the anticancer drugs are attached to small beads that are injected into an artery that feeds the tumor. The beads block blood flow to the tumor as they release the drug. This allows a higher amount of drug to reach the tumor for a longer period of time, which may kill more cancer cells. It also causes fewer side effects because very little of the drug reaches other parts of the body. TACE is used to treat liver cancer. Also called chemoembolization and transarterial chemoembolization.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000734634" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;TACE&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><SpanishTermName>QETA</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento por el que se bloquea el suministro de sangre al tumor después de que se administran medicamentos contra el cáncer en los vasos sanguíneos cercanos al tumor. A veces, los medicamentos contra el cáncer se adhieren a perlas pequeñas que se inyectan en una arteria que alimenta el tumor.   Las perlas bloquean el flujo sanguíneo hacia el tumor a medida que liberan el medicamento.   Esto permite que una cantidad mayor de medicamento llegue al tumor durante un período más largo, que pueda destruir más células cancerosas.   También causa menos efectos secundarios porque muy poca cantidad del medicamento llega hasta otras partes del cuerpo. La QETA se usa para tratar el cáncer de hígado. También se llama quimioembolización y quimioembolización transarterial.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2012-04-12</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2012-04-11</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
