<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000661165"><TermName>bronchial brush biopsy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(BRON-kee-ul brush BY-op-see)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure in which cells are taken from the inside of the airways that lead to the lungs. A bronchoscope (a thin, tube-like instrument with a light and a lens for viewing) is inserted through the nose or mouth into the lungs.  A small brush is then used to remove cells from the airways.  These cells are then looked at under a microscope. A bronchial brush biopsy is used to find cancer and changes in cells that may lead to cancer. It is also used to help diagnose other lung conditions. Also called bronchial brushing.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000725609" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;bronchial brush biopsy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000725608" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;biopsia con cepillo bronquial&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>biopsia con cepillo bronquial</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento mediante el que se toman células del interior de las vías respiratorias que conducen a los pulmones.   Se introduce un broncoscopio (tubo delgado con una luz y una lente para observar) a través de la nariz o la boca hasta los pulmones.   Luego se usa un cepillo pequeño para extraer células de las vías respiratorias.   Estas células luego se observan bajo un microscopio.   La biopsia con cepillo bronquial se usa para encontrar cáncer y cambios en las células que pueden conducir al cáncer.   También se usa para ayudar a diagnosticar otras afecciones de pulmón.   También se llama cepillado bronquial.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-03-30</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
