<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000686209"><TermName>virus-like particle</TermName><TermPronunciation>(VY-rus-like PAR-tih-kul)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A small particle that contains certain proteins from the outer coat of a virus. Virus-like particles do not contain any genetic material from the virus and cannot cause an infection. They are used to make vaccines that can help the body’s immune system kill microorganisms and certain cancer cells. Virus-like particles were used to make vaccines that prevent cervical cancer caused by human papilloma viruses (HPV).  They were also used to make vaccines that prevent liver cancer caused by infection with the hepatitis B virus.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000727521" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;virus-like particle&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000727522" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;partícula similar a un virus&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>partícula similar a un virus</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Partícula pequeña que contiene ciertas proteínas de la cubierta exterior de un virus.   Las partículas similares a los virus no contienen ningún material genético del virus y no pueden causa infección.   Se usan para elaborar las vacunas que ayudan al sistema inmunitario del cuerpo a destruir microorganismos y ciertas células cancerosas.   Estas  partículas se usaron en la producción de  vacunas que previenen el cáncer de cuello uterino por el papilomavirus humano (PVH).   También se usaron en la elaboración de vacunas que previenen el cáncer de hígado por la infección con el virus de la hepatitis B.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-09-23</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
