<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000635889"><TermName>Paraplatin</TermName><TermPronunciation>(PAYR-uh-PLA-tin)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug that is used to treat advanced ovarian cancer that has never been treated or symptoms of ovarian cancer that has come back after treatment with other anticancer drugs. It is also used with other drugs to treat advanced, metastatic, or recurrent non-small cell lung cancer and is being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Paraplatin is a form of the anticancer drug cisplatin and causes fewer side effects in patients. It attaches to DNA in cells and may kill cancer cells. It is a type of platinum compound. Also called carboplatin.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722940" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Paraplatin&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722939" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Paraplatin&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Paraplatin</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para tratar el cáncer avanzado de los ovarios que nunca se ha sometido a tratamiento o para los síntomas de cáncer de ovario que reapareció después del tratamiento con otros medicamentos contra el cáncer. También se usa con otros medicamentos para tratar el cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas avanzado, metastásico o recidivante y está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Paraplatin es una forma del medicamento contra el cáncer cisplatino el cual causa menos efectos secundarios en los pacientes. Este se une al ADN de las células y puede destruir las células cancerosas. Es un tipo de compuesto de platino. También se llama carboplatino.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2009-02-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2010-05-05</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000557107">Carboplatin</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
