<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000616060"><TermName>active surveillance</TermName><TermPronunciation>(AK-tiv ser-VAY-lents)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A treatment plan that involves closely watching a patient’s condition but not giving any treatment unless there are changes in test results that show the condition is getting worse. Active surveillance may be used to avoid or delay the need for treatments such as radiation therapy or surgery, which can cause side effects or other problems. During active surveillance, certain exams and tests are done on a regular schedule. It may be used in the treatment of certain types of cancer, such as prostate cancer, urethral cancer, and intraocular (eye) melanoma. It is a type of expectant management.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000721150" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;active surveillance&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000721149" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;vigilancia activa&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>vigilancia activa</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Plan de tratamiento que incluye la observación minuciosa del estado de un paciente sin administrarle ningún tratamiento, a menos que haya cambios en los resultados de las pruebas que muestren que la afección está empeorando. La vigilancia activa se puede usar para evitar o retrasar la necesidad de tratamientos como la radioterapia o la cirugía, los cuales pueden producir efectos secundarios u otros problemas. Durante la vigilancia activa, se realizan algunos exámenes y pruebas de manera regular. Esta se puede usar en el tratamiento de ciertos tipos de cáncer, como cáncer de próstata, cáncer de uretra y melanoma ocular. Es un tipo de conducta expectante.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-09-26</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-06-20</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
