<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000633090"><TermName>helical tomotherapy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(HEE-lih-kul toh-mah-THAYR-uh-pee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of therapy in which radiation is aimed at a tumor from many different directions. The patient lays on a table and is moved through a donut-shaped  machine. The radiation source in the machine rotates around the patient in a spiral pattern.  Before radiation, a 3-dimensional (3-D) image of the tumor is taken. This helps doctors find the highest dose of radiation that can be used to kill tumor cells while causing less damage to nearby tissue. Helical tomotherapy is a type of intensity-modulated radiation therapy (IMRT). Also called tomotherapy.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722617" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;helical tomotherapy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722618" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tomoterapia helicoidal&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>tomoterapia helicoidal</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de tratamiento mediante el cual se enfoca la radación en el tumor desde muchas direcciones distintas. El paciente se acuesta en una camilla que se mueve a través de una máquina con forma de  rosca o "salvavida". La fuente de radiación de la máquina rota alrededor del paciente en forma de espiral. Antes de administrar la radiación se obtiene una imagen tridimensional del tumor (3-D). Esto ayuda al médico a determinar la mayor dosis  de radiación que se puede usar para destruir las células cancerosas a la vez que se causa el menor daño posible al tejido vecino. La tomoterapia helicoidal es un tipo de radioterapia de intensidad modulada (RIM). También se llama tomoterapia.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2009-04-24</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
