<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000626500"><TermName>Cushing syndrome</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KUSH-ing SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A condition in which there is too much cortisol (a hormone made by the outer layer of the adrenal gland) in the body. Cushing syndrome may be caused by taking too many steroid drugs or by certain types of tumors. Tumors that make adrenocorticotropic hormone (ACTH) cause the adrenal gland to make too much cortisol. Symptoms of Cushing syndrome include a round face, thin arms and legs, severe fatigue and muscle weakness, high blood pressure, high blood sugar, purple or pink stretch marks on the skin, and weight gain, especially in the abdomen.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704888" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Cushing syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000704889" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de Cushing&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>síndrome de Cushing</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección por la que hay demasiado cortisol (hormona que se elabora en la capa exterior de la glándula suprarrenal) en el cuerpo. El síndrome de Cushing puede ser causado por la toma de demasiados medicamentos esteroides o por ciertos tipos de tumor. Los tumores que elaboran demasiada hormona adrenocorticotrópica (HACT) hacen que la glándula suprarrenal elabore demasiado cortisol. Los síntomas del síndrome de Cushing incluyen cara redonda, brazos y piernas delgadas, fatiga grave y debilidad muscular, presión arterial alta y concentración alta de azúcar en la sangre, estrías púrpuras o rosadas en la piel, y aumento de peso, especialmente en el abdomen.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-11-25</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
