<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000660981"><TermName>PARP-1 inhibitor ABT-888</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… in-HIH-bih-ter …)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A substance being studied in the treatment of breast cancers caused by mutations (changes) in the BRCA1 and BRCA2 genes. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. It blocks an enzyme involved in many functions of the cell, including the repair of DNA damage. DNA damage may be caused by normal cell actions, UV light, some anticancer drugs, and radiation used to treat cancer. PARP-1 inhibitor ABT-888 may cause cancer cells to die. It is a type of poly(ADP-ribose) polymerase inhibitor. Also called ABT-888 and veliparib.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000726219" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;PARP-1 inhibitor ABT-888&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000726218" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;inhibidor de PARP-1 ABT-888&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>inhibidor de PARP-1 ABT-888</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Sustancia en estudio para el tratamiento del cáncer de mama causado por mutaciones (cambios) en los genes BRCA1 y BRCA2. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Bloquea la acción de una enzima que participa en muchas funciones celulares, incluso la reparación del daño en el ADN. El daño al ADN se puede deber al funcionamiento normal de las células, la luz UV, ciertos medicamentos contra el cáncer y la radiación que se usa para tratar el cáncer. El inhibidor de PARP-1 ABT-888  podría destruir células cancerosas. Es un un tipo de inhibidor de la polimerasa poli (ADP-ribosa). También se llama ABT-888 y veliparib.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2009-12-04</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2009-12-04</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
