<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000663321"><TermName>rosuvastatin calcium</TermName><TermPronunciation>(roh-SOO-vuh-STA-tin KAL-see-um)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to lower the amount of cholesterol and other harmful substances, such as triglycerides, in the blood. It is also being studied in the prevention and treatment of some types of cancer and other conditions.  Rosuvastatin calcium blocks an enzyme that helps make cholesterol in the body and it helps break down cholesterol. It also may cause cancer cells to die and may inhibit  the growth of blood vessels that cancer cells need to grow.  It is a type of HMG-CoA reductase inhibitor and a type of statin. Also called Crestor.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000725868" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;rosuvastatin calcium&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000725869" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;rosuvastatina cálcica&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>rosuvastatina cálcica</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para disminuir la cantidad de colesterol y otras sustancias dañinas, como los triglicéridos, en la sangre.   Asimismo, está en estudio para la prevención y el tratamiento de algunos tipos de cáncer y otras afecciones. La rosuvastatina cálcica impide la acción de una enzima que ayuda a producir colesterol en el cuerpo y ayuda a descomponer el colesterol.   También puede eliminar células cancerosas e impedir el crecimiento de los vasos sanguíneos que las células cancerosas necesitan para crecer. Es un tipo de inhibidor de la HMG-CoA reductasa y un tipo de estatina.   También se llama Crestor.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-06-03</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
