<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000634971"><TermName>investigational agent</TermName><TermPronunciation>(in-VES-tih-GAY-shuh-nul AY-jent)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A substance
          that has been tested in the laboratory and has been
          approved by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) for
          testing in people. Clinical trials test how well
          investigational agents work and whether they are
          safe to use. An investigational agent may be
          approved by the FDA for use in one disease or condition but
          still be considered investigational in other diseases or
          conditions. Also called experimental drug, IND, investigational drug,  and investigational new drug.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722510" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;investigational agent&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722509" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sustancia en fase investigación&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>sustancia en fase de investigación</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Sustancia que se analizó en el
laboratorio y que obtuvo la aprobación de la Administración
de Alimentos y Medicamentos de los Estados Unidos (FDA)
para probarla en seres humanos. En los ensayos clínicos, se
estudia qué tan bien funciona una sustancia en fase de investigación y
si su administración es segura. La FDA puede aprobar
una sustancia en fase de investigación para una enfermedad o afección
pero, aun así, considerarla en fase de
investigación clínica para otras enfermedades o
afecciones. También se llama IND, medicamento en fase de investigación clínica, medicamento en fase experimental,  y medicamento nuevo en fase de investigación.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2009-02-20</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2014-09-17</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/drugs/investigational-drug-access-fact-sheet">Access
to Investigational
Drugs</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
