<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000636780"><TermName>GWAS</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A study that compares DNA markers across the genome (the complete genetic material in a person) in people with a disease or trait to people without the disease or trait. These studies may uncover clues to help prevent, diagnose, and treat disease. Also called genome-wide association study.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A GWAS (genome-wide association study) is a way for scientists to identify inherited genetic variants associated with risk of disease or a particular trait. This method surveys the entire genome for genetic polymorphisms, typically single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) (pronounced “snips”), that occur more frequently in cases (people with the disease or trait being assessed) than in controls (people without the disease or trait).  Also called genome-wide association study.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000734665" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;GWAS&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><SpanishTermName>GWAS</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Estudio que compara los marcadores de ADN en todo el genoma (material genético completo de una persona) de las personas con una enfermedad o rasgos de enfermedad, con las personas sin esta enfermedad o rasgos. Estos estudios pueden descubrir la clave para prevenir, diagnosticar y tratar una enfermedad. También se llama estudio de asociación de genoma completo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2009-02-26</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-04-23</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.genome.gov/Glossary/index.cfm?id=91">Genome-Wide Association Studies (GWAS)</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.genome.gov/GlossaryS/index.cfm?id=91">Estudio de asociación de genoma completo (GWAS)
</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
