<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000613507"><TermName>chimeric</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ky-MEER-ik)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Having parts of different origins. In medicine, refers to a person, organ, or tissue that contains cells with different genes than the rest of the person, organ, or tissue. This may happen because of a mutation (genetic change) that occurs during development, or as a result of a transplant of cells, organs, or tissues from another person or from a different species. In the laboratory, a chimeric protein can be made by combining two different genes. For example, a chimeric antibody is made by joining antibody genes from two different species, such as human and mouse.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720918" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;chimeric&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720919" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;híbrido&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>híbrido</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>En el campo de la medicina, algo formado con partes de orígenes diferentes. Se refiere a una persona, órgano o tejido que contiene células con genes diferentes al resto de la persona, órgano o tejido. Esto puede suceder debido a una mutación (cambio genético) que se presenta durante el desarrollo o como resultado de un trasplante de células, órganos o tejidos de otra persona o de una especie distinta. En el laboratorio, se puede producir una proteína híbrida al combinar dos genes diferentes. Por ejemplo, un anticuerpo híbrido, también conocido como anticuerpo quimérico,  se produce uniendo genes de anticuerpos de dos especies diferentes; por ejemplo, de un ser humano y de un ratón.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-08-29</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
