<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000618610"><TermName>odds ratio</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… RAY-shee-oh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A measure of the odds of an event happening in one group compared to the odds of the same event happening in another group. In cancer research, odds ratios are most often used in case-control (backward looking) studies to find out if being exposed to a certain substance or other factor increases the risk of cancer. For example, researchers may study a group of individuals with cancer (cases) and another group without cancer (controls) to see how many people in each group were exposed to a certain substance or factor. They calculate the odds of exposure in both groups and then compare the odds. An odds ratio of one means that both groups had the same odds of exposure and, therefore, the exposure probably does not increase the risk of cancer. An odds ratio of greater than one means that the exposure may increase the risk of cancer, and an odds ratio of less than one means that the exposure may reduce the risk of cancer. Also called relative odds.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722520" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;odds ratio&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722519" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;oportunidad relativa&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>oportunidad relativa</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medida de las probabilidades de que una situación suceda en un grupo en comparación con las probabilidades de que la misma situación suceda en otro grupo. En el campo de la investigación del cáncer, las oportunidades relativas se usan con mayor frecuencia en estudios de casos y testigos (mirada hacia atrás) para determinar si la exposición a cierta sustancia u otro factor aumenta el riesgo de contraer cáncer. Por ejemplo, los investigadores pueden estudiar un grupo de individuos con cáncer (casos) y otro grupo sin cáncer (testigos) para ver cuántas personas de cada grupo estuvieron expuestas a cierta sustancia o factor. Calculan las posibilidades de exposición en ambos grupos y luego comparan las probabilidades. Una oportunidad relativa de 1 significa que ambos grupos tuvieron la misma probabilidad de exposición y, por consiguiente, la exposición probablemente no aumenta el riesgo de cáncer. Una oportunidad relativa mayor de 1 significa que la exposición puede aumentar el riesgo de contraer cáncer y una oportunidad relativa de menos de 1 significa que la exposición puede reducir el riesgo de contraer cáncer. También se llama probabilidad relativa.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-10-28</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
