<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000658053"><TermName>poly (ADP-ribose) polymerase inhibitor</TermName><TermPronunciation>(PAH-lee (... RY-bose) puh-LIH-meh-rays in-HIH-bih-ter)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A substance that blocks an enzyme in cells called PARP. PARP  helps repair DNA when it becomes damaged. DNA damage may be caused by many things, including exposure to UV light, radiation, certain anticancer drugs, or other substances in the environment. In cancer treatment, blocking PARP may help keep cancer cells from repairing their damaged DNA, causing them to die. Poly (ADP-ribose) polymerase inhibitors are a type of targeted therapy. Also called PARP inhibitor.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000725856" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;poly (ADP-ribose) polymerase inhibitor&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000725857" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;inhibidor de la poli (ADP-ribosa) polimerasa&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>inhibidor de la poli (ADP-ribosa) polimerasa</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Sustancia que
          impide la acción de una enzima que se llama PARP en las células, ayuda a la reparación del ADN cuando esta sufre daños. Muchas cosas pueden causar daño al ADN, como la exposición a los rayos UV, radiación,  ciertos medicamentos contra el cáncer u otras sustancias en el medio ambiente. En el tratamiento de cáncer, impedir la acción del PARP puede impedir que las células cancerosas reparen el daño a su ADN causándoles la muerte. Los   inhibidores de la poli (ADP-ribosa) polimerasa son un tipo de
          terapia dirigida. También se llama inhibidor de PARP.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2009-12-01</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2015-04-16</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
