<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000688832"><TermName>comprehensive pediatric cancer center</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KOM-pree-HEN-siv pee-dee-A-trik ...)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A cancer research center that gets support from the National Cancer Institute (NCI). Scientists and doctors at these centers do basic laboratory research and clinical trials on childhood cancers, and they study the patterns, causes, and control of cancer in groups of children. Also, they treat patients from many parts of the country and give cancer information to health care professionals and the public. More information about the NCI Cancer Centers Program can be found on the NCI's Web site at <ExternalRef xref="http://cancercenters.cancer.gov/">http://cancercenters.cancer.gov/</ExternalRef>.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733056" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;comprehensive pediatric cancer center&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733055" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;centro integral del cáncer pediátrico&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>centro integral del cáncer pediátrico</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Centro de investigación del cáncer que recibe apoyo del Instituto Nacional del Cáncer (NCI). Los científicos y médicos de esos centros realizan investigaciones básicas de laboratorio y conducen ensayos clínicos sobre cáncer infantil; estudian los patrones, las causas y las formas de controlar el cáncer en grupos de niños. Además, tratan a pacientes en muchos lugares del país y proporcionan información a los profesionales de la salud y el público. Para mayor información en inglés sobre el Programa de Centros Integrales del Cáncer consultar la página de Internet del NCI en el siguiente enlace: <ExternalRef xref="http://www3.cancer.gov/cancercenters/">http://cancercenters.cancer.gov/</ExternalRef>.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2011-08-17</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
