<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000689546"><TermName>consent process</TermName><TermPronunciation>(kun-SENT PRAH-ses)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A process in which patients are given important information, including possible risks and benefits, about a medical procedure or treatment, a clinical trial, or genetic testing. This is to help them decide if they want to be treated, tested, or take part in the trial. Patients are also given any new information that might affect their decision to continue. Also called informed consent.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A process of information exchange between a clinician and an individual or their legal proxy designed to facilitate autonomous, informed decision making. The informed consent process for genetic testing should include an explanation of the medical and psychosocial risks, benefits, limitations, and potential implications of genetic analysis, a discussion of privacy, confidentiality, the documentation and handling of genetic test results, as well as options for managing the hereditary disease risk. Also called informed consent.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Genetics</Dictionary><Audience>Health professional</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733250" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;consent process&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733249" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;proceso de consentimiento&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>proceso de consentimiento</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Proceso en el que se proporciona al paciente información importante que incluye los riesgos y beneficios posibles de un procedimiento o tratamiento médico, un ensayo clínico o prueba genética. Esto se lleva a cabo para ayudar a los pacientes a decidir si se quieren someterse a tratamientos o pruebas,  o si quieren participar en un ensayo clínico. También se proporciona a los pacientes cualquier información nueva que pudiera afectar su decisión de continuar. También se llama consentimiento con conocimiento de causa.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2011-08-25</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2011-08-17</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
