<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000638175"><TermName>vacuum-assisted core biopsy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(VA-kyoom-uh-SIS-ted … BY-op-see)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure in which a small sample of tissue is removed from the breast. An imaging device is used to guide a hollow probe connected to a vacuum device.  The probe is inserted through a tiny cut made in numbed skin on the breast. The tissue sample is removed using gentle vacuum suction and a small rotating knife within the probe. Then the tissue sample is studied under a microscope to check for signs of disease. This procedure causes very little scarring and no stitches are needed. Also called VACB and vacuum-assisted biopsy.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000723064" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;vacuum-assisted core biopsy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000723065" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;biopsia central asistida por vacío&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>biopsia central asistida por vacío</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento por el cual se extrae una muestra pequeña de tejido de la mama.   Se usa un equipo de imaginología para guiar una sonda hueca conectada a un dispositivo de succión. La sonda se inserta mediante un corte diminuto en la piel adormecida de la mama.   Se extrae la muestra de tejido mediante una succión suave y un cuchillo rotatorio pequeño dentro de la sonda.   Luego, la muestra de tejido se estudia bajo un microscopio para verificar la presencia de signos de enfermedad.   Este procedimiento produce una cicatriz muy ligera y no se necesita dar puntos. También se llama BCAV y biopsia asistida por vacío.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2009-04-10</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
