<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000658757"><TermName>3 Tesla magnetic resonance imaging</TermName><TermPronunciation>(3 TES-luh mag-NEH-tik REH-zuh-nunts IH-muh-jing)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure in which radio waves and a powerful magnet linked to a computer are used to make detailed pictures of areas inside the body. These pictures can show the difference between normal and abnormal tissue. 3 Tesla magnetic resonance imaging has a stronger magnet and makes better images of organs and soft tissue than other types of MRI do. It is used to make images of the brain, the spine, the soft tissue of joints, and the inside of bones and blood vessels.  Also called 3 Tesla MRI and 3T MRI.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000726096" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;3 Tesla magnetic resonance imaging&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000726097" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;imágenes por resonancia magnética de 3 teslas&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>imágenes por resonancia magnética de 3 teslas</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento para el que se usan ondas de radio y un imán potente unido a una computadora para producir imágenes detalladas de las áreas internas del cuerpo.   Estas imágenes pueden mostrar la diferencia entre el tejido normal y el anormal.   La máquina de imágenes por resonancia magnética de 3 teslas tiene un imán más potente y produce mejores imágenes de los órganos y el tejido blando que otros tipos de procedimientos de IRM. Se usa para obtener imágenes del cerebro, la columna vertebral, el tejido blando de las articulaciones, y el interior de los huesos y los vasos sanguíneos.   También se llama IRM 3T y IRM de 3 teslas.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-03-30</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
