<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000637631"><TermName>vinblastine sulfate</TermName><TermPronunciation>(vin-BLAS-teen SUL-fayt)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat several types of cancer, including breast cancer and a type of gestational trophoblastic tumor that  have not gotten better with other treatment, lymphoma, testicular cancer, Kaposi sarcoma, and mycosis fungoides. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Vinblastine sulfate blocks cell growth by stopping cell division and may kill cancer cells. It is a type of vinca alkaloid and a type of antimitotic agent. Also called Velban and Velsar.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722781" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;vinblastine sulfate&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722782" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sulfato de vinblastina&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>sulfato de vinblastina</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa con otros medicamentos para tratar varios tipos de cáncer, incluso cáncer de mama y un tipo de tumor trofoblástico gestacional que no mejoraron con otro tratamiento, linfoma, cáncer de testículo, sarcoma de Kaposi y micosis fungoides. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El sulfato de vinblastina bloquea la formación de células al impedir la multiplicación celular y puede destruir células cancerosas. Es un tipo de alcaloide de vinca y un tipo de antimitótico. También se llama Velban y Velsar.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2009-03-10</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2012-02-23</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000688288">Vinblastine Sulfate</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
