<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000660871"><TermName>PARP inhibitor AZD2281</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... in-HIH-bih-ter ...)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat advanced ovarian cancer caused by mutations (changes) in the BRCA1 and BRCA2 genes. It is used in patients who have already received other anticancer drugs. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. PARP inhibitor AZD2281 blocks an enzyme involved in many cell functions, including the repair of DNA damage. DNA damage may be caused by normal cell actions, UV light, some anticancer drugs, and radiation used to treat cancer. PARP inhibitor AZD2281 may cause cancer cells to die. It is a type of targeted therapy agent and a type of poly (ADP-ribose) polymerase inhibitor. Also called AZD2281, Lynparza,  and olaparib.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000726142" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;PARP inhibitor AZD2281&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000726143" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;inhibidor de PARP AZD2281&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>inhibidor de PARP AZD2281</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Sustancia en estudio para el tratamiento del cáncer de ovario en estadio avanzado   causado por mutaciones (cambios) en los genes BRCA1 y BRCA2. Se usa en pacientes que ya recibieron otros medicamentos contra el cáncer. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El inhibidor de PARP AZD2281 bloquea una enzima que participa en muchas funciones celulares, como la reparación del ADN dañado. El daño en el ADN se puede deber al funcionamiento normal de las células, la luz UV y algunos medicamentos contra el cáncer, así como a la radiación que se usa para tratar el cáncer. El inhibidor de PARP AZD2281 podría destruir células cancerosas. Es un tipo de sustancia que se usa para la terapia dirigida y un tipo de inhibidor de la polimerasa poli (ADP-ribosa). También se llama AZD2281, Lynparza,  y olaparib.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2009-12-01</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2014-12-27</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000767622">Olaparib</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
