<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000617664"><TermName>heat-shock protein</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... PROH-teen)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>One of a group of proteins that help protect cells from stresses such as heat, cold, and low amounts of oxygen or glucose (sugar). Heat-shock proteins help other proteins function in normal cells and may be present at high levels in cancer cells. Blocking the activity of a heat-shock protein called HSP90 is being studied in the treatment of cancer. Other heat-shock proteins including HSP70 and gp96 are being studied in vaccines to treat cancer. Also called HSP and stress protein.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000723050" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;heat-shock protein&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000723051" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;proteína de choque térmico&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>proteína de choque térmico</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Pertenece a un grupo de proteínas que ayudan a proteger las células del estrés que les producen elementos como el calor, el frío y las cantidades bajas de oxígeno o glucosa (azúcar). Las proteínas de choque térmico ayudan a funcionar a las otras proteínas de las células normales y pueden estar presentes en concentraciones altas en las células cancerosas. Está en estudio el bloqueo de la actividad de una  proteína de choque térmico que se llama HSP90 para el tratamiento de cáncer. Otras proteínas de choque térmico, como la HSP70 y la gp96, están en estudio en vacunas para tratar el cáncer. También se llama HSP y proteína de estrés.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-10-15</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2008-11-21</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
