<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000635448"><TermName>normal range</TermName><TermPronunciation>(NOR-mul raynj)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>In medicine, a set of values that a doctor uses to interpret a patient’s test results.  The normal range for a given test is based on the results that are seen in 95% of the healthy population.  Sometimes patients whose test results are outside of the normal range may be healthy, and some patients whose test results are within the normal range may have a health problem. The normal range for a test may be different for different groups of people (for example, men and women). Also called reference interval, reference range,  and reference values.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722738" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;normal range&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722737" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;límite normal&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>límite normal</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>En el campo de la medicina, conjunto de valores que el médico utiliza para interpretar los resultados de las pruebas en un paciente. El límite normal para una prueba determinada se basa en los resultados de la prueba en el 95% de la población sana. A veces, los pacientes cuyos resultados están fuera  del límite normal pueden estar sanos y algunos pacientes cuyos resultados están dentro del límite normal pueden tener un problema de salud. El límite normal de una prueba puede ser diferente en distintos grupos de personas (por ejemplo, entre mujeres y hombres). También se llama intervalo de referencia, límite de referencia,  y valores de referencia.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2009-04-10</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2012-05-15</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
