<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000666667"><TermName>erythrogenesis imperfecta</TermName><TermPronunciation>(eh-RITH-roh-JEH-neh-sis IM-per-FEK-tuh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A very rare disorder in which the bone marrow doesn’t make enough red blood cells. It is usually seen in the first year of life.  Patients may have deformed thumbs and other physical problems. They also have an increased risk of leukemia and sarcoma, especially osteosarcoma (bone cancer). Patients with erythrogenesis imperfecta may have a mutation (change) in one of the genes that make proteins found in the cell’s ribosomes. Also called Blackfan–Diamond anemia, congenital hypoplastic anemia, congenital pure red cell aplasia, DBA, Diamond-Blackfan anemia,  and inherited erythroblastopenia.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000725992" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;erythrogenesis imperfecta&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000725993" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;eritrogénesis imperfecta&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>eritrogénesis imperfecta</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno muy poco frecuente por el que la médula ósea no produce suficientes glóbulos rojos. Habitualmente se observa en el primer año de vida. Los pacientes pueden tener los pulgares deformados y otros problemas físicos. También tienen un riesgo más alto de padecer de leucemia y sarcoma, especialmente osteosarcoma (cáncer de hueso). Los pacientes de eritrogénesis imperfecta pueden tener una mutación (cambio) en uno de los genes que elabora proteínas que se encuentran en los ribosomas de la célula.   También se llama ADB, anemia de Blackfan–Diamond, anemia de Diamond-Blackfan, anemia hipoplásica congénita, aplasia eritrocitaria pura congénita,  y eritroblastopenia hereditaria.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-06-04</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
