<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000698783"><TermName>panhypopituitarism</TermName><TermPronunciation>(pan-HY-poh-pih-TOO-ih-tuh-rih-zum)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare condition in which the pituitary gland stops making most or all hormones. Pituitary hormones help control the way many parts of the body work. Symptoms of the condition depend on the hormones that are missing. They include growth problems (in children), obesity (in adults), hair loss, slow heart rate, low blood sugar, low blood pressure, fatigue, and problems with reproduction. This condition may be caused by a tumor on or near the pituitary gland, infection, stroke, injury, surgery, or radiation therapy.  It may also be inherited. Also called PHP.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733274" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;panhypopituitarism&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733275" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;panhipopituitarismo&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>panhipopituitarismo</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección poco frecuente por la que la hipófisis deja de elaborar la mayoría de las hormonas. Las hormonas hipofisiarias ayudan a controlar el modo en que funcionan muchas partes del cuerpo. Los síntomas de la afección dependen de las hormonas que faltan. Incluyen problemas de crecimiento (en los niños), obesidad (en los adultos), pérdida de cabello, concentración baja de azúcar en la sangre, presión arterial baja, fatiga y problemas para la reproducción. La causa de esta afección puede ser un tumor en la hipófisis o cerca de ella, infecciones, accidentes cerebrovasculares, lesiones, cirugía o radioterapia. También puede ser hereditaria. También se llama PHP.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2011-08-17</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
