<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000666694"><TermName>ultraviolet A radiation</TermName><TermPronunciation>(UL-truh-VY-oh-let A RAY-dee-AY-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Invisible rays that are part of the energy that comes from the sun. Ultraviolet A radiation also comes from sun lamps and tanning beds. Ultraviolet A radiation may cause premature aging of the skin and skin cancer. It may also cause problems with the eyes and the immune system. Skin specialists recommend that people use sunscreens that protect the skin from ultraviolet radiation. In medicine, ultraviolet A radiation also comes from special lamps or a laser and is used to treat certain skin conditions such as psoriasis, vitiligo, and skin tumors of cutaneous T-cell lymphoma. Also called UVA radiation.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000726024" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ultraviolet A radiation&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000726025" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;radiación ultravioleta A&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>radiación ultravioleta A</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Rayos invisibles que forman parte de la energía que viene del sol. La radiación ultravioleta A también proviene de lámparas solares y camillas de bronceado. La radiación ultravioleta A puede causar envejecimiento prematuro de la piel y cáncer de piel. También puede causar problemas en los ojos y el sistema inmunitario. Los especialistas de la piel recomiendan que las personas usen filtros solares que protegen la piel de la radiación ultravioleta. En el campo de la medicina, la radiación ultravioleta A también surge de lámparas o rayos láser especiales que se usan para tratar ciertas afecciones de la piel como soriasis, vitiligo y tumores de la piel causa del linfoma cutáneo de células T. También se llama radiación UVA.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-06-08</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2010-06-14</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
