<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000629155"><TermName>vitamin B3</TermName><TermPronunciation>(VY-tuh-min …)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A nutrient in the vitamin B complex that the body needs in small amounts to function and stay healthy. Vitamin B3 helps some enzymes work properly and helps skin, nerves, and the digestive tract stay healthy. Vitamin B3 is found in many plant and animal products. It is water-soluble (can dissolve in water) and must be taken in every day. Not enough vitamin B3 can cause a disease called pellagra (a condition marked by skin, nerve, and digestive disorders). A form of vitamin B3 is being studied in the prevention of skin and other types of cancer. Vitamin B3 may help to lower blood cholesterol.  Also called niacin and nicotinic acid.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722687" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;vitamin B3&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722688" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;vitamina B3&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>vitamina B3</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Nutriente del complejo de la vitamina B que el cuerpo necesita en pequeñas cantidades para funcionar y mantenerse sano. La vitamina B3 ayuda a algunas enzimas a funcionar correctamente y ayuda a que la piel, los nervios y el aparato digestivo se mantengan saludables. La vitamina B3 se encuentra en muchos productos vegetales y animales. Es soluble en agua (puede disolverse en agua) y debe tomarse todos los días. La insuficiencia de vitamina B3 puede causar una enfermedad que se llama pelagra (una afección caracterizada por trastornos en la piel, los nervios y la digestión). Una forma de vitamina B3 está en estudio para la prevención del cáncer de piel y de otros tipos de cáncer. La vitamina B3 puede ayudar a disminuir el colesterol en la sangre. También se llama ácido nicotínico y niacina.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-12-05</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
