<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000633224"><TermName>stem cell factor receptor</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… sel FAK-ter reh-SEP-ter)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A protein found on the surface of many different types of cells. It binds to a substance called stem cell factor (SCF), which causes certain types of blood cells to grow. Stem cell factor receptor may also be found in higher than normal amounts, or in a changed form, on some types of cancer cells, including gastrointestinal stromal tumors and melanoma. Measuring the amount of stem cell factor receptor in tumor tissue may help diagnose cancer and plan treatment. Stem cell factor receptor is a type of receptor tyrosine kinase and a type of tumor marker. Also called c-kit and CD117.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722667" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stem cell factor receptor&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722668" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;receptor del factor de células madre&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>receptor del factor de células madre</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Proteína que se encuentra en la superficie de muchos tipos diferentes de células. Se une a una sustancia  llamada factor de células madre (SCF), que hace que ciertos tipos de células sanguíneas crezcan. El  receptor del factor de células madre se puede encontrar en concentraciones más altas de lo normal, o en forma cambiada en algunos tipos de células cancerosas, como en los tumores del estroma gastrointestinal y el melanoma. La medición de la cantidad de receptor del factor de células madre  en el tejido tumoral puede ayudar a diagnosticar el cáncer y planificar el tratamiento. El receptor del factor de células madre  es un tipo de receptor de la tirosina cinasa y de marcador tumoral. También se llama CD117 y receptor c-kit.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-12-16</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2012-10-15</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
