<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000661960"><TermName>therapeutic touch</TermName><TermPronunciation>(THAYR-uh-PYOO-tik tuch)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A form of complementary and alternative medicine based on the belief that vital energy flows through the human body. This energy is said to be balanced or made stronger by practitioners who pass their hands over, or gently touch, a patient's body. Therapeutic touch is being studied in patients receiving cancer therapy, to find out if it can improve quality of life, boost the immune system, or reduce side effects. Therapeutic touch is a type of energy therapy. Also called healing touch.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000725753" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;therapeutic touch&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000725754" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;toque terapéutico&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>toque terapéutico</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Forma de medicina complementaria y alternativa que se basa en la creencia de que existe una energía vital que recorre todo el cuerpo humano. Se dice que esta energía se equilibra o se fortifica cuando los profesionales pasan las manos por encima del cuerpo de un paciente o tocan suavemente el cuerpo. El toque terapéutico  está en estudio para los pacientes que reciben tratamientos para el cáncer con el fin de determinar si puede mejorar la calidad de vida, reforzar el sistema inmunitario o reducir los efectos secundarios. El toque terapéutico  es un tipo de terapia de energía. También se llama toque curativo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-04-07</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2010-04-07</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
