<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000666199"><TermName>ecological study</TermName><TermPronunciation>(EE-kuh-LAH-jih-kul STUH-dee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A study that compares large groups of people instead of individuals for differences in things such as cancer rates. The groups can differ by location (for example, city, county, or country). They can also differ by time (a few days, years, or decades). Groups can be immigrants (compared with people who are native to the country) or people with different types of jobs. The Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results (SEER) Program conducts ecological studies to collect information on cancer rates over time in certain parts of the United States. Also called ecologic study.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000725805" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ecological study&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000725804" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;estudio ecológico&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>estudio ecológico</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Estudio mediante el que se comparan grupos grandes de personas, en vez de individuos, para determinar las diferencias de cosas tales como las tasas del cáncer.   Los grupos pueden diferir por ubicación (por ejemplo, ciudad, condado, o país), también pueden diferir por tiempo (pocos días, años o decenios) o los grupos pueden ser de inmigrantes (en comparación con personas que son nativas del país) o de personas con diferentes tipos de trabajo.   El <ForeignWord>Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results (SEER) Program</ForeignWord> (Programa de Vigilancia, Epidemiología y Resultados Finales) realiza estudios ecológicos para recopilar información sobre las tasas del cáncer a medida que pasa el tiempo en ciertas partes de los Estados Unidos.  </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-06-04</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
