<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000674715"><TermName>Tc-99m Dextran</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... DEK-stran)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A substance being studied as a way to find sentinel lymph nodes in some types of skin cancer and breast cancer. It contains a radioactive substance called technetium linked to a substance called dextran.  Dextran helps technetium stay in blood and lymph vessels after it is injected. A machine or probe that detects radioactivity shows which lymph nodes near the tumor have Tc-99m Dextran in them. It is a type of radiopharmaceutical and a type of radioimaging agent. Also called 99m-Tc-Dx and technetium Tc 99m dextran.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000727645" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Tc-99m Dextran&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000727646" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Tc-99m dextran&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Tc-99m dextran</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Sustancia en estudio para encontrar los ganglios linfáticos centinela en algunos tipos de cáncer de piel y cáncer de mama.   Contiene una sustancia radiactiva que se llama tecnecio enlazada con una sustancia que se llama dextran.  El dextran ayuda a que el tecnecio permanezca en la sangre y los vasos linfáticos después de ser inyectado. Una máquina o sonda que detecta la radiactividad muestra los ganglios linfáticos cercanos al tumor que contienen  Tc-99m dextran. Es un tipo de radiofármaco y un tipo de sustancia para radioimaginología. También se llama 99m-Tc-Dx y tecnecio Tc-99m dextran.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-10-15</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2010-10-06</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
