<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000644773"><TermName>intra-arterial brachytherapy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(IN-truh-ar-TEER-ee-ul BRAY-kee-THAYR-uh-pee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of radiation therapy used to treat liver cancer that is advanced or has come back. Tiny beads that hold the radioisotope yttrium Y 90 are injected into the hepatic artery (the main blood vessel that carries blood to the liver). The beads collect in the tumor and the yttrium Y 90 gives off radiation.  This destroys the blood vessels that the tumor needs to grow and kills the cancer cells. Intra-arterial brachytherapy is a type of selective internal radiation therapy (SIRT). Also called radioembolization.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000726292" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;intra-arterial brachytherapy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000726293" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;braquiterapia intraarterial&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>braquiterapia intraarterial</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de radioterapia que se usa para tratar el cáncer de hígado avanzado o que ha reaparecido. Se inyectan unas cuentas pequeñas que contienen el radioisótopo itrio (Y 90) en la arteria hepática (el vaso sanguíneo principal que lleva sangre al hígado).   Las cuentas se juntan en el tumor y el itrio 90 emite radiación.   La braquiterapia intraarterial destruye los vasos sanguíneos que el tumor necesita para crecer y elimina las células cancerosas.   Es un tipo de radioterapia interna selectiva (SIRT).   También se llama radioembolización.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2009-11-13</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2009-12-08</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
