<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000637720"><TermName>Farydak</TermName><TermPronunciation>(FAYR-ah-dak)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used with bortezomib and dexamethasone to treat multiple myeloma. It is used in patients who have already been treated with bortezomib and an immunomodulating agent. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer.  Farydak blocks certain enzymes needed for cells to grow and divide and may kill cancer cells. It may also prevent the growth of new blood vessels that tumors need to grow. It is a type of histone deacetylase inhibitor and a type of antiangiogenesis agent. Also called LBH589 and panobinostat.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722814" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Farydak&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722813" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Faridak&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Faridak</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa con bortezomib y dexametasona para el tratamiento del mieloma múltiple.Se usa en pacientes que han sido tratados con bortezomib y un inmunomodulador. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Faridak impide la acción de ciertas enzimas que las células necesitan para formarse y multiplicarse, y podría destruir células cancerosas. Asimismo,  puede prevenir la formación de vasos sanguíneos nuevos que los tumores necesitan para crecer. Es un tipo de inhibidor de la histona deacetilasa y un tipo de antiangiogénico. También se llama LBH589 y panobinostat.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2009-03-13</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2015-03-26</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000769744">Panobinostat</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
