<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000628802"><TermName>eltrombopag olamine</TermName><TermPronunciation>(el-TROM-boh-pag OH-luh-meen)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat thrombocytopenia (a lower-than-normal number of platelets in the blood) in patients with chronic immune thrombocytopenic purpura (a condition in which platelets are destroyed by the immune system). It is used in patients who did not get better with corticosteroids, immunoglobulins, or surgery to remove the spleen. It is also being studied in the treatment of other conditions and types of cancer. Eltrombopag olamine causes more platelets to be made in the bone marrow. It is a type of thrombopoietin receptor agonist.  Also called Promacta.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722495" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;eltrombopag olamine&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722496" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;eltrombopag olamina&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>eltrombopag olamina</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para tratar la trombocitopenia (número de plaquetas menor de lo normal en la sangre) en pacientes con púrpura trombocitopénica inmunitaria crónica (afección por la que el sistema inmunitario destruye las plaquetas). Se usa en pacientes que no mejoraron con corticosteroides, inmunoglobulinas o cirugía para extirpar el bazo. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otras afecciones y tipos de cáncer. La eltrombopag olamina hace que la médula ósea elabore más plaquetas. Es un tipo de agonista del receptor de la trombopoyetina. También se llama Promacta.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-12-09</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2015-08-25</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000626822">Eltrombopag Olamine</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
