<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000693559"><TermName>childhood acute lymphoblastic leukemia risk group system</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... uh-KYOOT LIM-foh-BLAS-tik loo-KEE-mee-uh risk groop SIS-tem)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A way of grouping patients that is used to plan treatment for children with acute lymphoblastic leukemia.  A risk group is based on the patient’s age and white blood cell count at diagnosis. Risk groups are described as either standard (low) risk or high risk. Other factors that affect the risk group include the type of leukemia cells, whether there are certain chromosome changes, and how quickly the leukemia responds to treatment.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733182" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;childhood acute lymphoblastic leukemia risk group system&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733183" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sistema de grupo de riesgo para la leucemia linfoblástica aguda infantil&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>sistema de grupo de riesgo para la leucemia linfoblástica aguda infantil</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Forma de agrupar que se usa para planificar el tratamiento de niños con leucemia linfoblástica aguda. Un grupo de riesgo se basa en la edad del paciente y el recuento de glóbulos blancos en el momento del diagnóstico. Los grupos de riesgos se describen ya sea como de riesgo  estándar (bajo)  o riesgo alto. Otros factores que afectan el grupo de riesgo son el tipo de células leucémicas, si hay ciertos cambios en los cromosomas  y la rapidez con que la leucemia responde al tratamiento.</DefinitionText><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2011-08-22</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2012-08-19</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
