<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000658368"><TermName>Votrient</TermName><TermPronunciation>(VOH-tree-ent)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat advanced renal cell carcinoma, which is the most common type of kidney cancer. It is also used to treat advanced soft tissue sarcoma that has been treated with other anticancer drugs. It is being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Votrient may prevent the growth of new blood vessels that tumors need to grow. It is a type of protein tyrosine kinase inhibitor and a type of antiangiogenesis agent. Also called GW786034 and pazopanib hydrochloride.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000725925" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Votrient&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000725924" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Votrient&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Votrient</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para tratar el carcinoma renal en estadio avanzado, el cual es el tipo más común de cáncer de riñón. También se usa para tratar el sarcoma de tejido blando en estadio avanzado que ya se trató con otros medicamentos contra el cáncer. Está bajo estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Votrient podría prevenir la formación de los nuevos vasos sanguíneos que los tumores necesitan para crecer. Es un tipo de
inhibidor de la proteína tirosina cinasa y un tipo de
inhibidor de la angiogénesis. También se llama clorhidrato de pazopanib y GW786034.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2009-11-10</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2012-06-20</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000658515">Pazopanib Hydrochloride</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
