<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000658777"><TermName>polymeric enteral nutrition formula</TermName><TermPronunciation>(PAH-lih-MAYR-ik EN-teh-rul noo-TRIH-shun FOR-myoo-luh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A nutritional drink that may help people who cannot get everything they need in their diet from foods and other drinks. It may be taken by mouth or given through a small tube inserted through the nose into the stomach or the small intestine. It may also be given through a small tube that is put into the stomach or intestinal tract  through an opening made on the outside of the abdomen. One example of a polymeric enteral nutrition formula is Ensure. Polymeric enteral nutrition formula is a type of dietary supplement.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000726120" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;polymeric enteral nutrition formula&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000726121" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;fórmula entérica polimérica&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>fórmula enteral polimérica</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Bebida nutricional que puede ayudar a las personas que no pueden obtener todo lo que necesitan de su alimentación habitual y otras bebidas. Se puede tomar por boca o administrar a través de un tubo introducido en la nariz que llega hasta el estómago o el intestino delgado. También se puede administrar mediante un tubo pequeño colocado en el estómago o el tracto intestinal a través de una abertura hecha en el exterior del abdomen. Ensure es un ejemplo de fórmula nutricional entérica polimérica. Una fórmula nutricional entérica polimérica es un suplemento alimentario.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-03-30</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-01-14</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
