<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000635817"><TermName>needle/wire localization</TermName><TermPronunciation>(NEE-dul … LOH-kuh-lih-ZAY-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure used to mark a small area of abnormal tissue so it can be removed by surgery. An imaging device is used to guide a thin wire with a hook at the end through a hollow needle to place the wire in or around the abnormal area. Once the wire is in the right place, the needle is removed and the wire is left in place so the doctor will know where the abnormal tissue is. The wire is removed when a biopsy is done. Also called needle localization and wire localization.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722896" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;needle/wire localization&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722895" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;localización con aguja o alambre&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>localización con aguja o alambre</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento que se usa para marcar un área pequeña del tejido anormal a fin de poder eliminarlo mediante cirugía. Se usa un dispositivo de imaginología para guiar un alambre delgado con un gancho en el extremo a través de una aguja hueca y colocar el alambre en el área anormal o alrededor de ella. Una vez que el alambre está en el lugar adecuado, se quita la aguja y se deja el alambre para que el médico sepa  donde está el  tejido anormal. El alambre se saca cuando termina la biopsia. También se llama localizacion con aguja y localización con alambre.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2009-04-10</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2009-05-22</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
