<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000655046"><TermName>enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay</TermName><TermPronunciation>(EN-zime-linkt IH-myoo-noh-SOR-bent A-say)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A laboratory technique that uses antibodies linked to enzymes to detect and measure the amount of a substance in a solution, such as serum. The test is done using a solid surface to which the antibodies and other molecules stick.  In the final step, an enzyme reaction takes place that causes a color change that can be read using a special machine.  There are many different ways that an enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay can be done.   Enzyme-linked immunosorbent assays may be used to help diagnose certain diseases. Also called ELISA.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000725653" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000725654" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;enzimoinmunoanálisis de adsorción&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>enzimoinmunoanálisis de adsorción</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Técnica de laboratorio que usa anticuerpos ligados a enzimas a fin de detectar y medir la cantidad de una sustancia en una solución, como el suero. La prueba se hace usando una superficie sólida a la que los anticuerpos y otras moléculas se adhieren. En la etapa final, se produce una reacción enzimática que causa un cambio de color que puede leerse mediante el uso de una máquina especial. Hay muchas formas diferentes en las que el enzimoinmunoanálisis de adsorción se puede hacer. El  enzimoinmunoanálisis de adsorción se puede usar para ayudar a diagnosticar ciertas enfermedades. También se llama ELISA.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2009-11-17</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
