<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000691011"><TermName>Response Evaluation Criteria In Solid Tumors</TermName><TermPronunciation>(reh-SPONTS ee-VAL-yoo-AY-shun kry-TEER-ee-uh … SAH-lid TOO-mers)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A standard way to measure how well a cancer patient responds to treatment. It is based on whether tumors shrink, stay the same, or get bigger. To use Response Evaluation Criteria In Solid Tumors, there must be at least one tumor that can be measured on x-rays, CT scans, or MRI scans. The types of response a patient can have are a complete response (CR), a partial response (PR), progressive disease (PD), and stable disease (SD). Also called RECIST.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000727619" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Response Evaluation Criteria In Solid Tumors&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000727620" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Criterios de Evaluación de Respuesta en Tumores Sólidos&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Criterios de Evaluación de Respuesta en Tumores Sólidos</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Método estándar que se usa para medir el modo en que un paciente de cáncer responde al tratamiento.   Permite determinar si los tumores se reducen, permanecen igual o se agrandan. Para poder usar los Criterios de Evaluación de Respuesta en Tumores Sólidos, debe haber por lo menos un tumor que se pueda medir mediante radiografías, exploraciones por TC o exploraciones por IRM. Los tipos de respuesta que un paciente puede tener son: respuesta completa (RC), respuesta parcial (RP) enfermedad que avanza (EA) y enfermedad estable (EE). También se llama RECIST.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2011-03-03</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
