<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000644302"><TermName>botulinum toxin type A</TermName><TermPronunciation>(BAH-choo-LY-num TOK-sin ...)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A toxin made by the bacterium <ScientificName>Clostridium
          botulinum</ScientificName>. It can cause food poisoning. The drug Botox is a form of the toxin that can be used in small amounts to treat certain medical conditions. These include severe underarm sweating and severe muscle spasms in the neck and shoulders. Botulinum toxin type A is also used to smooth wrinkles on the face. It is being studied in the treatment of pain in patients with skin leiomyomas (benign smooth muscle tumors) and other conditions.  Also called Botox and botulinum toxin A.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000726055" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;botulinum toxin type A&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000726054" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;toxina botulina tipo A&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>toxina botulina tipo A</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Toxina elaborada por una bacteria, <ScientificName>Clostridium
          botulinum</ScientificName>. Puede envenenar los alimentos. El medicamento Botox es una forma de esta toxina que se usa en cantidades pequeñas para el tratamiento de ciertas afecciones médicas. Estas incluyen sudación extrema en las axilas y espasmos musculares violentos en el cuello y los hombros. La toxina botulina tipo A también se usa para eliminar las arrugas de la cara. Está bajo estudio para el tratamiento del dolor en pacientes con leiomiomas de la piel (tumores musculares lisos benignos) y otras afecciones. También se llama Botox y toxina botulina A.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2009-11-03</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2010-03-01</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
