<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000658849"><TermName>MET tyrosine kinase inhibitor PF-02341066</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… TY-ruh-seen KY-nays in-HIH-bih-ter …)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat advanced non-small cell lung cancer that has a mutated (changed) form of a gene called anaplastic lymphoma kinase (ALK). It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. MET tyrosine kinase inhibitor PF-02341066 blocks the protein made by the mutated ALK gene. Blocking this protein may stop the growth and spread of cancer cells. MET tyrosine kinase inhibitor PF-02341066 may also prevent the growth of new blood vessels that tumors need to grow. It is a type of tyrosine kinase inhibitor and a type of antiangiogenesis agent. Also called crizotinib, PF-02341066,  and Xalkori.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000726168" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;MET tyrosine kinase inhibitor PF-02341066&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000726169" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;inhibidor de la tirosina cinasa del MET PF-02341066&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>inhibidor de la tirosina cinasa del MET PF-02341066</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para tratar el cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas que tiene una forma mutada (cambiada) de un gen que se llama  cinasa del linfoma anaplásico (ALK). También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El inhibidor de la tirosina cinasa del MET PF-02341066 bloquea la proteína que elabora el gen mutado ALK. El bloqueo de esta proteína puede impedir la formación y diseminación de las células cancerosas. El inhibidor de la tirosina cinasa del MET PF-02341066 también puede prevenir la formación de los nuevos vasos sanguíneos que los tumores necesitan para crecer. Es un tipo de inhibidor de la tirosina cinasa y un tipo de antiangiogénico. También se llama crizotinib, PF-02341066,  y Xalkori.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-03-30</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2011-10-04</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000710816">Crizotinib</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
