<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000674942"><TermName>balloon catheter radiation</TermName><TermPronunciation>(buh-LOON KA-theh-ter RAY-dee-AY-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A system used to deliver internal radiation therapy to breast cancer patients after surgery to remove their cancer.  Balloon catheter radiation targets only the part of the breast where the cancer was found. After a patient has had a lumpectomy to remove the cancer, a small balloon on the end of a catheter (thin tube) is inserted into the empty space left by the surgery.  The balloon is then filled with liquid and left in place. Using the catheter, radioactive seeds are put into the balloon twice a day for five days and removed each time. Once treatment has ended, the catheter and balloon are removed.  Balloon catheter radiation is a type of intracavitary brachytherapy and partial breast irradiation therapy (PBRT). Also called MammoSite.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000727791" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;balloon catheter radiation&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000727792" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;radiación mediante catéter con balón&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>radiación mediante catéter con balón</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Sistema que se usa para aplicar radioterapia interna a los pacientes de cáncer de mama después de la cirugía para extirpar su cáncer.   La radiación mediante catéter con globo se dirige solo a la parte de la mama donde se encuentra el cáncer. Después de que un paciente se sometió a una lumpectomía para extirpar el cáncer, se introduce un catéter (tubo delgado) con un globo pequeño en el extremo  y se coloca dicho globo en el espacio que quedó vació después de la cirugía. A continuación, el globo se llena de líquido y se deja en el lugar. A través del catéter, se colocan semillas radiactivas en el interior del globlo dos veces por día durante cinco días y las semillas se extraen después de cada aplicación. Una vez que termina el tratamiento, el catéter y el balón se eliminan.   La radiación mediante catéter con globo es un tipo de braquiterapia intracavitaria y una terapia de irradiación parcial de la mama (TRPM). También se llama MammoSite.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-06-03</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
