<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000635451"><TermName>reference values</TermName><TermPronunciation>(REH-frents VAL-yooz)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>In medicine, a set of values that a doctor uses to interpret a patient’s test results.  The reference values for a given test are based on the results that are seen in 95% of the healthy population.  Sometimes patients whose test results are outside of the reference values may be healthy, and some patients whose test results are within the reference values may have a health problem. The reference values for a test may be different for different groups of people (for example, men and women). Also called normal range, reference interval,  and reference range.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722744" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;reference values&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722743" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;valores de referencia&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>valores de referencia</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>En el campo de la medicina, conjunto de valores que el médico utiliza para interpretar los resultados de las pruebas en un paciente. Los valores de referencia para una prueba determinada se basan en los resultados de la prueba en el 95% de la población sana. A veces, los pacientes cuyos resultados están fuera  de los valores de referencia pueden estar sanos y algunos pacientes cuyos resultados están dentro de los valores de referencia pueden tener un problema de salud. Los valores de referencia de una prueba pueden ser diferente en distintos grupos de personas (por ejemplo, entre mujeres y hombres). También se llama intervalo de referencia, límite de referencia,  y límite normal.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2009-05-01</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2012-05-15</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
