<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000644342"><TermName>Intron A</TermName><TermPronunciation>(IN-tron…)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat AIDS-related Kaposi sarcoma in certain patients, hairy cell leukemia, and melanoma that has been removed by surgery. It is also used with other anticancer drugs to treat a certain type of non-Hodgkin lymphoma. Intron A is also used to treat some infections caused by viruses, such as the hepatitis C virus. It is being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer and other conditions. Intron A is a form of interferon alfa (a substance normally made by cells in the immune system) and is made in the laboratory. It is a type of cytokine and a type of biological response modifier. Also called IFN alpha-2B, interferon alfa-2b,  and recombinant interferon alfa-2b.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000726085" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Intron A&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000726084" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Intron A&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Intron A</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para tratar el sarcoma de Kaposi relacionado con el sida en ciertos pacientes, la leucemia de células pilosas y el melanoma que se extirpó mediante cirugía. También se utiliza con otros medicamentos contra el cáncer para tratar cierto tipo de linfoma no Hodgkin. Asimismo,Intron A se usa para tratar algunas infecciones por virus, como el virus de la hepatitis C. Está en estudio para tratar otros tipos de cáncer y otras afecciones. Intron A es una forma de interferón alfa (sustancia que elaboran normalmente las células del sistema inmunitario) y se produce en el laboratorio. Es un tipo de citocina y de modificador de la respuesta biológica. También se llama IFN alfa 2B, interferón alfa 2b,  y interferón alfa 2b recombinante.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2009-10-05</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-10-22</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
