<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000666685"><TermName>adult progeria</TermName><TermPronunciation>(uh-DULT proh-JEER-ee-uh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>An inherited disorder marked by rapid aging that begins in early adolescence. Patients may be shorter than average, and have health problems such as loss and graying of hair, hardening of the arteries, thinning of the bones, diabetes, and thin, hardened skin. They also have an increased risk of cancer, especially osteosarcoma (a type of bone cancer). Adult progeria is caused by a mutation (change) in a gene involved in cell division. It is a type of autosomal recessive gene disease. Also called Werner syndrome and WS.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000726016" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;adult progeria&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000726017" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;progeria en adultos&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>progeria en adultos</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno hereditario caracterizado por un envejecimiento rápido que empieza en la adolescencia temprana. Los pacientes pueden tener una estatura más baja que el promedio y tener problemas de salud tales como la pérdida y encanecimiento del pelo, endurecimiento de las arterias, adelgazamiento de los huesos, diabetes, y piel fina y endurecida.   También tienen un mayor riesgo de cáncer, especialmente de osteosarcoma (tipo de cáncer de hueso). La causa de la progeria en adultos es una mutación (cambio) en un gen que participa en la multiplicación celular. Es un tipo de enfermedad genética recesiva autosómica.   También se llama síndrome de Werner y SW.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-06-04</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
