<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000643135"><TermName>Platinol</TermName><TermPronunciation>(PLA-tih-nol)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat malignant mesothelioma, non-small cell lung cancer, squamous cell carcinoma of the head and neck, and cancers of the bladder, cervix, ovaries, and testes. It is used in patients whose cancer cannot be treated with or has not gotten better with other anticancer treatment. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Platinol contains the metal platinum. It kills cancer cells by damaging their DNA and stopping them from dividing. It is a type of DNA crosslinking agent.  Also called cisplatin and Platinol-AQ.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000754486" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Platinol&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000754485" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Platinol&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Platinol</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para tratar el mesotelioma maligno, el cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas, el carcinoma de células escamosas de la cabeza y el cuello, y los cánceres de vejiga, cuello uterino, ovarios y testículos. Se utiliza para pacientes cuyo cáncer no se puede tratar o no ha mejorado con otros tratamientos contra el cáncer. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Platinol contiene el metal platino. Destruye las células cancerosas al dañar su ADN e impedir que se multipliquen. Es un tipo de reticulador del ADN. También se llama cisplatino y Platinol-AQ.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-10-22</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-10-22</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000533338">Cisplatin</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
