<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000663297"><TermName>anti-CCR2 monoclonal antibody MLN1202</TermName><TermPronunciation>(AN-tee … MAH-noh-KLOH-nul AN-tee-BAH-dee …)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A substance being studied as a treatment for atherosclerosis (a build-up of fat in the arteries). It is also being studied in the treatment of cancers that spread to the bone. Anti-CCR2 monoclonal antibody MLN1202 binds to a protein called CCR2, which is found on the surface of certain bone cells, white blood cells, and cancer cells.  Anti-CCR2 monoclonal antibody MLN1202 blocks the action of a substance that is involved in keeping healthy bone mass.  It may help keep the cancer cells from spreading to and growing in the bone. It is a type of monoclonal antibody. Also called MLN1202.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000726381" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;anti-CCR2 monoclonal antibody MLN1202&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000726380" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;anticuerpo monoclonal MLN1202 anti-CCR2&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>anticuerpo monoclonal MLN1202 anti-CCR2</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Sustancia en estudio para el tratamiento de la ateroesclerosis (acumulación de grasa en las arterias).   También está en estudio para el tratamiento de los cánceres que se diseminan hasta el hueso.   El anticuerpo monoclonal MLN1202 anti-CCR2 se une a una proteína que se llama CCR2, que se encuentra en la superficie de ciertas células óseas, glóbulos blancos y células cancerosas.   El anticuerpo monoclonal MLN1202 anti-CCR2 impide la acción de una sustancia que participa en el mantenimiento de la masa ósea sana.   Podría ayudar a impedir que las células cancerosas se diseminen hasta el hueso y crezcan en este. Es un tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal.   También se llama MLN1202.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-06-03</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
