<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000616114"><TermName>Nplate</TermName><TermPronunciation>(EN-playt)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat patients with immune thrombocytopenic purpura (ITP) who do not get better with other forms of treatment. In ITP, platelets (cells that cause blood clots to form) are destroyed by the immune system. Nplate is being studied as a way to treat low platelet counts caused by chemotherapy. It binds to the thrombopoietin receptor and causes the bone marrow to make more platelets. Nplate is also being studied in the treatment of myelodysplastic syndromes (a group of diseases in which the bone marrow does not make enough healthy blood cells). It is a type of thrombopoietin agonist. Also called AMG 531 and romiplostim.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000721162" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Nplate&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000721161" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Nplate&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Nplate</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento para tratar a los pacientes de púrpura trombocitopénica inmunitaria (PTI) que no mejoran con otras formas de tratamiento. En el caso de la PTI, el sistema inmunitario destruye las plaquetas (células que hacen coagular la sangre). Nplate está en estudio como una forma de tratar el recuento bajo de plaquetas causado por la quimioterapia. El medicamento se une a receptor de la trombopoyetina y hace que la médula ósea elabore más plaquetas. Asimismo, Nplate está en estudio para el tratamiento de los síndromes mielodisplásicos (un grupo de enfermedades por las que la médula ósea no elabora suficientes células sanguíneas sanas). Es un tipo de antagonista de la trombopoyetina. También se llama AMG 531 y romiplostim.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-09-29</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000613094">Romiplostim</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
