<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000635812"><TermName>Camptosar</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KAMP-toh-sar)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used alone or with other drugs to treat colon cancer or rectal cancer that has spread to other parts of the body or has come back after treatment with fluorouracil. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Camptosar blocks certain enzymes needed for cell division and DNA repair, and it may kill cancer cells. It is a type of topoisomerase inhibitor and a type of camptothecin analog. Also called CPT 11 and irinotecan hydrochloride.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722888" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Camptosar&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000722887" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Camptosar&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Camptosar</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa solo o con otros medicamentos para tratar el cáncer de colon o el cáncer de recto que se diseminó hasta otras partes del cuerpo o que reapareció después del tratamiento con fluorouracilo. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Camptosar impide la acción de ciertas enzimas que las células necesitan para multiplicarse y reparar el ADN, y puede destruir células cancerosas. Es un tipo de inhibidor de la topoisomerasa y un tipo de análogo de la camptotecina. También se llama clorhidrato de irinotecán y CPT 11.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2009-02-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2010-05-05</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000537382">Irinotecan Hydrochloride</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
