<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000648689"><TermName>IMC-1121B</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used with other drugs to treat colorectal cancer and non-small cell lung cancer that have spread to other parts of the body. It is used alone or with another drug to treat cancer of the stomach or gastroesophageal junction (area where the esophagus connects to the stomach) that is advanced or has spread to other parts of the body. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. IMC-1121B binds to receptors for a protein called vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF), which may be found on some types of cancer cells. This may prevent the growth of new blood vessels that tumors need to grow. IMC-1121B is a type of antiangiogenesis agent and a type of monoclonal antibody. Also called anti-VEGFR-2 fully human monoclonal antibody IMC-1121B, Cyramza,  and ramucirumab.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><SpanishTermName>IMC-1121B</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa junto con otros medicamentos en el tratamiento del cáncer colorrectal y el cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas que se ha diseminado a otras partes del cuerpo. Este se usa solo o con otros medicamentos para tratar el cáncer del estómago o de la unión gastroesofágica  (área en la que el esófago se conecta con el estómago) el cual se encuentra en estadio avanzado o que se ha diseminado a otras partes del cuerpo.  También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. IMC-1121B se une a los receptores de una proteína llamada factor de crecimiento endotelial vascular (FCEV), la cual pudiera encontrarse en algunos tipos de células cancerosas. Esto pudiera prevenir la formación de vasos sanguíneos nuevos  que los tumores necesitan para crecer. IMC-1121B es un tipo de antiangiogénico y  de anticuerpo monoclonal. También se llama anticuerpo monoclonal totalmente humano IMC-1121B anti-RFCEV, Cyramza,  y ramucirumab.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-01-11</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2015-08-14</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000760376">Ramucirumab</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
