<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000613206"><TermName>calcium levoleucovorin</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KAL-see-um LEE-voh-LOO-koh-VOR-in)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to lessen the toxic effects of substances that block the action of folic acid, especially the anticancer drug methotrexate. Calcium levoleucovorin is used to treat some types of anemia and is also used with fluorouracil to treat colorectal cancer. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer and other conditions.  Calcium levoleucovorin is a form of folic acid. It is a type of chemoprotective agent and a type of chemosensitizing agent. Also called citrovorum factor, leucovorin calcium,  and Wellcovorin.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720784" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;calcium levoleucovorin&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720785" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;levoleucovorina cálcica&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>levoleucovorina cálcica</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para reducir los efectos tóxicos de sustancias que bloquean la acción del ácido fólico, especialmente el medicamento contra el cáncer metotrexato. La levoleucovorina cálcica se usa para tratar ciertos tipos de anemia y también se usa con el fluorouracilo para tratar el cáncer colorrectal. Asimismo, está en estudio para tratar otros tipos de cáncer y otras afecciones. La levoleucovorina cálcica es una forma de ácido fólico. Es un tipo de quimioprotector y un tipo de quimiosensibilizador. También se llama factor citrovórum, leucovorina cálcica,  y Wellcovorin.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-08-25</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2010-05-05</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000599725">Leucovorin Calcium</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
