<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000612887"><TermName>stage II ovarian low malignant potential tumor</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… oh-VAYR-ee-un...muh-LIG-nunt poh-TEN-shul TOO-mer)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The tumor is found in one or both ovaries and has spread into other areas of the pelvis. Stage II is divided into stages IIA, IIB, and IIC. In stage IIA, the tumor has spread to the uterus and/or fallopian tubes (the long slender tubes through which eggs pass from the ovaries to the uterus). In stage IIB, the tumor has spread to other tissue within the pelvis. In stage IIC, the tumor is found inside one or both ovaries and has spread to the uterus and/or fallopian tubes, or to other tissue within the pelvis. Also, one of the following is true: (1) tumor cells are found on the outside surface of one or both ovaries; or (2) the capsule (outer covering) of the ovary has ruptured (broken open); or (3) tumor cells are found in the fluid of the peritoneal cavity (the body cavity that contains most of the organs in the abdomen) or in washings of the peritoneum (tissue lining the peritoneal cavity).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720665" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage II ovarian low malignant potential tumor&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720664" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tumor del ovario de bajo potencial maligno en estadio II&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>tumor del ovario de bajo potencial maligno en estadio II</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El tumor se encuentra en uno o ambos ovarios y se diseminó hacia otras áreas de la pelvis. El estadio II se divide en los estadios IIA, IIB y IIC. En el estadio IIA, el tumor se diseminó hasta el útero o las trompas de Falopio (tubos largos y delgados por donde pasan los óvulos desde los ovarios hasta el útero). En el estadio IIB, el tumor se diseminó hasta otro tejido dentro de la pelvis. En el estadio IIC, el tumor se encuentra en el interior de un ovario o ambos y se diseminó hasta el útero o las trompas de Falopio, o hasta otro tejido dentro de la pelvis. Además, se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) se encuentran células tumorales en la superficie exterior de un ovario o ambos; 2) la cápsula (cubierta externa) del ovario se rompió (se abrió); 3) se encuentran células tumorales en el líquido de la cavidad peritoneal (cavidad del cuerpo que contiene la mayoría de los órganos del abdomen) o en los lavados del peritoneo (tejido que reviste la cavidad peritoneal).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-08-21</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2012-07-16</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062968">Ovarian Low Malignant Potential Tumors Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef href="CDR0000256832">Tumores de células germinativas del ovario: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
