<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000689084"><TermName>peripherally inserted central catheter</TermName><TermPronunciation>(peh-RIH-feh-ruh-lee in-SER-ted SEN-trul KA-theh-ter)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A device used to draw blood and give treatments, including intravenous fluids, drugs, or blood transfusions.  A thin, flexible tube is inserted into a vein in the upper arm and guided (threaded) into a large vein above the right side of the heart called the superior vena cava.  A needle is inserted into a port outside the body to draw blood or give fluids.  A peripherally inserted central catheter may stay in place for weeks or months and helps avoid the need for repeated needle sticks.  Also called PICC.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733314" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;peripherally inserted central catheter&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733315" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;catéter central introducido periféricamente&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000756807" type="image/jpeg" alt="Peripherally inserted central catheter (PICC); drawing of a PICC line that goes from a vein in the upper right arm to a large vein above the right side of the heart called the superior vena cava. An inset shows a PICC line in the arm with a clear plastic dressing over it. An intravenous line attached to the PICC is also shown." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Peripherally inserted central catheter (PICC). A PICC is a thin, flexible tube that is inserted into a vein in the upper arm and guided (threaded) into a large vein above the right side of the heart called the superior vena cava. It is used to give intravenous fluids, blood transfusions,  chemotherapy, and other drugs. It is also used for taking blood samples. A PICC line may stay in place for weeks or months and helps avoid the need for repeated needle sticks.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000774020" type="image/jpeg" alt="Catéter central introducido periféricamente (CCIP); dibujo de una vía de un CCIP que va desde una vena de la parte superior del brazo derecho a una vena grande sobre el lado derecho del corazón que  se llama vena cava superior.   En un recuadro se puede observar una vía de un CCIP con un vendaje plástico claro sobre este. También se muestra un catéter intraveno unido al CCIP." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Catéter central introducido periféricamente (CCIP). Un CCIP es un tubo delgado y flexible que se introduce en una vena en el brazo y se guía  (inserta) hacia una vena grande sobre el lado derecho del corazón que se llama vena cava superior.   Se usa para administrar líquidos intravenosos, transfusiones de sangre y quimioterapia y otros medicamentos. También se usa para tomar muestras de sangre.   Una vía de CCIP puede permanecer en su lugar durante semanas o meses, y ayuda a evitar la necesidad de pinchazos repetidos de aguja.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>catéter central introducido periféricamente</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Dispositivo que se usa para extraer sangre y administrar tratamientos, como líquidos intravenosos, medicamentos o transfusiones de sangre. Se introduce un tubo delgado y flexible en una vena de la parte superior del brazo y se guía (entreteje) en una vena grande en el lado derecho del corazón que se llama vena cava superior. Se introduce una aguja en una vía de acceso afuera del cuerpo para extraer sangre o administrar líquidos. Un catéter central introducido periféricamente se puede dejar en su lugar durante semanas o meses para evitar la necesidad de repetidos pinchazos de aguja. También se llama CIIP.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2011-08-18</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2015-10-12</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
