<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000613763"><TermName>organelle</TermName><TermPronunciation>(OR-guh-NEL)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A small structure in a cell that is surrounded by a membrane and has a specific function. Examples of organelles are the nucleus (a structure that contains the cell’s chromosomes and is where RNA is made), mitochondria (structures that make energy for the cell), and lysosomes (sac-like containers filled with enzymes that digest and help recycle molecules in the cell).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000721031" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;organelle&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000721032" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;orgánulo&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000761780" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing showing a cell containing organelles, including the nucleus (contains DNA), the nucleolus, Golgi complex, mitochondria, and endoplasmic reticulum. Also shown are the cell membrane and a membrane receptor." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Parts of a cell.  A cell is surrounded by a membrane, which has receptors on the surface. A cell has several small structures inside it, including the nucleus, mitochondria, endoplasmic reticulum, and Golgi complex. These all have specific functions in the cell. </Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000765321" type="image/jpeg" alt="En la ilustración, se muestra una célula con sus organelos, como el núcleo (contiene ADN), el nucléolo, el aparato de Golgi, las mitocondrias y el retículo endoplasmático. También se muestran la membrana celular y un receptor de membrana." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Partes de una célula. La célula está rodeada por una membrana, con receptores en la superficie; además,  tiene varias estructuras pequeñas en su interior, como el núcleo, las mitocondrias, el retículo endoplasmático y el  aparato de Golgi. Estas desempeñan funciones específicas en la célula.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>orgánulo</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Estructura pequeña de una célula que está rodeada por una membrana y tiene una función específica. Entre los ejemplos de orgánulos están el núcleo (una estructura que contiene los cromosomas de la célula y donde se elabora el ARN), las mitocondrias (estructuras que elaboran energía para la célula) y los lisosomas (envases similares a bolsas llenos de enzimas que digieren y ayudan a reciclar las moléculas de la célula).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-08-29</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2014-11-19</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
