<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000613899"><TermName>B-cell leukemia/lymphoma 2 protein</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... sel loo-KEE-mee-uh/lim-FOH-muh 2 PROH-teen)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A protein that helps control whether a cell lives or dies by blocking a type of cell death called apoptosis. The gene for the B-cell leukemia/lymphoma 2 protein is found on chromosome 18, and transfer of the B-cell leukemia/lymphoma 2 gene to a different chromosome is seen in many B-cell leukemias and lymphomas. This causes the B-cell leukemia/lymphoma 2 protein to be made in larger amounts, which may keep cancer cells from dying. Also called BCL2.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000721086" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;B-cell leukemia/lymphoma 2 protein&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000721085" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;proteína 2 de la leucemia/linfoma de células B&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>proteína 2 de la leucemia/linfoma de células B</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Proteína que ayuda a controlar la supervivencia o destrucción de una célula al impedir un tipo de muerte celular que se llama apoptosis. El gen de la proteína 2 de la leucemia/linfoma de células B se encuentra en el cromosoma 18, y en muchas leucemias y linfomas de células B se observa la transferencia del gen de la proteína 2 de la leucemia/linfoma de células B a un cromosoma diferente. Esto hace que se elaboren cantidades tan grandes de la proteína 2 de la leucemia/linfoma de células B que podría impedir la muerte de las células cancerosas. También se llama BCL2.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-09-03</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
