<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000682421"><TermName>stage IIIB non-small cell lung cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... sel lung KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage III
          non-small cell lung cancer is divided into stages IIIA and
          IIIB. In stage IIIB, cancer has spread to lymph nodes above
          the collarbone or in the opposite side of the chest as the
          tumor. Also, (1) the tumor may be any size; (2) part of the
          lung (where the trachea joins the bronchus) or the whole
          lung may have collapsed or become inflamed; (3) there may
          be one or more separate tumors in any of the lobes of the
          lung with cancer; and/or (4) cancer may have spread to any
          of the following: main bronchus, diaphragm and the nerve
          that controls it, membrane around the lung, chest wall or
          the membrane that lines it, trachea, carina (where the
          trachea joins the bronchi), esophagus, sternum (chest
          bone), backbone, heart or the membrane around it, major
          blood vessels that lead to or from the heart, or the nerve
          that controls the larynx (voice box). OR in stage IIIB,
          cancer has spread to lymph nodes on the same side of the
          chest as the tumor. Also, (1) the tumor may be any size;
          (2) there may be separate tumors in different lobes of the
          same lung; and/or (3) cancer has spread to any of the
          following: trachea, carina, esophagus, sternum, backbone,
          major blood vessels that lead to or from the heart, or the
          nerve that controls the larynx.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000727574" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IIIB non-small cell lung cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000727573" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio IIIB&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000521915" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIIB non-small cell lung cancer (1). Drawing shows cancer in lymph nodes above the collarbone on the opposite side of the chest as the primary tumor, and in the trachea, carina, left main bronchus, esophagus, sternum, diaphragm, and major blood vessels that lead to or from the heart; there may be separate tumors in the same lung. Top inset shows cancer that has spread from the lung, through the lung lining and chest wall lining, into the chest wall; a rib is also shown. Bottom inset shows cancer that has spread from the lung, through the membrane around the heart, into the heart." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Stage IIIB non-small cell lung cancer (1). Cancer has spread to lymph nodes above the collarbone or on the opposite side of the chest as the primary tumor. The cancer may have spread to (a) the main bronchus; (b) lung lining, chest wall lining, or chest wall; (c) diaphragm; (d) heart or the membrane around it; (e) major blood vessels that lead to or from the heart; (f) trachea; (g) esophagus; (h) sternum; and/or (i) carina; and/or (j) there may be one or more separate tumors in any of the lobes of the lung. Part or all of the lung may have collapsed or become inflamed and cancer may have spread to the backbone and/or the nerves that control the diaphragm and larynx (not shown).</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000682124" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIIB non-small cell lung cancer (2). Drawing shows cancer in lymph nodes on the same side of the chest as the primary tumor, in the heart, major blood vessels that lead to or from the heart, the trachea, esophagus, sternum, carina, and in separate tumors in different lobes of the same lung; the diaphragm is also shown. Inset shows cancer that has spread from the lung, through the membrane around the heart, into the heart." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="en">Stage IIIB non-small cell lung cancer (2). Cancer has spread to certain lymph nodes on the same side of the chest as the primary tumor and to (a) the heart; (b) major blood vessels that lead to or from the heart; (c) trachea; (d) esophagus; (e) sternum; and/or (f) carina; and/or (g) there may be separate tumors in different lobes of the same lung. Cancer may have spread to the backbone and/or the nerve that controls the larynx (not shown).</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000537607" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio IIIB (1). El dibujo muestra cáncer en los ganglios linfáticos, encima de la clavícula en el lado opuesto del pecho en el que está el tumor primario y en la tráquea, la carina, el bronquio principal izquierdo, el esófago, el esternón, el diafragma y los vasos sanguíneos principales que van hacia el corazón o salen del mismo; puede haber tumores separados en el mismo pulmón. El recuadro superior muestra  cáncer que se diseminó desde el pulmón, a través del revestimiento del pulmón y el revestimiento de la pared del pecho, hacia la pared del pecho; también se muestra una costilla. El recuadro inferior muestra cáncer que se diseminó desde el pulmón, a través de la membrana que rodea el corazón, hacia el corazón." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_5"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio IIIB (1). El cáncer se diseminó hasta los ganglios linfáticos encima de la clavícula o los ganglios linfáticos del lado opuesto del pecho en el que está el tumor principal. El cáncer también se puede haber diseminado hasta: a) el bronquio principal, b) el revestimiento del pulmón, el revestimiento de la pared del pecho o la pared del pecho, c) el diafragma, d) el corazón o la membrana que lo rodea, e) los vasos sanguíneos principales que van hacia el corazón o salen del mismo, f) la tráquea, g) el esófago, h) el esternón, o i) la carina; o j) puede haber uno o más tumores separados en cualquiera de los lóbulos del pulmón. Parte del pulmón o todo el mismo se puede haber hundido o inflamado, y el cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta la espina dorsal o los nervios que controlan el diafragma y la laringe (no se muestran).</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000686830" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio IIIB (2). El dibujo muestra cáncer en los ganglios linfáticos del mismo lado del pecho en el que está el tumor primario, en el corazón, los vasos sanguíneos principales que van hacia el corazón o salen del mismo, la tráquea, el esófago, el esternón, la carina y en tumores separados en diferentes lóbulos del mismo pulmón; también se muestra el diafragma. El recuadro muestra  cáncer que se diseminó desde el pulmón, a través de la membrana que rodea el corazón, hacia el corazón." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_6"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio IIIB (2). El cáncer se diseminó hasta ciertos ganglios linfáticos del mismo lado del pecho en el que está el tumor primario y hasta a) el corazón, b) los vasos sanguíneos principales que van hacia el corazón o salen del mismo, c) la tráquea, d) el esófago, e) el esternón, o f) la carina, o g) puede haber tumores separados en diferentes lóbulos del mismo pulmón. El cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta la espina dorsal o el nervio que controla la laringe (no se muestra).</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas en estadio IIIB</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio III de cáncer de pulmón
de células no pequeñas se divide en estadios IIIA y IIIB.
En el estadio IIIB, el cáncer se diseminó hasta los
ganglios linfáticos encima de la clavícula o el lado
opuesto del pecho donde está el tumor. Asimismo, 1) el
tumor puede tener cualquier tamaño; 2) una parte del pulmón
(donde la tráquea se une con el bronquio) o todo el pulmón
se hundió o inflamó; 3) puede haber uno o más tumores
separados en cualquiera de los lóbulos del pulmón con
cáncer, o 4) el cáncer se puede haber diseminado hasta
cualquiera de los siguientes sitios: el bronquio principal,
el diafragma y el nervio que lo controla, la membrana que
rodea el pulmón, la pared del pecho o la membrana que la
rodea, la tráquea, la carina (donde la tráquea se une con
los bronquios) el esófago, el esternón (hueso del pecho),
la columna vertebral, el corazón o la membrana que lo
rodea, los vasos sanguíneos principales que van hacia el
corazón o salen del mismo, o el nervio que controla la
laringe. O, en el estadio IIIB, el cáncer se diseminó hasta
los ganglios linfáticos del mismo lado del pecho donde está
el tumor. Asimismo, 1) el tumor puede tener cualquier
tamaño; 2) puede haber tumores separados en diferentes
lóbulos del mismo pulmón, o 3) el cáncer se diseminó hasta
cualquiera de los siguientes sitios: la tráquea, la carina,
el esófago, el esternón, la columna vertebral, los vasos
sanguíneos principales que van hacia el corazón o salen del
mismo, o el nervio que controla la laringe. </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-07-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2010-10-21</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062956">Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer Treatment </RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256766">Cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
