<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000658059"><TermName>pancreatic function test</TermName><TermPronunciation>(PAN-kree-A-tik FUNK-shun …)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A test used to help diagnose problems in the pancreas, such as gastrinomas and pancreatitis. It measures the ability of the pancreas to respond to the hormone secretin (a hormone that causes other substances to be released by the stomach, liver, and pancreas). Secretin is given to the patient by a tube put through the nose or throat into the small intestine and stomach or by injection into a vein. After a certain amount of time, samples are taken to be sent to a laboratory for testing. It is a type of pancreatic function test. Also called secretin stimulation test.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000725863" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pancreatic function test&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000725862" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;prueba de la función pancreática&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>prueba de la función pancreática</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Prueba que se usa para ayudar a diagnosticar problemas del páncreas, como gastrinomas y pancreatitis.   Mide la capacidad del páncreas de responder a la hormona secretina (una hormona que hace que el estómago, el hígado y el páncreas segreguen otras sustancias).   La secretina se administra al paciente a través de un tubo colocado en la nariz o la garganta que llega hasta el estómago y el intestino delgado o se inyecta en una vena.   Después de cierto tiempo, se toman muestras que se envían a un laboratorio para someterlas a prueba.   Es un tipo de prueba del funcionamiento del páncreas. También se llama prueba de estimulación con secretina.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-03-01</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
