<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000612883"><TermName>stage I ovarian low malignant potential tumor</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… oh-VAYR-ee-un...muh-LIG-nunt poh-TEN-shul TOO-mer)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The tumor is found in one or both ovaries. Stage I is divided into stages IA, IB, and IC. In stage IA, the tumor is found inside a single ovary. In stage IB, the tumor is found inside both ovaries. In stage IC, the tumor is found inside one or both ovaries and one of the following is true: (1) tumor cells are found on the outside surface of one or both ovaries; or (2) the capsule (outer covering) of the ovary has ruptured (broken open); or (3) tumor cells are found in the fluid of the peritoneal cavity (the body cavity that contains most of the organs in the abdomen) or in washings of the peritoneum (tissue lining the peritoneal cavity).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720662" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage I ovarian low malignant potential tumor&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720663" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tumor del ovario de bajo potencial maligno en estadio I&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>tumor del ovario de bajo potencial maligno en estadio I</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El tumor se encuentra en un ovario o en ambos. El estadio I se divide en los estadios IA, IB y IC. En el estadio IA, el tumor se encuentra en un solo ovario. En el estadio IB, el tumor se encuentra en ambos ovarios. En el estadio IC, el tumor se encuentra en un ovario o en ambos, y se presenta una de las siguientes situaciones: 1) se encuentran células tumorales en la superficie exterior de un ovario o de ambos; 2) la cápsula (el revestimiento exterior) del tumor se rompió (se abrió); 3) se encuentran células tumorales en el líquido de la cavidad peritoneal (la cavidad del cuerpo que contiene la mayoría de los órganos del abdomen) o en los lavados del peritoneo (tejido que reviste la cavidad peritoneal).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-08-21</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2012-07-16</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062968">Ovarian Low Malignant Potential Tumors Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef href="CDR0000256832">Tumores de células germinativas del ovario: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
