<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000657831"><TermName>capsule endoscope</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KAP-sul EN-doh-SKOPE)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A device used to look at the inside of the intestines and other parts of the digestive tract. It is a capsule that is about the size of a large pill, with a lens, a light, a camera, a radio transmitter, and a battery inside. The patient swallows the capsule and it takes pictures as it travels through the digestive tract. The pictures are sent to a small recorder that is worn on the patient’s waist or shoulder. The pictures are then viewed on a computer by the doctor to check for signs of disease. The capsule endoscope passes out of the body during a bowel movement. Also called wireless capsule endoscope.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000725706" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;capsule endoscope&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000725705" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cápsula endoscópica&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cápsula endoscópica</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Dispositivo que se usa para observar el interior de los intestinos y otras partes de las vías digestivas. Es una cápsula que tiene un tamaño parecido al de una pastilla grande con una lente, una luz, una cámara, un transmisor de radio y una batería en su interior. El paciente traga la cápsula y esta toma imágenes a medida que se desplaza por las vías digestivas. Las imágenes se envían a un grabador pequeño que se coloca en la cintura o el hombro del paciente. Luego, un médico observa las imágenes en una computadora para determinar si hay signos de enfermedad. La cápsula endoscópica  se evacúa del cuerpo con la materia fecal. También se llama cápsula endoscópica inalámbrica.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-03-01</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-07-16</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
