<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000612891"><TermName>stage III ovarian low malignant potential tumor</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… oh-VAYR-ee-un...muh-LIG-nunt poh-TEN-shul TOO-mer)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The tumor is found in one or both ovaries and has spread outside the pelvis to other parts of the abdomen and/or nearby lymph nodes. Stage III is divided into stages IIIA, IIIB, and IIIC. In stage IIIA, the tumor is found in the pelvis only, but tumor cells that can be seen only with a microscope have spread to the surface of the peritoneum (tissue that lines the abdominal wall and covers most of the organs in the abdomen), the small intestines, or the tissue that connects the small intestines to the wall of the abdomen. In stage IIIB, the tumor has spread to the peritoneum and the tumor in the peritoneum is 2 centimeters or smaller. In stage IIIC, the tumor has spread to the peritoneum and the tumor in the peritoneum is larger than 2 centimeters and/or has spread to lymph nodes in the abdomen. The spread of tumor cells to the surface of the liver is also considered stage III disease.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720667" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III ovarian low malignant potential tumor&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720666" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tumor del ovario de bajo potencial maligno en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>tumor del ovario de bajo potencial maligno en estadio III</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El tumor se encuentra en un ovario o en ambos, y se diseminó fuera de la pelvis hasta otras partes del abdomen o ganglios linfáticos cercanos  El estadio III se divide en los estadios IIIA,  IIIB y  IIIC. En el estadio IIIA, el tumor se encuentra solo en la pelvis, pero las células tumorales —que solo se pueden ver con un microscopio— se diseminaron hasta la superficie del peritoneo (tejido que reviste la pared abdominal y contiene la mayoría de los órganos en el abdomen), el intestino delgado o el tejido que conecta el intestino delgado con la pared del abdomen. En el estadio IIIB, el tumor se diseminó hasta el peritoneo y el tumor en el peritoneo mide dos centímetros o menos. En el estadio IIIC, el tumor se diseminó hasta el peritoneo y el tumor en el peritoneo mide más de dos centímetros de diámetro, o se diseminó hasta los ganglios linfáticos del abdomen. La diseminación de las células tumorales hasta la superficie del hígado también se considera enfermedad en estadio III.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-08-21</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2012-07-16</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062968">Ovarian Low Malignant Potential Tumors Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef href="CDR0000256832">Tumores de células germinativas del ovario: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
