<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000661196"><TermName>methemoglobinemia</TermName><TermPronunciation>(MET-hee-moh-GLOH-bih-NEE-mee-uh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A condition in which a higher-than-normal amount of methemoglobin is found in the blood. Methemoglobin is a form of hemoglobin that cannot carry oxygen.  In methemoglobinemia, tissues cannot get enough oxygen. Symptoms may include headache, dizziness, fatigue, shortness of breath, nausea, vomiting, rapid heartbeat, loss of muscle coordination, and blue-colored skin. Methemoglobinemia can be caused by injury or being exposed to certain drugs, chemicals, or foods. It can also be an inherited condition.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000726339" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;methemoglobinemia&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000726338" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;metahemoglobinemia&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>metahemoglobinemia</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección por la que se encuentra en la sangre una cantidad mayor que la normal de metahemoglobina. La metahemoglobina es una forma de hemoglobina que no puede transportar oxígeno.   En el caso de la metahemoglobinemia, los tejidos no pueden conseguir suficiente oxígeno.   Los síntomas pueden incluir dolor de cabeza, mareo, fatiga, falta de aliento, náuseas, vómitos, latidos cardíacos rápidos, pérdida de coordinación muscular y piel de color azul.   La causa  de la metahemoglobinemia puede ser una lesión o por la exposición a ciertos medicamentos, sustancias químicas o alimentos.   También puede ser una afección hereditaria.  </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2010-03-31</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
