<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000613891"><TermName>[18F]-labeled substance P antagonist receptor quantifier</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… LAY-buld SUB-stunts P an-TA-guh-nist reh-SEP-ter KWAN-tih-FY-er)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A radiolabeled substance being studied in PET imaging of the brain. It is also being studied as a way to find where cancer cells have spread in patients with pancreatic cancer. It binds to cell receptors for substance P, also known as neurokinin-1, which is found on nerve cells and on some types of cancer cells, such as pancreatic cancer cells. [18F]-labeled substance P antagonist receptor quantifier is a type of PET radioligand and a type of radiolabeled neurokinin-1 receptor antagonist.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720864" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;[18F]-labeled substance P antagonist receptor quantifier&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000720865" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cuantificador del receptor del antagonista de la sustancia P marcada [F18]&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cuantificador del receptor del antagonista de la sustancia P marcada [F18]</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Sustancia radiomarcada en estudio para su uso en pruebas de imaginología del cerebro realizadas con TEP. También está en estudio como un medio para determinar a dónde se diseminaron las células cancerosas en los pacientes de cáncer de páncreas. Se une a los receptores de la sustancia P, que también se llama  neurokinina-1, la cual se encuentra en las células nerviosas y en algunos tipos de células cancerosas, como las células del cáncer de páncreas. El cuantificador del receptor del antagonista de la sustancia P marcada [F18] es un tipo de radioligando de TEP y un tipo de antagonista del receptor de la  neurokinina-1 radiomarcada.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2008-09-03</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2009-01-13</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
