<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000769815"><TermName>pancreatic tumor</TermName><TermPronunciation>(PAN-kree-A-tik TOO-mer)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A tumor that forms in the cells of the pancreas. The two main types of pancreatic tumors are pancreatic exocrine tumors and pancreatic neuroendocrine tumors. Most pancreatic cancers are exocrine tumors, which form in cells that make enzymes to help the body digest food. Pancreatic neuroendocrine tumors form in neuroendocrine pancreas cells (such as islet cells). These cells make hormones that help control sugar levels in the blood. Pancreatic neuroendocrine tumors may be benign (not cancer) or malignant (cancer). They are much less common than pancreatic exocrine tumors and have a better prognosis.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000771216" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pancreatic tumor&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000771215" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tumor pancreático&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>tumor pancreático</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tumor que se forma en las células del páncreas. Los dos tipos principales de tumores pancreáticos son los tumores de páncreas exocrino y los tumores de páncreas neuroendocrino. La mayoría de los cánceres de páncreas son tumores exocrinos, que se forman en las células que elaboran enzimas para ayudar al cuerpo a digerir los alimentos. Los tumores de páncreas neuroendocrino se forman en las células del páncreas neuroendocrino (como las células de los islotes). Estas células elaboran hormonas que ayudan a controlar las concentraciones de azúcar en la sangre. Los tumores de páncreas neuroendocrino pueden ser benignos (no cancerosos) o malignos (cancerosos). Son mucho menos comunes que los tumores de páncreas exocrino y tienen un pronóstico mejor.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2015-03-09</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
