<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000740897"><TermName>Stivarga</TermName><TermPronunciation>(stih-VAR-guh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat colorectal cancer that has spread to other parts of the body and has not gotten better with other treatment. It is also used to treat gastrointestinal stromal tumors (GIST) that cannot be removed by surgery or have spread to other parts of the body and have not gotten better with other anticancer drugs. It is being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Stivarga blocks the action of certain proteins, which may help keep cancer cells from growing and may kill them. It may also prevent the growth of new blood vessels that tumors need to grow. Stivarga is a type of kinase inhibitor and a type of antiangiogenesis agent. Also called regorafenib.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000742092" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Stivarga&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000742091" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Stivarga&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Stivarga</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para tratar el cáncer colorrectal que se diseminó hasta otras partes del cuerpo y no mejoró con otro tratamiento. También se usa para tratar tumores del estroma gastrointestinal (TEGI) que no se pueden extirpar por medio de cirugía, o que se diseminaron hasta otras partes del cuerpo y no mejoraron con otros medicamentos contra el cáncer. Está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Stivarga impide la acción de ciertas proteínas, lo cual puede ayudar a evitar el crecimiento de las células cancerosas y eliminarlas. También puede prevenir la formación de nuevos vasos sanguíneos que los tumores necesitan para crecer. Stivarga es un tipo de inhibidor de la cinasa y un tipo de antiangiogénico. También se llama regorafenib.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2012-10-03</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-03-21</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000740826">Regorafenib</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
