<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000774376"><TermName>testicular sperm extraction</TermName><TermPronunciation>(tes-TIH-kyoo-ler spurm ek-STRAK-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure in which sperm cells are removed and either used right away to fertilize eggs or frozen for future infertility treatment.  Tissue is removed from the testicle through a small incision (cut) and looked at under a microscope in the laboratory to find sperm cells. Testicular sperm extraction may be useful for men who want to have children after having treatment that may cause infertility, such as certain cancer treatments. Testicular sperm extraction is a type of sperm retrieval method. Also called TESE.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000776500" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;testicular sperm extraction&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000776501" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;extracción de esperma del testículo&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>extracción de esperma del testículo</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento por el cual se extraen espermatozoides, ya sea para usarlos inmediatamente para fecundar óvulos o congelarlos para tratar la esterilidad en un futuro. Se extrae tejido de un testículo a través de una pequeña incisión (corte) y se examina al microscopio en busca de espermatozoides.  La extracción de esperma del testículo puede ser útil  para los hombres que quieren tener hijos después de un tratamiento que puede causar esterilidad, como ciertos tratamientos para el cáncer. La extracción de esperma del testículo es un tipo de método de extracción de esperma. También se llama EET.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2015-09-16</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2015-09-29</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
