<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000774405"><TermName>oocyte cryopreservation</TermName><TermPronunciation>(OH-oh-site KRY-oh-PREH-zer-VAY-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The process of freezing one or more unfertilized eggs (eggs that have not been combined with sperm) to save them for future use. The eggs are thawed and fertilized in the laboratory to make embryos that can be placed in a woman’s uterus. Oocyte cryopreservation is being studied as a type of fertility preservation. It may be useful for women with cancer who want to have children 
after having radiation therapy, chemotherapy, or certain types of surgery, which can  cause infertility. Also called egg cryopreservation and egg freezing.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000775008" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;oocyte cryopreservation&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000775007" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;crioconservación de ovocitos&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>crioconservación de ovocitos</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Proceso mediante el cual se congelan uno o más óvulos sin fertilizar (óvulos que no se combinaron con espermatorzoides) a fin de  guardarlos para su uso en el futuro. Los óvulos se descongelan y fertilizan en el laboratorio para producir embriones que se colocan en el útero de una mujer. La crioconservación de ovocitos está en estudio como un tipo de preservación de la fecundidad. Puede ser útil para las mujeres con cáncer que quieren tener hijos después de recibir radioterapia o quimioterapia o ciertos tipos de cirugía, que pueden causar infertilidad. También se llama congelamiento de óvulos y criopreservación de óvulos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2015-07-23</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2012-11-21</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
