<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000773861"><TermName>nuclear factor-kappa B</TermName><TermPronunciation>(NOO-klee-er FAK-ter-KA-puh …)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A group of proteins that help control many functions in a cell, including cell growth and survival. These proteins also control the body’s immune and inflammatory responses. Nuclear factor-kappa B may be overactive or found in higher than normal amounts in some types of cancer cells. This may lead to cancer cell growth. High levels or overactivity of nuclear factor-kappa B may also lead to inflammatory disorders, such as asthma and ulcerative colitis, and autoimmune disorders, such as rheumatoid arthritis. Also called NF-kappa B and NF-kB.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000776498" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;nuclear factor-kappa B&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000776499" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;factor nuclear kappa B&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>factor nuclear kappa B</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Grupo de proteínas que ayudan a controlar muchas funciones en la célula, como el crecimiento y la supervivencia. Estas proteínas también controlan las respuestas inmunitarias e inflamatorias. El factor nuclear kappa B puede ser hiperactivo o encontrarse en cantidades mayor que lo normal en algunos tipos de células cancerosas. Esto puede conllevar al crecimiento de células cancerosas. Las concentraciones altas o la activación excesiva   del factor nuclear kappa B pueden producir trastornos inflamatorios, como el asma y la colitis ulcerativa,  y trastornos autoinmunitarios como la artritis reumatoide. También se llama NF-kappa B y NF-kB.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2015-08-13</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
