<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000757527"><TermName>hyper-CVAD regimen</TermName><TermPronunciation>(HY-per ... REH-jih-men)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>An abbreviation for a chemotherapy combination used to treat some types of acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL) and non-Hodgkin lymphoma (NHL). Hyper-CVAD regimen includes the drugs cyclophosphamide, vincristine sulfate, doxorubicin hydrochloride (Adriamycin), and dexamethasone. It also includes the drugs methotrexate and cytarabine.  It is given as hyperfractionated therapy, in which the total dose of the drugs is divided into small doses and given more than once a day. Also called hyper-CVAD.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000760850" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hyper-CVAD regimen&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000760849" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;régimen hiper-CVAD&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>régimen hiper-CVAD</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Abreviación de una combinación quimioterapéutica que se usa para tratar algunos tipos de leucemia linfoblástica aguda (LLA)  y el linfoma no Hodgkin (LNH). El régimen hiper-CVDA incluye medicamentos como ciclofosfamida, sulfato de vincristina, clorhidrato de doxorrubicina (Adriamicina), y dexametasona. Tambien incluye los medicamentos metotrexato y citarabina. Se administra como terapia hiperfraccionada, en la cual la dosis total del medicamento se divide en dosis pequeñas y se adminstra más de una vez al día. También se llama hiper-CVAD.</DefinitionText><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2014-03-05</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000757219">Hyper-CVAD</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
