<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000736223"><TermName>stage III nonmelanoma skin cancer on the eyelid</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... non-MEH-luh-NOH-muh skin KAN-ser ... I-lid)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage III is divided into stages IIIA, IIIB, and IIIC. In stage IIIA, to remove all of the tumor, the whole eye and part of the optic nerve must be removed. The bone, muscles, fat, and connective tissue around the eye may also be removed. In stage IIIB, the tumor may be anywhere in or near the eye and has spread to nearby lymph nodes. In stage IIIC, the tumor has spread to structures around the eye or in the face, or to the brain, and cannot be removed in surgery.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000738138" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III nonmelanoma skin cancer on the eyelid&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000738137" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de piel no melanoma del párpado en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de piel no melanoma del párpado en estadio III</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio III se divide en los estadios IIIA, IIIB y IIIC. En el estadio IIIA, para extirpar el tumor, se debe extirpar todo el ojo y parte del nervio óptico. También se pueden extirpar los huesos, los músculos, y el tejido conjuntivo y graso alrededor del ojo. En el estadio IIIB, el tumor puede estar en cualquier sitio del ojo o cerca del ojo, y se diseminó hasta los ganglios linfáticos cercanos. En el estadio IIIC, el tumor se diseminó hasta estructuras que rodean el ojo, la cara o el cerebro, y no se puede extirpar mediante cirugía.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2012-06-28</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258035">Skin Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256809">Cáncer de piel: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
