<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000739361"><TermName>stage IV perihilar extrahepatic bile duct cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... PAYR-ee-HY-ler EK-struh-heh-PA-tik bile dukt KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage IV is divided into stages IVA and IVB. In stage IVA,  the tumor may have spread to nearby lymph nodes and has spread to one or more of the following: (1)  the main part of the portal vein or both branches of the portal vein; (2) the hepatic artery; (3) the right and left hepatic ducts; (4) the right hepatic duct and the left branch of the hepatic artery or of the portal vein; and/or (5) the left hepatic duct and the right branch of the hepatic artery or of the portal vein. In stage IVB, the tumor has spread to other parts of the body, such as the liver.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000742084" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IV perihilar extrahepatic bile duct cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000742083" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;carcinoma de vía biliar extrahepática perihiliar en estadio IV&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>carcinoma de vía biliar extrahepática perihiliar en estadio IV</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio IV se divide en los estadios IVA y IVB. En el estadio IVA, el tumor se puede haber diseminado hasta los ganglios linfáticos cercanos y se diseminó hasta uno o más de los sitios siguientes: 1) la parte principal de la vena porta o ambas ramas de la vena porta; 2) la arteria hepática; 3) los conductos hepáticos derecho e izquierdo; 4) el conducto hepático derecho y la rama izquierda de la arteria hepática o de la vena porta; o 5) el conducto hepático izquierdo y la rama derecha de la arteria hepática o de la vena porta. En el estadio IVB, el tumor se diseminó hasta otras partes del cuerpo, como el hígado.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2012-09-06</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-10-30</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258011">Bile Duct Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256805">Cáncer de las vías biliares extrahepáticas: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
