<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000702096"><TermName>multiple endocrine adenomatosis type 2A</TermName><TermPronunciation>(MUL-tih-pul EN-doh-krin A-deh-NOH-muh-TOH-sis ...)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare,
          genetic disorder that affects the endocrine glands and
          causes a type of thyroid cancer called medullary thyroid
          cancer, pheochromocytoma, and parathyroid gland cancer. It
          may also cause benign (noncancerous) tumors in the
          parathyroid glands and adrenal glands. The affected
          endocrine glands may make high levels of hormones, which
          can lead to other medical problems such as high blood
          pressure and kidney stones. An itchy skin condition may
          also occur. Multiple endocrine adenomatosis type 2A is caused
          by a mutation (change) in a gene called
          RET. Also called MEN2A, MEN2A syndrome, multiple endocrine neoplasia type 2A syndrome,  and Sipple syndrome.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733003" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;multiple endocrine adenomatosis type 2A&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733004" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;adenomatosis endocrina múltiple tipo 2A&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>adenomatosis endocrina múltiple tipo 2A</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno genético poco
frecuente que afecta las glándulas endocrinas y causa un
tipo de cáncer de tiroides que se llama cáncer medular de
tiroides, feocromocitoma y cáncer de la glándula
paratiroidea. También puede causar tumores benignos (no
cancerosos) en las glándulas paratiroideas y las glándulas
suprarrenales. Las glándulas endocrinas afectadas pueden
elaborar concentraciones grandes de hormonas que pueden
conducir a otros problemas médicos como presión arterial
alta y cálculos renales. También se puede presentar una
afección con picazón de la piel. La adenomatosis endocrina múltiple tipo 2A
obedece a una mutación (cambio) en un gen que se llama
RET. También se llama NEM2A, síndrome de NEM2A, síndrome de neoplasia endocrina múltiple tipo 2A,  y síndrome de Sipple.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2011-10-21</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
