<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000774826"><TermName>electronic health record</TermName><TermPronunciation>(eh-lek-TRAH-nik helth REH-kurd)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>An electronic (digital) collection of medical information about a person that is stored on a computer. An electronic health record includes information about a patient’s health history, such as diagnoses, medicines, tests, allergies, immunizations, and treatment plans.  Electronic health records can be seen by all healthcare providers who are taking care of a patient and can be used by them to help make recommendations about the patient’s care. Also called EHR and electronic medical record.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000776466" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;electronic health record&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000776467" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;historia clínica digital&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>historia clínica digital</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Recopilación de la información médica de un paciente en formato digital (electrónico) que se guarda en una computadora. Una historia clínica digital incluye información sobre los antecedentes de salud de un paciente (como diagnósticos, medicamentos, pruebas, alergias, vacunaciones y planes de tratamiento). Todos los proveedores de atención de la salud a cargo de un paciente pueden ver y usar las historia clínicas digitales para ayudarlos a dar recomendaciones  acerca de la atención del paciente. También se llama HCE y historia clínica electrónica.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2015-09-22</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2015-09-29</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
