<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000739785"><TermName>individualized education plan</TermName><TermPronunciation>(in-dih-VIH-joo-wuh-lized EH-juh-KAY-shun plan)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>An education plan for children with certain disabilities or health conditions, such as cancer. By law, these children must  receive special education services and other support they need in school. An individualized education plan describes which special services the child needs and how those needs will be met. This may include special class placement, extra help with class assignments and tests, tutoring, and other services such as counseling, speech therapy, and physical therapy. Individualized education plans are covered in the U.S. law, Individuals with Disabilities Education Act. Also called IEP.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000745261" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;individualized education plan&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000745262" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;plan de educación individualizado&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>plan de educación individualizado</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Plan de ducación para niños con ciertas discapacidades o afecciones de salud, como el cáncer. Por ley, estos niños deben recibir servicios de educación especial y otras formas de apoyo que necesiten en la escuela. Un plan de educación individualizado describe cuáles son los servicios especiales que el niño necesita y el modo en que se van a satisfacer esas necesidades. Esto puede incluir la colocación del niño en clases especiales, ayuda extra con las tareas y exámenes en clases, tutoría y otros servicios como consejería, foniatría y fisioterapia. Los planes de educación individualizados están garantizados por la ley de los Estados Unidos <ForeignWord>Individuals with Disabilities Education Act</ForeignWord> (Ley para la educación de individuos con discapacidades). También se llama PEI.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2012-11-21</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000739789">504 plan</RelatedGlossaryTermRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
