<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000774384"><TermName>follow-up care</TermName><TermPronunciation>(FAH-loh-up kayr)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Care given to a patient over time after finishing treatment for a disease. Follow-up care involves regular medical checkups,   which may include a physical exam, blood tests, and imaging tests. Follow-up care checks for health problems that may occur months or years after treatment ends, including the development of other types of cancer. Follow-up care is given after positive screening test results, such as a positive Pap test result. In cancer patients, one purpose of follow-up care is checking to see if the cancer has come back or has spread to other parts of the body.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000776510" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;follow-up care&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000776509" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;atención de seguimiento&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>atención de seguimiento</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cuidado que se brinda a un paciente durante cierto tiempo después de terminar el tratamiento de una enfermedad. La atención de seguimiento consiste en reconocimientos médicos regulares, que pueden incluir un examen físico, análisis de sangre y pruebas de imágenes. Durante la atención de seguimiento, se vigilan problemas de salud que se pueden presentar meses o años después de terminar el tratamiento, como la presencia de otros tipos de cáncer. La atención de seguimiento se realiza después de que se obtienen resultados positivos en los exámenes de detección, como un resultado positivo de la prueba de Pap. En los pacientes de cáncer, uno de los propósitos de la atención de seguimiento es determinar si el cáncer volvió o se diseminó otras partes del cuerpo.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2015-09-16</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2015-09-29</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/coping/survivorship/follow-up-care/follow-up-fact-sheet">Follow-up Care After Cancer Treatment</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/sobrellevar/supervivencia/cuidados-de-seguimiento/hoja-informativa-cuidados-de-seguimiento">Cuidados de seguimiento después del tratamiento del cáncer</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
