<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000753376"><TermName>estrogen cream</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ES-truh-jin creem)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A cream that contains the hormone estrogen. It is used to treat some symptoms of menopause, such as vaginal dryness and painful intercourse. It may also be used to treat certain types of urinary incontinence (inability to control the flow of urine from the bladder). Estrogen cream is usually applied to the vagina, vulva, or opening of the urethra. It may also be applied to the cervix in some women who have certain abnormal cell changes caused by low hormone levels. Treatment with estrogen cream usually helps make these abnormal cells go away.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000759304" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;estrogen cream&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000759305" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;crema de estrógeno&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>crema de estrógeno</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Crema que contiene la hormona estrógeno. Se usa para tratar algunos síntomas de la menopausia, como la sequedad vaginal y el dolor durante las relaciones sexuales. También se puede usar para tratar ciertos tipos de incontinencia urinaria (incapacidad de controlar el flujo de orina de la vejiga). La crema de estrógeno se aplica habitualmente en la vagina, la vulva o la abertura de la uretra. También se puede aplicar en el cuello uterino de algunas mujeres con ciertos cambios celulares anormales causados por concentraciones hormonales bajas. Con frecuencia, el tratamiento con crema de estrógeno ayuda a que desaparezcan estas células anormales.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-12-19</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-12-19</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
