<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000744885"><TermName>stage IIB intraocular melanoma of the ciliary body and choroid</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... IN-truh-AH-kyoo-ler MEH-luh-NOH-muh ... SIH-lee-ayr-ee BAH-dee ... KOR-oyd)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage II is divided into stages IIA and IIB.  In stage IIB, the tumor (1) has spread to the ciliary body and is size category 2 (12.1 to 18 millimeters wide and not more than 3 millimeters thick; or 9.1 to 15 millimeters wide and 3.1 to 6 millimeters thick; or not more than 12 millimeters wide and 6.1 to 9 millimeters thick); or (2) is in the choroid only and is size category 3 (15.1 to 18 millimeters wide and 3.1 to 6 millimeters thick; or 12.1 to 18 millimeters wide and 6.1 to 9 millimeters thick; or 3.1 to 18 millimeters wide and 9.1 to 12 millimeters thick; or 9.1 to 15 millimeters wide and 12.1 to 15 millimeters thick).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000746291" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IIB intraocular melanoma of the ciliary body and choroid&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000746290" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;melanoma ocular del cuerpo ciliar y la coroides en estadio IIB&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>melanoma ocular del cuerpo ciliar y la coroides en estadio IIB</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio II se divide en los estadios IIA y IIB. En el estadio IIB, el tumor 1) se diseminó hacia el cuerpo ciliar y el tamaño es de categoría 2 (de 12,1 a 18 mm de ancho y no más de 3 mm de grosor, o de 9,1 a 15 mm de ancho y  3,1 a 6 mm de grosor; o no más de 12 mm de ancho y  6,1 a 9 mm de grosor); o 2) está en la coroides y el tamaño es de categoría 3 (15,1 a 18 mm de ancho y  3,1 a 6 mm de grosor; o de 12,1 a 18 mm de ancho y  6,1 a 9 mm de grosor; o de 3,1 a 18 mm de ancho y  9,1 a 12 mm de grosor; o de 9,1 a 15 mm de ancho y  12,1 a 15 mm de grosor).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-01-09</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258015">Intraocular (Uveal) Melanoma Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000537037">Melanoma ocular uveal: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
