<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000745787"><TermName>latissimus dorsi flap</TermName><TermPronunciation>(luh-TIH-sih-mus DOR-sy …)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of surgery used to rebuild the shape of the breast after a mastectomy.  A muscle in the back called the latissimus dorsi, along with skin, fat, and blood vessels, is moved from the back to the chest to form a new breast mound or to form a pocket for a breast implant. This is usually done by passing the muscle tissue and blood vessels through a tunnel under the skin to the chest.  A latissimus dorsi flap is a type of breast reconstruction.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000749840" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;latissimus dorsi flap&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000749841" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;colgajo de dorsal ancho&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>colgajo de dorsal ancho</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de cirugía que se usa para reconstruir la forma de la mama después de una mastectomía. Se lleva un músculo de la espalda, que se llama dorsal ancho,  junto con la piel, la grasa y los vasos sanguíneos hasta el pecho para formar un nuevo montículo en el pecho o una bolsa para un implante de mama. Esto se realiza habitualmente mediante el pasaje de tejido muscular y vasos sanguíneos a través de un túnel debajo de la piel hasta el pecho. Un colgajo  de dorsal ancho es un tipo de reconstrucción de la mama.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-04-01</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/breast/reconstruction-fact-sheet">Breast Reconstruction After Mastectomy</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/seno/hoja-informativa-reconstruccion">La reconstrucción del seno después de una mastectomía</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
