<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000773856"><TermName>yeast infection</TermName><TermPronunciation>(yeest in-FEK-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A condition in which too much yeast grows in certain areas of the body and causes symptoms and disease. Small amounts of yeast normally live on the skin and in other parts of the body, such as the mouth, throat, and vagina. Sometimes, too much yeast can grow in these areas and cause infection. Yeast infections may also occur in the blood and spread throughout the body, but this is rare. Certain conditions, such as a weakened immune system, diabetes, pregnancy, hormone changes, and stress, and use of certain medicines may increase the risk of yeast infection.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000776490" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;yeast infection&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000776491" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;infección por hongos&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>infección por hongos</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno en el que crecen muchos hongos en ciertas áreas del cuerpo causando síntomas y enfermedades. Por lo general,  cantidades pequeñas de hongos viven en la piel y otras partes del cuerpo  como la boca, la garganta y la vagina. Algunas veces una gran cantidad de hongos crece en estas áreas y ocasiona infecciones. Las infecciones con hongos también se pueden presentar en la sangre y diseminarse por todo el cuerpo, pero esto es poco común. Ciertos trastornos, como tener un sistema inmunitario débil, diabetes, embarazo, cambios hormonales,  tensión y el uso de ciertos medicamentos pueden aumentar el riesgo de infección por hongos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2015-08-13</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
