<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000753519"><TermName>gonadotropin-releasing hormone antagonist</TermName><TermPronunciation>(goh-NA-doh-TROH-pin-reh-LEE-sing HOR-mone an-TA-guh-nist)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A substance that blocks the pituitary gland from making hormones called follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH) and luteinizing hormone (LH). In men, this causes the testicles to stop making testosterone. In women, this causes the ovaries to stop making estrogen and progesterone. Some gonadotropin-releasing hormone antagonists are used to treat advanced prostate cancer. They are also used to treat certain gynecologic conditions and are being studied in the treatment of hormone-sensitive breast cancer.  Also called GnRH antagonist, LH-RH antagonist,  and luteinizing hormone-releasing hormone antagonist.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000757966" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;gonadotropin-releasing hormone antagonist&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000757965" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;antagonista de la hormona liberadora de gonadotropinas&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>antagonista de la hormona liberadora de gonadotropinas</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Sustancia que impide que la hipófisis elabore hormonas que se llaman hormona estimulante de los folículos  (FSH) y hormona luteinizante (HL). En los hombres, esta sustancia hace que los testículos dejen de producir testosterona. En las mujeres, hace que los ovarios dejen de producir estrógeno y progesterona. Algunos antagonistas de la hormona liberadora de hormona luteinizante se usan para tratar el cáncer de próstata en estadio avanzado. También se utilizan para tratar ciertas afecciones ginecológicas; además, se utilizan para tratar el cáncer de mama sensible a las hormonas. También se llama antagonista de la HL-HL, antagonista de la HLGn,  y antagonista de la hormona liberadora de hormona luteinizante.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-11-26</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/prostate/prostate-hormone-therapy-fact-sheet">Hormone Therapy for Prostate Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/prostata/hoja-informativa-terapia-hormonal">Terapia hormonal para el cáncer de próstata</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
