<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000770485"><TermName>cancer-related post-traumatic stress</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KAN-ser-ree-LAY-ted post-traw-MA-tik stress)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A condition
          that develops in some people who are diagnosed with cancer.
          Symptoms of cancer-related post-traumatic stress (PTS)
          include having frightening thoughts or trouble sleeping,
          being distracted or overexcited, feeling alone, or losing
          interest in daily activities. Symptoms may also include
          feelings of shock, fear, helplessness, or horror.
          Cancer-related PTS can occur anytime after diagnosis,
          including during or after treatment. Relaxation training,
          counseling, support groups, and certain medicines may be
          used to reduce symptoms of PTS.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000774997" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cancer-related post-traumatic stress&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000774998" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tensión postraumática relacionada con el cáncer&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>tensión postraumática relacionada con el cáncer</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección que se presenta en algunas personas diagnosticadas con cáncer. Los síntomas de tensión postraumática relacionada con el cáncer (TPT)
          incluyen tener pensamientos de temor o problemas para dormir, estar distraído o sobrexcitado, sentirse solo o perder el interés por las actividades diarias. Los síntomas también pueden incluir  sensaciones de perturbación, miedo, impotencia o  horror. La TPT relacionada con el cáncer se puede presentar en cualquier momento después del diagnóstico, incluso durante el tratamiento o después de este. Para reducir los síntomas de TPT se pueden usar  elentrenamiento para la relajación,  el asesoramiento, los grupos de apoyo y ciertos medicamentos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2015-06-17</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
