<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000775082"><TermName>school liaison</TermName><TermPronunciation>(skool lee-AY-zan)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A person who helps a child return to school after a serious illness, such as cancer, or a long hospital stay. A school liaison may also arrange for education services in the child’s home or at the hospital if the child is not able to return to school. School liaisons help parents, teachers, and other students understand special issues that the child may have in returning to the classroom as a result of the illness or its treatment. This may help in planning extra education services and support that the child may need.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000776519" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;school liaison&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000776518" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;coordinador de educación&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>coordinador de educación</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Persona que ayuda a un niño a volver a la escuela después de una enfermedad grave, como un cáncer o una hospitalización larga. Un coordinador de educación también puede organizar servicios educativos en el hogar o en el hospital para un niño que no puede volver a la institución educativa.  Los coordinadores de educación ayudan a los padres, educadores y otros estudiantes a entender los problemas especiales que el niño puede enfrentar al volver a la clase como consecuencia de la enfermedad o su tratamiento. Esto puede hacer más fácil la planificación de servicios educativos adicionales y el apoyo que el niño pueda necesitar.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2015-09-29</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
