<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000700845"><TermName>radiation poisoning</TermName><TermPronunciation>(RAY-dee-AY-shun POY-zuh-ning)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Serious illness caused by being exposed to high doses of certain types of radiation, usually over a short period of time. Symptoms of radiation poisoning usually occur right after exposure but they may happen over time, and they may come and go. Symptoms include nausea and vomiting, diarrhea, headache, dizziness, weakness, fatigue, bleeding, hair loss, swelling, itching, and redness of the skin, and other skin problems. Very large doses of radiation may cause death. Also called acute radiation sickness, acute radiation syndrome, radiation sickness,  and radiation sickness syndrome.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733299" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;radiation poisoning&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733298" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;intoxicación por radiación&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>intoxicación por radiación</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Enfermedad grave causada por la exposición a dosis alta de ciertos tipos de radiación, habitualmente durante un tiempo corto. Los síntomas de la intoxicación por radiacíon generalmente se presentan enseguida después de la exposición, pero pueden aparecer con el tiempo o presentarse y desaparecer. Los síntomas incluyen náuseas y vómitos, diarrea, dolor de cabeza, mareos, fatiga, sangrado, pérdida de cabello e hinchazón, enrojecimiento y problemas de la piel. Las dosis muy grandes de radiación pueden causar la muerte. También se llama enfermedad aguda por radiación, enfermedad por radiación, síndrome agudo por radiación,  y síndrome de enfermedad por radiación.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2011-07-08</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
