<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000748811"><TermName>water pipe</TermName><TermPronunciation>(WAH-ter …)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A device used to smoke a special type of tobacco that comes in different flavors. In a water pipe, charcoal is used to heat the tobacco. The smoke from the heated tobacco is cooled by passing it through a water-filled bowl. It is then inhaled through a flexible tube with a mouthpiece. Water pipe tobacco smoke contains nicotine and many cancer-causing chemicals that are harmful to both smokers and nonsmokers. Water pipe smoking can lead to nicotine addiction and can cause many of the same health problems as cigarette smoking. Water pipe smoking is not safer than cigarette smoking. Also called hookah.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752600" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;water pipe&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752601" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pipa de agua&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>pipa de agua</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Dispositivo que se usa para fumar un tipo especial de tabaco que viene en diferentes sabores. En una pipa de agua se utiliza carbón vegetal para calentar el tabaco. El humo caliente del tabaco se enfría al pasar a través de un recipiente lleno de agua. Se inhala luego a través de un tubo flexible con una boquilla. El humo del tabaco de una pipa de agua contiene nicotina y muchos sustancias químicas que causan cáncer y que son dañinas para los fumadores y los no fumadores. Fumar pipa de agua puede causar adicción a la nicotina y  a muchos de los mismos problemas de salud que el consumo de cigarrillo. Fumar  pipa de agua no es más seguro que fumar cigarrillos. También se llama narguile.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-07-18</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
