<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000774694"><TermName>grade</TermName><TermPronunciation>(grayd)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>In cancer, a description of a tumor based on how abnormal the cancer cells and tissue look under a microscope and how quickly the cancer cells are likely to grow and spread. Low-grade cancer cells look more like normal cells and tend to grow and spread more slowly than high-grade cancer cells. Grading systems are different for each type of cancer.  They are used to help plan treatment and determine prognosis. Also called histologic grade and tumor grade.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000776458" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;grade&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000776459" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;grado&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>grado</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>En el ámbito del cáncer, es la descripción de un tumor según cuán anormales se vean las células y los tejidos cancerosos al microscopio y con qué rapidez es posible que las células cancerosas se multipliquen y diseminen. Las células cancerosas de grado bajo tienen un aspecto más parecido al de las células normales y tienden a multiplicarse y diseminarse más lentamente que las células cancerosas de grado alto. Los sistemas de clasificación para cada tipo de cáncer son diferentes. Se usan para ayudar a planificar el tratamiento y determinar el pronóstico. También se llama grado del tumor y grado histológico.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2015-08-19</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2015-09-28</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/diagnosis-staging/prognosis/tumor-grade-fact-sheet">Tumor Grade</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/diagnostico-estadificacion/pronostico/hoja-informativa-grado-tumor">Grado de un tumor</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
