<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000764137"><TermName>Aicardi syndrome</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ay-KAR-dee SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare, genetic disorder marked by a lack of tissue connecting the left and right halves of the brain, seizures, lesions on the back of the eye (retina), and other brain and eye abnormalities. Other problems may include unusual facial features, defects of the hands, spine, and ribs, and developmental and gastrointestinal problems. When Aicardi syndrome occurs, it is almost always in a newborn girl. People with Aicardi syndrome have an increased risk of certain tumors, such as hepatoblastoma (a type of liver cancer) and choroid plexus tumors (a rare tumor that forms in the brain).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000769380" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Aicardi syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000769379" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de Aicardi&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>síndrome de Aicardi</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno genético poco frecuente que se caracteriza por una falta de tejido que conecta las mitades izquierda y derecha del cerebro, crisis epilépticas, lesiones en la parte posterior del ojo (retina), y otras anomalías en el cerebro y los ojos. Otros problemas pueden ser características faciales poco habituales, defectos en las manos, la columna vertebral y las costillas, y problemas gastrointestinales y de desarrollo. Las niñas recién nacidas son las más afectadas por el síndrome de Aicardi. Las personas con este síndrome tienen un mayor riesgo de ciertos tumores, como el hepatoblastoma (un tipo de cáncer de hígado) y los tumores del plexo coroideo (un tumor poco frecuente que se forma en el cerebro).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2014-11-07</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
