<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000744185"><TermName>ponatinib hydrochloride</TermName><TermPronunciation>(poh-NA-tih-nib HY-droh-KLOR-ide)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat chronic myelogenous leukemia (CML) and Philadelphia chromosome-positive acute lymphoblastic leukemia. It is used in patients who are not able to take or have not gotten better after treatment with other anticancer drugs.  It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Ponatinib hydrochloride blocks BCR-ABL and other proteins, which may help keep cancer cells from growing and may kill them. It may also prevent the growth of new blood vessels that tumors need to grow. It is a type of tyrosine kinase inhibitor and a type of angiogenesis inhibitor. Also called Iclusig.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000746318" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ponatinib hydrochloride&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000746319" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;clorhidrato de ponatinib&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>clorhidrato de ponatinib</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para tratar la leucemia mielógena crónica (LMC) y la leucemia linfoblástica aguda positiva para el cromosoma Filadelfia. Se utiliza para pacientes que pueden tomar otros medicamentos contra el cáncer o que no mejoraron con estos. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El clorhidrato de ponatinib bloquea la BCR-ABL y otras proteínas; esto puede impedir el crecimiento de células cancerosas y destruirlas. Asimismo, puede prevenir la formación de los nuevos vasos sanguíneos que los tumores necesitan para crecer. Es un tipo de inhibidor de la tirosina cinasa y un tipo de inhibidor de la angiogénesis. También se llama Iclusig.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2012-12-20</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000744060">Ponatinib Hydrochloride</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
