<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000742486"><TermName>positron emission tomography-computed tomography scan</TermName><TermPronunciation>(PAH-zih-tron ee-MIH-shun toh-MAH-gruh-fee-kum-PYOO-ted-toh-MAH-gruh-fee skan)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure that combines the pictures from a positron emission tomography (PET) scan and a computed tomography (CT) scan. The PET and CT scans are done at the same time with the same machine. The combined scans give more detailed pictures of areas inside the body than either scan gives by itself. A positron emission tomography-computed tomography scan may be used to help diagnose disease, such as cancer, plan treatment, or find out how well treatment is working. Also called PET-CT scan.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000746306" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;positron emission tomography-computed tomography scan&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000746307" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;exploración por tomografía con emisión de positrones-tomografía computarizada&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>exploración por tomografía con emisión de positrones-tomografía computarizada</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento en el que se combinan imágenes obtenidas en una exploración por tomografía con emisión de positrones (TEP) con una tomografía computarizada (TC). Las exploraciones por TEP y TC se realizan al mismo tiempo con el mismo aparato. Las exploraciones combinadas producen imágenes más detalladas de áreas del interior del cuerpo que la que produce cada exploración por separado. Una exploración por tomografía con emisión de positrones-tomografía computarizada ser puede usar para ayudar a diagnosticar una enfermedad como el cáncer, planificar un tratamiento o verificar si el tratamiento es eficaz. También se llama exploración por TEP-TC.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-01-15</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
