<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000702100"><TermName>multiple endocrine neoplasia type 2B syndrome</TermName><TermPronunciation>(MUL-tih-pul EN-doh-krin NEE-oh-PLAY-zhuh ... SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare, genetic disorder that affects the endocrine glands and causes a type of thyroid cancer called medullary thyroid cancer, pheochromocytoma, and parathyroid gland cancer. It may also cause benign (noncancerous) tumors in the adrenal glands and growths around the nerves in the lips, tongue, lining of the mouth, and eyelids. Gastrointestinal symptoms and trouble with the spine or bones in the feet and thighs may also occur.  Multiple endocrine neoplasia type 2B syndrome is caused by a mutation (change) in a gene called RET. Also called MEN2B, MEN2B syndrome,  and multiple endocrine adenomatosis type 2B.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733008" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;multiple endocrine neoplasia type 2B syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733007" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de neoplasia endocrina múltiple tipo 2B&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>síndrome de neoplasia endocrina múltiple tipo 2B</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno genético poco frecuente que afecta las glándulas endocrinas y causa un tipo de cáncer de tiroides que se llama cáncer medular de tiroides,  feocromocitoma y cáncer de la glándula paratiroidea. También puede causar tumores benignos (no cancerosos) en las glándulas paratiroideas y crecimientos alrededor de los nervios de los labios, la lengua, el revestimiento de la boca y los párpados. También se pueden presentar síntomas gastrointestinales y problemas en la espina vertebral o los huesos de los pies o los muslos. El síndrome de neoplasia endocrina múltiple tipo 2 obedece a una mutación (cambio) en un gen que se llama RET. También se llama adenomatosis endocrina múltiple tipo 2B, NEM2B,  y síndrome de NEM2B.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2011-10-21</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
