<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000753608"><TermName>complete androgen blockade</TermName><TermPronunciation>(kum-PLEET AN-droh-jen blah-KAYD)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Treatment used to block androgen (male hormone) activity in the body. This may be done by giving an antiandrogen drug and removing the testicles (orchiectomy) or by giving an antiandrogen drug with a gonadotropin-releasing hormone (GnRH) agonist. Complete androgen blockade may stop the growth of cancer cells that need androgens to grow, and is used in the treatment of prostate cancer. Also called combined androgen blockade and total androgen blockade.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000757939" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;complete androgen blockade&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000757938" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;bloqueo completo de andrógenos&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>bloqueo completo de andrógenos</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tratamiento que se usa para impedir la acción del  andrógeno (hormona masculina) en el cuerpo. Esto se puede hacer mediante la administración de un medicamento antiandrógeno y la extirpación de los testículos (orquiectomía), o la administración de un medicamento antiandrógeno con un agonista de la hormona liberadora de gonadotropina (HLGn). El bloqueo completo de andrógenos puede impedir la formación de células cancerosas que necesitan andrógenos para crecer y se usa para tratar el cáncer de próstata. También se llama bloqueo combinado de andrógenos y bloqueo total de andrógenos.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-12-05</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2014-01-21</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/prostate/prostate-hormone-therapy-fact-sheet">Hormone Therapy for Prostate Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/prostata/hoja-informativa-terapia-hormonal">Terapia hormonal para el cáncer de próstata</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
