<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000748155"><TermName>chronic bronchitis</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KRAH-nik bron-KY-tis)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A lung condition that develops over time in which the bronchi (large air passages that lead to the lungs) become inflamed and scarred. This causes the bronchi to make large amounts of mucus and can lead to a chronic cough and breathing problems. The most common cause of chronic bronchitis is cigarette smoking. It may also be caused by infection or by breathing in secondhand tobacco smoke, chemical fumes, or other forms of air pollution. Chronic bronchitis usually does not go away completely. It is a type of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752556" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;chronic bronchitis&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752555" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;bronquitis crónica&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>bronquitis crónica</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección pulmonar que se presenta con el tiempo en la que los bronquios (grandes conductos de aire que conducen a los pulmones) se inflaman y forman cicatrices. Esto hace que los bronquios produzcan grandes cantidades de moco y puede causar tos crónica y problemas respiratorios. La causa más común de la bronquitis crónica es el consumo de cigarrillo. También puede ser causada por infecciones o por la exposición pasiva al humo de tabaco en el ambiente, vapores químicos u otras formas de contaminación del aire. La bronquitis crónica generalmente no desaparece por completo. Es un tipo de enfermedad pulmonar obstructiva crónica (EPOC).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-07-18</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
