<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000748830"><TermName>Surgeon General</TermName><TermPronunciation>(SER-jun JEH-neh-rul)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The chief medical doctor and health educator for the United States. The mission of the U.S. Surgeon General is to give the public the best scientific information available on how to improve health and lower the risk of illness and injury. The U.S. Surgeon General oversees the U.S. Public Health Service and is chosen by the U.S. President. Each state public health agency and branch of the U.S. military also has its own Surgeon General. The office of the U.S. Surgeon General is part of the Department of Health and Human Services (DHHS).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752621" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Surgeon General&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752620" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Director general de sanidad&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Director general de sanidad</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Jefe médico y educador de la salud de los Estados Unidos. La misión del Director General de Sanidad de los Estados Unidos es proporcionar al público la mejor información científica disponible sobre la forma de mejorar la salud y reducir el riesgo de enfermedades y lesiones. El Director General de Sanidad de los Estados Unidos supervisa el Servicio de Salud Pública de los Estados Unidos; es elegido por el presidente del país. Cada agencia estatal de salud pública y rama militar del país también tienen su propio Jefe del cuerpo de Sanidad. La oficina del Director General de Sanidad de los Estados Unidos forma parte del Departamento de Salud y Servicios Humanos (DHHS).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-07-18</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
