<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000739945"><TermName>Synovir</TermName><TermPronunciation>(SIH-noh-veer)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used with another drug to treat multiple myeloma in patients who have just been diagnosed. It is also used to treat a painful skin disease related to leprosy. It is being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Synovir may help the immune system kill cancer cells. It may also prevent the growth of new blood vessels that tumors need to grow. It is a type of antiangiogenesis agent and a type of immunomodulating agent. Also called thalidomide and Thalomid.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000742100" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Synovir&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000742099" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Synovir&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Synovir</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa combinado con otro para tratar el mieloma múltiple en los pacientes recién diagnosticados. También se usa para el tratamiento de una enfermedad dolorosa de la piel relacionada con la lepra. Asimismo, está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Synovir podría ayudar al sistema inmunitario a eliminar las células cancerosas. También podría ayudar a prevenir la formación de vasos sanguíneos nuevos que los tumores necesitan para crecer. Es un tipo de inhibidor de la angiogénesis e inmunomodulador. También se llama talidomida y Thalomid.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2012-09-25</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2012-09-25</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000496418">Thalidomide</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
