<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000749906"><TermName>GTD</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare
          condition in which abnormal cells grow inside the uterus
          from tissue that forms after conception (the joining of
          sperm and egg). This tissue is made of trophoblastic cells,
          which normally surround the fertilized egg in the uterus
          and help connect the fertilized egg to the wall of the
          uterus. These cells also form part of the placenta (the
          organ that passes nutrients from the mother to the fetus).
          Most GTDs are benign (not
          cancer) and do not spread, but some types are malignant
          (cancer) and spread to nearby tissues or other parts of the
          body. The two main types of GTDs
          are hydatidiform mole and choriocarcinoma. Also called gestational trophoblastic disease, gestational trophoblastic tumor,  and GTT.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><SpanishTermName>ETG</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección poco frecuente en la que se forman células anormales en el interior del útero a partir del tejido que se origina después de la concepción (la unión de un espermatozoide y un óvulo). Este tejido está compuesto de células trofoblásticas, que normalmente envuelven el óvulo fertilizado en el útero y ayudan a conectarlo a la pared del útero. Estas células también forman parte de la placenta (el órgano que pasa los nutrientes de la madre al feto). La mayoría de las ETG son benignas (no cancerosas) y no se diseminan, pero algunos tipos son malignos (cancerosos) y se diseminan hasta los tejidos cercanos o hasta otras partes del cuerpo. Los dos tipos principales de ETG son la mola hidatiforme y el coriocarcinoma. También se llama enfermedad trofoblástica de la gestación, TTG,  y tumor trofoblástico de la gestación.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-07-17</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-07-16</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/gestational-trophoblastic">Gestational
Trophoblastic Disease </RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/trofoblastico-gestacion">Enfermedad
trofoblástica de la
gestación</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
