<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000753531"><TermName>pancreatic neuroendocrine tumor</TermName><TermPronunciation>(PAN-kree-A-tik NOOR-oh-EN-doh-krin TOO-mer)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A tumor that forms
          in islet cells (hormone-making cells) of the pancreas.
          Pancreatic neuroendocrine tumors may be
          benign (not cancer) or malignant (cancer). Islet cells make
          several different hormones that affect body functions,
          including controlling the amount of glucose (sugar) in the
          blood and helping digest food in the stomach. Functional
          pancreatic neuroendocrine tumors make extra
          amounts of these hormones, which can cause symptoms.
          Nonfunctional pancreatic neuroendocrine tumors
          do not make extra amounts of hormones, but they may cause
          symptoms as they grow and spread. Also called islet cell tumor and pancreatic endocrine tumor.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000757975" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pancreatic neuroendocrine tumor&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000757976" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tumor neuroendocrino de páncreas&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>tumor neuroendocrino de páncreas</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tumor que se forma en las células de los islotes (células que producen hormonas) del páncreas. Los tumores neuroendocrinos de páncreas pueden ser benignos (no cancerosos) o malignos (cancerosos). Las células de los islotes producen varias hormonas diferentes que afectan el funcionamiento del cuerpo, como controlar la cantidad de glucosa (azúcar) en la sangre y ayudar al estómago a digerir los alimentos. Los tumores neuroendocrinos de páncreas funcionantes producen cantidades adicionales de estas hormonas, lo que puede causar síntomas. Los tumores neuroendocrinos de páncreas no funcionantes no producen cantidades adicionales de hormonas, pero pueden causar síntomas a medida que crecen y se diseminan. También se llama tumor de células de los islotes y tumor endocrino de páncreas.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-12-03</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-12-03</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/pancreatic">Pancreatic Cancer
</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/pancreas">Cáncer de páncreas</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
