<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000737998"><TermName>HER2 positive</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… PAH-zih-tiv)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Describes cancer cells that have too much of a protein called HER2 on their surface. In normal cells, HER2 helps to control cell growth. When it is made in larger than normal amounts by cancer cells, the cells may grow more quickly and be more likely to spread to other parts of the body. Checking to see if a cancer is HER2 positive may help plan treatment, which may include drugs that kill HER2 positive cancer cells. Cancers that may be HER2 positive include breast, bladder, pancreatic, ovarian, and stomach cancers. Also called c-erbB-2 positive and human epidermal growth factor receptor 2 positive.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000743003" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;HER2 positive&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000743002" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;positivo al HER2&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>positivo al HER2</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Describe células cancerosas con demasiadas proteínas llamadas HER2 en su superficie. En las células normales, HER2 ayuda a controlar el crecimiento de las células. Cuando las células cancerosas elaboran cantidades más grandes de las normales, estas pueden crecer más rápido y es más probable que se diseminen hasta otras partes del cuerpo.  Determinar si el cáncer es positivo al HER2 puede ayudar a planificar el tratamiento, que puede incluir medicamentos que destruyen las células cancerosas positivas al HER2. Entre los cánceres que pueden ser positivos al HER2, se incluyen los cánceres de mama, de vejiga, de páncreas, de ovario y de estómago. También se llama positivo al c-erbB-2 y positivo al receptor del factor de crecimiento epidérmico humano 2.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2012-10-31</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
