<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000748813"><TermName>Department of Health and Human Services</TermName><TermPronunciation>(deh-PART-ment … helth … HYOO-mun SER-vih-ses)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The U.S. federal government agency responsible for protecting the public’s health and providing important services, especially for people in need. The Department of Health and Human Services works with state and local governments throughout the country to do research and provide public health services, food and drug safety programs, health insurance programs, and many other services. There are several federal agencies that are a part of the Department of Health and Human Services. They include the Food and Drug Administration (FDA), the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), the National Institutes of Health (NIH), and the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMMS). Also called DHHS.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752602" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Department of Health and Human Services&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752603" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Departamento de Salud y Servicios Humanos&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Departamento de Salud y Servicios Humanos</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Agencia del gobierno federal de los Estados Unidos responsable de la protección de la salud pública y la prestación de servicios importantes, especialmente para las personas necesitadas. El Departamento de Salud y Servicios Humanos trabaja con los gobiernos estatales y locales en todo el país para realizar investigaciones y prestar servicios públicos de salud, programas de seguridad de  alimentos y  medicamentos, programas de seguro médico de salud y muchos otros servicios. Hay varias agencias federales que forman parte del Departamento de Salud y Servicios Humanos: la  Administración de Medicamentos y Alimentos (FDA), los  Centros para el Control y la Prevención de Enfermedades (CDC), los Institutos Nacionales de la Salud (NIH) y los Centros de Servicios de Medicare y Medicaid (CMS). También se llama DHHS.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-07-18</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
