<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000748143"><TermName>chewing tobacco</TermName><TermPronunciation>(CHOO-ing tuh-BA-koh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of smokeless tobacco made from cured tobacco leaves. It may be sweetened and flavored with licorice and other substances. It comes in the form of loose tobacco leaves, pellets or “bits” (leaf tobacco rolled into small pellets), plugs (leaf tobacco pressed and held together with some type of sweetener), or twists (leaf tobacco rolled into rope-like strands and twisted). It is placed in the mouth, usually between the cheek and lower lip, and may be chewed. Chewing tobacco contains nicotine and many harmful, cancer-causing chemicals. Using it can lead to nicotine addiction and can cause cancers of the mouth, throat, esophagus, and pancreas. Chewing tobacco use may also cause gum disease, heart disease, stroke, and other health problems. Also called spit tobacco.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752543" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;chewing tobacco&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752544" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tabaco para mascar&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>tabaco para mascar</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de tabaco sin humo que se elabora con hojas de tabaco curadas. Se puede endulzar y darle sabor con regaliz y otras sustancias. Viene en forma de hojas sueltas de tabaco, bolitas o "bits" (hojas de tabaco enrolladas en bolitas pequeñas), tapones (hojas de tabaco prensadas que se mantienen unidas con algún tipo de edulcorante) o rollos (hojas de tabaco enrolladas como cuerda y trenzadas). Se coloca en la boca, por lo general entre la mejilla y el labio inferior, y se puede masticar. El tabaco para mascar contiene nicotina y muchas sustancias químicas dañinas que causan cáncer. Su uso puede producir adicción a la nicotina y causar cánceres de boca, garganta, esófago y páncreas. El uso de tabaco para mascar también puede causar enfermedad en las encías, cardiopatías, derrames cerebrales y otros problemas de salud. También se llama tabaco para escupir.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-07-17</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-07-12</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/risk/tobacco/smokeless-fact-sheet">Smokeless Tobacco and Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/riesgo/tabaco/hoja-informativa-tabaco-sin-humo">Tabaco sin humo y el cáncer
</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
