<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000766292"><TermName>stage IB esophageal adenocarcinoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... ee-SAH-fuh-JEE-ul A-deh-noh-KAR-sih-NOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage I is divided into stages IA and IB, depending on where the cancer is found. In stage IB, cancer has formed (1) in the mucosa or submucosa layer of the esophagus wall, and the cancer cells are grade 3. Grade 3 cancer cells look more abnormal under a microscope and grow and spread more quickly than grade 1 and 2 cancer cells; or (2) in the mucosa or submucosa layer and spread into the muscle layer of the esophagus wall, and the cancer cells are grade 1 or 2. Grade 1 and 2 cancer cells look more like normal cells under a microscope and grow and spread more slowly than grade 3 cancer cells.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000769362" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IB esophageal adenocarcinoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000769361" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;adenocarcinoma de esófago en estadio IB&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000762344" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IB adenocarcinoma of the esophagus; drawing shows the esophagus and stomach. A two-panel inset shows the layers of the esophagus wall: the mucosa, submucosa, muscle, and connective tissue layers. Also shown are lymph nodes. The left panel shows cancer in the mucosa and submucosa layers. The right panel shows cancer in the mucosa, submucosa, and muscle layers." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Stage IB adenocarcinoma of the esophagus. Cancer has formed in the mucosa or submucosa layer of the esophagus wall, and the cancer cells are grade 3. Grade 3 cancer cells look more abnormal under a microscope and grow and spread more quickly than grade 1 or 2 cancer cells; OR cancer has formed in the mucosa or submucosa layer and spread into the muscle layer of the esophagus wall, and the cancer cells are grade 1 or 2. Grade 1 and 2 cancer cells look more like normal cells under a microscope and grow and spread more slowly than grade 3 cancer cells.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000769720" type="image/jpeg" alt="Adenocarcinoma de esófago en estadio IB; la imagen muestra el esófago y el estómago. En un recuadro de dos paneles, se observan las capas de la pared del esófago: la mucosa, la submucosa, el músculo y el tejido conjuntivo. También se observan los ganglios linfáticos. El panel de la izquierda muestra cáncer en las capas mucosa y submucosa. El panel de la derecha muestra cáncer en las capas mucosa, submucosa y muscular." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Adenocarcinoma de esófago en estadio IB. El cáncer se formó en las capas mucosa o submucosa de la pared del esófago, y las células cancerosas son de grado 3. El aspecto de las células cancerosas de grado 3 es más anormal cuando se observan al microscopio, y crecen y se diseminan más rápido que las células cancerosas de grados 1 o 2; O el cáncer se formó en las capas mucosa o submucosa, y se diseminó a la capa muscular de la pared del esófago, y las células cancerosas son de grado 1 o 2. El aspecto de las células cancerosas de grados 1 y 2 es más parecido al de las células normales cuando se las observa al microscopio, y crecen y se diseminan más lentamente que las células cancerosas de grado 3.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>adenocarcinoma de esófago en estadio IB</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio I se divide en los estadios IA y IB, según el lugar donde se encuentre el cáncer. En el estadio IB, el cáncer se formó (1) en las capas mucosa o submucosa de la pared del esófago, y las células cancerosas son de grado 3. Al microscopio, el aspecto de las células cancerosas de grado 3 es más anormal,  y crecen y se diseminan más rápidamente que las células cancerosas de grados 1 y 2; o 2) en las capas mucosa o submucosa y se diseminaron hacia la capa muscular de la pared del esófago; las células cancerosas son de grado 1 o 2. Al microscopio, las células cancerosas de grados 1 y 2 se parecen más a las células normales, y crecen y se diseminan más lentamente que las células cancerosas de grado 3.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2014-11-25</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062960">Esophageal Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256773">Cáncer de esófago: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
