<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000753854"><TermName>intermediate grade</TermName><TermPronunciation>(IN-ter-MEE-dee-ut grayd)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A term used to describe how abnormal cancer cells look under a microscope. Intermediate-grade cancer cells look more abnormal than low-grade cancer cells but not as abnormal as high-grade cancer cells. They also tend to grow and spread more quickly than low-grade cancer cells but not as quickly as high-grade cancer cells. Cancer cell grade, along with cancer type and stage, may be used to help plan treatment and determine prognosis.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000759272" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;intermediate grade&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000759273" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;grado intermedio&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>grado intermedio</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Término que se usa para describir cuán anormal lucen las células cancerosas  al microscopio. Las células cancerosas de grado intermedio se ven más anormales que la células cancerosas de grado bajo, pero no tan anormales como las células cancerosas de grado alto. Estas tienden a crecer y diseminarse más rápido que las células cancerosas de grado bajo, pero no tan rápido como las células cancerosas de grado alto.  El grado de las células cancerosas junto con el tipo y estadio del cáncer, se pueden usar para ayudar a planificar el tratamiento y determinar el pronóstico.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2014-01-28</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/diagnosis-staging/prognosis/tumor-grade-fact-sheet">Tumor Grade</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/diagnostico-estadificacion/pronostico/hoja-informativa-grado-tumor">Grado de un tumor</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
