<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000759628"><TermName>HIV window period</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… WIN-doh PEER-ee-ud)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The time period that starts when a person becomes infected with the human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) and ends when the body makes enough antibodies against the virus or HIV DNA or RNA to be found with an HIV test. For the test that looks for antibodies against HIV, the HIV window period can last from 2 weeks to 6 months.  For the HIV DNA or RNA test, the HIV window period is about 9-11 days. During the HIV window period, an infected person may have negative HIV test results but still be able to infect other people.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000764463" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;HIV window period&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000764464" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;período silente del VIH&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>período silente del VIH</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Período que comienza cuando una persona se infecta por el virus de inmunodeficiencia humana (VIH) y que termina cuando el cuerpo produce suficientes anticuerpos contra este virus, o ADN o ARN del VIH para que se puedan detectar en una prueba. Para la prueba de detección de anticuerpos contra el VIH, el período silente puede durar entre 2 semanas y 6 meses. Para la prueba de ADN o ARN del VIH, el período silente es de aproximadamente 9 a 11 días. Es posible que en el período silente, una persona infectada tenga un resultado negativo de la prueba de VIH pero, que aún así, pueda infectar a otras personas.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2014-06-16</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
