<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000744887"><TermName>stage IIIB intraocular melanoma of the ciliary body and choroid</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... IN-truh-AH-kyoo-ler MEH-luh-NOH-muh ... SIH-lee-ayr-ee BAH-dee ... KOR-oyd)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage III is divided into stages IIIA, IIIB, and IIIC. In stage IIIB, the tumor (1) has spread to the ciliary body and is size category 3 (15.1 to 18 millimeters wide and 3.1 to 6 millimeters thick; or 12.1 to 18 millimeters wide and 6.1 to 9 millimeters thick; or 3.1 to 18 millimeters wide and 9.1 to 12 millimeters thick; or 9.1 to 15 millimeters wide and 12.1 to 15 millimeters thick). The tumor has spread through the sclera to the outside of the eyeball. The part of the tumor outside the eyeball is not more than 5 millimeters thick; or (2) has spread to the ciliary body and is size category 4 (more than 18 millimeters wide and may be any thickness; or 15.1 to 18 millimeters wide and more than 12 millimeters thick; or 12.1 to 15 millimeters wide and more than 15 millimeters thick); or 
(3) is size category 4 and has spread through the sclera to the outside of the eyeball. The part of the tumor outside the eyeball is not more than 5 millimeters thick. The tumor has not spread to the ciliary body.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000746292" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IIIB intraocular melanoma of the ciliary body and choroid&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000746293" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;melanoma intraocular del cuerpo ciliar y la coroides en estadio IIIB&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>melanoma intraocular del cuerpo ciliar y la coroides en estadio IIIB</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio III se divide en los estadio IIIA, IIIB y IIIC. En el estadio IIIB, el tumor 1) se diseminó hacia el cuerpo ciliar y el tamaño es de categoría 3 (15,1 a 18 mm de ancho y  3,1 a 6 mm de grosor; o de 12,1 a 18 mm de ancho y 6,1 a 9 mm de grosor; o de 3,1 a 18 mm de ancho y 9,1 a 12 mm de grosor; o de 9,1 a 15 mm de ancho y 12,1 a 15 mm de grosor). El tumor se diseminó a través de la esclerótica fuera del globo ocular. La parte del tumor fuera del globo ocular no mide más de 5 mm de grosor; o 2) se diseminó hacia el cuerpo ciliar y el tamaño es de categoría 4 (más de 18 mm de ancho y puede tener cualquier grosor; o de 15,1 a 18 mm de ancho y no más de 12 mm de grosor; o de 12,1 a 15 mm de ancho y no más de 15 mm de grosor); o 3) el tamaño es de categoría 4 y se diseminó a través de la esclerótica fuera del globo ocular. La parte del tumor fuera del globo ocular no mide más de 5 mm de grosor. El tumor no se diseminó hacia el cuerpo ciliar.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-01-09</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258015">Intraocular (Uveal) Melanoma Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000537037">Melanoma ocular uveal: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
