<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000749903"><TermName>double balloon endoscopy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(DUH-bul buh-LOON en-DOS-koh-pee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure used to look at the inside of the small intestine. A special instrument made up of two tubes (one inside the other) is inserted through the mouth or rectum and into the small intestine. The inside tube, which is an endoscope with a light and lens for viewing, is moved through part of the small intestine, and a balloon at the end of it is inflated to keep the endoscope in place. Next, the outer tube is moved through the small intestine to reach the end of the endoscope, and a balloon at the end of the outer tube is inflated to keep it in place. Then, the balloon at the end of the endoscope is deflated, and the endoscope is moved through the next part of the small intestine. These steps are repeated many times as the tubes move through the whole small intestine. This allows the doctor to see all of the small intestine. Tissue samples may be removed so they can be checked under a microscope for signs of disease. Also called DBE and double balloon enteroscopy.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752656" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;double balloon endoscopy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752655" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;endoscopia de doble balón&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>endoscopia de doble balón</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento que se usa para observar el interior del intestino delgado. Se introduce por la boca o el recto hacia el intestino delgado un instrumento especial formado por dos tubos (uno dentro del otro). El tubo interior, que es un endoscopio con una luz y una lente para observar, se mueve a través de una parte del intestino delgado; un globo en el extremo de ese tubo se infla para mantener el endoscopio en su lugar. A continuación, el tubo exterior se mueve a través del intestino delgado para llegar al final del endoscopio y se infla un globo en el extremo del tubo exterior para mantenerlo en su lugar. Entonces, el globo en el extremo del endoscopio se desinfla y se mueve el endoscopio a través de la siguiente parte del intestino delgado. Estos pasos se repiten muchas veces a medida que los tubos se mueven a través del intestino delgado. Esto le permite al médico ver todo el intestino delgado. Se pueden extraer muestras de tejido para observarlas al microscopio en busca de signos de enfermedad. También se llama EDB y enteroscopia de doble balón.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-07-17</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
