<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000748153"><TermName>snuff tobacco</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… tuh-BA-koh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of smokeless tobacco that is made of finely ground or shredded tobacco leaves. It may have different scents and flavors and may be moist or dry. Moist snuff tobacco is placed in the mouth, usually between the cheek and gum or behind the upper or lower lip. Dry snuff tobacco is inhaled through the nose. Snuff tobacco contains nicotine and many harmful, cancer-causing chemicals. Using it can lead to nicotine addiction and can cause cancers of the mouth, esophagus, and pancreas. Snuff tobacco use may also cause gum disease, heart disease, stroke, and other health problems. Using snuff tobacco is also called “dipping.”</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752663" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;snuff tobacco&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752664" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;rapé&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>rapé</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de tabaco sin humo que se hace con hojas de tabaco finamente molido o triturado. Puede tener diferentes aromas y sabores, y puede ser húmedo o seco. El rapé húmedo se coloca en la boca, por lo general entre la mejilla y la encía, o detrás del labio superior o inferior. El rapé seco se inhala por la nariz. El rapé contiene nicotina y muchos productos químicos dañinos, que causan cáncer. Su uso puede llevar a la adicción a la nicotina y causar cánceres de boca, esófago y páncreas. Asimismo, el consumo de rapé puede causar enfermedad de las encías, cardiopatías, derrames cerebrales y otros problemas de salud. El uso de rapé también se llama "frotar las encías con rapé".</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-07-17</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-07-16</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/risk/tobacco/smokeless-fact-sheet">Smokeless Tobacco and Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/riesgo/tabaco/hoja-informativa-tabaco-sin-humo">Tabaco sin humo y el cáncer</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
