<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000739821"><TermName>embryo cryopreservation</TermName><TermPronunciation>(EM-bree-oh KRY-oh-PREH-zer-VAY-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The process of freezing one or more embryos to save them for future use.  Embryo cryopreservation involves in vitro fertilization, a procedure in which eggs are removed from a woman’s ovary and combined with sperm in the laboratory to form embryos. The embryos are  frozen and can later be thawed and placed in a woman’s uterus. Embryo cryopreservation is a type of fertility preservation. It may be useful for women with cancer who want to have children after having radiation therapy, chemotherapy, or certain types of surgery, which can cause infertility.  Also called embryo freezing.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000745280" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;embryo cryopreservation&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000745279" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;criopreservación de embriones&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>criopreservación de embriones</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Proceso que se usa para congelar uno o más embriones y conservarlos para su uso en el futuro. La criopreservación de embriones incluye la fertilización in vitro, que es un procedimiento mediante el que se extraen óvulos del ovario de una mujer y se combina con espermatozoides en el laboratorio para formar embriones. Los embriones se congelan y después se pueden descongelar y colocar en el útero de una mujer. La criopreservación de embriones es un tipo de preservación de la fecundidad. Puede ser útil para mujeres con cáncer que quieren tener hijos después de someterse a radioterapia, quimioterapia o ciertos tipos de cirugía que pueden causar infertilidad. También se llama congelación de embriones.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2012-11-21</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
