<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000770168"><TermName>Unituxin</TermName><TermPronunciation>(yoo-nih-TUK-sin)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used with granulocyte-macrophage colony-stimulating factor (GM-CSF), aldesleukin (IL-2), and 13-cis-retinoic acid to treat high-risk neuroblastoma. It is used in children whose disease has improved with other anticancer treatment. Unituxin binds to a substance called GD2, which is found on some types of cancer cells. Unituxin may block GD2 and help the immune system kill cancer cells. It is a type of monoclonal antibody. Also called Ch14.18, dinutuximab, MOAB Ch14.18,  and monoclonal antibody Ch14.18.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000771246" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Unituxin&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000771245" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Unituxin&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Unituxin</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa con el factor estimulante de la colonia de macrófagos de granulocitos (FEC MG), aldesleucina (IL-2) y el ácido retinóico cis-13 para el tratamiento del neuroblastoma. Se usa en niños cuya enfermedad ha mejorado con otros tratamientos contra el cáncer. El unituxin se  une a una sustancia llamada GD2, que se encuentra en algunos tipos de células cancerosas.  El unituxin puede impedir la acción del GD2 y ayudar al sistema inmunitario a eliminar las células cancerosas. Es un tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal. También se llama anticuerpo monoclonal Ch14.18, Ch14.18, dinutuximab,  y MOAB Ch14.18.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2015-03-26</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2015-03-26</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000770044">Dinutuximab</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
