<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000759898"><TermName>alpha emitter radiation therapy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(AL-fuh ee-MIH-ter RAY-dee-AY-shun THAYR-uh-pee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Therapy that uses a radioactive substance that gives off a type of high-energy radiation called an alpha-particle to kill cancer cells. The radioactive substance is injected into a vein, travels through the blood, and collects in certain tissues in the body, such as areas of bone with cancer. This type of radiation may cause less damage to nearby healthy tissue. Alpha emitter radiation therapy is used to treat prostate cancer that has spread to the bone, and it is being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000764470" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;alpha emitter radiation therapy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000764469" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;radioterapia con emisores alfa&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>radioterapia con emisores alfa</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tratamiento para el que se usa una sustancia que emite un tipo de radiación de alta energía llamada partícula alfa para destruir células cancerosas. La sustancia radiactiva se inyecta en una vena, se desplaza por la sangre y se acumula en algunos tejidos del cuerpo, como las áreas de los huesos con cáncer. Este tipo de radiación puede causar menos daño a los tejidos sanos cercanos. La radioterapia con emisores alfa se usa para tratar el cáncer de próstata que se diseminó a los huesos y está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2014-06-16</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
