<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000748129"><TermName>acetone</TermName><TermPronunciation>(A-seh-tone)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A chemical substance found naturally in small amounts in plants, trees, volcanoes, and forest fires. Acetone is also made by the body when fats are broken down. It is also found in tobacco smoke, car exhaust, and trash landfills. In industry, acetone is used in some plastics, fibers, medicines, household cleaners, glues, and nail polish removers. Being exposed to high levels of acetone may irritate the skin, eyes, nose, throat, and lungs. It can cause headaches, nausea, vomiting, dizziness, confusion, loss of consciousness, and other health problems.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752530" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;acetone&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752529" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;acetona&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>acetona</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Sustancia química que se encuentra naturalmente en pequeñas cantidades en las plantas, los árboles, los volcanes y los incendios de bosques. El cuerpo también produce acetona cuando  se descomponen las grasas. Asimismo, se encuentra en el humo del tabaco, el escape de los automóviles y los vertederos de basura. En la industria, la acetona se utiliza en algunos plásticos, fibras, medicamentos, limpiadores domésticos, pegamentos y quitaesmaltes de uñas. La exposición a concentraciones altas de acetona puede irritar la piel, los ojos, la nariz, la garganta y los pulmones. Puede causar dolores de cabeza, náuseas, vómitos, mareos, confusión, pérdida del conocimiento y otros problemas de salud.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-07-17</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
