<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000760748"><TermName>Zykadia</TermName><TermPronunciation>(zy-KAY-dee-uh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat non-small cell lung cancer that has spread to other parts of the body and has a mutated (changed) form of a gene called anaplastic lymphoma kinase (ALK). It is used in patients whose cancer has gotten worse after treatment with or who cannot receive certain anticancer drugs. Zykadia blocks the protein made by the mutated ALK gene. Blocking this protein may stop the growth and spread of cancer cells. Zykadia is a type of tyrosine kinase inhibitor. Also called ceritinib.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000762449" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Zykadia&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000762448" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Zykadia&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Zykadia</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para el tratamiento del cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas que se ha diseminado hacia otras partes del cuerpo y tiene una forma mutada (cambiada) de un gen llamado cinasa de linfoma anaplásico (ALK).  Se usa en pacientes cuyo cáncer ha empeorado después del tratamiento  con medicamentos contra el cáncer o en aquellos que no los han recibido.  Zykadia impide el funcionamiento de la proteína elaborada por el gen mutado ALK.  El bloqueo de esta proteína puede impedir el crecimiento y diseminación de las células cancerosas.  Zykadia es un tipo de inhibidor de la tirosina cinasa.  También se llama ceritinib.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2014-05-15</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000761151">Ceritinib</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
