<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000750107"><TermName>minimally invasive surgery</TermName><TermPronunciation>(MIH-nih-muh-lee in-VAY-siv SER-juh-ree)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Surgery that is done using small incisions (cuts) and few stitches.  During minimally invasive surgery, one or more small incisions may be made in the body. A laparoscope (thin, tube-like instrument with a light and a lens for viewing) is inserted through one opening to guide the surgery. Tiny surgical instruments are inserted through other openings to do the surgery. Minimally invasive surgery may cause less pain, scarring, and damage to healthy tissue, and the patient may have a faster recovery than with traditional surgery.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000754448" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;minimally invasive surgery&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000754447" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cirugía mínimamente invasiva&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cirugía mínimamente invasiva</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Cirugía que se realiza por medio de incisiones (cortes) pequeñas y pocos puntos. Durante una cirugía mínimamente invasiva, se hace una o más incisiones pequeñas en el cuerpo y se introduce un laparoscopio (instrumento delgado en forma de tubo con una luz y una lente para observar) a través de una abertura a fin de guiar la cirugía. Para realizarla, se introducen instrumentos quirúrgicos diminutos a través de otras aberturas. Este tipo de cirugía puede causar menos dolor, cicatrices y daño al tejido sano; el paciente puede tener una recuperación más rápida que con la cirugía tradicional.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-09-03</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
