<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000744613"><TermName>stage IIA intraocular melanoma of the ciliary body and choroid</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... IN-truh-AH-kyoo-ler MEH-luh-NOH-muh ... SIH-lee-ayr-ee BAH-dee ... KOR-oyd)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage II is divided into stages IIA and IIB. In stage IIA, the tumor (1) has spread to the ciliary body  and is size category 1 (not more than 12 millimeters wide and not more than 3 millimeters thick; or not more than 9 millimeters wide and 3.1 to 6 millimeters thick); or (2) may have spread to the ciliary body and  is size category 1. The tumor has spread through the sclera to the outside of the eyeball. The part of the tumor outside the eyeball is not more than 5 millimeters thick; or (3) is in the choroid only and is size category 2 (12.1 to 18 millimeters wide and not more than 3 millimeters thick; or 9.1 to 15 millimeters wide and 3.1 to 6 millimeters thick; or not more than 12 millimeters wide and 6.1 to 9 millimeters thick).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000746308" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IIA intraocular melanoma of the ciliary body and choroid&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000746309" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;melanoma intraocular del cuerpo ciliar y la coroides en estadio II&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>melanoma intraocular del cuerpo ciliar y la coroides en estadio II</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio II se divide en los estadios IIA y IIB. En el estadio IIA, el tumor (1) se diseminó hacia el cuerpo ciliar y el tamaño es de categoría 1 (no más de 12 mm de ancho y no más de 3 mm de grosor, o no más de 9 mm de ancho y  3,1 a 6 mm de grosor); o 2) se puede haber diseminado hasta el cuerpo ciliar y el tamaño es de categoría 1. El tumor se diseminó a través de la esclerótica fuera del globo ocular. La parte del tumor fuera del globo ocular no mide más de 5 mm de grosor; o 3) está solamente en la coroides y el tamaño es de categoría 2 (12,1 a 18 mm de ancho y no más de 3 mm de grosor; o 9,1 a 15 mm de ancho y 3,1 a 6 mm de grosor; o no más de 12 mm de ancho y 6,1 a 9 mm de grosor).</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-01-09</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258015">Intraocular (Uveal) Melanoma Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000537037">Melanoma ocular uveal: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
