<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000748146"><TermName>cigar</TermName><TermPronunciation>(sih-GAR)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A tube-shaped tobacco product that is made of tightly rolled, cured tobacco leaves in a tobacco leaf wrapper or a wrapper that contains tobacco. It may also have other ingredients, including substances to add different flavors. A cigar is lit on one end and smoked, but the smoke is usually not inhaled into the lungs. Cigars contain nicotine and many cancer-causing chemicals that are harmful to both smokers and nonsmokers. Smoking cigars can lead to nicotine addiction and can cause cancers of the mouth, larynx (voice box), esophagus, lung, and pancreas. Heavy cigar smoking can also increase the risk of heart disease and lung diseases, such as emphysema and chronic bronchitis.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752548" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cigar&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752547" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cigarro&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cigarro</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Producto del tabaco en forma de tubo que se fabrica con hojas de tabaco curadas, firmemente enrolladas en una envoltura de hoja de tabaco o una envoltura que contiene tabaco. También puede tener otros ingredientes, como sustancias para añadirle diferentes sabores. Un cigarro se enciende en un extremo y se fuma pero, por lo general, no se inhala hacia los pulmones. Los cigarros contienen nicotina y muchos productos químicos que causan cáncer y que son perjudiciales tanto para los fumadores como para quienes no fuman. Fumar cigarros puede producir adicción a la nicotina y causar cáncer de boca, laringe, esófago, pulmón y páncreas. Fumar muchos cigarros también puede aumentar el riesgo de cardiopatías y enfermedades pulmonares, como el enfisema y la bronquitis crónica.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-07-17</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-07-16</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/risk/tobacco/cigars-fact-sheet">Cigar Smoking and Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/riesgo/tabaco/hoja-informativa-cigarros-puros">Fumar cigarros puros y el cáncer</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
