<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000757012"><TermName>transarterial embolization</TermName><TermPronunciation>(tranz-ar-TEER-ee-ul EM-boh-lih-ZAY-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure in which the blood supply to a tumor or an abnormal area of tissue is blocked. During transarterial embolization, a small incision (cut) is made in the inner thigh and a catheter (thin, flexible tube) is inserted and guided into an artery near the tumor or abnormal tissue. Once the catheter is in place, small particles made of tiny gelatin sponges or beads are injected. This blocks the artery and stops the flow of blood to the tumor or abnormal area of tissue. Transarterial embolization is used to treat some types of liver cancer, kidney cancer, and neuroendocrine tumors. It may also be used to treat uterine fibroids, aneurysms, and other conditions. Also called arterial embolization and TAE.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000760844" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;transarterial embolization&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000760843" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;embolización transarterial&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>embolización transarterial</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento mediante el que se impide el suministro de sangre a un tumor o un área de tejido anormal. Durante una embolización transarterial, se realiza una pequeña incisión (corte) en la parte interna del muslo y se introduce un catéter (tubo delgado y flexible) que se guía hacia una arteria cercana al tumor o el tejido anormal. Una vez que el catéter está en su lugar, se inyectan pequeñas partículas hechas de esponja o perlas de gelatina minúsculas. Esto bloquea la arteria y detiene el flujo de sangre al tumor o área de tejido anormal. La embolización transarterial se usa para tratar algunos tipos de cáncer de hígado, cáncer de riñón y tumores neuroendocrinos. También se puede usar para tratar fibroides uterinos, aneurismas y otras afecciones. También se llama embolización arterial y ETA.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2014-03-11</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2014-03-11</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
