<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000759626"><TermName>HIV test</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… test)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A test to check for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection. HIV is the virus that causes acquired immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS). The most common type of HIV test is called the HIV antibody test, which checks for antibodies against HIV in a sample of blood, urine, or fluid from the mouth. It can take from 2 weeks to 6 months after a person is infected with HIV before the antibodies are found with an HIV antibody test. Another type of HIV test checks for RNA or DNA from HIV in a sample of blood. This test can find HIV in a person’s blood about 9-11 days after the person is infected with the virus.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000764460" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;HIV test&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000764459" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;prueba de VIH&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>prueba de VIH</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Prueba para detectar la infección por el virus de inmunodeficiencia humana (VIH) que causa el síndrome de inmunodeficiencia adquirida (SIDA). El tipo más común de prueba de VIH se llama prueba de anticuerpos contra el VIH, en la que se detectan anticuerpos contra este virus en una muestra de sangre, orina o líquido de la boca. La detección de los anticuerpos en una prueba de VIH puede tomar entre 2 semanas y 6 meses después de que una persona se infecta por el virus. En otro tipo de prueba de VIH, se identifica el ARN o el ADN de este virus en una muestra de sangre. Con esta prueba, se puede detectar el VIH en la sangre de una persona entre 9 y 11 días después de la infección por el virus.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2014-06-16</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
