<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000753859"><TermName>United States Preventive Services Task Force</TermName><TermPronunciation>(yoo-NY-ted stayts pree-VEN-tiv SER-vih-ses …)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A volunteer group of health experts who review published research and make recommendations about prevention health care methods such as screening tests, counseling, immunizations, and medicines. Before making a recommendation, the United States Preventive Services Task Force looks at the strength (scientific quality and correctness) of the evidence found in the research and the benefits and harms of each method being reviewed. Recommendations are made to help healthcare providers and patients decide whether a specific method is right for a patient’s needs. The recommendations may change as new research studies are published. Also called USPSTF.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000759279" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;United States Preventive Services Task Force&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><SpanishTermName>United States Preventive Services Task Force</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Grupo de voluntarios expertos en salud que revisan las investigaciones publicadas y dan recomendaciones sobre los métodos de prevención para el cuidado de la salud, como exámenes de detección, orientación, inmunizaciones y medicamentos. Antes de hacer una recomendación, United States Preventive Services Task Force analiza la fortaleza (calidad científica y precisión) de las pruebas encontradas en la investigación y los beneficios y perjuicios de cada método en revisión. Se hacen recomendaciones para ayudar a los proveedores de atención de la salud y los pacientes a decidir si un método específico es adecuado para las necesidades del paciente. Las recomendaciones pueden cambiar a medida en que se publican nuevos estudios de investigación. También se llama USPSTF.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2014-01-28</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
