<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000711109"><TermName>risk group</TermName><TermPronunciation>(risk groop)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>In medicine, risk groups are used to describe people who are alike in important ways. For example, patients with the same type of cancer may be divided into different risk groups that depend on certain aspects of their disease. These risk groups may be based on the patients’ chance of being cured (good versus poor) or the chance that their disease will come back (high versus low). Treatment may be based on which risk group a patient falls into.  Risk groups can also be used to describe people who share traits and behaviors that affect their chance of developing a disease.  For example, people who do not smoke are in a lower risk group for lung cancer than people who smoke.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733367" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;risk group&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733368" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;grupo de riesgo&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>grupo de riesgo</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>En el campo de la medicina, los grupos de riesgo se usan para describir a las personas que tienen características importantes que se parecen. Por ejemplo, los pacientes del mismo tipo de cáncer se pueden dividir en distintos grupos de riesgo de acuerdo con ciertos aspectos de su enfermedad. Estos grupos de riesgo se pueden basar en la probabilidad de curación (probabilidad buena frente a probabilidad pobre) o la probabilidad de que su enfermedad vuelva (alta frente a baja). El tratamiento se puede basar en el grupo de riesgo al que el paciente pertenezca. Los grupos de riesgo también se pueden usar para describir a las personas que comparten  rasgos o comportamientos que afectan su probabilidad de padecer de una enfermedad. Por ejemplo, las personas que no fuman están en un grupo de riesgo más bajo de cáncer de pulmón que las personas que fuman.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2011-09-08</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
