<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000728326"><TermName>childhood cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A term used to describe cancers that occur between birth and 15 years of age.  Childhood cancers are very rare and may differ from adult cancers in the way they grow and spread, how they are treated, and how they respond to treatment. Common types of childhood cancer include leukemia (begins in blood-forming tissue such as bone marrow), lymphoma (begins in the cells of the immune system), neuroblastoma (begins in certain nerve cells), retinoblastoma (begins in the tissues of the retina), Wilms tumor (a type of kidney cancer), and cancers of the brain, bone, and soft tissue.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000736917" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;childhood cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000736916" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer infantil&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer infantil</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Término que se usa para describir cánceres que se presentan entre el nacimiento y los 15 años de edad. Los cánceres infantiles son muy poco frecuentes y pueden ser distintos de los cánceres en adultos por la forma en que se forman y diseminan, el modo en que se tratan y la manera en que responden al tratamiento. Los tipos comunes de cánceres infantiles son la leucemia (que empieza en el tejido que forma la sangre, como la médula ósea), el linfoma (que empieza en las células del sistema inmunitario), el neuroblastoma (que empieza en ciertas células nerviosas), el retinoblastoma (que empieza en los tejidos de la retina), el tumor de Wilms (que es un tipo de cáncer de riñón) y los cánceres de cerebro, hueso y tejido blando.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2012-05-03</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
