<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000772606"><TermName>immune checkpoint inhibitor</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ih-MYOON CHEK-poynt in-HIH-bih-ter)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of drug that blocks certain proteins made by some types of immune system cells, such as T cells, and some cancer cells.  These proteins help keep immune responses in check and can keep T cells from killing cancer cells. When these proteins are blocked, the “brakes” on the immune system are released and T cells are able to kill cancer cells better. Examples of checkpoint proteins found on T cells or cancer cells include PD-1/PD-L1 and CTLA-4/B7-1/B7-2.  Some immune checkpoint inhibitors are used to treat cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000775006" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;immune checkpoint inhibitor&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000775005" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;inhibidor de puntos de control inmunitario&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000774646" type="image/jpeg" alt="Immune checkpoint inhibitor; the panel on the left shows the binding of proteins PD-L1 (on the tumor cell) to PD-1 (on the T cell), which keeps T cells from killing tumor cells in the body. Also shown are a tumor cell antigen and T cell receptor. The panel on the right shows immune checkpoint inhibitors (anti-PD-L1 and anti-PD-1) blocking the binding of PD-L1 to PD-1, which allows the T cells to kill tumor cells." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Immune checkpoint inhibitor.  Certain proteins, such as PD-1 and PD-L1, are found on immune system cells and some tumor cells. PD-1 and PD-L1 help keep immune responses in check.  The binding of PD-L1 (on tumor cells) to PD-1 (on T cells) keeps T cells from killing tumor cells in the body (left panel). Blocking the binding of PD-L1 to PD-1 with an immune checkpoint inhibitor (anti-PD-L1 or anti-PD-1) allows the T cells to kill tumor cells (right panel).</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000776560" type="image/jpeg" alt="Immune checkpoint inhibitor; the panel on the left shows the binding of proteins B7-1/B7-2 (on the tumor cell) to CTLA-4 (on the T cell), which keeps T cells from killing tumor cells in the body. Also shown are a tumor cell antigen and T cell receptor. The panel on the right shows immune checkpoint inhibitors (anti-B7-1/B7-2 and anti-CTLA-4) blocking the binding of B7-1/B7-2 to CTLA-4, which allows the T cells to kill tumor cells." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="en">Immune checkpoint inhibitor.  Certain proteins, such as CTLA-4 and B7-1/B7-2, are found on immune system cells and some tumor cells.  CTLA-4 and B7-1/B7-2 help keep immune responses in check.  The binding of B7-1/B7-2 (on tumor cells) to CTLA-4 (on T cells) keeps T cells from killing tumor cells in the body (left panel). Blocking the binding of B7-1/B7-2 to CTLA-4 with an immune checkpoint inhibitor (anti-B7-1/B7-2 or anti-CTLA-4) allows the T cells to kill tumor cells (right panel).</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>inhibidor de puntos de control inmunitario</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de medicamento que impide la acción de ciertas proteínas elaboradas por determinados tipos de células del sistema inmunitario, como las células T, y por algunas células cancerosas. Estas proteínas ayudan a controlar las  reacciones inmunitarias y pueden evitar que las células T destruyan células cancerosas. Cuando se impide la acción de estas proteínas, se liberan "los frenos" del sistema inmunitario y las células T pueden eliminar, de mejor forma, las células cancerosas. PD-1/PD-L1 y CTLA-4/B7-1/B7-2 son ejemplos de proteínas de puntos de control que están presentes en las células T o en las células cancerosas. Algunos inhibidores de puntos de control inmunitario se usan para tratar el cáncer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2015-06-17</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2015-11-04</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
