<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000716287"><TermName>controlled substance</TermName><TermPronunciation>(kun-TROLD SUB-stunts)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug or other substance that is tightly controlled by the government because it may be abused or cause addiction. The control applies to the way the substance is made, used, handled, stored, and distributed. Controlled substances include opioids, stimulants, depressants, hallucinogens, and anabolic steroids. Controlled substances with known medical use, such as morphine, Valium, and Ritalin, are available only by prescription from a licensed medical professional. Other controlled substances, such as heroin and LSD, have no known medical use and are illegal in the United States.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000734747" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;controlled substance&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000734748" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sustancia controlada&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>sustancia controlada</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento u otra sustancia que es sumamente controlada por el gobierno porque se puede abusar de ellas o causar adicción.   El control se aplica en la manera en que se elabora la sustancia,  se usa, se manipula, se almacena o se distribuye. Las sustancias controladas incluyen opioides, estimulantes, depresores, alucinógenos y esteroides anabolizantes.   Las sustancias controladas con el uso médico conocido, como morfina, Valium y Ritalin, están disponibles solo por receta médica de un profesional médico autorizado.   Otras sustancias controladas, como heroína y LSD, no tienen uso médico conocido y son ilegales en los Estados Unidos.  </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2012-02-23</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
