<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000750072"><TermName>trametinib</TermName><TermPronunciation>(truh-MEH-tih-nib)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used alone or with dabrafenib to treat melanoma that cannot be removed by surgery or has spread to other parts of the body. It is used in patients with a mutated (changed) form of a cell protein called BRAF. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Trametinib blocks certain proteins, which may help keep cancer cells from growing and may kill them. It is a type of kinase inhibitor and a type of targeted therapy. Also called Mekinist.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752689" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;trametinib&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752688" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;trametinib&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>trametinib</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa solo o con dabrafenib para tratar el melanoma que no se puede extirpar mediante cirugía o que se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo. Se usa en pacientes con una forma mutada (cambiada) de proteína celular que se llama BRAF. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El trametinib impide la acción de ciertas proteínas, lo cual puede ayudar a detener el crecimiento de las células cancerosas y  eliminarlas. Es un tipo de inhibidor de la cinasa y un tipo de tratamiento dirigido. También se llama Mekinist.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-06-03</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2014-01-15</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000750074">Trametinib</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
