<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000754221"><TermName>inherited cancer syndrome</TermName><TermPronunciation>(in-HAYR-ih-ted KAN-ser SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of inherited disorder in which there is a higher-than-normal risk of certain types of cancer. Inherited cancer syndromes are caused by mutations (changes) in certain genes passed from parents to children. In an inherited cancer syndrome, certain patterns of cancer may be seen within families. These patterns include having several close family members (such as a mother, daughter, and sister) with the same type of cancer, developing cancer at an early age, or having two or more types of cancer develop in the same person. Examples of inherited cancer syndromes are hereditary breast and ovarian cancer syndrome, Li-Fraumeni syndrome, Cowden syndrome, and Lynch syndrome. Also called hereditary cancer syndrome.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000759264" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;inherited cancer syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000759265" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de cáncer heredado&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>síndrome de cáncer heredado</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de trastorno hereditario en el que hay un riesgo más alto que lo normal de ciertos tipos de cáncer. Los síndromes de cáncer heredado obedecen a mutaciones (cambios) en ciertos genes que se trasmiten de padres a hijos. En el caso de un síndrome de cáncer heredado, se pueden observar  ciertas características de cáncer en el seno de las familias. Estas características incluyen tener varios miembros cercanos de la familia (por ejemplo, una madre, una hija y una hermana) con el mismo tipo de cáncer que se presenta a una edad temprana o que se presenten dos o más tipos de cáncer en la misma persona. Algunos ejemplos de síndrome de cáncer heredado son los síndromes de cáncer heredado de cáncer de mama y ovario, el síndrome de Li-Fraumeni, el síndrome de Cowden y el síndrome de Lynch. También se llama síndrome de cáncer hereditario.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2014-01-17</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/genetics/genetic-testing-fact-sheet">Genetic Testing for Hereditary Cancer Syndromes</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/genetica/hoja-informativa-pruebas-geneticas">Pruebas genéticas para síndromes hereditarios de cáncer</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
