<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000748138"><TermName>heart disease</TermName><TermPronunciation>(hart dih-ZEEZ)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of disease that affects the heart or blood vessels. The risk of certain heart diseases may be increased by smoking, high blood pressure, high cholesterol, unhealthy diet, lack of exercise, and obesity. The most common heart disease is coronary artery disease (narrow or blocked coronary arteries), which can lead to chest pain, heart attacks, or stroke. Other  heart diseases include congestive heart failure, heart rhythm problems, congenital heart disease (heart disease at birth), and endocarditis (inflamed inner layer of the heart). Also called cardiovascular disease.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752539" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;heart disease&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752540" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cardiopatía&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cardiopatía</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de enfermedad que afecta el corazón o los vasos sanguíneos. El riesgo de ciertas cardiopatías puede aumentar por consumo de productos del tabaco, presión arterial alta, colesterol alto, mala alimentación, falta de ejercicio u obesidad. La cardiopatía más común es la enfermedad de la arteria coronaria (arteria coronaria estrecha u obstruida), que puede producir dolor de pecho, ataques cardíacos o derrame cerebral. Otras cardiopatías son  la insuficiencia cardíaca congestiva, los problemas del ritmo cardiaco, la enfermedad cardiaca congénita (enfermedad cardiaca desde el nacimiento) y la endocarditis (inflamación de la capa interna del corazón). También se llama enfermedad cardiovascular.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-07-17</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-07-12</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
