<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000738017"><TermName>human papillomavirus RNA test</TermName><TermPronunciation>(HYOO-mun PA-pih-LOH-muh-VY-rus … test)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A laboratory test in which cells are scraped from the cervix to look for RNA of the most common types of human papillomavirus (HPV). Certain types of HPV may cause abnormal tissue growth, such as warts, and other changes to cells. Infection for a long time with other types of HPV may cause cervical cancer. A human papillomavirus RNA test may be done with a Pap test to check for HPV infection and cervical cancer. HPV infection may also cause other types of cancer, such as cancers of the anus, vagina, vulva, penis, and oropharynx. Also called HPV RNA test.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000743019" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;human papillomavirus RNA test&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000743018" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;prueba del ARN del virus del papiloma humano&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>prueba del ARN del virus del papiloma humano</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Prueba de laboratorio mediante la cual se raspan células del cuello uterino para analizar el ARN de los tipos más comunes del virus del papiloma humano (VPH). Ciertos tipos del VPH  podrían ocasionar un crecimiento anormal del tejido, como verrugas y otros cambios en las células. La infección prolongada por otros tipos del  VPH puede ocasionar cáncer del cuello uterino.  La prueba del RNA del papilomavirus humano se puede hacer con una prueba Pap para ver si hay infección por VPH y cáncer de cuello uterino. La infección por VPH puede ocasionar otros tipos de cáncer, como cáncer de ano, vagina, vulva, pene y orofaringe. También se llama prueba del ARN del VPH.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2012-10-31</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
