<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000718931"><TermName>asparaginase Erwinia chrysanthemi</TermName><TermPronunciation>(as-PAYR-uh-jih-NAYS er-WIH-nee-uh krih-SAN-theh-my)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used with other anticancer drugs to treat acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL). It is an enzyme that comes from the Erwinia chrysanthemi bacterium. It is used in patients who cannot take a similar drug that comes from the E. coli bacterium. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. It breaks down the amino acid asparagine and may block the growth of cancer cells that need asparagine to grow. It may also kill cancer cells. Also called Erwinaze.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000732934" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;asparaginase Erwinia chrysanthemi&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000732933" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;asparaginasa Erwinia chrysanthemi&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>asparaginasa Erwinia chrysanthemi</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa con otros medicamentos contra el cáncer para tratar la leucemia linfoblástica aguda (LLA). Es una enzima que produce la bacteria Erwinia chrysanthemi.   Se administra a pacientes que no pueden tomar un medicamento similar que se elabora con la bacteria E. coli.   También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer.   Descompone el aminoácido asparagina y puede  impedir la formación de las células cancerosas que necesitan asparagina para crecer.   Asimismo, puede destruir células cancerosas.   También se llama Erwinaze.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2011-12-14</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000717920">Asparaginase Erwinia chrysanthemi</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
