<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000701635"><TermName>Hirschsprung disease</TermName><TermPronunciation>(HIRSH-sprung dih-ZEEZ)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A condition in which certain nerve cells are missing from the muscle layers of part of the large intestine. This causes severe constipation or blockage of the large intestine. Constipation is when stool becomes hard, dry, and difficult to pass and bowel movements occur less often than normal.  Other symptoms include swollen abdomen, vomiting, bloody diarrhea, gas, lack of energy, and trouble gaining weight. Hirschsprung disease is present from birth, but the symptoms may not appear until later in a child’s life. This condition has been linked to an increased risk of thyroid cancer and neuroblastoma. Also called aganglionic megacolon.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733059" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Hirschsprung disease&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733060" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;enfermedad de Hirschsprung&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>enfermedad de Hirschsprung</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección por la que faltan ciertas células nerviosas en las capas musculares de ciertas partes del intestino grueso. Esto causa estreñimiento o bloqueo grave del intestino grueso.   El estreñimiento aparece cuando las heces se vuelven duras, secas y difíciles de evacuar y las evacuaciones intestinales suceden con menor frecuencia que la normal.   Otros síntomas incluyen hinchazón del abdomen, vómitos, diarrea sanguinolenta, gases, falta de energía y dificultad para aumentar  de peso.   La enfermedad de Hirschsprung está presente desde el nacimiento, pero los síntomas pueden no aparecer hasta más tarde en la vida de un niño.   Esta afección se relaciona con un aumento del riesgo de cáncer de tiroides y neuroblastoma.  También se llama megacolon agangliónico.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2011-10-20</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
