<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000745784"><TermName>TRAM flap</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… flap)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of surgery used to rebuild the shape of the breast after a mastectomy. A muscle in the lower abdomen called the rectus abdominis, along with skin, fat, and blood vessels, is moved from the lower abdomen to the chest. This is usually done by passing the muscle tissue and blood vessels through a tunnel under the skin to the chest.  A TRAM flap forms a natural-looking breast, so the patient usually does not need a breast implant.  It is a type of breast reconstruction. Also called transverse rectus abdominis myocutaneous flap.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000749829" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;TRAM flap&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000749828" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;colgajo TRAM&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>colgajo TRAM</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de cirugía que se usa para reconstruir la forma de la mama después de una mastectomía. Se lleva un músculo de la parte inferior del abdomen, que se llama recto abdominal, junto con la piel, la grasa y los vasos sanguíneos hasta el pecho. Habitualmente, esto se realiza mediante el pasaje del tejido muscular y los vasos sanguíneos a través de un túnel debajo de la piel. Un colgajo TRAM permite formar una mama con aspecto natural de modo que la paciente no necesite un implante. Es un tipo de reconstrucción de la mama. También se llama colgajo musculocutáneo de recto abdominal transverso.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-04-01</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/breast/reconstruction-fact-sheet">Breast Reconstruction After Mastectomy</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/seno/hoja-informativa-reconstruccion">La reconstrucción del seno después de una mastectomía</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
