<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000701526"><TermName>lymphangitic carcinomatosis</TermName><TermPronunciation>(LIM-fan-JIH-tik KAR-sih-NOH-muh-TOH-sis)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A condition in which cancer cells spread from the original (primary) tumor and invade lymph vessels (thin tubes that carry lymph and white blood cells through the body’s lymph system). The invaded lymph vessels then fill up with cancer cells and become blocked. Although lymphangitic carcinomatosis can occur anywhere in the body, it commonly happens in the lungs. It can happen in many types of cancer but is most common in breast, lung, colon, stomach, pancreatic, and prostate cancer. Also called carcinomatous lymphangitis.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000732940" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;lymphangitic carcinomatosis&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000732939" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;carcinomatosis linfangítica&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>carcinomatosis linfangítica</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección por la que las células cancerosas se diseminan desde el tumor original (primario) e invaden los vasos linfáticos (tubos delgados que llevan la linfa y los glóbulos blancos a través del sistema linfático del cuerpo). Los vasos linfáticos invadidos se llenan luego de células cancerosas y quedan bloqueados. Aunque la carcinomatosis linfangítica se puede presentar en cualquier lugar del cuerpo, generalmente se presenta en los pulmones. Esto puede ocurrir debido a muchos tipos de cáncer, pero es más común en el cáncer de mama, pulmón, colon, estómago, páncreas y próstata.  También se llama linfangitis carcinomatosa.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2011-10-20</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
