<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000774381"><TermName>ovarian tissue cryopreservation</TermName><TermPronunciation>(oh-VAYR-ee-un TIH-shoo KRY-oh-PREH-zer-VAY-shun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>The process of freezing ovarian tissue to save for future infertility treatment. Part or all of an ovary is removed, and the tissue that contains the eggs is cut into thin slices and frozen. The tissue may later be thawed and placed back into the woman’s body, usually on the remaining ovary.  Ovarian tissue cryopreservation is a type of fertility preservation. It may be useful for women who want to have children after having treatment that may cause infertility, such as certain cancer treatments. Also called ovarian tissue freezing.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000776504" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ovarian tissue cryopreservation&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000776505" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;criopreservación de tejido de ovario&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>criopreservación de tejido de ovario</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Proceso mediante el cual se congela tejido de los ovarios  para usarlo en un futuro como tratamiento de la esterilidad. Se extrae total o parcialmente un ovario, y el tejido que contiene los óvulos se corta en rebanadas finas y se congela. El tejido se puede descongelar después  y volver a colocar en el cuerpo de la mujer, por lo general en el ovario que quedó.  La criopreservación de tejido de ovario es un tipo de preservación de la fertilidad. Puede ser útil para mujeres que quieren tener hijos luego de someterse a un tratamiento que puede causar esterilidad, como ciertos tratamientos del cáncer. También se llama congelación de tejido de ovario.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2015-09-16</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2015-09-29</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
