<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000748982"><TermName>Alagille syndrome</TermName><TermPronunciation>(a-luh-JEEL SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare disorder in which there are defects in the small tubes that carry bile (fluid that helps digest fat) out of the liver. These small tubes may be narrow or have an abnormal shape, or there may be fewer of them than normal. This can cause bile to build up in the liver, which may lead to cirrhosis (scarring of the liver) and liver damage. Alagille syndrome can also affect other parts of the body, including the heart, kidneys, blood vessels, eyes, face, and spine. It usually occurs in infants and children and may be inherited.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752674" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Alagille syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752673" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome de Alagille&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>síndrome de Alagille</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno poco frecuente en el que hay defectos en los conductos pequeños que trasportan la bilis (líquido que ayuda a digerir las grasas) fuera del hígado. Estos conductos pequeños pueden ser estrechos, tener una forma anormal o puede haber menor cantidad de estos que lo normal. Esto puede producir la acumulación de bilis en el hígado, la cual puede dar lugar a cirrosis (cicatrices en el hígado) y daño del hígado. El síndrome de Alagille también puede afectar otras partes del cuerpo, como el corazón, los riñones, los vasos sanguíneos, los ojos, la cara  y la columna vertebral. Por lo general, se presenta en lactantes y niños, y puede ser hereditario.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-06-20</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
