<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000766166"><TermName>molecular test</TermName><TermPronunciation>(muh-LEH-kyoo-ler …)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>In medicine, a laboratory test that checks for certain genes, proteins, or other molecules in a sample of tissue, blood, or other body fluid. Molecular tests also check for certain changes in a gene or chromosome that may cause or affect the chance of developing a specific disease or disorder, such as cancer. A molecular test may be done with other procedures, such as biopsies, to help diagnose some types of cancer. It may also be used to help plan treatment, find out how well treatment is working, or make a prognosis.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000771233" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;molecular test&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000771234" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;prueba molecular&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>prueba molecular</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>En el campo de la medicina, prueba de laboratorio para comprobar si hay ciertos genes, proteínas u otras moléculas en una muestra de tejido, sangre u otro líquido del cuerpo. Las pruebas moleculares también se usan para comprobar si hay ciertos cambios en un gen o cromosoma que pueden causar la presentación de una enfermedad o trastorno específico, como el cáncer. Se puede realizar una prueba molecular  junto con otros procedimientos, como biopsias, para ayudar a diagnosticar algunos tipos de cáncer. Asimismo, se puede utilizar para ayudar a planificar el tratamiento, determinar si el tratamiento es eficaz o establecer un pronóstico.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2015-01-21</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
