<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000741769"><TermName>precision medicine</TermName><TermPronunciation>(pree-SIH-zhun MEH-dih-sin)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A form of medicine that uses information about a person’s genes, proteins, and environment to prevent, diagnose, and treat disease. In cancer, precision medicine uses specific information about a person’s tumor to help diagnose, plan treatment, find out how well treatment is working, or make a prognosis. Examples of precision medicine include using targeted therapies to treat specific types of cancer cells, such as HER2-positive breast cancer cells, or using tumor marker testing to help diagnose cancer. Also called personalized medicine.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000742989" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;precision medicine&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000742988" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;medicina personalizada&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>medicina personalizada</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de medicina que usa la información de los genes, proteínas y ambiente de una persona para prevenir, diagnosticar y tratar la enfermedad. En el caso del cáncer, la  usa información específica acerca del tumor de una persona para facilitar el diagnóstico, planificar el tratamiento y determinar si el tratamiento es eficaz, o para dar un pronóstico. Los ejemplos de  incluyen el uso de terapias dirigidas para tratar tipos específicos de células cancerosas, como las células de cáncer de mama  positivas al HER2, o el uso de pruebas de marcadores tumorales para ayudar en el diagnóstico de cáncer. También se llama medicina individualizada.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2012-10-16</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-02-12</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
