<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000764538"><TermName>pembrolizumab</TermName><TermPronunciation>(pem-broh-LIH-zoo-mab)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat certain types of non-small cell lung cancer that have spread to other parts of the body. It is used in patients whose cancer has a certain protein and whose disease got worse during or after treatment with anticancer drugs that included platinum. Pembrolizumab is also used to treat melanoma that cannot be removed by surgery or has spread to other parts of the body. It is used in patients whose disease got worse after being treated with ipilimumab and who may have also been treated with a BRAF inhibitor (a type of anticancer drug). It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Pembrolizumab binds to a receptor for a substance called PD-1, which is found on T cells (a type of white blood cell). Pembrolizumab may block PD-1 and help the immune system kill cancer cells. It is a type of monoclonal antibody and an immune checkpoint inhibitor. Also called Keytruda.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000766721" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pembrolizumab&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000766720" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;pembrolizumab&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>pembrolizumab</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para tratar ciertos tipos de cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas que se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo. Se utiliza en pacientes cuyo cáncer tiene una determinada proteína y cuya enfermedad empeoró durante el tratamiento con medicamentos contra el cáncer que incluyen platino o después de este tratamiento. El pembrolizumab también se utiliza para tratar el melanoma que no se puede extirpar mediante cirugía o que se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo. Se utiliza para pacientes cuya enfermedad empeoró después de haber sido tratados con ipilimumab y que también pueden haber sido tratados con un inhibidor de BRAF (un tipo de medicamento contra el cáncer). También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El pembrolizumab se une a un receptor de una sustancia que se llama PD-1, que se encuentra en las células T (un tipo de glóbulo blanco). El pembrolizumab puede bloquear el PD-1 y ayudar al sistema inmunitario a destruir células cancerosas. Es un tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal y un inhibidor de puntos de control inmunitario. También se llama Keytruda.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2014-09-18</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2015-10-20</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000764622">Pembrolizumab</RelatedDrugSummaryRef><RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000772606">immune checkpoint inhibitor</RelatedGlossaryTermRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
