<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000738849"><TermName>liposomal vincristine sulfate</TermName><TermPronunciation>(LY-poh-SOH-mul vin-KRIS-teen SUL-fayt)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A form of the anticancer drug vincristine sulfate that is contained inside very tiny, fat-like particles. It may have fewer side effects and work better than vincristine. Liposomal vincristine sulfate is used to treat adults with acute lymphoblastic leukemia that is Philadelphia chromosome negative and has come back or has not gotten better with other treatment.  It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. It is a type of vinca alkaloid and a type of antimitotic agent. Also called Marqibo and vincristine sulfate liposome.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000740991" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;liposomal vincristine sulfate&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000740990" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;sulfato de vincristina liposomal&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>sulfato de vincristina liposomal</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Forma del medicamento contra el cáncer sulfato de vincristina contenido en partículas muy pequeñas parecidas a la grasa. Puede causar menos efectos secundarios y ser más eficaz que la vincristina. El sulfato de vincristina liposomal se usa para tratar a adultos con leucemia linfoblástica aguda que es negativa para el cromosoma Filadelfia que volvió o no mejoró con otro tratamiento. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Es un tipo de alcaloide  vinca y un tipo de antimitótico. También se llama Marqibo y sulfato de vincristina en liposomas.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2012-08-16</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000738511">Vincristine Sulfate Liposome</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
