<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000763774"><TermName>Golgi body</TermName><TermPronunciation>(GOL-jee BAH-dee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A stack of small flat sacs formed by membranes inside the cell’s cytoplasm (gel-like fluid). The Golgi body prepares proteins and lipid (fat) molecules for use in other places inside and outside the cell. The Golgi body is a cell organelle. Also called Golgi apparatus and Golgi complex.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000769397" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Golgi body&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000769398" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cuerpo de Golgi&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000761780" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing showing a cell containing organelles, including the nucleus (contains DNA), the nucleolus, Golgi complex, mitochondria, and endoplasmic reticulum. Also shown are the cell membrane and a membrane receptor." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Parts of a cell.  A cell is surrounded by a membrane, which has receptors on the surface. A cell has several small structures inside it, including the nucleus, mitochondria, endoplasmic reticulum, and Golgi complex. These all have specific functions in the cell. </Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000765321" type="image/jpeg" alt="En la ilustración, se muestra una célula con sus organelos, como el núcleo (contiene ADN), el nucléolo, el aparato de Golgi, las mitocondrias y el retículo endoplasmático. También se muestran la membrana celular y un receptor de membrana." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Partes de una célula. La célula está rodeada por una membrana, con receptores en la superficie; además,  tiene varias estructuras pequeñas en su interior, como el núcleo, las mitocondrias, el retículo endoplasmático y el  aparato de Golgi. Estas desempeñan funciones específicas en la célula.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>cuerpo de Golgi</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Sacos pequeños planos apilados formados  por membranas dentro del citoplasma (líquido parecido a la gelatina) de la célula. El cuerpo de Golgi elabora proteínas y moléculas de lípidos (grasa) para su uso en otros lugares dentro y fuera de la célula. El cuerpo de Golgi es un orgánulo celular. También se llama aparato de Golgi y complejo de Golgi.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2014-11-07</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2014-11-19</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
