<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000754026"><TermName>lead compound</TermName><TermPronunciation>(leed KOM-pownd)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>In medicine, a chemical compound that shows promise as a treatment for a disease and may lead to the development of a new drug. Thousands of compounds are tested in the laboratory to find a lead (“leading”) compound that may act on specific genes or proteins involved in a disease. Once a lead compound has been found, the chemical structure is used as a starting point to make a drug that has the most benefits and the least harms. Finding a lead compound is the first step in making a new drug to treat a disease.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000759308" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;lead compound&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000759309" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;molécula de partida&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>molécula de partida</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>En el campo de la medicina,  un compuesto químico que se muestra prometedor como tratamiento de una enfermedad y puede conducir al desarrollo de un nuevo medicamento. En el laboratorio, se prueban miles de compuestos para encontrar una molécula de partida ("líder") que pueda actuar sobre los genes o las proteínas específicos que participan en una enfermedad. Una vez que se encuentra una molécula de partida, se utiliza la estructura química como punto de partida para elaborar un medicamento que proporcione más beneficios y mínimos daños. Encontrar una molécula de partida es el primer paso en la producción de un medicamento nuevo para tratar una enfermedad.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2014-01-17</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
