<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000725034"><TermName>vismodegib</TermName><TermPronunciation>(VIS-moh-DEH-gib)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat advanced basal cell carcinoma that has spread to other parts of the body or has come back after surgery. It is also used in patients who cannot be treated with surgery or radiation therapy. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Vismodegib blocks a type of protein involved in tissue growth and repair and may block the growth of cancer cells. It is a type of Hedgehog signaling pathway antagonist. Also called Erivedge and GDC-0449.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000734568" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;vismodegib&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000734567" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;vismodegib&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>vismodegib</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para tratar el carcinoma de células basales en estadio avanzado que se diseminó hasta otras partes del cuerpo o que volvió después de la cirugía. También se usa para pacientes que no se pueden tratar con cirugía o radioterapia. Asimismo, está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El vismodegib impide la acción de un tipo de proteína que participa en el crecimiento de tejidos y puede combatir la formación de células cancerosas. Es un tipo de antagonista de la vía de señalización de Hedgehog. También se llama Erivedge y GDC-0449.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2012-02-10</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2012-02-10</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000724515">Vismodegib</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
