<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000771301"><TermName>chimeric antigen receptor T-cell therapy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ky-MEER-ik AN-tih-jen reh-SEP-ter T-sel THAYR-uh-pee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of treatment in which a patient's T cells (a type of immune system cell) are changed in the laboratory so they will attack cancer cells. T cells are taken from a patient’s blood. Then the gene for a special receptor that binds to a certain protein on the patient’s cancer cells is added in the laboratory. The special receptor is called a chimeric antigen receptor (CAR). Large numbers of the CAR T cells are grown in the laboratory and given to the patient by infusion. Chimeric antigen receptor T-cell therapy is being studied in the treatment of some types of cancer. Also called CAR T-cell therapy.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000774969" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;chimeric antigen receptor T-cell therapy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000774970" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;terapia con receptor de antígeno quimérico de las células T&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>terapia con receptor de antígeno quimérico de las células T</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de tratamiento en el que las células T del paciente (un tipo de célula del sistema inmunitario) se alteran en el laboratorio de modo que ataquen células cancerosas. Las células T se toman de la sangre del paciente. Después se agrega en el laboratorio el gen para un receptor especial que se une a cierta proteína de las células canceras del paciente. Este receptor especial se llama receptor de antígeno quimérico (CAR). Grandes cantidades de células T con CAR  se cultivan en el laboratorio y se devuelven al paciente mediante una infusión. La terapia con receptor de antígeno quimérico de las células T está en estudio  para el tratamiento de algunos tipos de cáncer. También se llama terapia con CAR de las células T.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2015-07-10</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
