<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000754024"><TermName>immune system disorder</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ih-MYOON SIS-tem dis-OR-der)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A condition
          that affects the immune system. The immune system is made
          up of cells, tissues, and organs that help the body fight
          infections and other diseases. There are many different
          types of immune system disorders, including
          immunodeficiency disease, autoimmune disorders, and
          allergic disorders. Immunodeficiency disease occurs when a
          part of the immune system is missing or not working
          properly. Autoimmune disorders occur when the immune system
          recognizes its own tissues as foreign and attacks them.
          Allergic disorders occur when the immune system overreacts
          to substances that are usually not harmful, such as pollen,
          molds, and certain foods. Cancers of the immune system
          (such as leukemia and lymphoma) are also immune system
          disorders.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000759307" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;immune system disorder&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000759306" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;trastorno del sistema inmunitario&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>trastorno del sistema inmunitario</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Afección que afecta el sistema inmunitario. El sistema inmunitario se compone de células, tejidos y órganos que ayudan al cuerpo a combatir infecciones y otras enfermedades. Hay muchos tipos diferentes de trastornos del sistema inmunitario, como la enfermedad por inmunodeficiencia, los trastornos autoinmunitarios y los trastornos alérgicos. La enfermedad por inmunodeficiencia se presenta cuando falta una parte del sistema inmunitario o este no funciona correctamente. Los trastornos autoinmunitarios se presentan cuando el sistema inmunitario no reconoce sus propios tejidos y los ataca. Los trastornos alérgicos se presentan cuando el sistema inmunitario reacciona de forma exagerada a sustancias que generalmente no son dañinas, como el polen, el moho y ciertos alimentos. Los cánceres del sistema inmunitario (como la leucemia y el linfoma) también son trastornos del sistema inmunitario.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2014-01-17</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
