<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000709264"><TermName>PEP02</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A form of the anticancer drug irinotecan hydrochloride that is contained in very tiny, fat-like particles. PEP02 is used together with fluorouracil and leucovorin to treat a certain type of pancreatic cancer that has spread to other parts of the body and has gotten worse after treatment with gemcitabine anticancer therapy. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Irinotecan hydrochloride blocks certain enzymes needed for cell division and DNA repair, and it may kill cancer cells. PEP02 may have fewer side effects and work better than irinotecan hydrochloride. It is a type of topoisomerase inhibitor and a type of camptothecin analog. Also called irinotecan hydrochloride liposome, liposome-encapsulated irinotecan hydrochloride PEP02,  and Onivyde.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><SpanishTermName>PEP02</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Una forma del medicamento contra el cáncer hidrocloruro de irinotecán que se encuentra en el interior de partículas muy pequeñas parecidas a la grasa. PEP02 se usa con el fluorouracilo y la leucovorina para el tratamiento de ciertos tipos de cáncer del páncreas que se ha diseminado a otras partes del cuerpo y que ha empeorado luego del tratamiento contra el cáncer con gemcitabina. También está en estudio como tratamiento para otros tipos de cáncer. El hidrocloruro de  irinotecán impide la acción de ciertas enzimas necesarias para la división celular y la reparación del ADN, y podría eliminar las células cancerosas. PEP02 podría presentar menos efectos secundarios y trabajar mejor que el hidrocloruro de irinotecán. Es un tipo de inhibidor de la topoisomerasa y un tipo de análogo de la camptotecina. También se llama hidrocloruro de irinotecán encapsulado por liposoma PEP02, liposoma de hidrocloruro de irinotecán,  y Onivyde.</DefinitionText><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2011-10-13</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2015-10-26</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000776561">Irinotecan Hydrochloride Liposome</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
