<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000752847"><TermName>human papillomavirus test</TermName><TermPronunciation>(HYOO-mun PA-pih-LOH-muh-VY-rus …)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A laboratory test in which cells are tested for DNA or RNA from certain types of human papillomavirus (HPV) that are known to cause cervical cancer. These high-risk types of HPV can also cause other types of cancer, including cancers of the anus, vagina, vulva, penis, and oropharynx. A human papillomavirus test may be done at the same time as a Pap test for cervical cancer screening in women aged 30 to 65 years. A human papillomavirus test  may also be done after certain abnormal Pap test results.  Also called HPV test.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000757955" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;human papillomavirus test&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000757956" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;prueba de virus del papiloma humano&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>prueba de virus del papiloma humano</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Prueba de laboratorio en la que se examinan las células para determinar si tienen ADN o ARN de ciertos tipos de virus del papiloma humano (VPH) de los que se sabe que causan cáncer de cuello uterino. Estos tipos de riesgo alto de VPH también pueden causar otros tipos de cáncer, como cáncer de ano, vagina, vulva, pene y orofaringe. La prueba de virus del papiloma humano se puede realizar al mismo tiempo que la prueba de Pap para detectar el cáncer de cuello uterino en las mujeres entre 30 y 65 años. La prueba de virus del papiloma humano también se puede realizar después de obtener ciertos resultados anormales de la prueba de Pap. También se llama prueba del VPH.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-11-05</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/cervical/pap-hpv-testing-fact-sheet">Pap and HPV Testing</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/risk/infectious-agents/hpv-fact-sheet">HPV and Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/cuello-uterino/hoja-informativa-prueba-pap-vph">Pruebas de Papanicolaou y del virus del papiloma humano (VPH)
</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/riesgo/germenes-infecciosos/hoja-informativa-vph">Virus del papiloma humano y el cáncer
</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
