<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000765624"><TermName>stage IIB esophageal squamous cell carcinoma</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... ee-SAH-fuh-JEE-ul SKWAY-mus sel KAR-sih-NOH-muh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage II is divided into stages IIA and IIB, depending on where the cancer has spread. In stage IIB, cancer (1) has spread into the muscle layer or the connective tissue layer of the esophagus wall, and the cancer cells are grade 2 and 3. Grade 2 and 3 cancer cells look more abnormal under a microscope and grow and spread more quickly than grade 1 cancer cells. The tumor is in either the upper or middle esophagus; or (2) is in the mucosa or submucosa layer and may have spread into the muscle layer of the esophagus wall. Cancer is found in 1 or 2 lymph nodes near the tumor.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000766719" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage IIB esophageal squamous cell carcinoma&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000766718" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;carcinoma de esófago de células escamosas en estadio IIB&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752733" type="image/jpeg" alt="Stage IIB squamous cell cancer of the esophagus; drawing shows the esophagus and stomach. A two-panel inset shows the layers of the esophagus wall: the mucosa, submucosa, muscle, and connective tissue layers. The left panel shows cancer in the mucosa, submucosa, muscle, and connective tissue layers. The right panel shows cancer in the mucosa, submucosa, and muscle layers and in 1 lymph node." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_2"><Caption language="en">Stage IIB squamous cell cancer of the esophagus. The tumor is in either the upper or middle esophagus. Cancer has spread into the muscle layer or the connective tissue layer of the esophagus wall, and the cancer cells are grade 2-3; OR cancer is in the mucosa or submucosa layer and may have spread into the muscle layer of the esophagus wall, and cancer is found in 1 or 2 lymph nodes near the tumor. Grade 2-3 cancer cells look more abnormal under a microscope and grow and spread more quickly than grade 1 cancer cells.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000765184" type="image/jpeg" alt="Cáncer de esófago de células escamosas en estadio IIB; en la ilustración, se muestran el esófago y el estómago. En el recuadro de dos paneles, se muestran las capas de la pared del esófago: la mucosa, la submucosa, el músculo y el tejido conjuntivo. En el panel izquierdo, se muestra el cáncer en las capas de la mucosa, la submucosa, el músculo y el tejido conjuntivo. En el panel derecho, se muestra el cáncer en las capas de la mucosa, la submucosa, el músculo y en un ganglio linfático." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Cáncer de esófago de células escamosas en estadio IIB. El tumor se ubica en la parte superior o media del esófago. El cáncer se diseminó a la capa del músculo o el tejido conjuntivo de la pared del esófago, y las células cancerosas son de grado 2 o 3; O el cáncer está en la capa de la mucosa o  la submucosa y se pudo diseminar a la capa muscular de la pared del esófago, y se encuentra cáncer en 1 o 2 ganglios linfáticos cercanos al tumor. Al microscopio, las células cancerosas de grado 2 o 3 parecen más células anormales, y crecen y se diseminan de modo más rápido que las células cancerosas de grado 1.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>carcinoma de esófago de células escamosas en estadio IIB</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio II se divide en los estadios IIA y IIB, según el sitio donde se haya diseminado el cáncer. En el estadio IIB, el cáncer 1) se diseminó a la capa del músculo o el tejido conjuntivo de la pared del esófago, y las células cancerosas son de grado 2 o 3. Al microscopio, las células cancerosas de grado 2 o 3 parecen más células anormales, y crecen y se diseminan de modo  más rápido que las células cancerosas de grado 1. El tumor se ubica en la parte superior o media del esófago; o 2) se ubica en la capa mucosa o submucosa, y se pudo diseminar a la capa muscular de la pared  del esófago. El cáncer se encuentra en 1 o 2 ganglios linfáticos cercanos al tumor.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2014-10-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2014-11-03</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000062960">Esophageal Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256773">Cáncer de esófago: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
