<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000754851"><TermName>ibrutinib</TermName><TermPronunciation>(i-BROO-tih-nib)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat Waldenstrom macroglobulinemia (a type of non-Hodgkin lymphoma). It is also used to treat mantle cell lymphoma and chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL) in patients who have already received other treatment.  It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Ibrutinib blocks a protein called Bruton’s tyrosine kinase (BTK), which may help keep cancer cells from growing. It is a type of tyrosine kinase inhibitor. Also called Imbruvica.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000757958" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ibrutinib&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000757957" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ibrutinib&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>ibrutinib</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para tratar la macroglobulinemia de Waldenström (tipo de linfoma no Hodgkin).  También se usa para tratar el linfoma de células del manto y la leucemia linfocítica crónica (LLC) en pacientes que ya recibieron otro tratamiento. También está en estudio para tratar otros tipos de cáncer.  ibrutinib impide la acción de una proteína que se llama tirosina cinasa de Bruton (BTK), la cual puede evitar el  crecimiento de células cancerosas.  Es un tipo de inhibidor de la tirosina cinasa. También se llama Imbruvica.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-11-26</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2015-02-09</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000754956">Ibrutinib</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
