<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000748241"><TermName>electronic cigarette</TermName><TermPronunciation>(eh-lek-TRAH-nik SIH-guh-ret)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A device that has the shape of a cigarette, cigar, or pen and does not contain tobacco. It uses a battery and contains a solution of nicotine, flavorings, and other chemicals, some of which may be harmful. When electronic cigarettes are used, the nicotine solution turns into a mist that can be inhaled into the lungs. The amount of nicotine in individual e-cigarettes can vary. It is not yet known whether electronic cigarettes are safe or if they can be used to help smokers quit smoking. Also called e-cigarette.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752581" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;electronic cigarette&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752580" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cigarrillo electrónico&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cigarrillo electrónico</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Dispositivo que tiene la forma de un cigarrillo, un cigarro o un bolígrafo y que no contiene tabaco. Utiliza una batería y contiene una solución de nicotina, aromatizantes y otras sustancias químicas, algunos de los cuales pueden ser dañinos. Cuando se utilizan cigarrillos electrónicos, la solución de nicotina se convierte en un vapor que se puede inhalar hacia los pulmones. La cantidad de nicotina en los cigarrillos electrónicos puede variar. Todavía no se sabe si los cigarrillos electrónicos son seguros o si se pueden utilizar para ayudar a los fumadores a dejar de fumar. También se llama cigarrillos-e.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-07-17</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
