<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000748247"><TermName>ultra light cigarette</TermName><TermPronunciation>(UL-truh lite SIH-guh-ret)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of cigarette that is claimed to give off less tobacco tar than a regular or light (“low-tar”) cigarette when smoked. Ultra light cigarettes have been shown to be no safer than regular cigarettes, and smoking them does not lower the risk of cancer or other diseases. A person smoking an ultra light cigarette can inhale the same amount of tobacco tar, nicotine, and harmful, cancer-causing chemicals as in a regular cigarette, depending on how the cigarette is smoked. Cigarettes are no longer allowed to be labeled or advertised as ultra light cigarettes.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752589" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ultra light cigarette&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752588" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cigarrillo ultralight&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cigarrillo ultralight</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de cigarrillo del que se asegura que emite menos alquitrán de tabaco que un cigarrillo normal o "light" (de bajo contenido de alquitrán) cuando se fuma. Los cigarrillos "ultralight" no han mostrado ser más seguros que los cigarrillos regulares y fumarlos no disminuye el riesgo de cáncer o de otras enfermedades. Una persona que fuma un cigarrillo ultralight puede inhalar la misma cantidad de alquitrán del tabaco, nicotina y sustancias químicas dañinas que causan cáncer que un cigarrillo normal, según como se fume el cigarrillo. Ya no está permitido etiquetar o publicitar los cigarrillos como ultralight.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-07-17</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/risk/tobacco/light-cigarettes-fact-sheet">"Light" Cigarettes and Cancer Risk</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/riesgo/tabaco/hoja-informativa-cigarillos-light">Los cigarrillos "light" y el riesgo de cáncer
</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
