<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000752840"><TermName>atypical squamous cells, cannot exclude a high-grade lesion</TermName><TermPronunciation>(AY-TIH-pih-kul SKWAY-mus sels, KA-not ek-SKLOOD … hy-grayd LEE-zhun)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A finding of abnormal cells in a Pap test. It means there are abnormal squamous cells in the tissue that lines the outer part of the cervix. Atypical squamous cells, cannot exclude a high-grade lesion may be a sign of a high-grade squamous intraepithelial lesion (HSIL), which may become cervical cancer if untreated. More testing may be needed. Also called ASC-H.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000757946" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;atypical squamous cells, cannot exclude a high-grade lesion&quot;" language="en" id="_2"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000767703" type="audio/mpeg" alt="" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>células escamosas atípicas, no se puede descartar una lesión de alto grado</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Hallazgo de células anormales en una prueba de Pap. Esto significa que hay células escamosas anormales en el tejido que reviste la parte exterior del cuello uterino. Es posible que  células escamosas atípicas, no se puede descartar una lesión de alto grado sea un signo de lesiones  escamosas intraepiteliales de grado alto (HSIL). A su vez, estas se pueden convertir en cáncer de cuello uterino si no se tratan. Pueden ser necesarias más pruebas.  También se llama ASC-H.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-11-05</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/cervical/pap-hpv-testing-fact-sheet">Pap and HPV Testing</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/cuello-uterino/hoja-informativa-prueba-pap-vph">Pruebas de Papanicolaou y del virus del papiloma humano (VPH)
</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
