<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000723335"><TermName>electrosurgery</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ee-LEK-troh-SER-juh-ree)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure that uses an electric current to cut, remove, or destroy tissue and control bleeding. The current is carried through an electrode that is placed on or near the tissue. Electrosurgery may be used to treat basal cell skin cancer or other types of skin problems, such as actinic keratoses, warts, and moles. It may also be used to remove abnormal cells from the cervix and to treat abnormal tissue of the vagina, vulva, penis, and anus that might become cancer. Examples of electrosurgery are electrodesiccation and fulguration.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000734678" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;electrosurgery&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000734677" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;electrocirugía&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>electrocirugía</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento para el que se usa corriente eléctrica para cortar, extirpar o destruir tejido, y controlar el sangrado. La corriente pasa a través de un electrodo que se coloca sobre el tejido o cerca del mismo. La electrocirugía se puede usar para tratar el cáncer de piel de células basales u otros tipos de problemas de la piel, como la queratosis actínica, las verrugas y los lunares. También se puede utilizar para eliminar células anormales del cuello del útero y para tratar tejido anormal de la vagina, la vulva, el pene y el ano que se puede convertir en cáncer. Ejemplos de electrocirugía son la electrodesecación y la fulguración.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2012-04-11</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
