<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000721316"><TermName>cytokeratin</TermName><TermPronunciation>(SY-toh-KAYR-uh-tin)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of protein found on epithelial cells, which line the inside and outside surfaces of the body. Cytokeratins help form the tissues of the hair, nails, and the outer layer of the skin. They are also found on cells in the lining of organs, glands, and other parts of the body. Certain cytokeratins may be found in higher than normal amounts in patients with different types of epithelial cell cancers, including lung, breast, colorectal, bladder, and head and neck cancers. Measuring the amount of specific cytokeratins in the blood may help to plan cancer treatment or find out how well treatment is working or if cancer has come back. A cytokeratin is a type of tumor marker. Also called keratin.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000734704" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cytokeratin&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000734705" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;citoqueratina&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>citoqueratina</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de proteína que se encuentra en las células epiteliales que revisten las superficies internas y externas del cuerpo. Las citoqueratinas ayudan a formar los tejidos del cabello, las uñas y la capa externa de la piel. También se encuentran en las células que revisten los órganos, las glándulas y otras partes del cuerpo. Ciertas citoqueratinas se pueden encontrar en cantidades mayores que las normales en pacientes con diferentes tipos de cánceres de células epiteliales, como cánceres de pulmón, mama, colorrectal, vejiga y de la cabeza y el cuello. La medición de la cantidad de citoqueratinas específicas en la sangre puede ayudar a planificar el tratamiento del cáncer o determinar si el trratamiento es eficaz, o si el cáncer volvió. Una citoqueratina es un tipo de marcador tumoral. También se llama queratina.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2012-02-06</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
