<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000752241"><TermName>chronic myeloproliferative neoplasm</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KRAH-nik MY-eh-loh-proh-LIH-feh-ruh-tiv NEE-oh-PLA-zum)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of disease in which the bone marrow makes too many red blood cells, platelets, or certain white blood cells. Chronic myeloproliferative neoplasms usually get worse over time as the number of extra cells build up in the blood and/or bone marrow. This may cause bleeding problems, anemia, infection, fatigue, or other signs and symptoms. Certain chronic myeloproliferative neoplasms may become acute myeloid leukemia (AML). Chronic myeloproliferative neoplasms include chronic myelogenous leukemia (CML), polycythemia vera, primary myelofibrosis, essential thrombocythemia, chronic neutrophilic leukemia, and chronic eosinophilic leukemia. Also called myeloproliferative neoplasm.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000757968" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;chronic myeloproliferative neoplasm&quot;" language="en" id="_5"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000757967" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;neoplasia mieloproliferativa crónica&quot;" language="es" id="_6"/><SpanishTermName>neoplasia mieloproliferativa crónica</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de enfermedad por la que la médula ósea produce demasiadas células de glóbulos rojos, plaquetas o ciertos glóbulos blancos. Habitualmente, las neoplasias mieloproliferativas crónicas empeoran con el tiempo a medida que se acumulan más células  en la sangre o la médula ósea. Esto puede causar problemas de sangrado, anemia, infecciones, cansancio, u otros signos y síntomas. Algunas neoplasias mieloproliferativas crónicas se pueden convertir en leucemia mieloide aguda (LMA). Las neoplasias mieloproliferativas crónicas incluyen leucemia mielógena crónica (LMC), policitemia vera, mielofibrosis primaria, trombocitemia esencial, leucemia neutrofílica crónica y leucemia eosinofílica crónica. También se llama neoplasia mieloproliferativa.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-12-03</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-12-03</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/myeloproliferative">Myeloproliferative Neoplasms</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/mieloproliferativas">Neoplasias mieloproliferativas y síndromes mielodisplásicos</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
