<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000747357"><TermName>erythropoiesis-stimulating agent</TermName><TermPronunciation>(eh-RITH-roh-poy-EE-sis-STIM-yoo-LAY-ting AY-jent)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A substance that stimulates the bone marrow to make more red blood cells. Erythropoiesis-stimulating agents are used to treat anemia caused by chronic kidney failure, some anticancer drugs, and certain treatments for HIV. They may also be used to lower the number of blood transfusions needed during and after certain major surgeries. Examples of erythropoiesis-stimulating agents are epoetin alfa (Epogen, Procrit) and darbepoetin alfa (Aranesp). Also called ESA.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000749866" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;erythropoiesis-stimulating agent&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000749867" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;medicamento estimulante de la eritropoyesis&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>medicamento estimulante de la eritropoyesis</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Sustancia que estimula la médula ósea para elaborar más glóbulos rojos. Los medicamentos estimulantes de la eritropoyesis se usan para tratar la anemia que produce la insuficiencia renal crónica, algunos medicamentos contra el cáncer y ciertos tratamientos para el VIH. También se pueden usar para disminuir el número de transfusiones de sangre que se necesitan durante ciertas operaciones importantes y después de estas. Entre los ejemplos de medicamentos estimulantes de la eritropoyesis, se encuentran la epoyetina alfa (Epogen, Procrit) y la darbepoyetina alfa (Aranesp). También se llama ESA.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-04-15</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
