<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000751176"><TermName>afatinib dimaleate</TermName><TermPronunciation>(ay-FA-tih-nib dy-MAY-lee-AYT)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat non-small cell lung cancer that has spread to other parts of the body. It is used in patients with certain mutations (changes) in a cell protein called epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR). It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer.  Afatinib dimaleate blocks certain EGFRs, which may help keep cancer cells from growing. It may also prevent the growth of new blood vessels that tumors need to grow. Afatinib dimaleate is a type of tyrosine kinase inhibitor and a type of antiangiogenesis agent. Also called Gilotrif.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752522" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;afatinib dimaleate&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752521" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;afatinib dimaleate&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>afatinib dimaleate</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento para tratar el cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas que se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo. Se usa en pacientes con ciertas mutaciones (cambios) en una proteína celular que se llama receptor del factor de crecimiento epidérmico (RFCE). También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El afatinib dimaleate impide la acción de ciertos tipos de RFCE, lo que puede prevenir el crecimiento de células cancerosas. También puede ayudar a prevenir la formación de vasos sanguíneos nuevos que los tumores necesitan para crecer. El afatinib dimaleate es un tipo de inhibidor de la tirosina cinasa y un tipo de antiangiogénico. También se llama Gilotrif.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-07-24</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-07-24</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000751154">Afatinib Dimaleate</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
