<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000739359"><TermName>stage III perihilar extrahepatic bile duct cancer</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... PAYR-ee-HY-ler EK-struh-heh-PA-tik bile dukt KAN-ser)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage III is divided into stages IIIA and IIIB. In stage IIIA, the tumor has spread to one branch of the hepatic artery or of the portal vein. In stage IIIB, the tumor has spread to nearby lymph nodes. Cancer has also spread into the wall of the perihilar extrahepatic bile duct (where the bile duct leaves the liver)   and may have spread through the wall to nearby fatty tissue, the liver, or to one branch of the hepatic artery or of the portal vein.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000742079" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage III perihilar extrahepatic bile duct cancer&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000742080" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;carcinoma de vía biliar extrahepática perihiliar en estadio III&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>carcinoma de vía biliar extrahepática perihiliar en estadio III</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio III se divide en los estadios IIIA y IIIB. En el estadio IIIA, el tumor se diseminó hasta  una rama de la arteria hepática o de la vena porta. En el estadio IIIB, el tumor se diseminó hasta los ganglios linfáticos cercanos. El cáncer también se diseminó hasta la pared de la vía biliar extrahepática perihiliar (donde la vía biliar sale del hígado) y se puede haber diseminado a través de la pared hasta el tejido graso cercano, el hígado o una rama de la arteria hepática o de la vena porta.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2012-09-06</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-10-30</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258011">Bile Duct Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256805">Cáncer de las vías biliares extrahepáticas: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
