<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000748148"><TermName>cigarette</TermName><TermPronunciation>(SIH-guh-ret)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A tube-shaped tobacco product that is made of finely cut, cured tobacco leaves wrapped in thin paper. It may also have other ingredients, including substances to add different flavors.  A cigarette is lit on one end and smoked, and the smoke is usually inhaled into the lungs. Cigarettes contain nicotine and many cancer-causing chemicals that are harmful to both smokers and nonsmokers. Smoking cigarettes can lead to nicotine addiction and can cause many types of cancer, including cancers of the lung, larynx, mouth, esophagus, throat, kidney, bladder, pancreas, stomach, and cervix, and acute myeloid leukemia. Smoking cigarettes also causes other health problems, including heart disease, stroke, and lung diseases, such as emphysema and chronic bronchitis.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752549" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cigarette&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752550" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cigarrillo&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cigarrillo</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Producto del tabaco en forma de tubo que se fabrica con hojas de tabaco curadas, cortadas finamente, enrolladas y envueltas en un papel delgado. También puede tener otros ingredientes, como sustancias para añadirle diferentes sabores. Un cigarrillo se enciende en un extremo y se fuma y, por lo general, se inhala hacia los pulmones. Los cigarrillos contienen nicotina y muchos productos químicos que causan cáncer y que son perjudiciales tanto para los fumadores como para quienes no fuman. Fumar cigarrillos puede producir adicción a la nicotina y causar muchos tipos de cáncer, como cánceres  de pulmón, laringe, boca, esófago, garganta, riñón, vejiga, páncreas, estómago y cuello uterino, así como leucemia mieloide aguda. Fumar cigarros también causa otros problemas de salud, como cardiopatías, derrames cerebrales y enfermedades pulmonares, como  enfisema y bronquitis crónica.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-07-17</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/risk/tobacco">Tobacco</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/riesgo/tabaco">Tabaco</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
