<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000739789"><TermName>504 plan</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… plan)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>An education plan for students with disabilities or certain health conditions, such as cancer. By law, these students must have the same access to school programs and activities as students without disabilities. A 504 plan may include extra help in the classroom, such as allowing the student more time to take a test or finish an assignment, or to use a computer or tape recorder. It may also include tutoring and other services, such as speech therapy and physical therapy.  It is covered under the U.S. law, Rehabilitation Act of 1973.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000745264" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;504 plan&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000745263" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;plan 504&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>plan 504</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Plan de educación para los estudiantes con discapacidades o ciertas afecciones de salud, como el cáncer.   Por ley, estos estudiantes deben tener el mismo acceso a los programas y las actividades escolares que los estudiantes sin discapacidades.   Un plan 504 puede incluir ayuda extra en el aula, como brindar al estudiante más tiempo para tomar una prueba o finalizar una tarea, o para usar una computadora o una grabadora.   También puede incluir instrucción y otros servicios tales como foniatría y fisioterapia.   Está garantizado por la ley de los Estados Unidos <ForeignWord>Rehabilitation Act</ForeignWord> (Ley de Rehabilitación) de 1973.  </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2012-11-21</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000739785">individualized education plan</RelatedGlossaryTermRef><RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000739786">IEP</RelatedGlossaryTermRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
