<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000736219"><TermName>stage I nonmelanoma skin cancer on the eyelid</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... non-MEH-luh-NOH-muh skin KAN-ser ... I-lid)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>Stage I is divided into stages IA, IB, and IC. In stage IA, the tumor is 5 millimeters or smaller and has not spread to the connective tissue of the eyelid or to the edge of the eyelid where the lashes are. In stage IB, the tumor is larger than 5 millimeters but not larger than 10 millimeters or has spread to the connective tissue of the eyelid or to the edge of the eyelid where the lashes are. In stage IC, the tumor is larger than 10 millimeters but not larger than 20 millimeters or has spread through the full thickness of the eyelid.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000738122" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;stage I nonmelanoma skin cancer on the eyelid&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000738121" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cáncer de piel no melanoma del  párpado en estadio I&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cáncer de piel no melanoma del párpado en estadio I</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>El estadio I se divide en los estadios IA, IB y IC. En el estadio IA, el tumor mide cinco milímetros o menos, y no se diseminó hasta el tejido conjuntivo del párpado o el borde del párpado donde están las pestañas. En el estadio IB, el tumor mide más de cinco milímetros, pero no más de 10 milímetros, o se diseminó hasta el tejido conjuntivo del párpado o hasta el borde del párpado donde están las pestañas. En el estadio IC, el tumor mide más de 10 milímetros, pero no más de 20 milímetros, y se diseminó a través de todo el grosor del párpado.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2012-06-28</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="en" href="CDR0000258035">Skin Cancer Treatment</RelatedSummaryRef><RelatedSummaryRef UseWith="es" href="CDR0000256809">Cáncer de piel: Tratamiento</RelatedSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
