<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000767205"><TermName>blinatumomab</TermName><TermPronunciation>(blih-nuh-TOO-moh-mab)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat B-cell acute lymphoblastic leukemia that is Philadelphia chromosome negative and has come back or has not gotten better with other anticancer treatment. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Blinatumomab binds to a protein called CD19, which is found on most B cells (a type of white blood cell) and some types of leukemia cells. It also binds to a protein called CD3, which is found on T cells (a type of white blood cell). This may help the immune system kill cancer cells. Blinatumomab is a type of monoclonal antibody. Also called Blincyto.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000769372" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;blinatumomab&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000769371" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;blinatumomab&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>blinatumomab</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para tratar la leucemia linfoblástica aguda de células B que es negativa para el cromosoma Filadelfia, y que volvió o no mejoró con otros tratamientos contra el cáncer. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. El blinatumomab se une a una proteína que se llama CD19, que se encuentra en la mayoría de las células B (un tipo de glóbulo blanco) y en algunos tipos de leucemia. También se une a una proteína que se llama CD3, que se encuentra en las células T ( tipo de glóbulo blanco). Este medicamento puede ayudar a que el sistema inmunitario destruya células cancerosas. El blinatumomab es un tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal. También se llama Blincyto.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2014-12-22</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000767077">Blinatumomab</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
