<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000740024"><TermName>enzalutamide</TermName><TermPronunciation>(EN-zuh-LOO-tuh-mide)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat prostate cancer that has spread to other parts of the body and did not get better with other treatment, including docetaxel. Enzalutamide binds to proteins called androgen receptors, which are found in some prostate cancer cells. These proteins bind to androgens (male hormones) and may cause cancer cells to grow. Blocking these proteins may keep cancer cells from growing. Enzalutamide is a type of antiandrogen. Also called Xtandi.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000742087" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;enzalutamide&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000742088" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;enzalutamida&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>enzalutamida</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para tratar el cáncer de próstata que se diseminó hasta otras partes del cuerpo y no mejoró con otro tratamiento, como el docetaxel. La enzalutamida se une a  proteínas que se llaman receptores de andrógeno, que se encuentran en algunas células cancerosas de la próstata. Estas proteínas se unen con los andrógenos (hormonas masculinas) y pueden hacer crecer células cancerosas. El bloqueo de estas proteínas puede impedir que las células cancerosas crezcan. La enzalutamida es un tipo de antiandrógeno. También se llama Xtandi.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2012-09-13</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2014-01-09</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000739828">Enzalutamide</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
