<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000762782"><TermName>Beleodaq</TermName><TermPronunciation>(BEE-lee-oh-dak)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat peripheral T-cell lymphoma that has come back or has not gotten better with other treatment. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Beleodaq blocks certain enzymes needed for cell division and may kill cancer cells. It may also prevent the growth of new blood vessels that tumors need to grow and may help make cancer cells easier to kill with other anticancer drugs. It is a type of histone deacetylase (HDAC) inhibitor, a type of angiogenesis inhibitor, and a type of chemosensitizer. Also called belinostat and PXD101.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000764454" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Beleodaq&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000764453" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Beleodaq&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Beleodaq</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para tratar el linfoma de células T periféricas que volvió o no mejoró con otro tratamiento.  También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Beleodaq bloquea ciertas enzimas necesarias para la multiplicación celular y puede destruir células cancerosas.  Además, puede prevenir el crecimiento de vasos sanguíneos nuevos que los tumores necesitan para crecer y puede ayudar a destruir con más facilidad células cancerosas con otros medicamentos contra el cáncer.  Es un tipo de inhibidor de la histona deacetilasa (HDAC), un tipo de inhibidor de la angiogénesis y un tipo de quimiosensibilizador. También se llama belinostat y PXD101.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2014-07-11</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2014-07-11</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000762728">Belinostat</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
