<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000759144"><TermName>gFOBT</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A test that checks for occult (hidden) blood in the stool. Small samples of stool are placed on special cards coated with a chemical substance called guaiac and sent to a doctor or laboratory for testing. A testing solution is put on the cards and the guaiac causes the stool sample to change color. If there is blood in the stool, the color changes very quickly. Blood in the stool may be a sign of colorectal cancer or other problems, such as polyps, ulcers, or hemorrhoids. Also called guaiac fecal occult blood test, guaiac smear test,  and stool guaiac test.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><SpanishTermName>gFOBT</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Prueba para identificar sangre oculta (escondida) en la materia fecal. Se colocan muestras pequeñas de materia fecal en tarjetas especiales con una sustancia química llamada guayacol y se envían a un médico o un laboratorio para examinarlas. Se agrega una solución de prueba en las tarjetas y el guayacol hace que la muestra de materia fecal cambie de color. Si hay sangre en la materia fecal, el color cambia muy rápido. La sangre en la materia fecal puede ser un signo de cáncer colorrectal o de otros problemas, como pólipos, úlceras o hemorroides. También se llama frotis de guayacol, prueba de guayacol en heces,  y prueba de sangre oculta en materia fecal con guayacol.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2014-06-16</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/colorectal/screening-fact-sheet">Tests to Detect Colorectal Cancer and Polyps</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/colorrectal/hoja-informativa-deteccion">Exámenes para detectar el cáncer colorrectal y los pólipos
</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
