<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000747093"><TermName>ado-trastuzumab emtansine</TermName><TermPronunciation>(A-doh-tras-TOO-zoo-mab em-TAN-seen)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat HER2-positive breast cancer that has spread to other parts of the body. It is used in patients who have already been treated with the anticancer drug called trastuzumab and a type of drug called a taxane. It may also be used in patients whose cancer has recurred (come back) after adjuvant therapy with these drugs. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Ado-trastuzumab emtansine contains a monoclonal antibody called trastuzumab that binds to a protein called HER2, which is found on some breast cancer cells. It also contains an anticancer drug called DM1, which may help kill cancer cells. Ado-trastuzumab emtansine is a type of antibody-drug conjugate. Also called Kadcyla and T-DM1.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000749859" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ado-trastuzumab emtansine&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000749858" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;ado-trastuzumab emtansina&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>ado-trastuzumab emtansina</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para tratar el cáncer de mama positivo al HER2 que se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo. Se usa para pacientes que ya fueron tratados con otro medicamento contra el cáncer que se llama trastuzumab y un tipo de sustancia que se llama taxano. También se usa en pacientes cuyo cáncer recidivó (volvió) después de recibir terapia adyuvante con estas sustancias. Asimismo, está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de cáncer. Ado-trastuzumab emtansina contiene un anticuerpo monoclonal que se llama trastuzumab que se liga a una proteína llamada HER2, que se encuentra en algunas células cancerosas. Además, contiene una sustancia contra el cáncer que se llama DM1 que puede ayudar a destruir células cancerosas. Ado-trastuzumab emtansina es un tipo de anticuerpo conjugado. También se llama Kadcyla y T-DM1.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-03-13</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000746946">Ado-Trastuzumab Emtansine</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
