<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000745805"><TermName>cerebrovascular accident</TermName><TermPronunciation>(seh-REE-broh-VAS-kyoo-ler AK-sih-dent)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>In medicine, a loss of blood flow to part of the brain, which damages brain tissue. Cerebrovascular accidents are caused by blood clots and broken blood vessels in the brain. Symptoms include dizziness, numbness, weakness on one side of the body, and problems with talking, writing, or understanding language. The risk of   cerebrovascular accident is increased by high blood pressure, older age, smoking, diabetes, high cholesterol, heart disease, atherosclerosis (a buildup of fatty material and plaque inside the coronary arteries), and a family history of cerebrovascular accident. Also called CVA and stroke.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000746298" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cerebrovascular accident&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000746299" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;accidente cerebrovascular&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>accidente cerebrovascular</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>En el campo de la medicina, pérdida del flujo de sangre a una parte del cerebro que  daña el tejido cerebral. La causa de los accidentes cerebrovasculares son los coágulos de sangre y los vasos sanguíneos del cerebro que se rompen. Los síntomas incluyen mareo, adormecimiento, debilidad en un lado del cuerpo y problemas para hablar, escribir o entender el lenguaje. El riesgo de un accidente cerebrovascular aumenta por la presión arterial alta, la edad avanzada, el tabaquismo, la diabetes, el colesterol alto, la enfermedad cardíaca, la aterosclerosis (acumulación de materia grasa y placas en el interior de las arterias coronarias) y antecedentes familiares de accidente cerebrovascular. También se llama ACV y derrame cerebral.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-01-30</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-01-29</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
