<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000774688"><TermName>blood chemistry test</TermName><TermPronunciation>(blud KEH-mih-stree …)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A test done on a sample of blood to measure the amount of certain substances in the body. These substances include electrolytes (such as sodium, potassium, and chloride), fats, proteins, glucose (sugar), and enzymes. Blood chemistry tests give important information about how well a person’s kidneys, liver, and other organs are working.  An abnormal amount of a substance in the blood can be a sign of disease or side effect of treatment. Blood chemistry tests are used to help diagnose and monitor many conditions before, during, and after treatment. Also called blood chemistry study.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000776450" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;blood chemistry test&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000776451" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;análisis bioquímico de la sangre&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>análisis bioquímico de la sangre</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Prueba de una muestra de sangre que se realiza para medir la cantidad de ciertas sustancias en el cuerpo. Estas sustancias incluyen electrolitos (como sodio, potasio y cloruro), grasas, proteínas, glucosa (azúcar) y enzimas. Los análisis bioquímicos de la sangre proporcionan información importante sobre si los riñones, el hígado y otros órganos de una persona funcionan bien. Una cantidad anormal de una sustancia en la sangre puede ser un signo de enfermedad o de un efecto secundario del tratamiento. Los análisis bioquímicos de la sangre se usan para ayudar a diagnosticar y controlar muchas afecciones antes, durante y después del tratamiento. También se llama estudio bioquímico de la sangre.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2015-09-22</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2015-09-21</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
