<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000767746"><TermName>Opdivo</TermName><TermPronunciation>(op-DEE-voh)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat advanced renal cell carcinoma (a type of kidney cancer) that was treated with antiangiogenesis therapy. Opdivo is also used alone or with ipilimumab to treat melanoma that cannot be removed by surgery or has spread to other parts of the body. It is used with ipilimumab in patients whose cancer does not have a certain BRAF gene mutation. It is used alone in patients whose disease got worse after being treated with ipilimumab and who may have also been treated with a BRAF inhibitor. Opdivo is also used to treat non-small cell lung cancer that has spread to other parts of the body. It is used in patients whose disease got worse during or after treatment with anticancer drugs that included platinum and who may have also been treated with other anticancer therapy. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of cancer. Opdivo binds to a substance called PD-1, which is found on T cells (a type of white blood cell). Opdivo may block PD-1 and help the immune system kill cancer cells. It is a type of monoclonal antibody and a type of immune checkpoint inhibitor. Also called nivolumab.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000771200" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Opdivo&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000771199" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Opdivo&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>Opdivo</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa solo o con ipilimumab para tratar el melanoma que no se puede extirpar mediante cirugía o que se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo. Se usa con ipilimumab en pacientes cuyo cáncer no tiene una determinada mutación en el gen BRAF. Se usa solo en pacientes cuya enfermedad empeoró después del tratamiento con ipilimumab y que también se pueden haber tratado con un inhibidor de BRAF (un medicamento contra el cáncer). Opdivo también se utiliza para tratar el cáncer de pulmón de células no pequeñas que se diseminó a otras partes del cuerpo. Se administra a pacientes cuya enfermedad empeoró durante o después del tratamiento con otros medicamentos contra el cáncer que incluyeron platino y que también pueden haber sido tratados con otros tratamientos contra el cáncer. Asimismo, está en estudio para tratar otros tipos de cáncer. Opdivo se une a una sustancia que se llama PD-1, que se encuentra en las células T (un tipo de glóbulo blanco).  Opdivo puede bloquear el PD-1 y ayudar a que el sistema inmunitario destruya células cancerosas. Es un tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal y de inhibidor de puntos de control inmunitario. También se llama nivolumab.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2015-01-06</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2015-11-25</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000767749">Nivolumab</RelatedDrugSummaryRef><RelatedGlossaryTermRef href="CDR0000772606">immune checkpoint inhibitor</RelatedGlossaryTermRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
