<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000763770"><TermName>endoplasmic reticulum</TermName><TermPronunciation>(EN-doh-PLAZ-mik reh-TIH-kyoo-lum)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A network of sac-like structures and tubes in the cytoplasm (gel-like fluid) of a cell. Proteins and other molecules move through the endoplasmic reticulum. The outer surface of the endoplasmic reticulum can be smooth or rough. The rough endoplasmic reticulum has many ribosomes on its outer surface and makes proteins the cell needs. The smooth endoplasmic reticulum makes other substances that the cell needs, such as lipids (fats) and carbohydrates (sugars). The endoplasmic reticulum is a cell organelle.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000769370" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;endoplasmic reticulum&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000769369" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;retículo endoplasmático&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000761780" type="image/jpeg" alt="Drawing showing a cell containing organelles, including the nucleus (contains DNA), the nucleolus, Golgi complex, mitochondria, and endoplasmic reticulum. Also shown are the cell membrane and a membrane receptor." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_3"><Caption language="en">Parts of a cell.  A cell is surrounded by a membrane, which has receptors on the surface. A cell has several small structures inside it, including the nucleus, mitochondria, endoplasmic reticulum, and Golgi complex. These all have specific functions in the cell. </Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000765321" type="image/jpeg" alt="En la ilustración, se muestra una célula con sus organelos, como el núcleo (contiene ADN), el nucléolo, el aparato de Golgi, las mitocondrias y el retículo endoplasmático. También se muestran la membrana celular y un receptor de membrana." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="es">Partes de una célula. La célula está rodeada por una membrana, con receptores en la superficie; además,  tiene varias estructuras pequeñas en su interior, como el núcleo, las mitocondrias, el retículo endoplasmático y el  aparato de Golgi. Estas desempeñan funciones específicas en la célula.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>retículo endoplasmático</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Red de estructuras parecidas a bolsas y tubos en el citoplasma (líquido parecido a la gelatina) de una célula. Las proteínas y otras moléculas se mueven a través del retículo endoplasmático, cuya superficie exterior  puede ser lisa o rugosa. El retículo endoplasmático rugoso tiene muchos ribosomas en su superficie exterior y elabora las proteínas que la célula necesita. El retículo endoplásmico liso elabora otras sustancias que necesita la célula, como los lípidos (grasas) y los carbohidratos (azúcares). El retículo endoplasmático es un orgánulo   celular.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2014-11-07</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2014-11-19</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
