<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000753856"><TermName>National Lung Screening Trial</TermName><TermPronunciation>(NA-shuh-nul … SKREE-ning TRY-ul)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A lung cancer screening trial sponsored by the National Cancer Institute (NCI). In the trial, low-dose spiral CT scans were compared with chest x-rays for their ability to detect lung cancer early. The trial included more than 50,000 participants who were aged 55 to 74 years, were current or former heavy smokers, and had no signs or symptoms of lung cancer. The results of the trial showed that participants who were screened with  spiral CT scans had about a 20% lower risk of dying from lung cancer than those who were screened with chest x-rays. Also called NLST.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000759277" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;National Lung Screening Trial&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><SpanishTermName>National Lung Screening trial</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Ensayo de detección del cáncer de pulmón patrocinado por el Instituto Nacional del Cáncer (NCI). En este ensayo se compararon exploraciones por TC en espiral de dosis bajas con radiografías del tórax para determinar su capacidad de detectar temprano el cáncer de pulmón. El ensayo incluyó a más de 50.000 participantes de 55 a 74 años, que eran o fueron fumadores persistentes, y que no presentaban signos o síntomas de cáncer de pulmón. Los resultados del ensayo mostraron que los participantes sometidos a detección con exploraciones por TC en espiral tuvieron un riesgo de alrededor de 20% más bajo de morir por cáncer de pulmón que aquellos sometidos a detección con radiografías de tórax. También se llama NLST.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2014-01-28</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
