<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000753862"><TermName>Cancer Intervention and Surveillance Modeling Network</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KAN-ser IN-ter-VEN-shun … ser-VAY-lents MAH-duh-ling NET-wurk)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A group of researchers supported by the National Cancer Institute (NCI) who use statistical models to help understand how cancer prevention, screening, and treatment programs can affect the number of new cases of cancer diagnosed each year and the number of deaths from cancer each year. The Cancer Intervention and Surveillance Modeling Network is now studying breast, colorectal, esophageal, lung, and prostate cancers. The models they create help guide future cancer control strategies, research priorities, policies, and decision making. Also called CISNET.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000759281" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;Cancer Intervention and Surveillance Modeling Network&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><SpanishTermName>Cancer Intervention and Surveillance Modeling Network</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Grupo de investigadores auspiciado por Instituto Nacional del Cáncer (NCI) que utiliza modelos estadísticos que ayudan a entender el modo en que los programas de prevención, los exámenes de detección y los tratamientos de cáncer afectan el número de casos nuevos de cáncer que se diagnostican cada año y el número anual de muertes por cáncer.  El Cancer Intervention and Surveillance Modeling Network estudia ahora los cánceres de mama, colorrectar, de esófago, de pulmón  y de próstata. Los modelos que crean ayudan a guiar en el futuro el control, las estrategias, las prioridades de investigación, las políticas y la toma de decisiones sobre el cáncer.  También se llama CISNET.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2014-01-28</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
