<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000776051"><TermName>NCI-supported clinical trial</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… suh-POR-ted KLIH-nih-kul TRY-ul)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A research study conducted by researchers and institutions that receive funding or other resources from the National Cancer Institute (NCI). Resources from NCI include programs that provide scientific review and Institutional Review Board (IRB) support and management of patient tissue sample collection and storage.  NCI also provides information about the clinical trials, such as regulatory requirements, patient enrollment, funding, and education materials to these researchers. This support allows the people who run the clinical trials more time for patient care and research. NCI-supported trials include trials that are part of NCI’s national networks, such as National Clinical Trials Network (NCTN), NCI Community Oncology Research Program (NCORP), and Experimental Therapeutics Clinical Trials Network (ETCTN). NCI also funds, in full or in part, trials taking place at NCI-designated cancer centers throughout the U.S. and trials taking place at the NIH Clinical Center in Bethesda, Maryland.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><SpanishTermName>ensayo clínico patrocinado por el NCI</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Estudio de investigación realizado por investigadores e instituciones para recibir fondos u otros recursos del Instituto Nacional del Cáncer (NCI). Los recursos del NCI incluyen programas que proporcionan apoyo y manejo para la recolección y almacenamiento de muestras de tejidos de pacientes mediante la revisión científica y el patrocinio del Comité Institucional de Revisión (Institutional Review Board [IRB]). El NCI también provee a estos investigadores de información sobre los ensayos clínicos, como los requisitos normativos, la inscripción de pacientes, la financiación y los materiales de educación. Este apoyo permite que las personas que dirigen los ensayos clínicos tengan más tiempo para la atención del paciente y la investigación. Los ensayos respaldados por el NCI incluyen ensayos que forman parte de las redes nacionales de NCI, como la Red Nacional de Ensayos Clínicos (National Clinical Trials Network [NCTN], el Programa Comunitario de Investigación Oncológica del NCI (NCI Community Oncology Research Program [NCORP]) y la Red de Ensayos Clínicos Terapéuticos Experimentales (Experimental Therapeutics Clinical Trials Network [ETCTN]). El NCI también financia total o parcialmente los ensayos que se realizan en los centros oncológicos asignados por el NCI en todos los Estados Unidos y los ensayos que se realizan en el Centro Clínico (Clinical Center) del NIH en Bethesda, Maryland.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2015-10-07</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
