<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000740854"><TermName>hereditary paraganglioma-pheochromocytoma syndrome</TermName><TermPronunciation>(heh-REH-dih-tayr-ee PAYR-uh-GANG-glee-OH-muh-FEE-oh-KROH-moh-sy-TOH-muh SIN-drome)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A rare, genetic disorder marked by tumors called paragangliomas, which are found in paraganglia. Paraganglia are groups of nerve-like cells found near the adrenal glands and near blood vessels or nerves in the head, neck, chest, abdomen, and pelvis. Paragangliomas that form in the adrenal glands are called pheochromocytomas. Paragangliomas are usually benign (not cancer), but sometimes become malignant (cancerous).  People with hereditary paraganglioma-pheochromocytoma syndrome usually have more than one paraganglioma, and may have an increased risk of certain types of cancer, such as kidney cancer and thyroid cancer.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000745274" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;hereditary paraganglioma-pheochromocytoma syndrome&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000745273" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;síndrome hereditario de paraganglioma-feocromocitoma&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>síndrome hereditario de paraganglioma-feocromocitoma</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno genético poco frecuente que se caracteriza por tumores se llaman paragangliomas, los cuales se encuentran en la paraganglia.   La paraganglia está formada por grupos de células similares a los nervios que se encuentran cerca de las glándulas suprarrenales y los vasos sanguíneos o nervios cercanos de la cabeza, el cuello, el pecho, el abdomen y la pelvis.   Los paragangliomas son generalmente benignos (no cancerosos), pero a veces se pueden volver malignos (cancerosos).   Las personas con el síndrome hereditario de paraganglioma-feocromocitoma tienen habitualmente más de un paraganglioma y pueden tener un riesgo más alto de ciertos tipos de cáncer, como el cáncer de riñón y el cáncer de tiroides.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2012-11-21</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
