<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000748137"><TermName>cardiovascular disease</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KAR-dee-oh-VAS-kyoo-ler dih-ZEEZ)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of disease that affects the heart or blood vessels. The risk of certain cardiovascular diseases may be increased by smoking, high blood pressure, high cholesterol, unhealthy diet, lack of exercise, and obesity. The most common cardiovascular disease is coronary artery disease (narrow or blocked coronary arteries), which can lead to chest pain, heart attacks, or stroke. Other  cardiovascular diseases include congestive heart failure, heart rhythm problems, congenital heart disease (heart disease at birth), and endocarditis (inflamed inner layer of the heart). Also called heart disease.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752537" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cardiovascular disease&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752538" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;enfermedad cardiovascular&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>enfermedad cardiovascular</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de enfermedad que afecta el corazón o los vasos sanguíneos. El riesgo de ciertas enfermedades cardiovasculares puede aumentar por consumo de productos del tabaco, presión arterial alta, colesterol alto, mala alimentación, falta de ejercicio u obesidad. La enfermedad cardiovascular más común es la enfermedad de la arteria coronaria (arteria coronaria estrecha u obstruida), que puede producir dolor de pecho, ataques cardíacos o derrame cerebral. Otras enfermedades cardiovasculares son  la insuficiencia cardíaca congestiva, los problemas del ritmo cardiaco, la enfermedad cardiaca congénita (enfermedad cardiaca desde el nacimiento) y la endocarditis (inflamación de la capa interna del corazón). También se llama cardiopatía.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-07-17</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2013-07-12</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
