<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000774492"><TermName>testicular tissue freezing</TermName><TermPronunciation>(tes-TIH-kyoo-ler TIH-shoo FREE-zing)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A process being developed to freeze testicular tissue from boys who have not gone through puberty, to save for future infertility treatment. Tissue that contains cells that make sperm is removed from the testicles through a small incision (cut). It is then frozen and stored. At a later date, the tissue can be thawed to retrieve sperm. Testicular tissue freezing is being studied as a type of fertility preservation. It may be useful for young boys who are going to have treatments that may cause infertility, such as certain cancer treatments. Also called testicular tissue cryopreservation.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000776489" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;testicular tissue freezing&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000776488" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;congelación de tejido testicular&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>congelación de tejido testicular</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Proceso que se está perfeccionando para congelar tejido de los testículos de varones jóvenes que no llegaron a la pubertad, a fin de  guardarlo para usarlo en futuros tratamientos de esterilidad. Se extrae de los testículos el tejido que contiene las células que elaboran los espermatozoides mediante una pequeña incisión (corte). Luego se congela y se guarda. En una fecha posterior, el tejido se descongela para extraer esperma.   La congelación de tejido testicular está en estudio como un tipo de preservación de la fertilidad. Esta puede ser útil para los varones jóvenes que se someterán a tratamientos que pueden causar esterilidad, como ciertos tipos de tratamientos del cáncer. También se llama criopreservación de tejido testicular.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2015-09-16</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2015-09-29</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
