<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000733789"><TermName>childhood cancer risk group</TermName><TermPronunciation>(… KAN-ser risk groop)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A group of children with cancer that has been formed based on certain characteristics of the children and their disease.  These may include age at diagnosis, stage of cancer, and cancer biology. Risk groups may also be based on the chance of being cured or the chance that the cancer will come back. Childhood cancer risk groups are used to plan treatment and follow-up care for certain types of cancer, such as neuroblastoma and rhabdomyosarcoma. Risk groups may be described as low risk, intermediate risk, or high risk. </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000741037" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;childhood cancer risk group&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000741036" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;grupo de riesgo de cáncer infantil&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>grupo de riesgo de cáncer infantil</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Grupo de niños con cáncer el cual se  forma según ciertas características de los niños y su enfermedad. Estas pueden incluir la edad en el momento del diagnóstico, el estadio del cáncer y la biología del cáncer. Los grupos de riesgo también se pueden basar sobre la probabilidad de curación o la probabilidad de que el cáncer vuelva. Los grupos de riesgo de cáncer infantil se usan para planificar el tratamiento y la atención de seguimiento de ciertos tipos de cáncer, como el neuroblastoma y el rabdomiosarcoma. Los grupos de riesgo se pueden describir como de riesgo bajo, riesgo intermedio o riesgo alto.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2012-08-14</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
