<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000748157"><TermName>chronic cough</TermName><TermPronunciation>(KRAH-nik kof)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A cough that lasts for 8 weeks or longer. It may occur with other symptoms, including a runny or stuffy nose, extra mucus in the back of the throat, wheezing, shortness of breath, or heartburn. A chronic cough may be caused by allergies, sinus infections, asthma, gastroesophageal reflux disease (GERD), or other conditions. It may also be caused by smoking tobacco or by breathing in secondhand tobacco smoke over a long period of time. It usually improves when the problem that caused the cough is treated. For example, a chronic cough may get better when a person quits smoking.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752558" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;chronic cough&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752557" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tos crónica&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>tos crónica</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tos que dura ocho semanas o más. Se puede presentar con otros síntomas, como secreción o congestión nasal, más mucosidad en la parte posterior de la garganta, respiración sibilante, falta de aire o acidez estomacal. La tos crónica puede ser causada por alergias, sinusitis, asma, enfermedad por reflujo gastroesofágico (ERGE) u otras afecciones. También puede ser causada por el consumo directo de tabaco o por la inhalación de humo de tabaco en el ambiente durante un período largo. Por lo general, mejora cuando se trata el problema que causó la tos. Por ejemplo, una tos crónica puede mejorar cuando una persona deja de fumar.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-07-17</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
