<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000753530"><TermName>testosterone flare</TermName><TermPronunciation>(tes-TOS-teh-rone flayr)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A temporary
          increase in testosterone levels in the body caused by
          certain types of hormone therapy used to treat prostate
          cancer. A testosterone flare may occur in patients who are
          taking drugs called gonadotropin-releasing hormone (GnRH)
          agonists. When first given, these drugs cause the testicles
          to make more testosterone. This may cause symptoms, such as
          bone pain and urinary problems, to get worse, but they
          usually go away after the first few weeks of treatment.
          </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000757974" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;testosterone flare&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000757973" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;repunte de testosterona&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>repunte de testosterona</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Elevación temporal de las concentraciones de testosterona en el cuerpo debido a
           ciertos tipos de tratamientos hormonales que se usan para tratar el cáncer de próstata. Se puede presentar un repunte de testosterona en pacientes que toman medicamentos que se llaman agonistas de la hormona liberadora de gonadotropina (HLGn). Cuando se administran por primera vez, estos medicamentos hacen que los testículos
           elaboren más testosterona. Esto puede causar que síntomas como
           el dolor en los huesos y  problemas urinarios empeoren; sin embargo, estos síntomas generalmente desaparecen después de las primeras semanas de tratamiento.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-11-26</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/prostate/prostate-hormone-therapy-fact-sheet">Hormone Therapy for Prostate Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/prostata/hoja-informativa-terapia-hormonal">Terapia hormonal para el cáncer de próstata</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
