<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000710543"><TermName>brentuximab vedotin</TermName><TermPronunciation>(bren-TUK-sih-mab veh-DOH-tin)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat Hodgkin lymphoma in patients who did not get better with other treatment, cannot be treated with autologous stem cell transplant  (ASCT), or  have a high risk that the cancer will come back or get worse after ASCT. It is also used to treat systemic anaplastic large cell lymphoma that did not get better with other treatment. It is also being studied in the treatment of other types of lymphoma. Brentuximab vedotin is made up of a monoclonal antibody linked to an anticancer drug. It binds to a protein called CD30, which is on the surface of some lymphoma cells, and may kill cancer cells. Brentuximab vedotin is a type of antibody-drug conjugate. Also called Adcetris and SGN-35.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733253" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;brentuximab vedotin&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000733254" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;brentuximab vedotina&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>brentuximab vedotina</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para tratar el linfoma de Hodgkin en pacientes que no mejoraron con otro tratamiento, que no pueden ser tratados con trasplante autógeno de células madre (TACM), o que tienen riesgo alto de que el cáncer vuelva o empeore después del trasplante. También se usa para tratar el linfoma anaplásico de células grandes  sistémico en pacientes que no mejoraron con otro tratamiento. También está en estudio para el tratamiento de otros tipos de linfoma. La brentuximab vedotina se elabora combinando un anticuerpo monoclonal con un medicamento contra el cáncer. Se une a una proteína que se llama CD30, que está en la superficie de algunas células de linfoma, y puede destruir células cancerosas. La brentuximab vedotina es un tipo de conjugado de fármaco y anticuerpo. También se llama Adcetris y SGN-35.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2011-09-12</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2015-08-31</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000709777">Brentuximab Vedotin</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
