<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000743063"><TermName>tobacco tar</TermName><TermPronunciation>(tuh-BA-koh tar)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A chemical substance made when tobacco is burned. Tar contains most of the cancer-causing and other harmful chemicals found in tobacco smoke. When tobacco smoke is inhaled, the tar can form a sticky layer on the inside of the lungs. This damages the lungs and may lead to lung cancer, emphysema, or other lung problems. Cigarettes and other smoked tobacco products may produce different amounts of tar, depending on how they are made. Inhaling tobacco smoke also causes other types of cancer, including cancers of the mouth and throat.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000746273" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;tobacco tar&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000746272" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;alquitrán del tabaco&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>alquitrán del tabaco</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Sustancia química que se produce cuando se quema el tabaco. El alquitrán contiene la mayoría de las sustancias químicas que causan cáncer y otras sustancias químicas nocivas del humo de tabaco. Cuando se inhala el humo de tabaco, el alquitrán forma una capa pegajosa en el interior de los pulmones. Esto daña los pulmones y puede conducir a un cáncer de pulmón, enfisema u otros problemas pulmonares. Los cigarrillos y otros productos del tabaco que se fuman pueden producir distintas cantidades de alquitrán, según cómo se elaboren. La inhalación del humo de tabaco también causa oros tipos de cáncer, como los cánceres de boca y garganta. </DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-01-15</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/risk/tobacco">Tobacco</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/riesgo/tabaco">Tabaco</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
