<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000732578"><TermName>human leukocyte antigen matching</TermName><TermPronunciation>(HYOO-mun LOO-koh-site AN-tih-jen MA-ching)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A process in which blood or tissue samples are tested for human leukocyte antigens (HLAs). HLAs are molecules found on the surface of most cells in the body. They make up a person’s tissue type, which varies from person to person. They play an important part in the body's immune response to foreign substances. Human leukocyte antigen matching is done before a donor stem cell or organ transplant to find out if tissues match between the donor and the person receiving the transplant. Also called HLA matching.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000740993" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;human leukocyte antigen matching&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000740992" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;compatibilidad de antígenos leucocitarios humanos&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>compatibilidad de antígenos leucocitarios humanos</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Proceso mediante el cual se prueban muestras de sangre o tejido para determinar los antígenos leucocitarios humanos (HLA) presentes.   Los HLA son moléculas que se encuentran en la superficie de la mayoría de las células del cuerpo.   Conforman el tipo de tejido de una persona, que varía de una a otra. Desempeñan una  función  importante en la respuesta inmunitaria del cuerpo ante las sustancias extrañas. La compatibilidad de antígenos leucocitarios humanos se realiza antes de un trasplante de células madre o de  un órgano de un donante para determinar si son compatibles los tejidos del donante y los de la persona que recibe el trasplante. También se llama compatibilidad del ALH.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2012-08-15</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
