<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000756462"><TermName>siltuximab</TermName><TermPronunciation>(sil-TUK-sih-mab)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat a rare condition called Castleman disease in patients who do not have HIV or human herpesvirus 8. It is also being studied in the treatment of multiple myeloma. Siltuximab binds to a protein called interleukin-6 (IL-6), which is made by some white blood cells and other cells in the body. Siltuximab may help reduce inflammation and stop the growth of cancer cells or abnormal blood cells. It is a type of monoclonal antibody.  Also called anti-IL-6 chimeric monoclonal antibody, cCLB8, CNTO 328,  and Sylvant.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000760880" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;siltuximab&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000760879" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;siltuximab&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>siltuximab</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Sustancia en estudio para el tratamiento de una afección rara llamada enfermedad de Castleman en pacientes que no tienen el VIH o el virus del herpes 8. También está en estudio para el tratamiento del mieloma múltiple. El siltuximab se une a una proteína que se llama interleucina-6 (IL-6), elaborada por algunos glóbulos blancos y otras células del cuerpo. El siltuximab podría ayudar a reducir la inflamación, así como impedir la formación de células cancerosas o de células sanguíneas anormales. Es un tipo de anticuerpo monoclonal. También se llama anticuerpo monoclonal quimérico anti-IL-6, cCLB8, CNTO 328,  y Sylvant.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2014-03-10</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2014-05-07</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000760470">Siltuximab</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
