<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000772812"><TermName>bone scintigraphy</TermName><TermPronunciation>(... sin-TIH-gruh-fee)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure to check for abnormal areas or damage in the bones. A very small amount of radioactive material is injected into a vein and travels through the blood. The radioactive material collects in the bones and is detected by a scanner (a special camera that takes pictures of the inside of the body). A bone scintigraphy may be used to diagnose bone tumors or cancer that has spread to the bone. It may also be used to help diagnose fractures, bone infections, or other bone problems. Also called bone scan.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000773727" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;bone scintigraphy&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000773728" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;centellografía ósea&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000466541" type="image/jpeg" alt="Bone scan; drawing shows patient lying on a table that slides under the scanner, a technician operating the scanner, and a monitor that will show images made during the scan." language="en" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_4"><Caption language="en">Bone scan. A small amount of radioactive material is injected into the patient's bloodstream and collects in abnormal cells in the bones. As the patient lies on a table that slides under the scanner, the radioactive material is detected and images are made on a computer screen or film.</Caption></MediaLink><MediaLink ref="CDR0000742469" type="image/jpeg" alt="Exploración ósea; la figura muestra al paciente acostado sobre una camilla que se desliza bajo un escáner, un técnico que maneja el escáner y una pantalla que mostrará imágenes durante la exploración." language="es" audience="Patients" thumb="Yes" id="_5"><Caption language="es">Exploración ósea. Se inyecta una cantidad pequeña de material radiactivo en el torrente sanguíneo del paciente. El material radiactivo se acumula en las células anormales de los huesos. Mientras el paciente está acostado sobre una camilla que se desliza debajo del escáner, se detecta el material radiactivo y se crean imágenes en la pantalla de una computadora o en una película.</Caption></MediaLink><SpanishTermName>centellografía ósea</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento para identificar áreas anormales  o dañadas de los huesos. Se inyecta en una vena una cantidad muy pequeña de material radiactivo que fluye a través de la sangre. El material radiactivo se acumula en los huesos y se detecta con un escáner (una cámara especial que toma imágenes del interior del cuerpo).  La centellografía ósea se puede usar para diagnosticar tumores óseos o cáncer que se diseminó al hueso. También se puede usar para diagnosticar fracturas, infecciones  óseas u otros problemas en los huesos.  También se llama exploración ósea.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2015-06-01</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2015-06-01</DateLastModified></GlossaryTerm>
