<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000748114"><TermName>glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase deficiency</TermName><TermPronunciation>(GLOO-kose-6-FOS-fayt dee-hy-DRAH-jeh-nays deh-FIH-shun-see)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>An inherited disorder in which a person doesn’t have enough of an enzyme called G6PD that helps red blood cells work the way they should. In glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase deficiency, the red blood cells break down when the body is exposed to infection, severe stress, or certain drugs, chemicals, or foods. This may lead to a condition called hemolytic anemia. This disorder is most common in African-American men and in men of Middle Eastern or Mediterranean descent. Also called G6PD deficiency.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752911" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary&#10;         term &quot;glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase deficiency&quot;" language="en" id="_4"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752514" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;deficiencia de glucosa-6-fosfato deshidrogenasa&quot;" language="es" id="_3"/><SpanishTermName>deficiencia de glucosa-6-fosfato deshidrogenasa</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Trastorno hereditario en el que una persona no tiene suficiente cantidad de una enzima que se llama G6PD, que ayuda a que los glóbulos rojos funcionen bien. En el caso de la deficiencia de glucosa-6-fosfato deshidrogenasa, los glóbulos rojos se  descomponen cuando el cuerpo está expuesto a  infección, estrés grave o ciertos medicamentos, productos químicos o alimentos.   Esto puede conducir a una afección que se llama anemia hemolítica.   Este trastorno es sumamente frecuente en los hombres Estadounidenses de raza negra y en los hombres de ascendencia del Oriente Medio o mediterránea.   También se llama deficiencia de G6PD.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-05-09</DateFirstPublished></GlossaryTerm>
