<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000767370"><TermName>lanreotide acetate</TermName><TermPronunciation>(lan-REE-oh-tide A-seh-tayt)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A drug used to treat gastroenteropancreatic neuroendocrine tumors that are advanced or have spread to other parts of the body. These tumors form in the stomach, small and large intestines, rectum, and pancreas. Lanreotide acetate is used for tumors that cannot be removed by surgery. It is also used to treat some patients with acromegaly (a condition in which the pituitary gland makes too much growth hormone). Lanreotide acetate is like somatostatin (a hormone made by the body), and may help stop the body from making extra amounts of certain hormones, including growth hormone, insulin, glucagon, and hormones that affect digestion. It may also help keep certain types of tumor cells from growing. Lanreotide acetate is a type of somatostatin analog. Also called Somatuline Depot.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000769337" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;lanreotide acetate&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000769336" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;acetato de lanreotida&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>acetato de lanreotida</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Medicamento que se usa para  el tratamiento de tumores neuroendocrinos gastroenteropancreáticos en estadio avanzado o que se diseminaron a otras partes del cuerpo. Estos tumores se forman en el estómago, los intestinos delgado y grueso, el recto y el páncreas. El acetato de lanreotida se usa para los tumores que  no se pueden extirpar mediante cirugía. También se usa para tratar a algunos pacientes de acromegalia (afección por la que la hipófisis elabora demasiada hormona del crecimiento). El acetato de lanreotida es como la somatostatina (hormona elaborada por el cuerpo), y puede ayudar a impedir que el cuerpo elabore cantidades excesivas de ciertas hormonas, como la hormona del crecimiento, la insulina, el glucagón y las hormonas que afectan la digestión. También puede prevenir el crecimiento de ciertos tipos de células tumorales. El acetato de lanreotida es un tipo de análogo de la somatostatina. También se llama Somatulina Depot.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2014-12-22</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedDrugSummaryRef href="CDR0000767468">Lanreotide Acetate</RelatedDrugSummaryRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
