<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000748244"><TermName>light cigarette</TermName><TermPronunciation>(lite SIH-guh-ret)</TermPronunciation><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A type of cigarette that is claimed to give off less tobacco tar than a regular cigarette when smoked. Light cigarettes have been shown to be no safer than regular cigarettes, and smoking them does not lower the risk of cancer or other diseases. A person smoking a light cigarette can inhale the same amount of tobacco tar, nicotine, and harmful, cancer-causing chemicals as in a regular cigarette, depending on how the cigarette is smoked. Cigarettes are no longer allowed to be labeled or advertised as light cigarettes. Also called low tar cigarette.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752585" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;light cigarette&quot;" language="en" id="_3"/><MediaLink ref="CDR0000752584" type="audio/mpeg" alt="Pronunciation of dictionary term &quot;cigarrillo light&quot;" language="es" id="_4"/><SpanishTermName>cigarrillo light</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Tipo de cigarrillo del que se asegura que emite menos alquitrán de tabaco que un cigarrillo normal cuando se fuma. Los cigarrillos light  han mostrado que no son más seguros que los cigarrillos convencionales  y que fumarlos no reduce el riesgo de cáncer u otras enfermedades. Una persona que fuma un cigarrillo light puede inhalar la misma cantidad de alquitrán de tabaco, nicotina y sustancias químicas dañinas que causan cáncer  que en un cigarrillo normal, según cómo se fume el cigarrillo. Ya no está permitido etiquetar o publicitar los cigarrillos como cigarrillos light. También se llama cigarrillo bajo en alquitrán.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2013-07-17</DateFirstPublished><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/risk/tobacco/light-cigarettes-fact-sheet">"Light" Cigarettes and Cancer Risk</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/riesgo/tabaco/hoja-informativa-cigarillos-light">Los cigarrillos "light" y el riesgo de cáncer
</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
