<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE GlossaryTerm >
<GlossaryTerm id="CDR0000766286"><TermName>Pap/HPV cotest</TermName><TermDefinition><DefinitionText>A procedure in which a human papillomavirus (HPV) test and a Pap test are done at the same time to check for cervical cancer. The HPV test looks for DNA or RNA from certain high-risk types of HPV in samples of cells taken from the cervix. The Pap test checks for cervical cancer cells and cell changes that may lead to cervical cancer. The same cell sample may be used for both the HPV test and the Pap test. Women aged 30 to 65 years may have a Pap/HPV cotest every 5 years. Cotesting is more likely to find abnormal cells or cervical cancer than a Pap test alone is. Also called HPV/Pap cotest.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></TermDefinition><SpanishTermName>prueba conjunta de Pap y VPH</SpanishTermName><SpanishTermDefinition><DefinitionText>Procedimiento en el que se realizan al mismo tiempo una prueba de virus del papiloma humano (VPH) y una prueba de Pap para determinar si hay cáncer de cuello uterino. Con la prueba de VPH, se busca ADN o ARN de ciertos tipos de VPH de riesgo alto en muestras de células del cuello uterino. Con la prueba de Pap, se busca identificar células cancerosas de cuello uterino o cambios en las células que puedan causar este tipo de cáncer. Se puede usar la misma muestra de células tanto para la prueba de VPH como para la prueba de Pap. Las mujeres entre 30 y 65 años se deben realizar una prueba conjunta de Pap y VPH cada 5 años. Es más probable encontrar células anormales o cáncer de cuello uterino con una prueba conjunta que con la prueba de Pap solamente. También se llama prueba conjunta de VPH y Pap.</DefinitionText><Dictionary>Cancer.gov</Dictionary><Audience>Patient</Audience></SpanishTermDefinition><DateFirstPublished>2014-11-10</DateFirstPublished><DateLastModified>2014-11-10</DateLastModified><RelatedInformation><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/types/cervical/pap-hpv-testing-fact-sheet">Pap and HPV testing</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="en" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/causes-prevention/risk/infectious-agents/hpv-fact-sheet">HPV and Cancer</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/tipos/cuello-uterino/hoja-informativa-prueba-pap-vph">Pruebas de Papanicolaou y del virus del papiloma humano (VPH)
</RelatedExternalRef><RelatedExternalRef UseWith="es" xref="http://www.cancer.gov/espanol/cancer/causas-prevencion/riesgo/germenes-infecciosos/hoja-informativa-vph">Virus del papiloma humano y el cáncer
</RelatedExternalRef></RelatedInformation></GlossaryTerm>
